<bill session="114" type="s" number="427" updated="2018-06-02T06:33:13Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Domestic Reduction In Vehicle Expenditure and Lowering Emissions from State Sources Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DRIVE LESS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reduce the number of nonessential vehicles purchased and leased by the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">DRIVE LESS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2015-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2015-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2015-02-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3111"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2354"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Domestic Reduction In Vehicle Expenditure and Lowering Emissions from State Sources Act of 2015 or the DRIVE LESS Act

Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to determine: (1) the total number of civilian vehicles purchased and leased by each executive agency in FY2010, (2) the total dollar amount obligated by each executive agency to purchase and to lease civilian vehicles in FY2010, and (3) the amount that would be 20% less than such total dollar amount. Prohibits each executive agency from obligating more than the reduced dollar amount for FY2010 to purchase and lease civilian vehicles in each of FY2016-FY2020. Exempts the purchase or procurement of any vehicle determined by the President to be essential for reasons of national security.

Directs the Administrator of General Services to ensure that agencies may share excess or unused vehicles for temporary or long-term use through the Federal Fleet Management System.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
