<bill session="115" type="s" number="1473" updated="2019-04-18T16:37:36Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for a five-year extension to the homeless veterans reintegration programs and to provide clarification regarding eligibility for services under such programs.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Homeless Veterans' Reintegration Programs Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Homeless Veterans&#8217; Reintegration Programs Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Homeless Veterans' Reintegration Programs Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001236"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2017-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="4451"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Homeless Veterans' Reintegration Programs Reauthorization Act of 2017

This bill extends through FY2022 the Department of Labor's: (1) homeless veterans reintegration programs, and (2) homeless women veterans and homeless veterans with children reintegration grant program.

Currently, the homeless veterans reintegration programs provide job training, counseling, and placement services to expedite the reintegration of homeless veterans into the labor force. The bill expands eligibility for the programs to include: (1) veterans participating in the Department of Housing and Urban Development-Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) Supportive Housing Program, (2) Native American veterans receiving assistance under the Native American Housing Assistance and Self Determination Act of 1996, (3) veterans who are transitioning from being incarcerated, and (4) veterans participating in the VA's Supportive Services for Veteran Families Program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
