<bill session="114" type="s" number="1509" updated="2018-06-02T06:54:58Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Treat and Reduce Obesity Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for the coordination of programs to prevent and treat obesity, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Treat and Reduce Obesity Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2016-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2015-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2015-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2015-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2015-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2016-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2015-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2015-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2015-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2015-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2015-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2015-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2016-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="2404"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-04T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Treat and Reduce Obesity Act of 2015

Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to authorize the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), in addition to qualified primary care physicians and other primary care practitioners, to cover intensive behavioral therapy for obesity furnished by: (1) a physician who is not a qualified primary care physician; (2) an evidence-based, community-based HHS-approved lifestyle counseling program; or (3) any other appropriate health care provider (including a physician assistant, nurse practitioner, clinical nurse specialist, a clinical psychologist, and a registered dietitian or nutrition professional).

Allows coverage of intensive behavioral therapy for obesity furnished by another appropriate health care provider or program only if it is furnished: (1) upon referral from, and in coordination with, a physician or primary care practitioner in a primary care or other HHS-specified setting; and (2) in an office setting, a hospital outpatient department, a community-based site that complies with the federal regulations concerning the privacy of individually identifiable health information, or another HHS-specified setting.

Authorizes HHS to cover under Medicare part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) medication for treatment of obesity or for weight loss management for an overweight individual with one or more related comorbidities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
