<bill session="114" type="s" number="2833" updated="2018-06-02T07:16:54Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Visa Transparency Anti-Trafficking Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend section 214(c)(8) of the Immigration and Nationality Act to modify the data reporting requirements relating to nonimmigrant employees, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Visa Transparency Anti-Trafficking Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2016-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5006"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Visa Transparency Anti-Trafficking Act of 2016

This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to expand nonimmigrant employer annual data reporting requirements to include all nonimmigrant worker categories and compensated cultural exchange, training, and business classifications.

Expanded reporting requirements include information regarding: (1) the age and gender of admitted nonimmigrants, (2) categories and numbers of visas issued, (3) numbers of persons admitted under each visa classification and subclassification, (4) blanket petitions, (5) the occupation and country of origin of beneficiaries, (6) nonimmigrant worker employers, (7) compensation, and (8) citizens of nations with Compacts of Free Association with the United States who are authorized to reside permanently in the United States as nonimmigrants and their ports of U.S. entry.

The Department of Labor shall: (1) submit such report and post the information along with the corresponding raw data and a searchable database to a public website, and (2) ensure that such posted information does not include information that would identify a specific person with reasonable certainty.

Any government official who uses such information shall take steps to: (1) protect individual identities, and (2) prevent the information from being disaggregated into its component parts.

 The Department of State or the Department of Homeland Security, if requested by Labor, shall share information necessary for Labor to file its annual report regarding employer petitions for H-, P-, O-, and Q-visa nonimmigrant aliens.

"Employment" means employment in the United States and includes cultural exchanges, training, or business activities for which the nonimmigrant receives any form of compensation.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
