<bill session="114" type="h" number="5699" updated="2019-04-11T15:42:42Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To award grants to school food authorities for the purchase of equipment for school meal programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Serve More Kids Act</title>
    <title type="display">Serve More Kids Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001160"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2016-07-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-08T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Serve More Kids Act 

This bill amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act and the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to make several changes to the Department of Agriculture's (USDA's) child nutrition programs.

USDA must: (1) award equipment assistance grants to states for the school lunch and breakfast programs, (2) provide commodity assistance to states for the School Breakfast Program (SBP), and (3) establish a pilot program for providing a third daily meal under the Summer Food Service Program (SFSP).

USDA may waive or modify the verification sample size requirements under the National School Lunch Program for local educational agencies that demonstrate that the requirement would increase the number of eligible children losing access to benefits or have a disproportionate and adverse impact on vulnerable populations such as migrants and homeless youth.

USDA may grant a request to allow children to consume SFSP meals off-site due to specified factors, including extreme weather, violence and other public safety concerns, or efforts to support innovative meal delivery methods to address transportation barriers and low program participation in rural areas.

The bill modifies the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC) to:

 specify that the food must be nutritious; specify certification periods for breastfeeding women, infants, and postpartum women; require state agencies to submit plans and distribute information related to improving access for members of the Armed Forces; and require USDA to provide additional annual performance bonus payments to state agencies for improving the proportion of breast-fed infants participating in the program. The bill also reauthorizes USDA grants to states for expanding school breakfast programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
