<bill session="113" type="h" number="4106" updated="2016-10-25T16:11:07Z">
  <state datetime="2014-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Saving Lives, Saving Costs Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the development and dissemination of clinical practice guidelines and the establishment of a right of removal to Federal courts for defendants in medical malpractice actions involving a Federal payor, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Saving Lives, Saving Costs Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001282"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000013" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001287" joined="2014-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001255" joined="2014-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001289" joined="2014-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001077" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2014-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000548" joined="2014-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000567" joined="2014-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001065" joined="2014-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001180" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001187" joined="2014-07-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000588" joined="2014-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000606" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000591" joined="2014-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000587" joined="2014-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000582" joined="2014-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000592" joined="2014-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001187" joined="2014-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="State and local courts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-02-27T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Saving Lives, Saving Costs Act - Establishes a framework for health care liability lawsuits to undergo review by independent medical review panels if health care professionals (practicing physicians or their agents or employees) allege adherence to applicable clinical practice guidelines in the provision of health care goods or services.

Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to publish clinical practice guidelines that have been provided and maintained by national or state medical societies or medical specialty societies designated by the Secretary. Sets forth standards for the development of guidelines, including related to transparency, the composition of the panel, and the review of existing evidence.

Declares that this Act does not preempt or supersede any state or federal law that imposes greater procedural or substantive protections for health care providers and health care organizations from liability, loss, or damages than those provided under this Act nor does it create a cause of action or preempt any defenses otherwise available.

Allows a defendant to remove any health care liability action brought in a state court to a district court.

Requires an independent medical review in health care liability actions if the eligible professionals allege that they adhered to applicable clinical practice guideline. Sets forth procedures for the use of the panel's findings at trial. Enables defendants to recover costs and attorneys' fees from plaintiffs if the defendants prevail subsequent to preliminary findings in their favor.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
