<bill session="115" type="h" number="6673" updated="2019-04-18T16:26:58Z">
  <state datetime="2018-08-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-08-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-08-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that certain requirements are included before tolls can be collected on certain routes, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">I-5 Corridor Cooperation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">I&#8211;5 Corridor Cooperation Act</title>
    <title type="display">I-5 Corridor Cooperation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001056"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-08-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-08-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-08-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Highways and Transit" code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-08-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">I-5 Corridor Cooperation Act

 This bill prohibits tolls of any kind from being collected along Interstate 5 and Interstate 205 between State Route 500 in the state of Washington and U.S. Route 30 in the state of Oregon for any purpose unless: (1) the economic impact study required by this bill is completed; and (2) the governors of such states sign an agreement to allow the collection of a toll in those areas.

The Federal Highway Administration, as part of any review process that may be required by the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 for the proposed project to toll Interstate 5 and Interstate 205 between Portland, Oregon, and Vancouver, Washington, shall conduct an economic impact study examining the impact of tolls, including any value pricing tolls, on businesses, communities, and federally-recognized Indian Tribes within Clark and Cowlitz counties in Washington.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
