<bill session="114" type="s" number="79" updated="2018-06-02T06:29:10Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Remittance Status Verification Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to impose a fine with respect to international remittance transfers if the sender is unable to verify legal status in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Remittance Status Verification Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000127"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Remittance Status Verification Act of 2015

Amends the Electronic Fund Transfer Act to require a remittance transfer provider, before initiating a transfer, to request from the sender of a remittance whose recipient is located in a country other than the United States proof of the sender's status under U.S. immigration laws.

Cites admissible documentation attesting to the sender's status, including a state-issued driver's license or federal passport.

Directs a remittance transfer provider to impose, upon any sender unable to provide such proof of status, a fine equal to 7% of the U.S. dollar amount to be transferred.

Requires submission to the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau of all fines imposed and collected by a remittance transfer provider in order to pay the administrative and enforcement costs of implementing this Act.

Requires the Comptroller General to study the effects of the enactment of this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
