<bill session="114" type="h" number="4529" updated="2018-11-09T00:09:25Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Social Security Parent Penalty Repeal Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title II of the Social Security Act to provide for an annual increase in the contribution and benefit base, to exclude a certain number of childcare years from the benefit computation formula, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Social Security Parent Penalty Repeal Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000370" joined="2016-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001281" joined="2016-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2016-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2016-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2016-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2016-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000130" joined="2016-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Social Security" code="HSWM01" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Social Security Administration"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Social Security Parent Penalty Repeal Act 

 This bill amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to direct the Social Security Administration to determine and publish in the Federal Register on or before November 1 of each year a revised contribution and benefit base, which shall be effective with respect to remuneration paid in subsequent calendar and taxable years. The bill also revises the formula for determining that base.

The number of an individual's benefit computation years, for the purpose of determining the individual's primary OASDI insurance amount, shall be further reduced (after a specified initial reduction) by the number of the individual's childcare years (not exceeding five), except that not more than two years may be determined to be a childcare year on the basis of the individual's status as a primary caregiver for the same child.

"Childcare year" means an elapsed year of the individual:

 during which the individual is the primary caregiver for a child under age 6, and for which the total of the individual's wages and self-employment income is $0.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
