<bill session="114" type="s" number="1653" updated="2018-06-02T06:56:42Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Equalizing the Playing Field for Agents and Brokers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to enhance access for independent agents and brokers to information regarding marketplace enrollment.</title>
    <title type="display">Equalizing the Playing Field for Agents and Brokers Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001075"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Equalizing the Playing Field for Agents and Brokers Act

 Directs the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a toll-free customer service support help line to enable certified health insurance agents and brokers to seek assistance regarding qualified health plans offered in the federal health insurance marketplace.

Amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to require HHS to:

 make available on the federal government website for health insurance coverage a list of all certified agents and brokers; contract with the National Insurance Producers Registry to regularly verify the licensure status of all such agents and brokers and develop a mechanism to enable submission of changes to contact and licensure information; and provide trained navigators, agents, and brokers, no later than five business days after promulgation or issuance of any new cost- or enrollment-related policies, with a clear description of such policy changes.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
