<bill session="115" type="s" number="1410" updated="2019-04-18T16:37:21Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to further the development of unmanned aircraft system technology through investing in additional research, building a trained workforce, and establishing working groups to address near-term and long-term challenges, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Development, Research, and Opportunities Needed for Entrepreneurship Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Development, Research, and Opportunities Needed for Entrepreneurship Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe DRONE Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe DRONE Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Safe DRONE Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000805"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2017-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2017-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2017-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Safe Development, Research, and Opportunities Needed for Entrepreneurship Act of 2017 or the Safe DRONE Act of 2017

This bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT), in coordination with the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) and industry stakeholders, to develop an implementation plan to achieve full operational capability of unmanned aircraft systems traffic management and to ensure the safety and security of all aircraft..

DOT shall designate consortia of public, two-year institutions of higher education as Community and Technical College Centers of Excellence in Small Unmanned Aircraft System Technology Training.

The FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 is amended to extend the pilot program for the integration of unmanned aircraft systems into the National Airspace System through September 30, 2024. The bill permits the operation of unmanned aircraft (i.e., drones) without specific operating authority from the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) if specified conditions apply, such as if the aircraft is flown strictly for hobby or recreational use.

The FAA shall: (1) initiate a process to periodically update the operational parameters for drones, and (2) maintain on its website a list of community-based organizations under which small drones may be operated.

The bill requires the Government Accountability Office to report on developments and protections relating to cybersecurity and operational control concerns with respect to drones.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
