<bill session="114" type="s" number="1379" updated="2018-06-02T06:54:05Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">African Free Trade Initiative Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the African Growth and Opportunity Act to require the development of a plan for each sub-Saharan African country for negotiating and entering into free trade agreements and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">African Free Trade Initiative Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000024"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2015-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-19T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">African Free Trade Initiative Act

This bill amends the African Growth and Opportunity Act to revise certain plan and reporting requirements relating to the President's negotiating and entering into free trade agreements with interested beneficiary sub-Saharan African countries.

The President shall develop a plan for negotiating and entering into one or more free trade agreements with 15 of the sub-Saharan African countries that are most ready for a free trade agreement with the United States.

The United States Trade Representative and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) shall coordinate with the Millennium Challenge Corporation regarding countries with shared development objectives that have entered into a Millennium Challenge Compact in order to develop and carry out such plans.

USAID long-term development assistance funds for sub-Saharan Africa may be used to:

 carry out plans, including deployment of resources in individual eligible sub-Saharan African countries to assist them in the development of institutional capacities to carry out those plans; and coordinate U.S. efforts to establish free trade agreements in order to increase trade between the United States and sub-Saharan African countries, as well as investment in those countries.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
