<bill session="114" type="s" number="2768" updated="2018-06-02T07:16:27Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clean Water Affordability Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to update a program to provide assistance for the planning, design, and construction of treatment works to intercept, transport, control, or treat municipal combined sewer overflows and sanitary sewer overflows, and to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to update certain guidance used to develop and determine the financial capability of communities to implement clean water infrastructure programs.</title>
    <title type="display">Clean Water Affordability Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1705"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Clean Water Affordability Act of 2016

This bill amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to revise and reauthorize through FY2021 a grant program for intercepting, transporting, controlling, or treating combined sewer overflows or sanitary sewer overflows. The bill: (1) expands the grant program to include support for measures that manage, reduce, treat, or recapture stormwater or subsurface drainage water; (2) allows local or regional authorities to receive grant funds; and (3) increases the federal cost-sharing requirement by requiring the federal share of the costs of a project carried out using grant funds to be at least 75% of the total costs of the project.

The bill also revises the Clean Water Act by establishing requirements concerning managing water pollution during periods of heavy precipitation, including by requiring the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish a green infrastructure portfolio standard, which contains voluntary goals for increasing the percentage of annual water managed by eligible entities that use green infrastructure. (Green infrastructure is an approach used to manage stormwater by capturing stormwater in vegetation or porous surfaces.)

The EPA must update the guidance entitled "Combined Sewer Overflows - Guidance for Financial Capability Assessment and Schedule Development" to ensure that the evaluations of community financial capability and schedule development meet specified criteria.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
