<bill session="114" type="h" number="3289" updated="2018-11-21T20:17:06Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Natural Gas Environmental and Economic Security Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prevent the waste of gas produced under oil and gas leases on Federal land and to collect royalty on all gas production.</title>
    <title type="display">Natural Gas Environmental and Economic Security Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000579"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001292" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001066" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000574" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2016-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000480" joined="2015-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2015-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1156"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-08-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Natural Gas Environmental and Economic Security Act

This bill amends the Federal Oil and Gas Royalty Management Act of 1982 to direct the Department of the Interior to establish specified requirements for:

 reducing and preventing the waste of natural gas, including by venting, flaring, and fugitive releases, from all oil and gas operations subject to mineral leasing law or the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976; and measuring and reporting the production and disposition of all gas subject to the mineral leasing laws to allow for more accurate accounting of gas consumed or lost by venting and flaring, and of fugitive releases of such gas. All such requirements shall include consistent enforcement mechanisms for any operations not in compliance with them.

 Royalties otherwise authorized or required to be paid for natural gas shall be assessed on all gas produced under the mineral leasing laws, including:

 gas used or consumed within the area of a tract for the benefit of the lease (commonly referred to as "beneficial use gas"); and all gas consumed or lost by venting, flaring, or fugitive releases through any equipment during upstream operations. Exempted from assessment of these royalties is any natural gas:

 vented or flared in an acute emergency situation posing danger to human health that occurs for no more than 48 hours, or injected into the ground on a lease tract.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
