<bill session="114" type="s" number="1718" updated="2018-06-02T06:57:10Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Four Rationers Repeal Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the repeal of certain provisions of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act that have the effect of rationing health care.</title>
    <title type="display">Four Rationers Repeal Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000307"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="484"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-08T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Four Rationers Repeal Act of 2015

This bill repeals provisions of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) related to the establishment of the Independent Payment Advisory Board (also known as the Independent Medicare Advisory Board), effective as of enactment of PPACA. (The purpose of the board is to develop proposals to reduce the growth rate of Medicare spending without restricting benefits or modifying eligibility.) Provisions amended by the repealed provisions are restored.

This bill amends the Public Health Service Act and title XI, title XVIII (Medicare), and title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to eliminate the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation. (The purpose of the center is to test innovative payment and service delivery models to reduce expenditures while preserving or enhancing the quality of care.)

Group health plans and health insurers are no longer required to cover, without cost-sharing, certain items and services recommended by the United States Preventive Services Task Force (USPSTF).

The Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality is no longer required to convene the USPSTF.

The Community Preventive Services Task Force is eliminated. (This task force developed recommendations regarding community preventive interventions based on scientific evidence.)

The Department of Health and Human Services may not use comparative effectiveness research to deny or delay coverage of an item or service under a federal health care program. Comparative effectiveness research conducted or supported by the federal government must account for factors contributing to differences in the treatment response and treatment preferences of patients.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
