<bill session="114" type="h" number="4060" updated="2019-02-13T17:31:15Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Imperial Valley Desert Conservation and Recreation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish certain conservation and recreation areas in the State of California, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Imperial Valley Desert Conservation and Recreation Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000130"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="414"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-18T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Imperial Valley Desert Conservation and Recreation Act of 2015

This bill directs the Department of the Interior to convey to the state of California approximately 934 acres of specified public lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) in San Diego County in order to allow California to include it as part of the Anza-Borrego Desert State Park.

The Department of Transportation shall seek a conveyance from Interior of approximately 3,500 acres of BLM-administered land adjacent to the Imperial County Holtville Airport in Imperial County, California, to allow the county to expand the airport.

The bill establishes the Vinagre Wash Special Management Area in California, which shall consist of approximately 81,880 acres of certain public lands in Imperial County. Interior shall manage specified lands in the Management Area to preserve their character for eventual inclusion in the National Wilderness Preservation System.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
