<bill session="114" type="h" number="1004" updated="2019-04-11T15:42:41Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize the Enhancing Education Through Technology Act of 2001.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Achievement Through Technology and Innovation Reauthorization Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Achievement Through Technology and Innovation Reauthorization Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000486"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2015-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2015-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2015-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2015-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-13T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Achievement Through Technology and Innovation Reauthorization Act of 2015

Amends title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to rename part D (Achievement through Technology and Innovation) as the Achievement Through Technology and Innovation Act of 2015 or the ATTAIN Act and to reauthorize it through FY2020.

Authorizes the Secretary of Education to reserve a portion of the part D funding to provide states with technical assistance and information in adopting evidence-based best practices for using technology to transform learning.

Directs the Secretary to allot part D grants to states on the basis of each state's share of school improvement funds under part A of title I of the ESEA.

Requires state grantees to develop and implement challenging academic content and achievement standards to ensure that students are technologically literate. Declares that such standards are only for tracking technological literacy and not for assessing adequate yearly progress (AYP) under title I. Permits the assessment of student performance in gaining technology literacy through embedding assessment items in other state tests or performance-based assessments portfolios or through other valid and reliable means.

Directs states to use the bulk of their allotment to award competitive subgrants to local educational agencies (LEAs) to improve student learning, technology literacy, and achievement. Requires that priority be given to LEAs serving schools that have been identified as needing improvement.

Require an LEA to: (1) include a new or updated local long-range strategic educational technology plan in its subgrant application, (2) use up to 5% of its subgrant to evaluate its use of the subgrant, and (3) use its remaining subgrant to implement a plan for systemic school redesign through technology integration in at least one of its schools.

Requires the plans for systemic school redesign to include: (1) professional development activities for educators; (2) the acquisition and application of technology, in conjunction with curricular or instructional changes, to improve students' learning opportunities, academic achievement, and technical literacy; and (3) the acquisition and application of technology to identify individual student learning needs and support personalized learning.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
