<bill session="115" type="s" number="1038" updated="2019-04-18T16:35:45Z">
  <state datetime="2017-08-02">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to submit to Congress a report on the utilization of small businesses with respect to certain Federal contracts.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to require the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to submit to Congress a report on the utilization of small businesses with respect to certain Federal contracts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2017-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2017-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2017-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-08-02" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-08-02">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Reported by Senator Risch with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-08-02" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="198">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 198.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-08-02T14:15:13Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">(Sec. 3) This bill requires the Small Business Administration (SBA) to report to specified congressional committees on determinations as to:

 whether small business concerns and each category of covered small business concerns (specified below) are being utilized in a significant portion of the federal market on multiple award contracts, including whether awards are being reserved for one or more of those categories and whether each such category is being given the opportunity to perform on such contracts; and whether current performance requirements for such contracts are feasible and appropriate for small business concerns. The term "covered small business concerns" means:

 HUBZone small business concerns, small business concerns owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans, small business concerns owned and controlled by women, and socially and economically disadvantaged small business concerns receiving SBA procurement contracts. In making such determinations, the SBA shall use information from multiple award contracts: (1) with varied assigned North American Industry Classification System codes, and (2) that were awarded by at least eight federal agencies.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
