<bill session="114" type="s" number="758" updated="2018-06-02T06:42:27Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Trade Enforcement Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an Interagency Trade Enforcement Center in the Office of the United States Trade Representative, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Trade Enforcement Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000770"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2015-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2015-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1587-1588" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Office of the U.S. Trade Representative"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Trade Enforcement Act of 2015

Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to establish within the Office of the United States Trade Representative (USTR) an Interagency Trade Enforcement Center to:

 serve as the primary forum within the federal government for coordinating with specified agencies the enforcement of U.S. trade rights under international trade agreements and of U.S. trade remedy laws; coordinate among the USTR, other agencies with trade-related responsibilities, and the intelligence community the exchange of information related to potential violations of international trade agreements by foreign trading partners of the United States; and conduct outreach to U.S. workers, businesses, and other interested persons to foster greater participation in the identification and reduction or elimination of foreign trade barriers and unfair foreign trade practices. Establishes in the Center the position of a Director, who shall be the Deputy USTR for Trade Enforcement to head the Trade Enforcement Division, as well as a Deputy Director and an Intelligence Community Liaison.

Establishes within the Office of the USTR a Chief Manufacturing Negotiator to conduct trade negotiations and enforce trade agreements relating to U.S. manufacturing products and services.

Makes it the principal functions of the Deputy USTR for Trade Enforcement to:

 ensure that U.S. trading partners comply with trade agreements to which the United States is a party, and assist the USTR in investigating and prosecuting disputes before the World Trade Organization and pursuant to other bilateral or regional trade agreements to which the United States is a party. Makes it the principal function of the Chief Manufacturing Negotiator to act as a vigorous advocate on behalf of this country's manufacturing interests.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
