<bill session="113" type="s" number="327" updated="2016-10-25T16:20:56Z">
  <state datetime="2013-06-18">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Good Neighbor Forestry Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Good Neighbor Forestry Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to enter into cooperative agreements with State foresters authorizing State foresters to provide certain forest, rangeland, and watershed restoration and protection services.</title>
    <title type="display">Good Neighbor Forestry Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2013-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000444" joined="2013-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2013-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2013-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000038" joined="2013-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-28.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-06-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-09-10">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Wyden with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 113-97.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-09-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="175">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 175.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2401"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1526"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="4"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Insects"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-09-10T13:00:21Z" status="Reported to Senate amended">Good Neighbor Forestry Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA), with respect to National Forest System land, and the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to Bureau of Land Management (BLM) land, to enter into a good neighbor agreement (a cooperative agreement or contract, including a sole source contract) with a governor of a state to coordinate the procurement and implementation of authorized restoration services.

Defines "authorized restoration services" as similar and complementary forest, rangeland, and watershed restoration services carried out on federal land and non-federal land by either the Secretary concerned or a governor pursuant to a good neighbor agreement.

Requires the Secretaries to make good neighbor agreements available to the public.

Makes certain National Forest System timber sales requirements of the National Forest Management Act of 1976 inapplicable to services performed under a cooperative agreement or contract entered into under this Act.

Requires the Secretaries to provide or approve all silviculture prescriptions and marking guides to be applied on federal land in all timber sale projects conducted under this Act.

Prohibits delegation to a governor of any decision required under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA) with respect to any authorized restoration services to be provided on federal land.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 113-97</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
