<bill session="115" type="h" number="2682" updated="2019-04-18T16:09:40Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To support foster youth in successful parenting by reducing unintended pregnancies and promoting the well-being of expectant or parenting foster youth and their children.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Foster Youth in Successful Parenting Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Foster Youth in Successful Parenting Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Supporting Foster Youth in Successful Parenting Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000096"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Worker and Family Support" code="HSWM03" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Supporting Foster Youth in Successful Parenting Act of 2017

This bill amends part B (Child and Family Services) of title IV of the Social Security Act to require states to report to the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) on steps taken to address pregnancy and parenthood among foster youth.

HHS shall make grants to states to identify and implement approaches to support foster youth in successful parenting.

The bill specifies that: (1) pregnancy and parenting are sufficient reasons to remain in foster care until age 21, (2) states must strive to keep parents with their children, and (3) children born to foster youth are not required to enter foster care.

The Federal Interagency Work Group on Child Abuse and Neglect shall identify and address issues facing foster youth who are expectant or parenting.

HHS is encouraged to promote the sharing of emerging lessons, research, and best practices about preventing teen pregnancy among foster youth, and enable foster youth who are parents to receive support from those working in the areas of teen pregnancy prevention and child welfare.

State certifications under the John H. Chafee Foster Care Independence Program must ensure that each youth in the program who is expectant or parenting will receive independent and transition planning services that can support them in raising a child.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
