<amendment session="114" chamber="s" number="3266" updated="2019-02-27T14:41:45Z">
  <amends type="s" number="2012" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2016-04-19">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000127"/>
  <offered datetime="2016-02-03"/>
  <description>To require the Comptroller General of the United States to prepare a report relating to the statutory and regulatory authority of the Bureau of Safety and Environmental Enforcement relating to the legal procurement of privately owned helicopter fuel, without agreement, from lessees, permit holders, operators of federally leased offshore facilities, or independent third parties.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2016-04-19" how="Voice Vote" result="pass">
      <text>Amendment SA 3266 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-04-19">
      <text>Amendment SA 3266 proposed by Senator Murkowski for Senator Vitter to Amendment SA 2953. (consideration: CR S2145-2191; text: CR S2150) To require the Comptroller General of the United States to prepare a report relating to the statutory and regulatory authority of the Bureau of Safety and Environmental Enforcement relating to the legal procurement of privately owned helicopter fuel, without agreement, from lessees, permit holders, operators of federally leased offshore facilities, or independent third parties.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-03"/>
    <action datetime="2016-04-19">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 3266 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-19">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 3266 proposed by Senator Murkowski for Senator Vitter to Amendment SA 2953.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2145-2191" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2150" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-03">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
