<bill session="114" type="h" number="5468" updated="2019-02-08T20:13:44Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to allow for prepayment of repayment obligations under Repayment Contracts between the United States and the Weber Basin Water Conservancy District.</title>
    <title type="display">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to allow for prepayment of repayment obligations under Repayment Contracts between the United States and the Weber Basin Water Conservancy District.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001250"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-12">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-09-06">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 114-719.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-09-06" calendar="Union" number="558">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 558.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water, Oceans, and Wildlife" code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="612"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2848"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-06T18:44:35Z" status="Reported to House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

This bill directs the Department of the Interior to permit the prepayment of repayment obligations under Repayment Contract No. 14-06-400-33 between the United States and the Weber Basin Water Conservancy District, including all related applicable contracts, providing for repayment of Weber Basin Project construction costs allocated to irrigation and municipal and industrial purposes under terms and conditions similar to those used in implementing the provisions in the Central Utah Project Completion Act for prepayment of Central Utah Project, Bonneville Unit repayment obligations.

The prepayment:

 shall result in the United States recovering the net present value of all repayment streams that would have been payable to the United States if this bill was not in effect; may be provided in several installments; may not be adjusted on the basis of the type of prepayment financing used by the District; and shall result in total repayment by September 30, 2026.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-719</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
