<bill session="114" type="s" number="2527" updated="2018-06-02T07:14:48Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sergeant Daniel Somers Classified Veterans Access to Care Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the mental health treatment provided by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to veterans who served in classified missions.</title>
    <title type="display">Sergeant Daniel Somers Classified Veterans Access to Care Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2016-02-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2921"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="421"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Sergeant Daniel Somers Classified Veterans Access to Care Act

 This bill expresses the sense of Congress that veterans who experience combat-related mental health wounds should have immediate and consistent access to comprehensive mental health care.

 The Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) shall:

 establish standards and procedures to ensure that a veteran who participated in a classified mission or served in a sensitive unit while in the Armed Forces may access VA mental health care in a manner that fully accommodates the veteran's obligation to not improperly disclose classified information; disseminate guidance to employees of the Veterans Health Administration, including mental health professionals, on such standards and procedures and on how to best engage such veterans during the course of mental health treatment with respect to classified information; and ensure that an individual may elect to identify as such a veteran on an appropriate form.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
