<bill session="115" type="s" number="701" updated="2019-04-18T16:34:11Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-04-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the competitiveness of United States manufacturing by designating and supporting manufacturing communities.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Made in America Manufacturing Communities Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Made in America Manufacturing Communities Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Made in America Manufacturing Communities Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Made in America Manufacturing Communities Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Made in America Manufacturing Communities Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000555"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2017-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2017-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2017-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2017-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2017-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2017-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2017-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2017-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-04-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-02-05">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Thune with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 115-204.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-02-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="298">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 298.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2264"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1672"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Industrial policy and productivity"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-02-05T14:13:47Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Made in America Manufacturing Communities Act of 2017

(Sec. 3) This bill requires the Department of Commerce to establish a Manufacturing Community Support Program to improve the competitiveness of U.S. manufacturing by: (1) designating consortiums as manufacturing communities, and (2) authorizing federal agencies electing to participate in the program to provide such communities preferential consideration in awarding financial and technical assistance.

A consortium, to be eligible for such designation and assistance, must:

 represent a region that is large enough to contain critical elements of the key technologies or supply chain prioritized by the consortium and small enough to enable close collaboration among the consortium's members; include at least one institution of higher education, a private sector entity, and a government entity; and have a lead applicant that is a district organization, an Indian tribe, a state or political subdivision of a state, an institution of higher education, a nonprofit organization or association with an application supported by a state, a political subdivision of a state, or a native community. Commerce shall make such designations for a two-year period, and may renew a designation for additional two-year periods, based on specified criteria.

 Recipients may use such financial or technical assistance to support investments in ecosystems that will improve the competitiveness of U.S. manufacturing, including:

 infrastructure; access to capital; promotion of exports and foreign direct investment; equipment or facility upgrades; workforce training, retraining, or recruitment and retention, including that of women and underrepresented minorities; energy or process efficiency; business incubators; site preparation; advanced research; supply chain development; and small business assistance.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-204</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
