<bill session="114" type="s" number="2933" updated="2019-03-03T14:41:08Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit certain health care providers from providing non-Department health care services to veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans ACCESS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Acquiring Community Care Expect Safe Services Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="display">Veterans ACCESS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2016-05-16" withdrawn="2016-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2016-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2577"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Employee performance"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Veterans Acquiring Community Care Expect Safe Services Act of 2016 or the Veterans ACCESS Act

This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to deny or revoke a health care provider's eligibility to provide non-VA health care services to veterans if such provider: (1) was removed from VA employment for violating VA policy, (2) violated medical license requirements, (3) had a VA certification revoked, or (4) violated a law for which a prison term of more than one year may be imposed.

The VA may deny, revoke, or suspend a health care provider's eligibility to provide non-VA health care services if the VA has reasonable belief that such action is necessary to protect the health or safety of veterans and: (1) the provider is under investigation by the medical board of a state in which the provider is licensed or practices, (2) the provider has entered into a settlement agreement for a medical-related disciplinary charge, or (3) the VA otherwise determines that such action is appropriate.

The VA shall suspend a health care provider's eligibility to provide non-VA health care services to veterans if such provider is suspended from VA service.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
