<bill session="114" type="s" number="2179" updated="2018-06-02T07:11:06Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veteran CARE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veteran Care Agreements Rule Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to allow the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to enter into certain agreements with non-Department of Veterans Affairs health care providers if the Secretary is not feasibly able to provide health care in facilities of the Department or through contracts or sharing agreements, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Veteran CARE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2016-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2000"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-08T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Veteran Care Agreements Rule Enhancement Act or Veteran CARE Act

This bill authorizes the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), if unable to furnish hospital care, medical services, or extended care at VA facilities or under other authorized contracts or sharing agreements, to enter into a Veterans Care Agreement with an eligible provider to furnish such care and services.

The VA shall review agreements exceeding $1 million annually at least once every two years.

The VA shall establish a process for the certification of eligible providers.

An eligible provider is:

 a physician or provider of services that has entered into a provider agreement under the Social Security Act; a provider of items and services receiving payments under a state Medicaid plan; an aging and disability resource center, an area agency on aging, or a center for independent living; or any other health care provider the VA considers appropriate. The VA shall establish a system or systems to monitor the quality of care and services furnished to veterans, which shall be used in assessing whether to renew an agreement.

An agreement may be made with a health care provider to provide veterans with nursing home care.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
