<bill session="114" type="sr" number="96" updated="2018-06-02T06:16:19Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution condemning the murder of Boris Nemtsov, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution condemning the murder of Boris Nemtsov, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000303"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2015-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1307-1308" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-04T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Condemns the murder of Boris Nemtsov, an advocate for reform and human rights in the Russian Federation, and the assassinations of other human rights and democracy activists in the Russian Federation since President Vladimir Putin came to office.

Calls on the Government of Russia to: (1) support and facilitate an independent inquiry into the murder; (2) release all political prisoners and end the ongoing harassment of political opponents, human rights activists, and journalists; (3) restore an independent judiciary and the rule of law; and (4) end all restrictions on the media and freedom of speech.

 Urges the President to: (1) seek a United Nations Security Council resolution that establishes an independent investigation into Mr. Nemtsov's assassination, (2) add the names of persons that Mr. Nemtsov requested be added to the visa ban list as provided for under the Sergei Manitsky Rule of Law Accountability Act of 2012, (3) continue to sanction human rights violators in the Russian Federation, and (4) significantly increase U.S. support to like-minded partners and human rights activists in the Russian Federation.

Urges the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) to obtain, examine, and publish the investigative report Mr. Nemtsov planned to release as part of the OSCE observer role in eastern Ukraine.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
