<bill session="115" type="h" number="4100" updated="2019-04-18T16:16:45Z">
  <state datetime="2018-07-23T16:42:30-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-07-23T16:42:30-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 36, United States Code, to revise the Federal charter for the Foundation of the Federal Bar Association.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Foundation of the Federal Bar Association Charter Amendments Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Foundation of the Federal Bar Association Charter Amendments Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Foundation of the Federal Bar Association Charter Amendments Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Foundation of the Federal Bar Association Charter Amendments Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Foundation of the Federal Bar Association Charter Amendments Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000266"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-10-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-23T16:31:11-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Goodlatte moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-23T16:31:20-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6618-6620" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-23T16:31:22-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4100.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2018-07-23T16:42:30-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6618-6619" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-07-23T16:42:31-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Citizenship" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Federally chartered organizations"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-07-23T14:41:04Z" status="Passed House without amendment">Foundation of the Federal Bar Association Charter Amendments Act of 2017

(Sec. 2) This bill revises the federal charter for the Foundation of the Federal Bar Association:

 to eliminate the provision that requires the foundation to be incorporated and domiciled in the District of Columbia; to require the board of directors to decide, and specify in the bylaws, the location of the principal office; to specify that the bylaws&#8212;not the charter&#8212;must provide for the terms of membership, the responsibilities of the board of directors, and the election of officers; to prohibit a director or officer, in his or her corporate capacity, from contributing to, supporting, or participating in political activities; to allow income and assets of the corporation to be used to reasonably compensate or reimburse expenses of an officer, director, or member; to award a grant to the Federal Bar Association chapter of an officer, director, or member; and to reasonably compensate employees; to expand a prohibition on loans for directors and officers to include members and employees; and to specify that on dissolution or final liquidation, any remaining assets must be distributed as provided by the board of directors instead of deposited in the Treasury.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
