<bill session="114" type="h" number="566" updated="2019-04-11T15:42:40Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To award grants to improve equality of access to technology-enabled education innovations and understanding of how partnerships of educational agencies and research institutions design and implement such innovations in ways that improve student outcomes, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Technology-Enabled Education Innovation Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="display">Technology-Enabled Education Innovation Partnership Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2015-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-27T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Technology-Enabled Education Innovation Partnership Act

 Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award competitive, renewable grants to eligible partnerships to design, implement, refine, and scale technology-enabled education innovation programs.

Defines an "eligible partnership" as a partnership composed of at least one state or local educational agency (LEA) and at least one institution of higher education or nonprofit research organization working with the state or LEA as a research and evaluation partner.

Requires at least 75% of the students participating in each technology-enabled education innovation program to be attending schools in which at least 50% of the student body is eligible for free or reduced-price lunches under the school lunch program.

Requires an independent evaluation of each innovation program by a research and evaluation collaborator.

Directs each partnership to provide a data set containing the student records of innovation program participants to a Technology-Enabled Education Innovation Partnership Coordinating Center that is created by the Secretary to: (1) conduct meta-analyses and other syntheses of such data, and (2) allow independent researchers access to the data.

Directs the Secretary to support national technology activities that provide the technology-enabled education innovation programs with information on, and technical assistance in, effectively implementing technology in schools.

Requires the Secretary to establish and oversee at least one advanced learning technology research and development center to address the priorities and grand challenges for learning technology set forth in the Department of Education's 2010 National Education Technology Plan.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
