<bill session="113" type="s" number="1750" updated="2016-10-25T16:27:46Z">
  <state datetime="2014-11-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-11-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Access to Public Land Guarantee Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Public Access to Public Land Guarantee Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture to enter into agreements with States and political subdivisions of States providing for the continued operation, in whole or in part, of public land, units of the National Park System, units of the National Wildlife Refuge System, and units of the National Forest System in the State during any period in which the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture is unable to maintain normal level of operations at the units due to a lapse in appropriations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Public Access to Public Land Guarantee Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000444"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2013-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2013-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-23">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-493.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-11-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-10">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Landrieu without amendment. With written report No. 113-295.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="635">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 635.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks" code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="3661"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-12-10T19:02:51Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Public Access to Public Land Guarantee Act - (Sec. 4) Directs the Department of the Interior or the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to enter into an agreement under which they may accept funds from the state or local government to reopen units of the National Park System, the National Wildlife Refuge System, or the National Forest System during any period in which Interior or USDA is unable to maintain normal level of operations at their units because of a lapse in appropriations.

Requires Interior or USDA, as appropriate, to refund all amounts it provided under the agreement to the state or local government: (1) upon enactment of an Act retroactively appropriating amounts sufficient to maintain normal operating levels at the reopened units, or (2) on the date on which the state or local government establishes that Interior or USDA collected entrance or user fees for the units during the agreement period.

Allows Interior or USDA to reimburse the state or local government voluntarily for any amounts it provided to the United States under the agreement if the refund requirements are not met.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 113-295</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
