<bill session="115" type="h" number="5869" updated="2019-04-18T16:23:43Z">
  <state datetime="2018-09-04T17:46:32-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-09-04T17:46:32-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Maritime Border Security Review Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Maritime Border Security Review Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Maritime Border Security Review Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Maritime Border Security Review Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Maritime Border Security Review Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Maritime Border Security Review Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to conduct a maritime border threat analysis, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000582"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2018-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000600" joined="2018-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000625" joined="2018-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000614" joined="2018-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2018-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001202" joined="2018-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-24">
      <text>Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-07-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-09-04">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 115-918.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-09-04" calendar="Union" number="713">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 713.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-09-04T17:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Katko moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-04T17:29:25-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7796-7799" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-04T17:29:28-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5869.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2018-09-04T17:46:32-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7796" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-09-04T17:46:37-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-05">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Border Security, Facilitation, and Operations" code="HSHM11" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="302"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3478"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-09-04T12:26:45Z" status="Passed House amended">Maritime Border Security Review Act

(Sec. 3) This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to submit to Congress a maritime border (i.e., the transit zone and the borders and territorial waters of Puerto Rico and the U.S. Virgin Islands) threat analysis that includes an identification and description of:

 current and potential terrorism and criminal threats posed by individuals and groups seeking to enter the United States through the maritime border or exploit border vulnerabilities on the maritime border; improvements needed at U.S. seaports to prevent terrorists and instruments of terror from entering the United States and reduce criminal activity, as measured by the total flow of illegal goods and illicit drugs, related to the maritime border; improvements needed with respect to the maritime border to prevent terrorists and instruments of terror from entering the United States and reduce criminal activity related to the maritime border; vulnerabilities in law, policy, cooperation between state, territorial, and local law enforcement, or international agreements that hinder effective and efficient border security, counterterrorism, anti-human trafficking efforts, and the flow of legitimate trade relating to the maritime border; and metrics and performance parameters used by DHS to evaluate maritime security effectiveness. In preparing the threat analysis, DHS shall consider and examine:

 technology and personnel needs and challenges; the role of state, territorial, and local law enforcement in general border security activities; the need for cooperation among federal, state, territorial, local, and appropriate international law enforcement entities relating to border security; the geographic challenges of the maritime border; and the impact and consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, Maria, and Nate on general border security activities relating to the maritime border.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-918</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
