<bill session="114" type="s" number="1700" updated="2018-06-02T06:57:02Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mitigation Facilitation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, to establish a program to provide loans and loan guarantees to enable eligible public entities to purchase credits from mitigation banks or in-lieu fee programs or acquire interests in real property that are acquired pursuant to mitigation projects required under certain Federal Water Pollution Control Act permits, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Mitigation Facilitation Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Mitigation Facilitation Act of 2015

This bill requires the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers to establish a mitigation loan and loan guarantee program to enable political subdivisions of states to: (1) purchase credits from mitigation banks or in-lieu fee programs, or (2) acquire interests in property that are acquired pursuant to a mitigation project required by the Corps of Engineers under a Clean Water Act permit to discharge dredged or fill material into waters of the United States.

Mitigation banks and in-lieu fee programs are designed to compensate for lost functions of waters of the United States resulting from activities under those permits.

The authority provided by the bill expires in 10 years.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
