<bill session="114" type="s" number="1250" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:38Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Nicholas and Zachary Burt Memorial Carbon Monoxide Poisoning Prevention Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nicholas and Zachary Burt Memorial Carbon Monoxide Poisoning Prevention Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to encourage States to require the installation of residential carbon monoxide detectors in homes, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Nicholas and Zachary Burt Memorial Carbon Monoxide Poisoning Prevention Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2015-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2015-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2015-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2015-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-06-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-12-14">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Thune with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 114-179.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-12-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="323">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 323.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4701"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-12-14T13:12:57Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Nicholas and Zachary Burt Memorial Carbon Monoxide Poisoning Prevention Act of 2015 

(Sec. 4) This bill directs the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to establish a grant program to provide assistance to states or tribal organizations that require compliant carbon monoxide alarms to be installed in dwelling units.

A "compliant carbon monoxide alarm" is an alarm that complies with: (1) the Standard for Single and Multiple Station Carbon Monoxide Alarms of the American National Standards Institute and UL (ANSI/UL 2034) or a successor standard, and (2) the Standard for Gas and Vapor Detectors and Sensors of the American National Standards Institute and UL (ANSI/UL 2075) or a successor standard.

 In selecting grant recipients, the CPSC must give favorable consideration to states or tribal organizations that: (1) require compliant alarms in specified facilities with fuel-burning appliances or attached garages, including educational facilities, childcare facilities, health care facilities, adult dependent care facilities, government buildings, restaurants, theaters, lodging establishments, or dwelling units; and (2) have strategies to protect vulnerable populations such as children, the elderly, or low-income households.

States or tribal organizations receiving grants may use such funds to: (1) purchase and install such alarms in dwelling units of low-income families or elderly persons, childcare facilities, public schools, senior centers, or student dwelling units owned by public universities; (2) train state, tribal, or local fire code enforcement officials regarding compliance and installation; or (3) educate the public about the risk of carbon monoxide poisoning.

The CPSC must report to Congress regarding the implementation of such grant program.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-179</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
