<bill session="113" type="h" number="3459" updated="2016-10-25T16:08:32Z">
  <state datetime="2013-11-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Article 32 Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to provide for preliminary hearings on alleged offenses under the Uniform Code of Military Justice.</title>
    <title type="display">Article 32 Reform Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001175"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2013-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000216" joined="2013-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2013-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001181" joined="2013-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000465" joined="2013-11-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7059-7060"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="3360"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="identical" number="1644"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-11-12T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Article 32 Reform Act - Revises requirements relating to an Article 32 investigative hearing under the Uniform Code of Military Justice (UCMJ) to require a judge advocate to conduct a preliminary hearing prior to referring a charge or specification to a general court-martial for trial. Requires such judge advocate to have a grade equal to or higher than the grade of the trial counsel and any defense counsel who is representing the accused at the preliminary hearing. Limits the preliminary hearing to the purpose of determining whether there is probable cause to believe an offense has been committed and whether the accused committed it.

Requires the judge advocate conducting the preliminary hearing to prepare a report which shall include: (1) determinations as to the court-martial jurisdiction over the offense and the accused and as to probable cause, (2) a consideration of the form of charges, and (3) a recommendation as to the disposition of the case.

Allows a victim of the alleged offense to decline to testify at the preliminary hearing. Requires the preliminary hearing to be recorded by a court reporter or by a suitable recording device.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
