<bill session="114" type="s" number="1153" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:53Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Red River Private Property Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide legal certainty to property owners along the Red River in Texas, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Red River Private Property Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2015-04-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2572-2573" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="2130"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Red River Private Property Protection Act

 Declares that the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) of the Department of the Interior disclaims any right, title, and interest to certain lands along a stretch of the Red River between Texas and Oklahoma (the affected area) located south of the South Bank boundary line.

Directs the BLM, in identifying the current South Bank boundary line along the affected area, to commission a new survey that: (1) adheres to the gradient boundary survey method, (2) spans the entire length of the affected area, (3) is conducted by Licensed State Land Surveyors chosen by the Texas General Land Office, and (4) is completed within two years of enactment of this Act. Requires submission of the survey to the Texas General Land Office for approval.

Permits a private property owner who holds, right, title, or interest in the affected area, after the survey is completed and approved, to appeal public domain claims by the BLM to an Administrative Law Judge.

Instructs the BLM to:

 ensure that no parcels of land in the affected area are treated as federal land for the purpose of any resource management plan until the survey has been completed and approved and the parcel is no longer subject to further appeal, and, subsequently, offer any remaining identified federal lands for disposal by competitive sale for at least fair market value. Requires the BLM to submit to Congress a list of identified federal lands that have not been sold and the reasons why.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
