<bill session="114" type="s" number="3402" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:45Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect consumers from deceptive practices with respect to online booking of hotel reservations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Online Booking Scams Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="display">Stop Online Booking Scams Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2016-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2016-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6141-6142" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6141-6142" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stop Online Booking Scams Act of 2016

This bill prohibits third party online hotel reservation sellers from charging a consumer's credit card or financial accounts in an Internet transaction for a hotel unless they disclose: (1) a description of the offered good or service, the cost, and other material terms before the conclusion of the transaction; (2) that the third party seller is not affiliated with the person who owns or provides the hotel services or accommodations and is not an exhibition organizer, a meeting planner, or the official housing bureau for an event at the hotel; and (3) the brand identity of the third party both online and over the phone.

The bill provides authority to the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) and states to enforce against violations.

The bill also expresses the sense of Congress that the FTC should revise its website to make it easier for consumers and businesses to report complaints of deceptive practices with respect to online booking of hotel reservations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
