<bill session="114" type="h" number="2809" updated="2018-06-02T04:28:28Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Great Lakes Water Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to prohibit sewage dumping into the Great Lakes, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Great Lakes Water Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000613"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000563" joined="2015-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001150" joined="2015-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2015-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4448"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="1586"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1645"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2132"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Great Lakes Water Protection Act 

This bill amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to prohibit a publicly owned treatment works (POTW) from discharging untreated or partially treated sewage into the Great Lakes or a tributary of the Great Lakes when the discharge is the result of the POTW intentionally diverting waste streams to bypass any portion of a treatment facility. A bypass is allowed if: (1) it is unavoidable to prevent loss of life, personal injury, or severe property damage, there is no feasible alternative, and the treatment works provides notice; or (2) it does not cause effluent (waste) limitations to be exceeded and is for essential maintenance to ensure efficient operation of the treatment facility.

The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) must work with relevant states to create requirements for providing immediate notice to the public about discharges.

The EPA must establish procedures to ensure that permits issued to POTWs under the National Pollutant Discharge Elimination System include requirements to comply with this bill.

This bill establishes a maximum civil penalty of $100,000 per day for violations of the bill occurring on or after January 1, 2035. The penalties must be deposited into the Great Lakes Cleanup Fund, which is established by this bill. The Fund must be used for improving wastewater discharges.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
