<bill session="114" type="h" number="3493" updated="2019-02-14T22:54:56Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-20T18:58:51-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-10-20T18:58:51-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing the Cities Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Securing the Cities Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish the Securing the Cities program to enhance the ability of the United States to detect and prevent terrorist attacks and other high consequence events utilizing nuclear or other radiological materials that pose a high risk to homeland security in high-risk urban areas, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Securing the Cities Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000625"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2015-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2015-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2015-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Security Technologies.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-17">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-09-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-10-20">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 114-295.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-10-20" calendar="Union" number="224">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 224.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-10-20T16:18:14-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Donovan moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-20T16:18:43-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6988-6989" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-20T16:18:45-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3493.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-20T16:26:03-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-20T18:32:50-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7010" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="550" datetime="2015-10-20T18:58:51-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 411 - 4 (Roll no. 550).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6988" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-10-20T18:58:51-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-21">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Innovation" code="HSHM08" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Radiation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-20T15:47:57Z" status="Passed House amended">(Securing the Cities Act of 2015

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Director for Domestic Nuclear Detection to establish the Securing the Cities program to enhance the ability of the United States to detect and prevent terrorist attacks and other high consequence events utilizing nuclear or other radiological materials that pose a high risk to homeland security in high-risk urban areas.

Under such program, the Director shall:

 assist state, local, tribal, and territorial governments in designing and implementing, or enhancing existing, architectures for coordinated and integrated detection and interdiction of nuclear or other radiological materials that are out of regulatory control; support the development of a region-wide operating capability to detect and report on nuclear and other radioactive materials out of operational control; provide resources to enhance detection, analysis, communication, and coordination to better integrate state, local, tribal, and territorial assets into federal operations; facilitate alarm adjudication and provide subject matter expertise and technical assistance on concepts of operations, training, exercises, and alarm response protocols; communicate with, and promote sharing of information about the presence or detection of nuclear or other radiological materials among, appropriate federal, state, local, tribal, and territorial governments in a manner that ensures transparency; and designate participating jurisdictions from among high-risk urban areas and other cities and regions, as appropriate, and notify Congress at least three days before designating or changing such jurisdictions. The Comptroller General is required to submit an assessment evaluating the effectiveness of the program.

(Sec. 3) This section requires the Director to report to Congress on the feasibility of developing model exercises to test the preparedness of jurisdictions participating in the program in meeting the challenges that may be posed by a range of nuclear and radiological threats.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-295</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
