<bill session="115" type="h" number="3049" updated="2019-04-18T16:11:53Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to require the windows in military family housing units to be equipped with fall prevention devices that protect against unintentional falls by young children, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Evan's Law</title>
    <title type="display">Evan's Law</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000463"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5114"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Readiness" code="HSAS03" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2810"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Evan's Law

This bill requires the military department concerned to ensure that any window of a military family housing unit the bottom sill of which is within 36 inches of the floor is equipped with fall prevention devices that protect against unintentional falls by young children and that comply with applicable International Building Code (IBC) standards.

Each department must brief the House Committee on Armed Services on the implementation of such requirement and include in the briefing: (1) a plan to retrofit existing military family housing units to meet such requirement; (2) the feasibility and cost-effectiveness of expanding such requirement to apply to windows with higher sills, modifying such requirement to require windows to be equipped with additional fall prevention devices that meet specified criteria, or extending such requirement to private housing leased or otherwise used by military families; and (3) the feasibility and cost-effectiveness of other potential methods to protect against unintentional window falls by young children in military family housing units.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
