<bill session="114" type="s" number="2082" updated="2018-06-04T15:55:25Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-30">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Veterans Affairs Expiring Authorities Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of Veterans Affairs Expiring Authorities Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Department of Veterans Affairs Expiring Authorities Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Department of Veterans Affairs Expiring Authorities Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to extend certain expiring provisions of law administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Department of Veterans Affairs Expiring Authorities Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2015-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-25">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-25">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6955-6959" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2015-09-25" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6956-6958" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-09-25">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-28T14:06:39-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-28T17:38:47-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-30T12:29:04-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Miller (FL) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-30T12:29:34-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6719-6727" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-30T12:29:35-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 2082.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-30T13:09:25-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-30T15:02:31-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6730-6731" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="526" datetime="2015-09-30T15:08:19-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 423 - 0 (Roll no. 526).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6719-6722" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-09-30T15:08:19-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2015-09-30">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2015-09-30" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="114-58" type="public" datetime="2015-09-30">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 114-58.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3596"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2048"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3246"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3249"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5985"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Philippines"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2700"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2015-10-01T03:59:58Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the Senate passed version is repeated here.)

Department of Veterans Affairs Expiring Authorities Act of 2015

This bill extends specified Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) programs.

TITLE I--EXTENSIONS OF AUTHORITY RELATING TO HEALTH CARE

(Sec. 101) Authority for collection of copayments for hospital care and nursing home care is extended through FY2016.

(Sec. 102) The requirement to provide nursing home care to certain veterans with service-connected disabilities is extended through December 31, 2016.

(Sec. 103) The authorization of appropriations for assistance and support services for caregivers is extended through FY2016.

(Sec. 104) Authority for recovery from third parties of the cost of care and services furnished to veterans with health-plan contracts for non-service-connected disability is extended through FY2016.

(Sec. 105) Authority for the pilot program on assistance for child care for certain veterans receiving health care is extended through December 31, 2016.

(Sec. 106) Authority to make grants to veterans service organizations for transportation of highly rural veterans is extended through FY2016.

(Sec. 107) Authority for the Department of Defense (DOD)-VA Health Care Sharing Incentive Fund is extended through FY2016.

(Sec. 108) Authority for the Joint DOD-VA Demonstration Fund is extended through FY2017.

(Sec. 109) Authority for the pilot program on counseling in retreat settings for women veterans newly separated from service is extended through December 31, 2016.

TITLE II--EXTENSIONS OF AUTHORITY RELATING TO BENEFITS

(Sec. 201) Authority for the Veterans' Advisory Committee on Education is extended through December 31, 2016.

(Sec. 202) Specified housing loan provisions and definitions, including the calculation of net value of real property at time of foreclosure, are extended through FY2016.

(Sec. 203) Authority relating to vendee loans is extended through FY2016.

(Sec. 204) Authority for rehabilitation and vocational benefits at VA facilities to members of the Armed Forces with severe injuries or illnesses is extended through December 31, 2016.

TITLE III--EXTENSIONS OF AUTHORITY RELATING TO HOMELESSNESS

(Sec. 301) Authority for homeless veterans reintegration programs is extended through FY2016.

(Sec. 302) Authority for the homeless women veterans and homeless veterans with children reintegration program is extended through FY2016.

(Sec. 303) Authority for housing assistance for homeless veterans is extended through FY2016.

(Sec. 304) Authority for financial assistance for supportive services for very low-income veteran families in permanent housing is extended through FY2016.

(Sec. 305) Authority for the grant program for homeless veterans with special needs is extended through FY2016.

(Sec. 306) Authority for the Advisory Committee on Homeless Veterans is extended through December 31, 2016.

(Sec. 307) Authority for treatment and rehabilitation services for seriously mentally ill and homeless veterans, including a program to provide homeless veterans with benefits and services at certain locations, is extended through FY2016.

(Sec. 308) Authority for referral and counseling services for certain veterans at risk of homelessness is extended through FY2016.

TITLE IV--OTHER EXTENSIONS AND MODIFICATIONS OF AUTHORITY

(Sec. 401) Authority for transportation of individuals to and from VA facilities for vocational rehabilitation, counseling, treatment, or care is extended through December 31, 2016.

(Sec. 402) Authority for monthly assistance allowances under the Office of National Veterans Sports Programs and Special Events is extended through December 31, 2016.

(Sec. 403) Authority for operation of the VA regional office in Manila, the Republic of the Philippines is extended through FY2016.

(Sec. 404) The requirement to provide annual reports to Congress regarding equitable relief in the case of administrative error is extended through December 31, 2016.

(Sec. 405) The authorization for appropriations for adaptive sports programs for disabled veterans and members of the Armed Forces is extended through FY2016.

(Sec. 406) Authority for the Advisory Committee on Minority Veterans is extended through December 31, 2016.

(Sec. 407) Authority for temporary eligibility expansion for specially adapted housing assistance for certain veterans with disabilities causing difficulty ambulating is extended through FY2016.

(Sec. 408) Authority to enter into agreement with the National Academy of Sciences regarding associations between diseases and exposure to dioxin and other chemical compounds in herbicides is extended through December 31, 2016.

(Sec. 409) Authority for performance of medical disabilities examinations by contract physicians is extended through December 31, 2016.

(Sec. 410) The current multipliers used in calculating the fees the VA may pay to educational institutions and apprenticeship providers for reports regarding each eligible individual's enrollment in veterans' education or training programs and the interruption or termination of their participation in such programs is extended through FY2016.

(Sec. 411) The requirement for an annual report on the DOD-VA Interagency Program Office is extended through FY2016.

(Sec. 412) Funding authority is modified to provide for constructing a new bed tower at the VA medical center in Tampa, Florida, in lieu of providing bed tower upgrades at such medical center.

(Sec. 413) The VA may carry out the following major medical facility projects (with each project not to exceed specified amounts):

 construction of a community living center, outpatient clinic, renovated domiciliary, and renovation of existing buildings in Canandaigua, New York; seismic corrections to the mental health and community living center in Long Beach, California; seismic correction of 12 buildings in West Los Angeles, California; and construction of a spinal cord injury building and seismic corrections in San Diego, California. TITLE V--MATTERS RELATING TO MEDICAL FACILITY PROJECT IN DENVER

(Sec. 501) The amount authorized for the replacement of the existing VA Medical Center in Denver, Colorado, is increased.

It is the sense of Congress that the Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2016 authorizes the VA to transfer discretionary unobligated balances appropriated for FY2015 and discretionary advance appropriations for FY2016 to fund such increase.

The VA may not transfer amounts from the Veterans Choice Fund to carry out this medical facility construction project.

(Sec. 502) The VA shall enter into an agreement with an appropriate non-VA federal entity to provide full project management services for any super construction project, including management over the project design, acquisition, construction, and contract changes. Such agreement shall require reimbursement to the federal entity for project management service costs.

TITLE VI--OTHER MATTERS

(Sec. 601) Various technical and clerical amendments are made.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
