<bill session="114" type="s" number="2776" updated="2018-06-02T07:16:29Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TEST for Lead Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transparent Environment in School Testing for Lead Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to condition the receipt of funds by a State for a drinking water treatment revolving loan fund on the State carrying out a program to test for lead in drinking water for schools.</title>
    <title type="display">TEST for Lead Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4879"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Transparent Environment in School Testing for Lead Act or the TEST for Lead Act 

This bill amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to: (1) allow funds from the Drinking Water State Revolving Fund to be used to train school personnel on issues relating to lead contamination in drinking water and to assist in lead remediation efforts, and (2) condition a state's receipt of funding from such Fund on the state establishing a program to test for lead in school drinking water.

Program requirements include testing water from: (1) faucets used for food preparation, (2)sinks in bathrooms, and (3)drinking water coolers.Testing must be conducted at least biannually at schools built prior to 1996 and at least annually at schools built in 1996 or after.

Additionally, local education agencies must notify parents or guardians, the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), the state in which they are located, the local municipal government, and local health agencies within 48 hours if a level of lead exceeds the EPA's lead action level.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
