<bill session="114" type="h" number="4858" updated="2018-06-02T04:58:08Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide a declaration of nonnavigability for the central Delaware River, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To provide a declaration of nonnavigability for the central Delaware River, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001227"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5303"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="612"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill declares the following portions of the Delaware River in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, bounded by the former bulkhead and pierhead lines that were established by the Secretary of War and successors, to be nonnavigable waters of the United States unless the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers finds that there are substantive objections:

 Piers 70 South through 38 South, encompassing an area bounded by the southern line of Moore Street extended to the northern line of Catherine Street extended; and Piers 24 North through 72 North, encompassing an area bounded by the southern line of Callowhill Street extended to the northern line of East Fletcher Street extended. The Army Corps of Engineers shall make such public interest determination separately for each proposed project to be undertaken within the boundaries described, using reasonable discretion, within 150 days of the date of submission of appropriate plans for such project.

This bill's declaration shall apply only to those parts of the areas described that are or will be bulkheaded and filled or otherwise occupied by permanent structures, including marina and recreation facilities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
