<bill session="114" type="h" number="2566" updated="2018-11-21T21:40:13Z">
  <state datetime="2016-11-14T15:31:40-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-11-14T15:31:40-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Rural Call Quality and Reliability Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Improving Rural Call Quality and Reliability Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to ensure the integrity of voice communications and to prevent unjust or unreasonable discrimination among areas of the United States in the delivery of such communications.</title>
    <title type="display">Improving Rural Call Quality and Reliability Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2016-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000614" joined="2015-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000546" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000188" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000368" joined="2016-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2015-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000566" joined="2016-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000565" joined="2015-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000569" joined="2015-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000184" joined="2016-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000127" joined="2015-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000258" joined="2015-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2015-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001192" joined="2016-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2015-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000018" joined="2015-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-12">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-13">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-13">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-09-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-11-14">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 114-805.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-11-14" calendar="Union" number="629">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 629.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-11-14T15:19:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Burgess moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-14T15:19:13-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6127-6129" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-14T15:19:16-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2566.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2016-11-14T15:31:40-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6127-6128" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-11-14T15:31:42-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-15">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-11-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="668">
      <text>Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 668.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Communications and Technology" code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="827"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="253"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-11-14T14:54:56Z" status="Passed House amended">Improving Rural Call Quality and Reliability Act of 2016

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require intermediate providers that offer the capability to transmit voice communications and signaling information from one destination to another, and that charge a rate to any other entity (including an affiliated entity) for such a transmission, to: (1) register with the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), and (2) comply with service quality standards to be established by the FCC.

An "intermediate provider" is an entity that: (1) enters a business arrangement with a long-distance voice service provider that makes the initial call path choice for more than 100,000 domestic retail subscriber lines, or with another intermediate provider, to carry, route, or transmit voice traffic from a call placed from or to an end user connection using a North American Numbering Plan resource; and (2) does not itself (directly or in conjunction with an affiliate) serve as such a long-distance initial call path choice provider in the context of originating or terminating a given call.

The bill prohibits such long-distance providers (including local exchange carriers, interexchange carriers, commercial mobile radio services, interconnected voice over Internet Protocol [VoIP] services, and certain non-interconnected VoIP services) from using an intermediate provider to transmit voice communications and signals unless the intermediate provider is so registered.

The FCC must: (1) ensure the integrity of the transmission of voice communications to all customers in the United States, (2) prevent unjust or unreasonable discrimination among areas of the United States in the delivery of such voice communications, and (3) make a registry of intermediate providers publicly available on the FCC website.

The bill shall not be construed to preempt or expand the authority of a state agency or public utility commission to collect data, or enforce state law and regulations, regarding the completion of intrastate voice communications.

Certain long-distance providers that make initial call path choices are exempt from service quality standards that the FCC is required to establish under this bill if they certify under a safe harbor provision in existing FCC rules that they monitor the performance of, or do not use, intermediate providers.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-805</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
