<bill session="114" type="s" number="2309" updated="2018-08-16T22:54:11Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">U.S. Civil Rights Network Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">African American Civil Rights Network Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 54, United States Code, to establish within the National Park Service the U.S. Civil Rights Network, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">African American Civil Rights Network Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000360" joined="2015-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-17">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-09-08">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 114-348.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-09-08" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="623">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 623.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks" code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3683"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-08T14:24:45Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">African American Civil Rights Network Act of 2016

(Sec. 3) This bill requires the Department of the Interior to establish within the National Park Service (NPS) an African American Civil Rights Network that encompasses: (1) all NPS units and programs that relate to the African American civil rights movement during the period from 1939 through 1968; (2) other federal, state, local, and privately owned properties that relate to the African American civil rights movement and that are included in, or eligible for, the National Register of Historic Places; and (3) other governmental and nongovernmental facilities and programs of an educational, research, or interpretive nature that are directly related to such movement.

In carrying out the network, Interior must: (1) review civil rights movement studies and reports that may already be underway or completed, such as the Civil Rights Framework Study; (2) produce and disseminate educational materials, such as handbooks, maps, interpretive guides, or electronic information; (3) provide technical assistance; and (4) adopt an official, uniform symbol or device for the network and issue regulations for the symbol's use.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-348</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
