<bill session="114" type="h" number="4797" updated="2019-02-14T23:30:54Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GET THE LEAD OUT Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Grants and Education To Tackle Homeowner Exposure to Lead Ensuring America Drinks Only from Unpolluted Taps Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide grants to eligible entities to reduce lead in drinking water.</title>
    <title type="display">GET THE LEAD OUT Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000622"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2016-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2016-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2016-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Environment and Climate Change" code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="2588"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2821"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2848"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="612"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Grants and Education To Tackle Homeowner Exposure to Lead Ensuring America Drinks Only from Unpolluted Taps Act of 2016 or the GET THE LEAD OUT Act of 2016

This bill requires the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish a grant program to provide assistance to eligible entities (i.e., certain water systems, nonprofit organizations, and government agencies) for reducing lead levels in water for human consumption.

Grant funds may be used to assist low-income homeowners in carrying out lead reduction projects, as long as the grant amount does not exceed the cost of replacing the privately owned portion of the service line.

If an eligible entity uses funds for replacing lead service lines, it must: (1) notify customers of the planned replacement of any publicly owned portions of the lead service line; (2) inform each customer that it will replace the public portions of the line only if it obtains the customer's consent to simultaneously replace the privately owned portions of the line; and (3) demonstrate that it has considered multiple options for reducing lead in drinking water, including an evaluation of options for corrosion control.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
