<bill session="114" type="h" number="4806" updated="2019-02-14T23:30:54Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CLEAR Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Copper and Lead Evaluation and Reporting Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to promulgate national primary drinking water regulations regarding lead and copper.</title>
    <title type="display">CLEAR Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Q000023"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001286" joined="2016-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2016-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2016-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2016-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2016-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2016-05-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Environment and Climate Change" code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2587"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2821"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Copper and Lead Evaluation and Reporting Act of 2016 or the CLEAR Act

This bill amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to require the Environmental Protection Agency to promulgate new lead and copper regulations that would set a health-based, household action level for lead and copper that triggers: (1) a consumer notification of drinking water contamination; (2) a report to the appropriate public health agency; and (3) an examination by the public water system of service line material and, if applicable, the removal of lead portions of the service line.

 That action level must be based on the amount of lead that would result in a blood lead level greater than five micrograms per deciliter in an average, healthy infant who consumes infant formula made with water.

The regulations must also:

 provide outreach about the health risk and protection available to consumers with known or suspected lead service lines, institutions and facilities that serve other vulnerable populations, and the caregivers and health care providers of those consumers or populations; require reporting by public water systems for each monitoring period to the populations they serve on information concerning lead and copper levels; require public water systems to provide a public statement of lead service line ownership where a community has such lines; modify monitoring requirements to provide for voluntary, consumer-requested tap samples for lead; and provide for utilizing the results of those samples.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
