<bill session="114" type="h" number="3545" updated="2018-11-09T00:09:04Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Corrosive Drywall Remediation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a credit for replacement costs associated with certain imported corrosive drywall, and to amend the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to allow use of community development block grant amounts for repairs to housing constructed using such corrosive drywall, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Corrosive Drywall Remediation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000296"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Corrosive Drywall Remediation Act 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an individual taxpayer a tax credit for the cost of repairing damage to a personal residence or household appliance due to corrosive drywall.

The bill amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to allow community development&#160;grants under such Act to pay for activities necessary to remove or remedy the use of corrosive drywall installed in housing during construction or rehabilitation that occurred between 2001 and 2009.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
