<bill session="114" type="h" number="6424" updated="2019-01-29T14:40:40Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-12-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-12-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NIST Plumbing Research Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the National Institute of Standards and Technology to establish a premise plumbing research laboratory, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">NIST Plumbing Research Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2016-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2016-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2016-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000248" joined="2016-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2016-12-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-12-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Lighting, heating, cooling"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-02T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">NIST Plumbing Research Act of 2016

This bill directs the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) to:

 establish or designate a laboratory to conduct research on premise plumbing in relation to water safety, security, efficiency, sustainability, and resilience; conduct an organizational review of all research and other activities related to premise plumbing conducted by federal entities; and appoint one or more officers or employees of the NIST to liaise with non-federal entities that are conducting research or other activities related to premise plumbing. The bill defines "premise plumbing" as the water distribution system within the property lines of a property, including all buildings and permanent structures on such property. This term also includes building supply and distribution pipes, fixtures, fittings, water heaters, water-treating and water-using equipment, and all respective joints, connections, devices, and appurtenances.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
