<bill session="114" type="s" number="2515" updated="2018-06-02T07:14:43Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Child Care Protection Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to ensure criminal background checks of employees of the military child care system and providers of child care services and youth program services for military dependents.</title>
    <title type="display">Military Child Care Protection Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001135"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2016-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2016-02-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-09T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Military Child Care Protection Act of 2016

This bill requires that the criminal background check of military child care system employees that is required pursuant to the Crime Control Act of 1990 be conducted pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Department of Defense in accordance with the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990, which includes:

 searches of state criminal and sex offender registries and child abuse and neglect registries, a search of the National Crime Information Center, and a Federal Bureau of Investigation fingerprint check. A provider of military child care services or youth program services must comply with criminal background check requirements under the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 for the state in which such services are provided.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
