<bill session="115" type="s" number="1318" updated="2019-04-18T16:36:56Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect the rights of passengers with disabilities in air transportation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Air Carrier Access Amendments Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Air Carrier Access Amendments Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Air Carrier Access Amendments Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2017-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2017-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2017-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2017-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2017-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2018-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2018-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="5004"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Access Board"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Service animals"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-08T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Air Carrier Access Amendments Act of 2017

This bill expands provisions prohibiting discrimination against disabled individuals by an air carrier. Specifically, it enumerates certain actions that an air carrier must take or may not take with respect to a disabled individual. It also requires the Department of Transportation (DOT) to ensure that disabled individuals traveling in air transportation are able to file complaints with DOT in response to disability-related discrimination and receive assistance from DOT through a hotline or comparable electronic means.

The bill authorizes an aggrieved individual and the Department of Justice to bring a civil action for discrimination. The civil penalty for damage for discrimination involving damage to a wheelchair or other mobility aid of a disabled passenger may be increased up to three times the maximum penalty otherwise allowed.

The Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board shall prescribe regulations for aircraft with new or existing type certificates to ensure the accessibility of individuals with disabilities. The board shall: (1) conduct a study to determine the ways in which individuals with significant disabilities who use wheelchairs can be accommodated through in-cabin wheelchair restraint systems, and (2) issue minimum guidelines for such systems.

DOT shall: (1) prescribe or revise regulations to ensure that individuals with disabilities who request assistance receive timely and effective assistance at airports and on aircraft from trained personnel, (2) develop an Airline Passengers with Disabilities Bill of Rights, and (3) establish an advisory committee for air travel needs of passengers with disabilities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
