<bill session="114" type="h" number="2483" updated="2018-11-09T00:08:54Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Independent Contractor Tax Fairness and Simplification Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide standards for determining employment status, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Independent Contractor Tax Fairness and Simplification Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000594"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000294" joined="2016-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000363" joined="2015-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001158" joined="2015-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000018" joined="2015-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001176" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2016-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Independent Contractor Tax Fairness and Simplification Act of 2015 

 Amends the Internal Revenue Code to set forth criteria for classifying a worker as an employee or an independent contractor.

Prohibits: (1) any retroactive assessment of employment tax, except with respect to certain skilled workers, for tax periods after December 31, 1978, unless the employer had no reasonable basis for not treating a worker as an employee, and (2) the issuance, after the enactment of this Act, of Treasury regulations with respect to the employment status of any individual for purposes of the employment tax.

Establishes safe harbor provisions upon which a service recipient or payor may rely in classifying a service provider as an independent contractor rather than as an employee where the service provider: (1) incurs significant financial responsibility for providing and maintaining equipment and facilities to perform work under a contract; (2) incurs unreimbursed expenses or risks income fluctuations because remuneration is directly related to sales or other output rather than solely to the number of hours actually worked or expenses incurred; (3) is compensated on factors related to the work performed and not solely on the basis of hours or time expended; and (4) substantially controls the means and manner of performing the contract services, the specifications of the service recipient or payor, and any additional contractual requirements.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
