<bill session="114" type="h" number="4139" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:35Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-23T16:08:52-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-05-23T16:08:52-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fostering Innovation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Fostering Innovation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Fostering Innovation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 to provide a temporary exemption for low-revenue issuers from certain auditor attestation requirements.</title>
    <title type="display">Fostering Innovation Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000620" joined="2016-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000451" joined="2015-12-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-02">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises Prior to Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-02">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-03-02" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 42 - 15.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-05-23">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 114-588.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-05-23" calendar="Union" number="458">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 458.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-05-23T15:57:13-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Luetkemeyer moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-23T15:57:24-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2907-2910" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-23T15:57:25-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4139.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2016-05-23T16:08:52-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2907" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-05-23T16:08:53-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises" code="HSBA16" name="House Financial Services" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5983"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-23T13:47:53Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Fostering Innovation Act of 2015 

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 with respect to the requirement that each registered public accounting firm that prepares or issues an audit report for an issuer of securities (other than an emerging growth company) shall attest to, and report on, the internal control assessment made by the issuer's management.

This requirement shall not apply with respect to any audit report prepared for an issuer that:

 ceased to be an emerging growth company on the last day of its fiscal year following the fifth anniversary of its first sale of common equity securities, had average annual gross revenues of less than $50 million as of its most recently completed fiscal year, and is not a large accelerated filer. This temporary exemption for low-revenue issuers shall expire upon the earliest of:

 the last day of the issuer's fiscal year following the tenth anniversary of its first sale of common equity securities pursuant to an effective registration statement under the Securities Act of 1933, the last day of the issuer's fiscal year during which the issuer's average annual gross revenues exceed $50 million, or the date upon which the issuer becomes a large accelerated filer.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-588</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
