<bill session="115" type="s" number="823" updated="2019-06-17T18:45:25Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure the digital contents of electronic equipment and online accounts belonging to or in the possession of United States persons entering or exiting the United States are adequately protected at the border, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Data at the Border Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Data at the Border Act</title>
    <title type="display">Protecting Data at the Border Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2017-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2017-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000603" joined="2017-04-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-11">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Subcommittee on Federal Spending Oversight and Emergency Management. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 115-365.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Spending Oversight and Emergency Management" code="SSGA18" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Hearings"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Legislative Interest"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="1899"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-04T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting Data at the Border Act

This bill prohibits a governmental entity from: (1) accessing the digital contents of electronic equipment belonging to, or in the possession of, a U.S. person (person) at the border without a valid warrant; or (2) denying a person's U.S. entry or exit based on the person's refusal to disclose an access credential or in order to determine whether such person will consensually provide an access credential, access, or online account information.

A border officer may access the digital contents of electronic equipment without a warrant if the officer determines that an emergency situation exists. The officer must subsequently apply for a warrant within seven days, and if such warrant is not granted: (1) digital content copies must be destroyed, (2) digital contents or information may not be disclosed, and (3) the person shall be notified of such destruction.

A governmental entity may not make or retain a copy of the digital contents of electronic equipment, an online account, or online account information without probable cause to believe that such information contains evidence of, or constitutes the fruits of, a crime.

Unlawfully accessed information: (1) must be destroyed and the person notified of its destruction; (2) may not be disclosed; and (3) may not be received in evidence in any trial, hearing, or other proceeding.

A governmental entity shall keep a record of each instance in which it obtains access to an individual's digital information.

A governmental entity may not seize electronic equipment belonging to, or in the possession of, a person at the border without probable cause to believe that such equipment contains information relevant to a felony.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
