<bill session="114" type="s" number="2191" updated="2018-06-02T07:11:10Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PARTNERSHIPS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Access and Retention Through New Efforts to Require Shared Higher Investments in Postsecondary Success Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish Federal-State higher education financing partnerships to drive down the cost of tuition for millions of American students.</title>
    <title type="display">PARTNERSHIPS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2015-10-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5756"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Promoting Access and Retention Through New Efforts to Require Shared Higher Investments in Postsecondary Success Act or the PARTNERSHIPS Act

This bill amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to establish a state-federal partnership to promote state investment in public higher education. The bill directs the Department of Education to award annual block grants to states that increase public higher education operating support on a per student basis, using a specified formula. As a condition of receiving grants, states must use grant funds to reduce tuition costs and support the enrollment of low-income students in state public educational institutions.

The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) expand and make permanent the American Opportunity Tax Credit; (2) increase the amount of the tax exclusion for employer-provided educational assistance programs and make such exclusion available to the spouses and dependents of employees; (3) allow tax exclusions for the discharge of certain public interest student loans, repayments of student loans by tax-exempt organizations, and student loans subject to an income-based or income contingent repayment plan; (4) allow a full exclusion from gross income of Federal Pell Grants; and (5) repeal the requirement that distributions from a qualified tuition plan (529 plan) be aggregated for purposes of determining the amount includible in taxpayer income.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
