<bill session="115" type="s" number="1875" updated="2019-04-18T16:39:17Z">
  <state datetime="2017-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to move the United States toward greater energy independence and security, to increase the flexibility, efficiency, and reliability of the electric grid, to increase the competitiveness of the United States economy, to protect consumers, and to improve the energy performance of the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Flexible Grid Infrastructure Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Flexible Grid Infrastructure Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Flexible Grid Infrastructure Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2017-10-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-09-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6188" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-11-29">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Energy. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy" code="SSEG01" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1874"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hybrid, electric, and advanced technology vehicles"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Lighting, heating, cooling"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-09-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Flexible Grid Infrastructure Act of 2017 

This bill amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to require the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) and the Department of Energy (DOE) to address the flexibility, reliability, resilience, affordability, efficiency, and security of the electric grid. Specifically, FERC and DOE must: (1) access the technical and economic potential of distributed energy resources, and (2) establish an online clearinghouse of data relating to distributed energy resources. A distributed energy resource means an electric device that can produce or consume energy that is located on the grid distribution system or on the customer side of the electric grid (e.g., solar roofs).

DOE must also:

 provide technical assistance, an action plan, tools, and information relating to the deployment of distributed energy resources and grid-scale energy storage; research and develop the electrification of transportation, heating, and other technologies; develop model standards to assist states, electric cooperatives, and publicly owned electric utilities in the voluntary updating of standards for resource and energy assurance planning, ensuring distribution-grid reliability from natural disasters, and improving security; evaluate whether new performance standards and testing procedures are needed to ensure the resilience of electrical equipment to security threats or natural disasters; develop guidelines for calculating the costs and benefits of investments in resilience and security solutions for the electric grid; provide related workforce training; and establish the Flexible Grid Challenge 2022, a grant program that helps states enhance the peak load management and flexibility of the electric grid.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
