<bill session="115" type="h" number="4133" updated="2019-04-18T16:16:54Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-10-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish a Medicare payment option for patients and eligible professionals to freely contract, without penalty, for Medicare fee-for-service items and services, while allowing Medicare beneficiaries to use their Medicare benefits.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Patient Empowerment Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Patient Empowerment Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Medicare Patient Empowerment Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001077" joined="2018-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2017-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000292" joined="2018-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2017-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000582" joined="2017-10-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-10-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3610"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-10-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Medicare Patient Empowerment Act of 2017

This bill allows any Medicare beneficiary to enter into a contract with an eligible professional, regardless of whether the professional is a participating or non-participating physician or practitioner, for any item or service covered by Medicare. Such beneficiaries may submit a claim for Medicare payment in the amount that would otherwise apply, except that, where the professional is considered to be non-participating, payment shall be paid as if the professional were participating. An eligible professional is&#160; a physician, physician assistant, nurse practitioner, clinical nurse specialist, certified registered nurse anesthetist, certified nurse-midwife, clinical social worker, clinical psychologist, physical or occupational therapist, qualified speech-language pathologist, or qualified audiologist.

A Medicare beneficiary must agree in writing in such a contract to: (1) pay the eligible professional for a Medicare-covered item or service; and (2) submit, in lieu of the eligible professional, a claim for Medicare payment. However, a beneficiary may negotiate, as a term of the contract, for the eligible professional to file such claims on the beneficiary's behalf.

The bill preempts state laws from limiting the amount of charges for physician and practitioner services for which Medicare payment is made.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
