<bill session="113" type="h" number="5271" updated="2016-10-25T16:15:42Z">
  <state datetime="2014-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Healthy Climate and Family Security Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To cap the emissions of greenhouse gases through a requirement to purchase carbon permits, to distribute the proceeds of such purchases to eligible individuals, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Healthy Climate and Family Security Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000128"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2014-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001032" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2014-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Power" code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-07-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Healthy Climate and Family Security Act of 2014 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to require the Department of the Treasury to establish for 2015 and thereafter a carbon trading program that caps the emissions of carbon dioxide (CO2) from crude oil, coal, and natural gas by requiring crude oil refineries, petroleum importers, coal mines, and natural gas suppliers or processors to purchase carbon permits.

Establishes a declining cap on the quantity of permits issued to reduce CO2 emissions until they are reduced to 80% below 2005 levels by 2050.

Sets forth provisions concerning compliance with permit obligations, issuance of permits for carbon capture and sequestration, and permit auctioning, trading, banking, and borrowing.

Establishes the Healthy Climate Trust Fund and appropriates auction proceeds and penalty payments to it. Returns Trust Fund amounts not used for administrative expenses (as a fraction of auction proceeds) to individuals with a valid Social Security number in the form of Healthy Climate Dividend Payments.

Requires the Department of the Treasury to: (1) impose carbon equivalency fees to be collected by U.S. Customs and Border Protection on imports of carbon-intensive goods, and (2) give payments to exporters of comparable domestically produced carbon-intensive goods.

Requires the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to publish a rule listing greenhouse gases (GHGs) that includes anthropogenically emitted (caused by human activity) gases that contribute to global warming but excludes CO2 emitted by the combustion of crude oil, coal, and natural gas and gases attributable to the production of animals for food. Directs the EPA to promulgate regulations to reduce such non-auction GHGs and ensure the regulation of all sources of them within 10 years.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
