<bill session="114" type="h" number="3836" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:23Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FAIR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Foreign Affairs Inclusion Reporting Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require a report on diversity recruitment, employment, retention, and promotion at the Department of State, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">FAIR Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001270" joined="2015-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2015-10-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Foreign Affairs Inclusion Reporting Act or the FAIR Act

This bill directs the Department of State to report to Congress within 180 days and quadrennially thereafter on State Department efforts to promote equal opportunity for all American employees in direct hire and personal service contractors status, particularly Foreign Service employees.

Beginning in FY2016, the State Department shall: (1) increase by 10 the number of fellows selected for the Charles B. Rangel International Affairs Program, and (2) increase by 10 the number of fellows selected for the Thomas R. Pickering Foreign Affairs Fellowship Program.

 The State Department is urged to provide oversight to the employment, retention, and promotion of underrepresented groups to promote a diverse ethnic representation among mid- and senior-level career professionals through programs such as: (1) the International Career Advancement Program, (2) Seminar XXI at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology's Center for International Studies, and (3) other international leadership programs.

The State Department is also urged to review past programs designed to increase minority representation in international affairs positions, including: (1) the Public Policy and International Affairs Fellowship Program, and (2) the Institute for International Public Policy Fellowship Program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
