<bill session="115" type="h" number="3242" updated="2019-04-18T16:12:43Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To expand access to the Rural Community Facilities Program of the Department of Agriculture, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To expand access to the Rural Community Facilities Program of the Department of Agriculture, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001053"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2017-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-08-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commodity Exchanges, Energy, and Credit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Commodity Exchanges, Energy, and Credit" code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to modify the requirements for the Department of Agriculture (USDA) Rural Community Facilities Program, which provides funding to develop essential community facilities in rural areas.

For the purposes of the program, a "rural area" may not have a population of more than 20,000 inhabitants. The bill increases the limit to 35,000 inhabitants for determinations made under the program on or after April 1 of any fiscal year. In making a grant or loan on or after April 1, USDA must give priority to applications with respect to community facilities at which public safety, health care, and job training are to be provided.

In awarding grants for essential community facilities technical assistance and training, USDA must allow applications for grants from qualified organizations for the sole purpose of providing on-site training and technical assistance on a national or multi-state regional basis.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
