<bill session="115" type="h" number="3922" updated="2019-06-13T17:59:43Z">
  <state datetime="2017-11-03T11:06:59-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-11-03T11:06:59-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To extend funding for certain public health programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">CHAMPIONING HEALTHY KIDS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Continuing Community Health And Medical Professional Programs to Improve Our Nation, Increase National Gains, and Help Ensure Access for Little Ones, Toddlers, and Hopeful Youth by Keeping Insurance Delivery Stable Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Continuing Community Health And Medical Professional Programs to Improve Our Nation, Increase National Gains, and Help Ensure Access for Little Ones, Toddlers, and Hopeful Youth by Keeping Insurance Delivery Stable Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">CHAMPION Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">CHAMPION Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Community Health And Medical Professionals Improve Our Nation Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Community Health And Medical Professionals Improve Our Nation Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">HEALTHY KIDS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">HEALTHY KIDS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Helping Ensure Access for Little Ones, Toddlers, and Hopeful Youth by Keeping Insurance Delivery Stable Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Helping Ensure Access for Little Ones, Toddlers, and Hopeful Youth by Keeping Insurance Delivery Stable Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">CHAMPION Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">CHAMPION Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Community Health And Medical Professionals Improve Our Nation Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Community Health And Medical Professionals Improve Our Nation Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CHAMPION Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CHAMPION Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Health And Medical Professionals Improve Our Nation Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Health And Medical Professionals Improve Our Nation Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">CHAMPIONING HEALTHY KIDS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000791"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-10-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-04">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-10-04" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 28 - 23.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-10-19">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 115-359, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-19">
      <text>Committee on Ways and Means discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-10-19" calendar="Union" number="262">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 262.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-11-01T18:41:17-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 601 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3922 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-02T15:39:24-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 601 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-03T09:15:10-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 601.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8449-8475" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-03T09:15:15-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3922 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-03T09:16:02-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 3922.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-03T10:27:50-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-03T10:28:09-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Clyburn moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8466-8472" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-03T10:28:50-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Clyburn motion to recommit with instructions pending reservation of a point of order. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to strike all after the enacting clause and insert a complete new text entitled "Continuing Community Health and Medical Professional Programs to Improve Our Nation and Keep Insurance Delivery Stable Act of 2017". Subsequently, the reservation was removed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-03T10:34:52-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-03T10:59:33-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 187 - 231 (Roll no. 605).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="606" datetime="2017-11-03T11:06:59-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 242 - 174 (Roll no. 606).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8449-8456" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-11-03T11:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-06">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="4541"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1892"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3917"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3924"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="829"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2209"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3926"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2597"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="procedurally-related" number="601"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3900"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3932"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3921"/>
    <bill type="hj" session="115" relation="unknown" number="124"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2959"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h476"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2017-11-03T12:26:47Z" status="Passed House amended">Continuing Community Health And Medical Professional Programs to Improve Our Nation, Increase National Gains, and Help Ensure Access for Little Ones, Toddlers, and Hopeful Youth by Keeping Insurance Delivery Stable Act of 2017 or the CHAMPIONING HEALTHY KIDS Act

DIVISION A--CHAMPION ACT

Community Health And Medical Professionals Improve Our Nation Act of 2017 or the Champion Act

TITLE I--EXTENSION OF PUBLIC HEALTH PROGRAMS

(Sec. 101) This bill amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to extend funding through FY2019 for community health centers and the National Health Service Corps. Health centers that serve medically underserved populations may receive supplemental grant funds to increase access to primary care services. In awarding health center operating grants, special consideration may be given to a new center that&#160;is located in a sparely populated area or in an area that has a higher level of unmet need. Loan guarantees are no longer made to assist health centers to plan and&#160;develop a managed care network or to plan and develop practice management networks. The bill provides funds for FY2018 to support the participation of health centers in the All of Us Research Program&#160;in the National Institutes of Health's&#160;Precision Medicine Initiative.

The bill increases and extends funding through FY2019 for teaching health centers that sponsor graduate medical residency training programs. Priority is given to teaching health centers that serve health professional shortage areas, serve medically underserved communities, or are in rural areas.The Department of Health and Human Services must report on expenses associated with graduate medical residency training programs.

(Sec. 102) The bill amends the Public Health Service Act to extend funding through FY2019 for type I diabetes research and the prevention and treatment of diabetes&#160;in Native Americans.

(Sec. 103) The bill amends the Social Security Act to increase and extend funding through FY2019 for family-to-family health information centers, which assist families of children with disabilities or special health needs.

(Sec. 104) The bill creates, and makes appropriations in FY2018 and FY2019 for, the Youth Empowerment Program. The program shall fund allotments to states or other entities to implement education exclusively&#160;about sexual risk avoidance (voluntarily refraining from sexual activity). Up to 20% of&#160;an allotment may be used to build evidence for sexual&#160;risk avoidance education.

The bill extends funding for the grant program&#160;for personal responsibility education through FY2019.

TITLE II--OFFSETS

(Sec. 201) The bill revises the grace period that health insurers must provide to recipients of premium subsidies before discontinuing health coverage for nonpayment of premiums. The grace period is shortened from three months to one month unless state law includes an&#160;applicable grace period.

The Government Accountability Office must report about the effects on consumers of aligning grace periods for Medicaid, Medicare, and plans offered on health insurance exchanges, including whether such an alignment may reduce fraud, waste, and abuse under Medicaid.

(Sec. 202) The bill reduces appropriations for the Prevention and Public Health Fund through FY2025 and continues funding through FY2027.

DIVISION B--HEALTHY KIDS ACT

Helping Ensure Access for Little Ones, Toddlers, and Hopeful Youth by Keeping Insurance Delivery Stable Act of 2017 or the HEALTHY KIDS Act

TITLE I--CHIP EXTENSION AND OTHER MEDICAID AND CHIP PROVISIONS

 (Sec. 301) The bill extends funding through FY2022 for&#160;the&#160;Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP).

In addition, the bill reauthorizes through FY2022:

 the qualifying-states option (which allows states that provided coverage to now CHIP-eligible children prior to CHIP's enactment to continue to provide such coverage), and the express-lane eligibility option (which allows states to use eligibility findings from other public benefit programs to determine&#160;children's eligibility for Medicaid and CHIP). Beginning in FY2020, the bill allows&#160;state child-health plans&#160;to adopt more restrictive eligibility standards with respect to children in families whose income exceeds 300% of the poverty line.

(Sec. 302) The bill extends funding through FY2022 for the Childhood Obesity Demonstration Project and the Pediatric Quality Measures Program.

(Sec. 303) The bill: (1)&#160;extends funding through FY2022 for specified outreach and enrollment grants, and (2) makes eligible for such grants "parent-mentors" who are trained to assist families with children who have no health-insurance coverage.

(Sec. 304) Current law provides states with an enhanced Federal Matching Assistance Percentage (FMAP) for child-health assistance through FY2019. The bill&#160;maintains the&#160;enhanced FMAP&#160;in FY2020, but&#160;halves the&#160;percentage-point increase.

(Sec. 305) The bill eliminates Medicaid payment reductions for disproportionate-share hospitals (which receive additional payment&#160;under Medicaid for treating a large share of low-income patients) in FY2018 and FY2019, but increases such reductions from FY2021-FY2025.

(Sec. 306) The bill also increases Medicaid funding for Puerto Rico and the U.S. Virgin Islands through FY2019. Such funding&#160;shall be further increased through 2019 for both territories if Puerto Rico takes specified actions&#160;to improve its&#160;Medicaid program.

TITLE II--OFFSETS

(Sec. 401) The bill alters provisions related to third-party liability under Medicaid and CHIP.

(Sec. 402) The bill specifies how a state must treat qualified lottery winnings and lump-sum income for purposes of determining Medicaid eligibility.

(Sec. 403) The bill eliminates&#160;Medicare premium subsidies&#160;for beneficiaries with annual incomes&#160;exceeding $500,000.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-359</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
