<bill session="115" type="h" number="2804" updated="2019-04-18T16:10:10Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Transportation to implement changes to improve air transportation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Airline Consumer Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Airline Consumer Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Airline Consumer Protection Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2017-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2017-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Aviation" code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Airline Consumer Protection Act of 2017

This bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to issue a final rule to require an air carrier to:

 seek, for a delay exceeding three hours, a cancellation, or a misconnection as a result of circumstances within the air carrier's control, alternative transportation for a displaced passenger; and accept, for a reasonable fee, a displaced passenger from another air carrier or a passenger involuntarily denied boarding due to a lack of available seats. The Government Accountability Office shall submit a report that reviews airline computer network functions.

 Any air carrier schedule change resulting from a computer network disruption, security breach, or other inoperability may be considered an event within a carrier's control.

DOT shall:

 publish a final rule to require an air carrier to submit to the Federal Aviation Administration a plan for restoring full functionality of its computer network systems in the event of a service disruption; establish an airline industry computer network resiliency working group; modify federal regulations to require each air carrier to adopt a contingency plan for any delay, cancellation, or misconnection affecting a passenger; and issue regulations to ensure that a ticketed passenger shall not pay a fee to select an alternative flight if the aircraft's lavatory is not functioning.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
