<bill session="114" type="h" number="4189" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:26Z">
  <state datetime="2015-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Funding for Terrorism Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to require congressional approval of rescissions of determinations of countries as state sponsors of terrorism and waivers of prohibitions on assistance to state sponsors of terrorism under that Act.</title>
    <title type="display">Stop Funding for Terrorism Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000458"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000569" joined="2015-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-12-08T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop Funding for Terrorism Act

This bill amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 with respect to requirements the Department of State must meet to rescind any determination that the government of a foreign country:

 has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism; and for this reason may not receive assistance under the Act, the Food for Peace Act, the Peace Corps Act, or the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945. The State Department may rescind such a determination and waive the prohibition on assistance only if, in addition to other existing requirements for rescission and waiver, Congress enacts a joint resolution of approval according to a specified procedure.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
