<amendment session="114" chamber="s" number="801" updated="2018-06-04T02:15:43Z">
  <amends type="sc" number="11" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2015-03-25">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001111"/>
  <offered datetime="2015-03-25"/>
  <description>To build on the Bipartisan Budget Act of 2013 by restoring a below-sequester level cut of $9,000,000,000 to nondefense discretionary spending in 2017, replacing sequestration in 2016 and 2017 and increasing funding above sequester levels by a total of $148,000,000,000 for the 2 years, increasing defense and nondefense discretionary spending above sequester levels by equal amounts, eliminating the overseas contingency operations gimmick contained in the committee-reported resolution, and offsetting the net increase in defense and nondefense discretionary spending by closing tax loopholes.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2015-03-25" how="roll" result="fail" roll="91">
      <text>Amendment SA 801 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 46 - 53. Record Vote Number: 91.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Amendment SA 801 proposed by Senator Murray. (consideration: CR S1863-1864, S1871) To build on the Bipartisan Budget Act of 2013 by restoring a below-sequester level cut of $9,000,000,000 to nondefense discretionary spending in 2017, replacing sequestration in 2016 and 2017 and increasing funding above sequester levels by a total of $148,000,000,000 for the 2 years, increasing defense and nondefense discretionary spending above sequester levels by equal amounts, eliminating the overseas contingency operations gimmick contained in the committee-reported resolution, and offsetting the net increase in defense and nondefense discretionary spending by closing tax loopholes.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25"/>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 801 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 46 - 53. Record Vote Number: 91.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Senate amendment not agreed to: Amendment SA 801 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 46 - 53. Record Vote Number: 91.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 801 proposed by Senator Murray.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1863-1864, S1871" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
