<bill session="114" type="s" number="1517" updated="2018-06-02T06:55:00Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VOW to Hire Heroes Extension Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend the work opportunity credit for hiring veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">VOW to Hire Heroes Extension Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2015-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2015-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2015-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2015-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2265"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-04T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">VOW to Hire Heroes Extension Act of 2015

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) extend through 2018 the work opportunity tax credit for hiring a qualified veteran (defined as an unemployed veteran who is certified as being a member of a family receiving food stamp assistance and who is entitled to compensation for a service-connected disability), (2) revise tax credit eligibility requirements for documenting the status of veterans and their receipt of unemployment compensation, and (3) extend the payroll tax offset for such credit to certain for-profit employers.

Directs the Internal Revenue Service, in consultation with the Department of Labor, to make annual reports on the effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of this Act in increasing the employment of veterans.

Requires the Department of the Treasury to pay: (1) each U.S. possession (i.e., American Samoa, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and the U.S. Virgin Islands) with a mirror code tax system amounts equal to the loss to such possession due to this Act; and (2) each U.S. possession without such a tax system an amount estimated to equal the loss to such possession that would have occurred due to this Act if such a tax system had been in effect in that possession.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
