<amendment session="114" chamber="h" number="1405" updated="2019-01-09T21:26:35Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5620" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2016-09-14T15:06:15-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000570"/>
  <offered datetime="2016-09-14"/>
  <description>Amendment directs the VA to produce a report on the number of part-time active duty military physicians in VA health facilities, the hiring process for part-time active duty military physicians, the hiring process for part-time civilian physicians in, and the steps the VA is taking to recruit active duty military physicians for part-time employment in VA health facilities.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 14 printed in House Report 114-742 to direct the VA to produce a report on the number of part-time active duty military physicians in VA health facilities, the hiring process for part-time active duty military physicians, the hiring process for part-time civilian physicians in, and the steps the VA is taking to recruit active duty military physicians for part-time employment in VA health facilities.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2016-09-14T15:06:15-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Lujan, Ben Ray (NM) amendment (A013) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-09-14T15:02:03-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A013) offered by Mr. Lujan, Ben Ray (NM).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5463-5464" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5463" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-14"/>
    <action datetime="2016-09-14T15:02:03-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A013) offered by Mr. Lujan, Ben Ray (NM).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5463-5464" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5463" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-14T15:06:15-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Lujan, Ben Ray (NM) amendment (A013) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-14T15:06:15-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-14">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
