<bill session="113" type="h" number="3961" updated="2016-10-25T16:10:26Z">
  <state datetime="2014-01-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-01-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide Israel a license exception to the Export Administration Regulations currently made available to 36 other nations.</title>
    <title type="display">To provide Israel a license exception to the Export Administration Regulations currently made available to 36 other nations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000556"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-01-29T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Directs the President to direct the Secretary of State to undertake discussions with Israel to identify the steps necessary to include Israel within the list of countries eligible for the Strategic Trade Authorization exception to the requirement for a license for the export, re-export, or in-country transfer of an item subject to certain export controls.

(This exception authorizes exports, re-exports, and transfers [in-country], including releases within a single country of software source code and technology to foreign nationals, in lieu of a license that would otherwise be required. The list of countries eligible for the license exception covers those countries with respect to which the reasons for control that would ordinarily impose the license requirement include national security, chemical or biological weapons, nuclear nonproliferation, regional stability, crime control, and/or significant items authorized for destinations in or nationals of a specified Country Group.)</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
