<bill session="114" type="h" number="2712" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:13Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Commonsense Reporting and Verification Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To streamline the employer reporting process and strengthen the eligibility verification process for the health care premium tax credit and cost-sharing subsidy, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Commonsense Reporting and Verification Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001273"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001255" joined="2016-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001077" joined="2016-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2016-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2015-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001055" joined="2015-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000586" joined="2015-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000583" joined="2015-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2015-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1996"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Commonsense Reporting and Verification Act of 2015

This bill requires the Department of Treasury to implement and maintain a voluntary prospective reporting system for employers subject to the employer mandate under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA).

Employers satisfy the information return requirement if they voluntarily report general information about the health coverage offered to full-time employees. Employers satisfy the employee statement requirement if they provide statements to employees after receiving exchange notification that employee or spouse or dependent enrolled in a qualified health plan or qualified for premium tax credits or cost-sharing subsidies.

The legislation amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) permit employers and health insurance issuers that provide minimum essential coverage to submit an information return with names and birth dates of covered dependents if the employer or health insurance issuer does not already collect or maintain their taxpayer identification numbers, and (2) permit electronic delivery of employee statement if employee consented previously to electronic delivery of other notices and does not refuse consent in writing.

It directs the Government Accountability Office to: (1) evaluate the exchange notification and appeals processes for employers whose employee or spouse or dependent enrolls in a qualified health plan or qualifies for premium tax credits or cost-sharing subsidies, and (2) evaluate the prospective reporting system functionality.

The legislation permits a health insurance exchange to automatically reenroll an individual into a qualified health plan after annually redetermining the individual's eligibility for premium tax credits or cost-sharing subsidies.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
