<bill session="114" type="h" number="5893" updated="2019-02-14T23:05:49Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Regulation Without Representation Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To regulate certain State impositions on interstate commerce.</title>
    <title type="display">No Regulation Without Representation Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000244"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-08-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Antitrust, Commercial, and Administrative Law" code="HSJU05" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">No Regulation Without Representation Act of 2016 

This bill prohibits a state from imposing sales and use tax obligations or assessments on a person who is not a purchaser or seller with a physical presence in the state during the calendar quarter for which the obligation or assessment is imposed.

The person must be physically present for a state to: (1) impose obligations for collecting a sales, use, or similar tax or for collecting related information; (2) assess such a tax on a person; or (3) treat a person as doing business in the state for the purposes of such a tax.

A person is physically present if the person's business activities in the state include:

 owning or leasing certain property in the state; having one or more employees, agents, or independent contractors in the state specifically soliciting product or service orders from customers in the state or who provide on-site design, installation, or repair services on behalf of the remote seller; or maintaining an office in the state with at least three employees. Physical presence does not include: (1) certain referral agreements, (2) presence for less than 15 days in a year, (3) delivery and product placement services offered by an interstate or in-state common carrier, or (4) Internet advertising services provided by in-state residents which are not exclusively directed towards or exclusively soliciting in-state customers.

The bill specifies that U.S. district courts have original jurisdiction over civil actions to enforce this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
