<bill session="114" type="s" number="3535" updated="2018-06-02T07:49:04Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clean Up the Department of Veterans Affairs Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to prohibit the Secretary of Veterans Affairs from employing any individual who has been convicted of a felony and medical personnel who have had their medical licenses or credentials revoked or suspended, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Clean Up the Department of Veterans Affairs Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000444"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-08T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Clean Up the Department of Veterans Affairs Act of 2016

This bill prohibits the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) from employing any individual who has been convicted of any of the following state or federal criminal offenses for which the minimum term of imprisonment is more than one year:

 a sex offense, an offense involving the sale or distribution of a controlled substance, fraud, theft, assault, battery, a crime of violence, an offense involving the use of a firearm or other deadly weapon, bank robbery, or kidnapping. The VA may not employ any individual in a health care position who has had a license or credential relating to such position revoked or suspended.

The VA shall: (1) conduct background checks before hiring, and (2) terminate any individual employed by the VA in violation of this bill in a manner consistent with merit system principles.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
