<bill session="114" type="h" number="3893" updated="2018-06-02T04:47:46Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AIPM Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Areawide Integrated Pest Management Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reform Act of 1998 with respect to grants for certain areawide integrated pest management projects, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">AIPM Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2015-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001166" joined="2015-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000596" joined="2015-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2015-11-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7638"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Biotechnology, Horticulture, and Research.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Biotechnology, Horticulture, and Research" code="HSAG14" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Areawide Integrated Pest Management Act of 2015 or the AIPM Act of 2015 

This bill amends the Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reform Act of 1998 to expand the Department of Agriculture's (USDA's) Integrated Research, Education, and Extension Competitive Grants Program to include grants to colleges, universities, and other entities for qualified areawide integrated pest management projects to prevent the spread of pests and invasive species.

The bill establishes an areawide integrated pest management committee to consider stakeholder feedback and determine priorities for the projects.

The projects must be implemented on a landscape scale or larger and include collaboration with specified federal, regional, state, and nongovernmental entities. The projects may prevent the spread of pests and invasive species through: prevention, avoidance, monitoring, and suppression; educational programs; and physical, mechanical, cultural biologically-based, or chemical controls.

A qualified project must:

 provide for significant benefits for the prevention, eradication, or management of pests and invasive species; provide for economic and environmental benefits to agriculture, individuals, wildlife, and the environment; address the annual priorities established by the integrated pest management committee; last no more than five years; establish a regional advisory committee to oversee the project; and involve the cooperative extension services in translating the results of research into practical information and tools to be shared. USDA must transfer to the National Institute of Food and Agriculture the authority for the Integrated Research, Education, and Extension Competitive Grants Program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
