<bill session="115" type="h" number="3978" updated="2019-06-13T17:59:58Z">
  <state datetime="2018-02-14T17:05:08-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-02-14T17:05:08-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act of 1974 to modify requirements related to mortgage disclosures, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">TRID Improvement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">TRID Improvement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TRID Improvement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TRID Improvement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">TRID Improvement Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001072"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001282" joined="2017-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000294" joined="2017-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000581" joined="2017-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2017-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001074" joined="2017-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000390" joined="2017-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000569" joined="2017-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001189" joined="2017-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000190" joined="2017-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000588" joined="2017-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000593" joined="2017-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000487" joined="2017-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2017-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2017-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001187" joined="2017-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000478" joined="2017-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000816" joined="2017-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000017" joined="2017-11-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-09-07">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit Prior to Introduction and Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-11-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 53 - 5.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-01-25">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 115-524.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-01-25" calendar="Union" number="389">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 389.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-02-13T19:12:03-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 736 Reported to House. Provides for consideration of H.R. 620 and H.R. 3978 under structured rules and H.R. 3299 under a closed rule. Each bill shall be debatable for one hour. The resolution provides for proceedings during the period of February 16, 2018 through February 23, 2018.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-14T13:50:13-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 736 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-14T15:13:35-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 736.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1155-1169" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-14T15:13:40-05:00">
      <text>Provides for consideration of H.R. 620 and H.R. 3978 under structured rules and H.R. 3299 under a closed rule. Each bill shall be debatable for one hour. The resolution provides for proceedings during the period of February 16, 2018 through February 23, 2018.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-14T15:15:11-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 3978.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-14T16:11:40-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 736, the House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Foster amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-14T16:18:39-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the bill and amendment pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-14T16:19:26-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Capuano moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Financial Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1166" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-14T16:20:53-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the motion to recommit with instructions, pending the reservation of a point of order.The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back with an amendment to extend exemptions to include companies that have claw back policies that require any executive officer incentive-based compensation to be clawed-back in the event that the issuer is required to prepare an accounting restatement due to the material noncompliance of the issuer with any financial reporting requirement under the securities laws, regardless of whether such compensation was paid to an officer who was a party to the actions that resulted in such restatement. Subsequently, the point of order was removed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-14T16:31:03-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-14T16:57:17-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 189 - 228 (Roll no. 76).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="77" datetime="2018-02-14T17:05:08-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 271 - 145 (Roll no. 77).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1155-1156" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-02-14T17:05:10-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-15">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Consumer Protection and Financial Institutions" code="HSBA15" name="House Financial Services" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="10"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1645"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2948"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3948"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="4546"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1753"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2126"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3733"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="5078"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="procedurally-related" number="736"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2490"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h518"/>
    <amendment number="h517"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2018-02-14T14:39:02Z" status="Passed House amended">(Sec. 2) This bill specifies that the amount deposited in the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) Reserve Fund for FY2018 may not exceed $48 million.

TITLE I--TRID IMPROVEMENT

(Sec. 101) The bill amends the Real Estate Settlement Procedures of 1974 to modify disclosure requirements&#160;applicable to mortgage loan transactions. Specifically, the disclosed charges for any title insurance premium shall be equal to the amount charged for each individual title insurance policy, subject to any discounts as required by either state regulation or the title company rate filings.

TITLE II--PROTECTION OF SOURCE CODE

(Sec. 201) The bill amends the Securities Act of 1933, the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, the Investment Company Act of 1940, and the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 to specify that the SEC may not compel a person to produce a source code or similar intellectual property without first issuing a subpoena.

TITLE III--FOSTERING INNOVATION

(Sec. 301) The bill amends the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 with respect to auditor-attestation requirements for public companies.

These requirements shall not apply with respect to any audit report prepared for an issuer that:

 ceased to be an emerging growth company on the last day of its fiscal year following the fifth anniversary of its first sale of common equity securities, had average annual gross revenues of less than $50 million as of its most recently completed fiscal year, and is not a large accelerated filer. This exemption shall expire at the earliest of: (1) the last day of the fiscal year 10 years after the issuer's first sale of common equity securities, (2) the end of the fiscal year in which the issuer's average annual gross revenues exceed $50 million, or (3) when the issuer becomes a large accelerated filer.

TITLE IV--NATIONAL SECURITIES EXCHANGE REGULATORY PARITY

(Sec. 401) The bill amends the Securities Act of 1933 to exempt from state registration securities qualified for national trading by the SEC and authorized to be listed on a national securities exchange. Currently, securities listed on exchanges specified by statute or rule are exempt.

TITLE V--ELIMINATING BARRIERS TO JOBS FOR LOAN ORIGINATORS

(Sec. 501) The bill amends the S.A.F.E. Mortgage Licensing Act of 2008 to temporarily allow loan originators that meet specified requirements to continue to originate loans after moving: (1) from one state to another, or (2) from a depository institution to a non-depository institution.

(Sec. 502) The bill revises the S.A.F.E. Mortgage Licensing Act's civil liability immunity provisions.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-524</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
