<bill session="114" type="h" number="3581" updated="2019-04-11T15:42:42Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require full funding of part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 and the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keep Our PACT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keep Our Promise to America's Children and Teachers Act</title>
    <title type="display">Keep Our PACT Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000128"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="551"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Keep Our Promise to America's Children and Teachers Act or the Keep Our PACT Act

This bill: (1) amends the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA) to reauthorize and mandate funding levels for&#160;a program that awards grants to states for the provision of special education and related services to children with disabilities, and (2) mandates funding levels for school improvement programs under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA).

With respect to the IDEA grant program, the bill establishes funding levels for each year from FY2016-FY2024 in amounts equal to&#160;the greater of: (1) a specified amount for the applicable fiscal year, or (2) a specified percentage of an amount determined pursuant to a formula that multiplies the number of children receiving special education services by the national average per-pupil expenditure in public elementary and secondary schools. Funding levels for FY2025 and beyond must equal the greater of a specified amount or 40% of the amount determined using this formula.

With respect to school improvement programs under ESEA, the bill establishes funding levels for each year from FY2016-FY2025 in amounts equal to the difference between: (1) the amount appropriated for the programs in FY2015, and (2) the greater of a specified amount for the applicable fiscal year or the full amount authorized to be appropriated for that fiscal year for such programs.

Amounts appropriated under the bill must be expended in a manner consistent with pay-as-you-go requirements.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
