<bill session="114" type="s" number="176" updated="2018-06-02T06:29:57Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">W21</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Water in the 21st Century Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to advance integrated water management and development through innovation, resiliency, conservation, and efficiency in the 21st century, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Water in the 21st Century Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000711"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2015-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000146" joined="2015-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="291"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="813"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="653"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4497"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6022"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-13T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Water in the 21st Century Act or W21

This bill establishes within the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) a WaterSense program to identify, label, and promote water efficient products, buildings, landscapes, facilities, processes, and services.

This bill establishes a program to provide financial incentives for consumers to purchase and install products, buildings, landscapes, facilities, processes, and services labeled under the WaterSense program.

The EPA is required to make grants to owners or operators of water systems to address any ongoing or forecasted impact of climate change on a region's water quality or quantity.

The Department of the Interior may: (1) provide financial assistance to water projects in specified states, including projects for water recycling, water infrastructure, enhanced energy efficiency, desalination, and water storage and conveyance; and (2) transfer to nonfederal entities title to any reclamation projects or facility in need of rehabilitation that are authorized before enactment of this Act.

The U.S. Geological Survey must establish an open water data system to advance the availability, timely distribution, and widespread use of water data and information for water management, education, research, assessment, and monitoring purposes.

This bill reauthorizes through FY2020 the Water Desalination Act of 1996 and water resources research and technology institutes under the Water Resources Research Act of 1984.

After receiving a request from a nonfederal sponsor, the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers must review the operation of a reservoir and, if appropriate, update the water control manual to incorporate improved weather and runoff forecasting methods.

The EPA is required to develop voluntary national drought resilience guidelines relating to preparedness planning and investments for water users and providers.

The U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service must prepare a salmon drought plan for California.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
