<bill session="114" type="h" number="5780" updated="2019-05-09T23:32:59Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide greater conservation, recreation, economic development and local management of Federal lands in Utah, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Utah Public Lands Initiative Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Scofield Land Transfer Act</title>
    <title type="display">Utah Public Lands Initiative Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001076" joined="2016-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22">
      <text>Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-09-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 21 - 13.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indigenous Peoples of the United States" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="14"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Utah Public Lands Initiative Act

This bill designates specified federal lands as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System in Utah.

The bill also:

 establishes in Utah specified National Conservation Areas and Watershed Management Areas and Special Management Areas, adds specified lands to Arches National Park, and establishes the Jurassic National Monument. The Wild and Scenic Rivers Act is amended to designate specified segments of the Colorado, Dolores, Green, Dark Canyon, and San Juan Rivers as wild, scenic, or recreational rivers.

The bill establishes the Ashley Karst National Geologic and Recreation Area.

The bill arranges for a land exchange between Utah and the Department of the Interior involving specified federal and state trust lands, and reserves a wellbore interest in certain oil and gas wells on the federal lands.

Interior shall convey specified federal land to the Utah State Parks and Recreation Division of the Department of Natural Resources for inclusion in Goblin Valley State Park.

The bill arranges for a land exchange between Interior and Utah's Division of Forestry, Fire, and State lands involving specified federal and state lands in order for Utah to create the Price Canyon State Forest.

The bill arranges for a land exchange between the Department of Agriculture (USDA) and the Deer Lodge Homeowners Association involving specified National Forest System and private lands.

Scofield Land Transfer Act

The bill arranges for conveyances to specified claimants of the federal lands used in the construction and operation of Scofield Dam and Reservoir, and establishes the Scofield Reservoir Fund.

The bill specifies other land conveyances and land disposals, and establishes specified Recreation Zones and the Hole-in-the-Rock Trail.

The bill approves Utah's application for a specified Title V right-of-way concerning travel in Recapture Canyon.

The Big Burrito Non-Motorized Trail in the Sand Flats Recreation Area shall not be subject to administrative or judicial review.

The bill designates the Red Rock Country Off-Highway Vehicle Trail.

The bill transfers the federal minerals within the McCraken Extension of the Navajo Nation to the Utah Navajo Trust Fund.

Interior shall hold certain interests in mineral or surface estate in trust for the Ute Indian Tribe. The bill transfers title to the mineral estate in the Hill Creek Extension to the Bureau of Indian Affairs to be held in trust for the Ute Tribe.

Utah may establish a program covering the permitting processes, regulatory requirements, and any other provisions by which it would exercise its rights to develop and permit all forms of energy resources on certain available federal land.

The bill recognizes Utah state and county rights-of-way for public travel and access on certain Class B roads.

The bill requires Interior to implement the Grand County Council's recommendations for Hey Joe Canyon, Tenmile Canyon, and Mineral Canyon roads.

Interior shall grant a right-of-way to Uintah County for public travel and access on all Class D roads.

The bill allows current domestic livestock grazing in specified counties to continue.

The bill states that the viability or existence of bighorn sheep shall not be used to remove or alter the use of domestic sheep or cattle where such use was permitted as of January 1, 2016, on certain federal lands.

Interior and USDA shall establish the Public Lands Initiative Planning and Implementation Advisory Committee.

The bill establishes the Bears Ears National Conservation Area, the Bears Ears Tribal Commission, and the Bears Ears Advisory Committee.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
