<bill session="113" type="h" number="1422" updated="2016-10-25T16:45:59Z">
  <state datetime="2014-11-18T18:02:17-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-11-18T18:02:17-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">EPA Science Advisory Board Reform Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">EPA Science Advisory Board Reform Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">EPA Science Advisory Board Reform Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Environmental Research, Development, and Demonstration Authorization Act of 1978 to provide for Scientific Advisory Board member qualifications, public participation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">EPA Science Advisory Board Reform Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001192"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001256" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000213" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001271" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001250" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001262" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000448" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000552" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000067" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001052" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001053" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000363" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000591" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000409" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001183" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000583" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000937" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000796" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2013-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-04-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 21 - 16.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-07-22">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology. H. Rept. 113-165.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-22" calendar="Union" number="119">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 119.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17T19:26:47-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 756 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1422, H.R. 4012 and H.R. 4795. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 1422, H.R. 4012, and H.R. 4795. General debate is limited to 1 hour for each bill. The resolution specifies certain amendments are in order for H.R. 1422, H.R. 4012, and H.R. 4795. One motion to recommit with instructions is permitted for each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-18T13:35:37-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 756.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8050-8064" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8050-8051" label="text of measure as reported in the House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-18T13:35:42-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1422, H.R. 4012 and H.R. 4795. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 1422, H.R. 4012, and H.R. 4795. General debate is limited to 1 hour for each bill. The resolution specifies certain amendments are in order for H.R. 1422, H.R. 4012, and H.R. 4795. One motion to recommit with instructions is permitted for each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-18T13:37:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 1422.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-18T14:29:09-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair announced that pursuant to clause 1(c) of rule 19, further proceedings on H.R. 1422 had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-18T17:01:26-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8060-8064" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-18T17:02:10-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 756, the House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Stewart Part A amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-18T17:37:04-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Maloney, Sean moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8062-8063" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="H8062" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-18T17:37:17-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Sean Maloney motion to recommit with instructions, pending reservation of a point of order. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to prohibit people from serving on the Science Advisory Board if they represent a corporation or a trade association with a financial interest in the outcome of the Boards decisions. The reservation of the point of order was subsequently withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-18T17:45:33-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8062" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-18T17:53:39-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 195 - 225 (Roll no. 524).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="525" datetime="2014-11-18T18:02:17-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 229 - 191 (Roll no. 525).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-11-18T18:02:19-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-19">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1853"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="113" relation="unknown" number="756"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1145"/>
    <amendment number="h1144"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2014-11-18T13:03:04Z" status="Passed House amended">EPA Science Advisory Board Reform Act of 2014 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Environmental Research, Development, and Demonstration Authorization Act of 1978 to revise requirements for the Science Advisory Board, which gives scientific advice to the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), and address public disclosure of scientific and technical information that the EPA uses as a basis for agency actions.

Emphasizes that the Board provides such advice independently.

Revises the process of selecting members of the Board. Requires at least 10% of Board membership to represent state, local, or tribal governments. Excludes from membership any federally registered lobbyists.

Directs the Board to ensure that:

 the points of view represented on the Board are fairly balanced among the members, persons with substantial and relevant expertise are not excluded from the Board because of affiliation with or representation of entities that might have a potential interest in the Board's advisory activities, and members do not participate in advisory activities that involve review or application of their own work. Revises Board terms of office.

Revises the procedures for providing advice and comments to the EPA by: (1) including draft risk or hazard assessments in the regulatory proposals and documents made available to the Board, and (2) requiring advice and comments to be included in the record regarding any such proposal and published in the Federal Register. Revises the operation of Board member committees and investigative panels to: (1) require that they operate in accordance with the membership, participation, and policy requirements (including new requirements for public participation in advisory activities of the Board) contained in this Act; (2) deny them authority to make decisions on behalf of the Board; and (3) prohibit direct reporting to EPA. Revises requirements for public participation and transparency. Requires the EPA and the Board to make all reports and relevant scientific information available to the public concurrently when that information is made available to the Board. Adds guidelines for the conduct of Board advisory activities, including: (1) avoidance of making policy determinations or recommendations, (2) communication of uncertainties, (3) dissenting members' views, and (4) periodic reviews to ensure that such activities address the most important scientific issues affecting EPA. (Sec. 3) Prohibits this Act from being construed as supplanting the requirements of the Federal Advisory Committee Act or the Ethics in Government Act of 1978.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 113-165</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
