<bill session="114" type="s" number="1227" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:56Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Energy to develop an implementation strategy to promote the development of hybrid micro-grid systems for isolated communities.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to require the Secretary of Energy to develop an implementation strategy to promote the development of hybrid micro-grid systems for isolated communities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2012"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2089"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill requires the Department of Energy to develop an implementation strategy to promote the development of hybrid micro-grid systems for isolated communities, particularly communities exposed to extreme weather conditions and high costs of energy, including electricity, space heating and cooling, and transportation.

A hybrid micro-grid system is a stand-alone electrical system composed of conventional generation and at least one alternative energy resource.

Mandatory considerations in developing the strategy include:

 the potential for renewable resources, including wind, solar, and hydropower, to be integrated into a hybrid micro-grid system; the capacity of the local workforce to operate, maintain, and repair a hybrid micro-grid system; and the need for basic infrastructure to develop, deploy, and sustain a hybrid micro-grid system.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
