<bill session="113" type="s" number="2719" updated="2016-10-25T16:31:54Z">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Manufacturing Universities Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to emphasize manufacturing in engineering programs by directing the National Institute of Standards and Technology, in coordination with other appropriate Federal agencies including the Department of Defense, Department of Energy, and National Science Foundation, to designate United States manufacturing universities.</title>
    <title type="display">Manufacturing Universities Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2014-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="identical" number="5526"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-07-31T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Manufacturing Universities Act of 2014 - Authorizes the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) to establish a program to designate up to 25 institutions of higher education as U.S. manufacturing universities that are to be awarded funds over a four-year period.

Requires an institution applying for such program to submit a plan describing its engineering programs, its relationship to manufacturing industries, and its ability to positively impact local and regional economic development.

Requires NIST to recommend adaptations to certain Small Business Act programs to assist small businesses that collaborate with such universities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
