<bill session="115" type="s" number="737" updated="2019-04-18T16:34:22Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Mineral Leasing Act to improve coal leasing, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coal Oversight and Leasing Reform Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coal Oversight and Leasing Reform Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COAL Reform Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COAL Reform Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">COAL Reform Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Coal Oversight and Leasing Reform Act of 2017or the COAL Reform Act of 2017

This bill amends the Mineral Leasing Act to revise the U.S. coal leasing program.

The bill repeals the requirement that the Department of the Interior offer at least 50% of total acreage for coal leasing in any one-year under a deferred bonus payment system.

A proposed lease sale shall not be held until the Bureau of Land Management (BLM)determines, and includes in a formal appraisal report, the fair market value of the coal to be extracted.Interior shall make certain data available to the public, including the BLM appraisal reports and information on lease sales.

Coal lease modifications shall not result in revenue reduction and may not exceed 160 acres.

Interior shall prepare, periodically revise, and maintain a coal leasing program consisting of a schedule of proposed lease sales indicating the size, timing, and location of leasing activity that will best meet national needs for the five-year period following approval of the program.The bill revises the conditions of a coal lease, including lease terms, rental rates, and royalties.

The BLM shall promulgate regulations for inspections and enforcement of coal operations, including oversight of state inspection and enforcement programs. The BLM may also assess civil penalties for noncompliance.

There shall be a moratorium on new coal lease sales until this bill is implemented by Interior.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
