<bill session="114" type="h" number="5153" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:49Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FISA COURT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FISA Court Oversight Underscoring Responsibility and Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 to provide for the designation of Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court judges by the President, majority of the Supreme Court, Speaker and minority leader of the House of Representatives, and majority leader and minority leader of the Senate.</title>
    <title type="display">FISA COURT Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000057"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">FISA Court Oversight Underscoring Responsibility and Transparency Act or the FISA COURT Act 

This bill amends the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 to require that the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court consist of 11 publicly designated district court judges, of whom:

 2 judges are designated by the President; 1 judge is designated by a majority of the Supreme Court; and 2 judges each are designated, respectively, by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the minority leader of the House of Representatives, and the majority and minority leaders of the Senate. (Currently, the Chief Justice designates all 11 judges.)

A majority of the Supreme Court (currently, the Chief Justice alone) shall designate three judges from the U.S. district courts or courts of appeals who shall comprise the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court of Review.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
