<bill session="113" type="h" number="1169" updated="2018-06-05T16:10:51Z">
  <state datetime="2013-05-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Naval Air Station Fallon Housing and Safety Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Naval Air Station Fallon Housing and Safety Development Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to transfer to the Secretary of the Navy certain Federal land in Churchill County, Nevada.</title>
    <title type="display">Naval Air Station Fallon Housing and Safety Development Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000369"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-15">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-05-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-06-17">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-111.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-06-17" calendar="Union" number="79">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 79.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="5205"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-06-17T13:00:43Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">Naval Air Station Fallon Housing and Safety Development Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to transfer to the Secretary of the Navy, without consideration, approximately 400 acres of federal land that is adjacent to Naval Air Station Fallon in Churchill County, Nevada, and that was withdrawn under a specified public land order.

Prohibits anything in this Act from being construed as: (1) establishing a reservation that favors the United States respecting any water or water right on lands transferred by this Act, or (2) authorizing the appropriation of water on such lands except in accordance with applicable state law.

Withdraws the federal land to be transferred under this Act from all forms of appropriation under the public land laws, including the mining laws and geothermal leasing laws, so long as such land remains under the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Navy.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 113-111</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
