<bill session="114" type="h" number="515" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:36Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-08">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">International Megan's Law to Prevent Demand for Child Sex Trafficking</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">International Megan's Law to Prevent Child Exploitation and Other Sexual Crimes Through Advanced Notification of Traveling Sex Offenders</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">International Megan's Law to Prevent Demand for Child Sex Trafficking</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">International Megan's Law to Prevent Child Exploitation and Other Sexual Crimes Through Advanced Notification of Traveling Sex Offenders</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">International Megan's Law to Prevent Child Exploitation and Other Sexual Crimes Through Advanced Notification of Traveling Sex Offenders</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect children from exploitation, especially sex trafficking in tourism, by providing advance notice of intended travel by registered child-sex offenders outside the United States to the government of the country of destination, requesting foreign governments to notify the United States when a known child-sex offender is seeking to enter the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by senate">An act to protect children and others from sexual abuse and exploitation, including sex trafficking and sex tourism, by providing advance notice of intended travel by registered sex offenders outside the United States to the government of the country of destination, requesting foreign governments to notify the United States when a known sex offender is seeking to enter the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">International Megan's Law to Prevent Child Exploitation and Other Sexual Crimes Through Advanced Notification of Traveling Sex Offenders</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000522"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001105" joined="2015-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2015-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000451" joined="2015-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000564" joined="2015-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001053" joined="2015-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001056" joined="2015-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2015-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2015-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000606" joined="2015-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000592" joined="2015-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000487" joined="2015-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001165" joined="2015-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000812" joined="2015-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2015-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000065" joined="2015-01-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-25">
      <text>Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-26T15:51:10-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Royce moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-26T15:51:23-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H542-546" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-26T15:51:24-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 515.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2015-01-26T16:08:48-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H542-544" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-01-26T16:08:51-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-27T16:25:01-05:00">
      <text>ENGROSSMENT CORRECTION - Unanimous consent was granted for the Clerk to make a correction in the engrossment to H.R. 515 in a form placed at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-11-10">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-11-17">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Corker with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-11-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="296">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 296.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-12-17">
      <text>The committee substitute agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8831-8834" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S8832-8834" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2015-12-17" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-12-18">
      <text>Notwithstanding the passage of H.R. 515, the committee reported title amendment was agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-18">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01T16:21:28-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (NJ) moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H387-394" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01T16:21:43-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the motion to suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments to H.R. 515.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="pingpong" datetime="2016-02-01T16:51:10-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H387-390" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendments"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01T16:51:11-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2016-02-04">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2016-02-08" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="114-119" type="public" datetime="2016-02-08">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 114-119.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1867"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2936"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2016-02-09T04:59:58Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on December 17, 2015. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

International Megan's Law to Prevent Child Exploitation and Other Sexual Crimes Through Advanced Notification of Traveling Sex Offenders 

(Sec. 4) This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish the Angel Watch Center within the U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement. The center must identify outbound sex offender travelers who failed to provide advanced notice of international travel and provide a list of such individuals to the Marshals Service (USMS) to investigate.

The center may receive notifications of inbound sex offender travel. It must share information with the Department of Justice (DOJ) and other government agencies.

The center may also transmit advance notice of sex offender travel to a destination country. It must comply with certain procedures, collect specified data, and establish a process to receive, review, and respond to individual complaints of erroneous notifications.

(Sec. 5) The USMS may receive and transmit notification of international travel by sex offenders. It may also share information about sex offender travel with other government agencies.

This bill requires the USMS to ensure consistent advance notification to destination countries of international travel by registered sex offenders.

The USMS must share certain information with the center, including a list of individuals who provided advanced notice of international travel, a determination of compliance with sex offender registration requirements, and sex offender travel information. It must also establish a process to receive, review, and respond to individual complaints of erroneous notifications.

DOJ must collect specified data related to transmitted notifications.

(Sec. 6) The bill amends the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act (SORNA) to require a registered sex offender to also report information on intended international travel for inclusion in the sex offender registry.

It amends the federal criminal code to make it a crime for a sex offender to knowingly fail to provide such information. A violation is subject to a fine, up to 10 years in prison, or both.

(Sec. 7) It expresses the sense of Congress that the Department of State should negotiate reciprocal international agreements to further the purposes of this Act and SORNA.

(Sec. 8) This bill amends the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 to prohibit the State Department from issuing a passport to a sex offender, unless the passport contains a unique identifier. A "unique identifier" is any visual sex offender designation that is conspicuously affixed to a passport.

(Sec. 9) DHS, DOJ, and the State Department must develop and report jointly to Congress on a process to implement the unique identifier requirement on sex offender passports.

(Sec. 10) The State Department may provide technical assistance to foreign authorities to facilitate effective participation in the notification program established by this Act.

(Sec. 11) The bill authorizes appropriations for FY2017-FY2018.

(Sec. 12) It prohibits construing this Act to limit international information sharing or law enforcement cooperation pursuant to any authority of DOJ, DHS, or any other department or agency.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
