<bill session="114" type="s" number="2946" updated="2018-06-02T07:45:23Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Law Enforcement Officers Equity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 5, United States Code, to include certain Federal positions within the definition of law enforcement officer for retirement purposes, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Law Enforcement Officers Equity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2016-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2016-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2016-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2977-2978" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2254"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Law Enforcement Officers Equity Act

 This bill expands the definition of "law enforcement officer" under provisions of the Federal Employees Retirement System (FERS) and the Civil Service Retirement System (CSRS) to include: (1) federal employees not otherwise covered whose duties include the investigation or apprehension of suspected or convicted criminals and who are authorized to carry a firearm; (2) Internal Revenue Service employees whose duties are primarily the collection of delinquent taxes and the securing of delinquent returns; (3) U.S. Postal Inspection Service employees; (4) Department of Veterans Affairs police officers; and (5) certain U.S. Customs and Border Protection employees who are seized-property specialists with duties relating to custody, management, and disposition of seized and forfeited property.

Service performed by an incumbent (an individual appointed before enactment of this bill to a position that is considered to be a law enforcement officer under FERS and the CSRS only by virtue of the expanded definition in this bill) on or after enactment of this bill shall be treated as service performed as a law enforcement officer. Service performed by an incumbent before enactment of this bill shall be treated for federal retirement purposes as service performed as such an officer only if a written election is submitted to the Office of Personnel Management within five years after enactment of this bill or before separation from service, whichever is earlier. An incumbent who makes an election before enactment of this bill may pay a deposit into the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund to cover prior service.

Nothing under current law respecting mandatory separation from government service under CSRS or FERS shall cause the mandatory separation of an officer during the three-year period beginning on the enactment of this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
