<bill session="114" type="h" number="299" updated="2018-09-07T15:04:15Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-13T16:11:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-04-13T16:11:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Capital Access for Small Community Financial Institutions Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Capital Access for Small Community Financial Institutions Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Capital Access for Small Community Financial Institutions Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Home Loan Bank Act to authorize privately insured credit unions to become members of a Federal home loan bank, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Capital Access for Small Community Financial Institutions Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001187"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001281" joined="2015-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2015-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000462" joined="2015-01-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-03-26" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 56 - 1.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-04-13">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 114-58.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-04-13" calendar="Union" number="39">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 39.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-04-13T16:02:05-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Neugebauer moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-13T16:02:09-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2119-2120" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-13T16:02:12-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 299.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2015-04-13T16:11:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2119" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-04-13T16:11:03-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2642"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1491"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1484"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="22"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1910"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1367"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2132"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-13T15:14:44Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Capital Access for Small Community Financial Institutions Act of 2015

(Sec. 2) Amends the Federal Home Loan Bank Act to treat certain privately insured credit unions as insured depository institutions for purposes of determining eligibility for membership in a federal home loan bank.

Permits a credit union which lacks federal deposit insurance and has applied for membership in a federal home loan bank to be treated as meeting all the eligibility requirements for federal deposit insurance if the supervisor of the chartering state has determined that it meets all federal deposit insurance eligibility requirements.

Deems such a credit union to have met the eligibility criteria for federal home loan bank membership if, six months after its application date, the state supervisor has failed to act upon the application.

Prohibits the application of a state law authorizing a conservator or liquidating agent of a credit union to repudiate contracts to any: (1) extension of credit from a federal home loan bank to a credit union which is a member of that bank, or (2) security interest in the assets of the credit union securing such extension of credit.

Declares that if a federal home loan bank makes an advance to a state-chartered credit union that is not federally insured: (i) the bank's interest in any collateral securing such advance has the same priority and is afforded the same standing and rights that the security interest would have had if the advance had been made to a federally-insured credit union, and (2) the bank has the same right to access such collateral that it would have had if the advance had been made to a federally-insured credit union.

Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to require private deposit insurers of credit unions that are members of a federal home loan bank to submit copies of their audit reports within seven days to the Federal Housing Finance Agency.

(Sec. 3) Directs the Government Accountability Office to study: (1) the adequacy of insurance reserves held by a private deposit insurer that insures deposits in an insured credit union or any credit union eligible to apply to become one, and (2) such credit unions' compliance with federal regulations governing disclosure of a lack of federal deposit insurance.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-58</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
