<bill session="114" type="h" number="4551" updated="2019-01-09T21:10:12Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keeping our Promise to Seniors Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the establishment of a Consumer Price Index for Older Americans to compute cost-of-living increases for monthly insurance benefits under title II of the Social Security Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Keeping our Promise to Seniors Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000296"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" code="HSED02" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Social Security" code="HSWM01" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3961"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-12T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Keeping Our Promise to Seniors Act

This bill directs the Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS) of the Department of Labor to prepare and publish a monthly Consumer Price Index for Older Americans (CPI-OA) that:

 measures changes over time in the cost of living for a population that consists solely of individuals living in the United States who are age 62 or older; is specifically designed to reflect the geographic areas in which such individuals reside, the goods and services they purchase, and the typical prices for those goods and services; and is not based on any other consumer price index published by the BLS. The bill amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to use this new CPI-OA in the computation of cost-of-living increases for OASDI benefits.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
