<bill session="115" type="h" number="2850" updated="2019-04-18T16:11:04Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Military Resale Patron Benefits Advisory Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Patron Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Patron Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Military Patron Protection Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000255"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000799" joined="2017-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-08T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Military Patron Protection Act of 2017

This bill establishes the Military Resale Patron Benefits Advisory Commission to advise the Department of Defense (DOD) on:

 the effects of military commissary and exchange operations on their patrons and on morale, welfare, and recreation programs; the sources and uses of commissary and exchange revenues; and fulfillment of the requirement to implement a comprehensive strategy to optimize management practices across the defense commissary and exchange systems. The Commission shall advise DOD on proposed reforms to commissary and exchange operations that could affect:

 the use of revenue; the morale, welfare, and recreation programs provided for, and the morale of, military members and dependents; and philanthropic programs that benefit members and their families. The bill requires DOD to: (1) report annually on the use of funds generated by commissaries and exchanges, the constitution and purpose of the boards of directors of the Military Exchanges and Commissary Operations and any determination to use such funds, and DOD responses to any commission proposals; (2) notify Congress before expending certain funds; and (3) notify Congress before taking action that would reduce a contract awarded by the Defense Commissary Agency to a small, veteran-owned, woman-owned, or disadvantaged business concern or a qualified nonprofit agency for the blind or other severely disabled.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
