<bill session="115" type="s" number="1365" updated="2019-04-18T16:37:09Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Defense to include victims of acts of terror in the evaluation and treatment of veterans and civilians at military treatment facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jessica Kensky and Patrick Downes Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jessica Kensky and Patrick Downes Act</title>
    <title type="display">Jessica Kensky and Patrick Downes Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2017-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Jessica Kensky and Patrick Downes Act

This bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to include victims of acts of terror in the evaluation and treatment of veterans and civilians at military treatment facilities.

The Department of Defense (DOD) shall establish implementing procedures: (1) for outreach and communication to local medical facilities after an act of terror in the United States; (2) to coordinate and provide medical expertise to local medical facilities that are treating victims of an act of terror that caused blast related injuries, mass shooting related injuries, burn related injuries, or other serious injuries; and (3) for medical evaluations of such victims.

DOD may not release a victim of an act of terror who is receiving such care to a private health care provider until a comprehensive treatment plan is communicated to the individual or his or her health care provider.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
