<bill session="114" type="h" number="5176" updated="2018-11-21T20:31:15Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Success in Transition for All Veterans Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Labor to carry out a research program to evaluate the effectiveness of the Transition Assistance Program in addressing the needs of certain minority veterans.</title>
    <title type="display">Success in Transition for All Veterans Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000472"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000600" joined="2016-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Success in Transition for All Veterans Act

This bill directs the Department of Labor to carry out a research program to evaluate whether the transition assistance program addresses the differentiated needs, challenges, and post-military service aspirations of women veterans, veterans with disabilities, Native American veterans, veterans who are residents of a U.S. territory, veterans who are part of the indigenous population of a U.S. territory, and other groups of minority veterans. (The transition assistance program is a Labor program that assists members of the armed forces separating from active duty and their spouses in identifying and obtaining employment and training opportunities.)

The research program shall address:

 whether and how employment barriers and employment aspirations facing such veterans are substantively different from other veteran populations; and whether the transition program is designed to address such differences and, if not, changes that could be made to do so.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
