<bill session="114" type="h" number="3418" updated="2019-04-11T15:39:45Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Protective Service Improvement and Accountability Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance homeland security, including domestic preparedness and the collective response to terrorism, by improving the Federal Protective Service, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Federal Protective Service Improvement and Accountability Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000193"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001038" joined="2015-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2015-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000604" joined="2015-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000588" joined="2015-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000474" joined="2015-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2015-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1163"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-08-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight and Management Efficiency.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Oversight, Management, and Accountability" code="HSHM09" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Protective Service Improvement and Accountability Act of 2015

 Directs the Federal Protective Service (FPS) to maintain not fewer than 1,870 full-time equivalent positions, with at least 1,350 of such positions designated for fully trained federal law enforcement officers.

Authorizes positions in the FPS inspector force to be designated as: (1) Federal Facility Security Officers responsible for performing security assessments at facilities protected by FPS, making security countermeasure recommendations for such facilities, participating in security training and disseminating homeland security information to occupants and security guards of such facilities, and assessing the security of such facilities and the extent to which security countermeasure recommendations have been implemented; or (2) law enforcement officers responsible for patrolling and on-site monitoring of the physical security of FPS-protected facilities, conducting investigations at such facilities, and providing physical law enforcement at such facilities in the event of a terrorist attack, security incident, or other incident.

Directs FPS to: (1) establish the FPS contract oversight force responsible for overseeing contract guards, (2) establish uniform minimum training and certification standards for security guard services at FPS-protected facilities, (3) establish a process to verify the accuracy of training and certification data maintained by FPS, and (4) provide training to individuals in guard positions who have not successfully completed training on the effective utilization of screening equipment and active shooter scenario-based training.

Directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) develop and implement a strategy for using covert-testing data and data on prohibited items to improve screening at facilities protected by FPS, and (2) submit an assessment of the degree to which the standards specified in the "The Risk Management Process: An Interagency Security Committee Standard" are utilized by all non-military federal facilities and of any barriers to utilizing such standards.

Requires FPS to: (1) commence a one-year pilot program to research the advantages of converting guard positions at the highest-risk federal facilities protected by FPS from contract guard positions to positions held by federal employees; and (2) establish, and hire individuals for, a federal facility security guard position.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
