<bill session="114" type="h" number="5490" updated="2019-02-14T23:05:48Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 to require that no deference be given to the interpretation of consumer financial law by the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, to define the scope of judicial review of Bureau actions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 to require that no deference be given to the interpretation of consumer financial law by the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, to define the scope of judicial review of Bureau actions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000584"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Antitrust, Commercial, and Administrative Law" code="HSJU05" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill amends the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 to repeal the declaration that the deference that a court affords to the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) regarding its determination of the meaning or interpretation of any provision of a federal consumer financial law shall be applied as if the CFPB were the only agency authorized to apply, enforce, interpret, or administer the provisions of that law.

In any judicial review of a CFPB agency action, the reviewing court shall determine the meaning or applicability of the terms of a CFPB agency action and decide de novo all relevant questions of law, including the interpretation of constitutional and statutory provisions, as well as CFPB rules. No law may exempt any civil action for judicial review from the application of this bill except by specific reference to it.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
