<bill session="114" type="h" number="5120" updated="2019-02-06T22:37:46Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Free Rent for Freeloaders Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a penalty for the Department of Housing and Urban Development for failure to enforce compliance with the public housing community service and self-sufficiency requirement under law, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">No Free Rent for Freeloaders Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000018"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="National and community service"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">No Free Rent for Freeloaders Act of 2016

This bill directs the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) each year, for each public housing agency, to:

 monitor the extent of noncompliance with the community service and economic self-sufficiency requirements of the United States Housing Act of 1937, and determine the aggregate amount provided in federal subsidies for all public housing dwelling units that were occupied by noncompliant tenants. By September 30 of each fiscal year, HUD shall publish this amount in the Federal Register.

In each new fiscal year this amount, as determined and published for the preceding fiscal year, shall be rescinded from funds made available for the Management and Administration account of HUD.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
