<bill session="115" type="h" number="4997" updated="2019-04-18T16:20:19Z">
  <state datetime="2018-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to authorize a new composite multiemployer pension plan design, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Giving Retirement Options to Workers Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Giving Retirement Options to Workers Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GROW Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GROW Act</title>
    <title type="display">GROW Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000582"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001106" joined="2018-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2018-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000625" joined="2018-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000188" joined="2018-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000034" joined="2018-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-02-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" code="HSED02" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-02-13T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Giving Retirement Options to Workers Act of 2018 or the GROW Act 

This bill amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) and the Internal Revenue Code to authorize a new composite multiemployer pension plan, which combines features of defined benefit and defined contribution pension plans.

Under a composite plan, employer contributions are set at a fixed rate. Benefits are based on a formula, are paid to participants in the form of life annuities (except for benefits that may be immediately distributed from certain plans with a low value), and may be reduced based on the plan's funded status.

The plan sponsor must take corrective actions through a realignment program whenever the plan's projected funded ratio is below 120% for the plan year. The realignment program may include measures such as benefit reductions or proposed contribution increases.

A composite plan is not covered by the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC) or required to pay PBGC premiums. The plan sponsors are also not subject to liability for withdrawing from the plan.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
