<bill session="113" type="h" number="135" updated="2018-06-05T15:58:07Z">
  <state datetime="2013-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Natomas Basin Flood Protection Improvements Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize improvements to flood damage reduction facilities adjacent to the American and Sacramento Rivers near Sacramento, California, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Natomas Basin Flood Protection Improvements Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001163"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001287" joined="2013-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Natomas Basin Flood Protection Improvements Act of 2013 - Modifies the project for flood damage reduction, American and Sacramento Rivers, California, to authorize the Secretary of the Army to construct improvements to flood damage reduction facilities adjacent to those rivers in the vicinity of Sacramento, substantially in accordance with the report of the Chief of Engineers entitled "American River Watershed (Common Features) Project, Natomas Basin, Sacramento and Sutter Counties, California," dated December 30, 2010, at a specified cost.

Requires the nonfederal interest to receive credit for expenses and in-kind contributions incurred for planning, design, and construction of the project and acquisition of lands, easements, rights-of-way, relocations, and dredged material disposal areas for the project. Requires such credit to be applied toward the nonfederal share of the project or of any other project for which the nonfederal interest has entered into a cost-sharing agreement with the Secretary.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
