<bill session="115" type="h" number="3771" updated="2019-04-18T16:15:11Z">
  <state datetime="2017-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure independent investigations by allowing judicial review of the removal of a special counsel, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Special Counsel Integrity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Special Counsel Integrity Act</title>
    <title type="display">Special Counsel Integrity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000714"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2017-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-09-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-14T11:27:52-05:00">
      <text>ASSUMING FIRST SPONSORSHIP - Mr. Cohen asked unanimous consent that he may hereafter be considered as the first sponsor of H.R. 3771, a bill originally introduced by Representative Conyers, for the purpose of adding cosponsors and requesting reprintings pursuant to clause 7 of rule XII. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="1741"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="4669"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-09-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Special Counsel Integrity Act

This bill sets forth requirements and limitations with respect to the discipline or removal from office of a special counsel appointed under Department of Justice (DOJ) regulations.

Specifically, a special counsel may be disciplined or removed only by the personal action of an Attorney General who has been confirmed by the Senate. If the Attorney General is recused from the matter, then a special counsel may be disciplined or removed by the most senior DOJ official who has been confirmed by the Senate and is not recused from the matter.

A special counsel: (1) may only be removed for misconduct, dereliction of duty, incapacity, conflict of interest, or other good cause, including violation of DOJ policies; (2) must be informed in writing of the specific reason for the removal; and (3) may file an action for judicial review of the removal.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
