<bill session="115" type="s" number="875" updated="2019-04-18T16:34:59Z">
  <state datetime="2018-01-10">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-01-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study and submit a report on filing requirements under the Universal Service Fund programs.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to require the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study and submit a report on filing requirements under the Universal Service Fund programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001198"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-06-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-12-11">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Thune with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 115-192.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-12-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="282">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 282.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2018-01-10" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S141-142" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S142" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-01-11T09:37:31-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-11">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Communications and Technology" code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3523"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Libraries and archives"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-01-10T15:02:41Z" status="Passed Senate amended">(Sec. 1) This bill requires the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to report to the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) and Congress on the filing requirements for telecommunications carriers or service providers that receive Universal Service Fund support under the Communications Act of 1934 to provide service to qualifying low-income consumers, rural or high-cost areas, rural health care providers, schools, or libraries under the Connect America Fund, Lifeline, E-Rate, Rural Health Care, Remote Areas Fund, Connect America Fund Broadband Loop Support, Mobility Fund, and High Cost Loop Support for Rate-of-Return Carriers&#160;programs. The report must analyze the financial impact of those filing requirements and provide any recommendations on how to consolidate redundant filing requirements.

After receiving the GAO's report, the FCC must initiate a rulemaking to consolidate redundant filing requirements and incorporate any GAO recommendations that would not violate the Administrative Procedure Act into such rulemaking or any ongoing rulemakings.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-192</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
