<bill session="115" type="h" number="1650" updated="2019-04-18T16:05:10Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a national, research-based, and comprehensive home study assessment process for the evaluation of prospective foster parents and adoptive parents and provide funding to States and Indian tribes to adopt such process.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Adoption and Foster Care Home Study Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Adoption and Foster Care Home Study Act</title>
    <title type="display">National Adoption and Foster Care Home Study Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001270" joined="2017-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000559" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2017-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000170" joined="2017-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000604" joined="2017-03-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="684"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">National Adoption and Foster Care Home Study Act

This bill amends the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act and Adoption Reform Act of 1978 to direct the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a demonstration program through which each participating state or Indian tribe: (1) adopts the uniform, research-based home study methodology developed by HHS for the evaluation of prospective foster parents and adoptive parents; and (2) provides data gathered through operation of the program to HHS, as HHS may require for purposes of the national database established by this bill.

HHS shall: (1) make grants to states and Indian tribes to enable and encourage them to establish demonstration programs, (2) establish a secure national database of home study reports, and (3) contract with an independent entity to carry out a periodic evaluation of the home study methodology developed by HHS and the demonstration programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
