<bill session="114" type="s" number="1995" updated="2018-08-16T22:54:00Z">
  <state datetime="2015-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Outdoor Recreation Legacy Partnership Grant Program Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide grants for projects to acquire land and water for parks and other outdoor recreation purposes and to develop new or renovate existing outdoor recreation facilities.</title>
    <title type="display">Outdoor Recreation Legacy Partnership Grant Program Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000148"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-08-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-08-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-08-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Outdoor Recreation Legacy Partnership Grant Program Act of 2015

This bill directs the Department of the Interior to establish an outdoor recreation legacy partnership grant program under which Interior awards grants to eligible entities (the states, their political subdivisions, special purpose districts, and Indian Tribes) for projects to: (1) acquire land and water for parks and other outdoor recreation purposes, and (2) develop new or renovate existing outdoor recreation facilities.

As a condition for receiving a grant, an eligible entity shall provide matching funds in cash or in kind equal to 100% of the amounts available under the grant.

A grant recipient may use the grant to acquire land or water providing outdoor recreation opportunities to the public.

A grant may also be used to develop or renovate outdoor recreational facilities, with priority given to projects that:

 create or significantly enhance access to park and recreational opportunities in an urban neighborhood or community; engage and empower underserved communities and youth; provide opportunities for youth employment or job training; establish or expand public-private partnerships; take advantage of coordination among various levels of government. Grant funds may not be used for specified costs, facilities, and activities, including the acquisition of lands or interests that restrict access to particular persons.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
