<bill session="113" type="h" number="5511" updated="2016-10-25T16:16:34Z">
  <state datetime="2014-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Oregon Coastal Lands Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require that certain Federal lands be held in trust by the United States for the benefit of the Confederated Tribes of Coos, Lower Umpqua, and Siuslaw Indians, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Oregon Coastal Lands Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000191"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="5701"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="5512"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1414"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1415"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1784"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2734"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-09-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Oregon Coastal Lands Act - Requires all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to approximately 14,408 acres of land generally depicted on the map entitled "Oregon Coastal Land Conveyance," dated March 27, 2013 (Oregon Coastal land) to be held in trust for, and to be part of the reservation of, the Confederated Tribes of Coos, Lower Umpqua, and Siuslaw Indians (Tribes).

Applies federal law relating to the export of unprocessed logs harvested from federal land to any unprocessed logs harvested from such land. Prohibits gaming on such land. Requires commercial forestry activity on such land to be managed in accordance with applicable federal laws. Exempts such land from the land use planning requirements of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976.

Directs the Tribes to consult with the Secretary of the Interior and other parties to develop agreements to provide for access to such land that provide for: (1) honoring existing reciprocal right-of-way agreements, (2) administrative access by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), and (3) management of any such land acquired or developed under the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 in accordance with such Act.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) identify any such land that is Oregon and California Railroad grant land, (2) identify public domain land in Oregon that is approximately equal in acreage and condition to such Oregon and California Railroad grant land, and (3) reclassify such public domain land as Oregon and California Railroad grant land.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
