<bill session="114" type="h" number="5445" updated="2018-11-09T00:09:28Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Health Care Security Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to improve the rules with respect to health savings accounts.</title>
    <title type="display">Health Care Security Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000594"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001248" joined="2016-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001187" joined="2016-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-06-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 23 - 15.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-06-17">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 114-627.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-06-17" calendar="Union" number="486">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 486.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1270"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1169"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-17T16:00:13Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">Health Care Security Act of 2016

 This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to modify the rules for health savings accounts (HSAs) with respect to catch-up contributions for married couples, medical expenses incurred before an HSA is established, and contribution limits.

(Sec. 2) If both spouses of a married couple have family coverage under a high deductible health plan, each spouse may make catch-up contributions to the same HSA. (Catch-up contributions are additional contributions which individuals who are at least 55 years of age may make to an HSA.)

(Sec. 3) If an HSA is established within 60 days of the beginning of coverage under a high deductible health plan, any distribution from the HSA used to pay a qualified medical expense incurred during that 60-day period after the health coverage began is excludible from gross income. (Under current law, the medical expense must be incurred on or after the date that the HSA is established.)

(Sec. 4) The bill increases the maximum contribution limits for HSAs to equal the maximum for the sum of the annual deductible and out-of-pocket expenses that may be required to be paid for covered benefits under a high deductible health plan.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-627</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
