<bill session="114" type="h" number="2532" updated="2019-01-09T21:26:39Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">EASY Savings Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Employees of America Streamlining for Your Savings Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Bonuses for Cost-Cutters Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to enhance the authority under which Federal agencies may pay cash awards to employees for making cost saving disclosures, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Bonuses for Cost-Cutters Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000459"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000754" joined="2016-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-09-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-11-14">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 114-824.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-11-14" calendar="Union" number="646">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 646.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1378"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-11-14T14:52:48Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">Bonuses for Cost-Cutters Act of 2016

(Sec. 2) This bill expands the cash awards program for disclosures by federal employees of fraud, waste, or mismanagement that result in cost savings to the employee's agency to include identification of surplus salaries and expenses funds that: (1) an agency employee identifies as unnecessary, (2) the inspector general and the chief financial officer of the agency determine are not required for the purpose for which the amounts were made available, and (3) the rescission of which would not be detrimental to the full execution of the purposes for which the amounts were made available.

Any savings resulting from such identifications must be deposited in the Treasury and used to reduce a budget deficit or the federal debt. But agencies may retain up to 10% of such savings for the purpose of paying cash awards to employees who identify surplus salaries and expenses funds.

Each fiscal year, agencies must submit reports to the Department of the Treasury regarding: (1) the total savings achieved through disclosures of possible fraud, waste, or mismanagement and identifications of surplus salaries and expenses funds by an employee; and (2) each disclosure that has merit and the number and amount of cash awards by the agency. This information must also be included in agency budget requests submitted to the Office of Management and Budget.

Treasury must report annually to Congress on federal cost saving and awards based on agency reports about such employee disclosures. The Office of Personnel Management must certify annually whether each agency's cash award program complies with this bill.

Every three years, the Government Accountability Office must report on the operation of the program and any recommendations for legislative improvements.

The bill prohibits the payment of awards to: (1) federal officers who serve in a position at level I of the Executive Schedule; (2) the head of an agency; or (3) a commissioner, board member, or other voting member of an independent establishment.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-824</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
