<bill session="114" type="s" number="703" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:53Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Weatherization Enhancement and Local Energy Efficiency Investment and Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize the weatherization and State energy programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Weatherization Enhancement and Local Energy Efficiency Investment and Accountability Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2015-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2015-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2015-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3420"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2012"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2089"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor and aged"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Weatherization Enhancement and Local Energy Efficiency Investment and Accountability Act 

This bill amends the Energy Conservation and Production Act to reauthorize the Weatherization Assistance Program for low-income persons through FY2020.

The Department of Energy (DOE) must make competitive grants to qualified tax-exempt charitable organizations for energy efficiency retrofit of low-income homes. The grants may be used for single-family and multifamily housing.

Contractors carrying out weatherization with funds under the bill must be selected through a competitive bidding process and be accredited as specified by this bill. In order to receive a grant, organizations must use a crew chief who is certified or accredited as required by this bill.

Beginning on October 1, 2016, DOE must ensure that: (1) each retrofit for which weatherization assistance is provided meets minimum efficiency and quality of work standards, (2) at least 10% of the dwelling units are randomly inspected by an accredited third party to ensure compliance with the standards, and (3) the standards meet or exceed the current industry standards for home performance work.

The Energy Policy and Conservation Act is amended to reauthorize the program for state energy conservation plans through FY2020.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
