<bill session="114" type="h" number="2952" updated="2019-02-14T22:59:18Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Employment Outcomes of TANF Recipients Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Improving Employment Outcomes of TANF Recipients Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide payments to States for increasing the employment, job retention, and earnings of former TANF recipients.</title>
    <title type="display">Improving Employment Outcomes of TANF Recipients Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001255"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-05-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 23 - 12.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-06-28">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 114-648.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-06-28" calendar="Union" number="500">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 500.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Worker and Family Support" code="HSWM03" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-28T12:55:58Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">Improving Employment Outcomes of TANF Recipients Act

 (Sec. 2) This bill amends part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF) of title IV of the Social Security Act to replace the current program of bonus grants for high performing states with a program requiring each state to collect and report information necessary to measure the state's level of performance for FY2018 and each ensuing fiscal year for each employment percentage, retention percentage, and earnings advancement measure for adults in unsubsidized employment after exiting the TANF program (indicators). The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) shall use the information collected for FY2018 to establish the baseline level of performance of each state for each indicator.

The state shall reach agreement with HHS: (1) on the requisite level of performance for each indicator for FY2019-FY2020; and (2) before FY2021 on the requisite level of performance for each indicator for that fiscal year.

HHS shall revise the requisite levels of performance for a fiscal year and a state to reflect the actual economic conditions and characteristics of participants.

HHS shall use an objective statistical model to make such performance level adjustments, and shall consult with the Department of Labor to develop a statistical adjustment model similar to one described in the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act.

HHS shall also develop a template which each state shall use to report on outcomes achieved under the new program or any other state program funded with qualified state expenditures.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-648</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
