<bill session="114" type="s" number="3243" updated="2018-06-02T07:47:37Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rebuilding and Renewing Rural America Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to help rebuild and renew rural communities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Rebuilding and Renewing Rural America Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000562"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2313"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Rebuilding and Renewing Rural America Act of 2016 

This bill modifies: (1) tax and regulatory policies that affect certain rural communities, and (2) tax rules that apply to private foundations.

The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to program-related investments made by private foundations for a charitable purpose, to:

 modify the definition of and requirements for program-related investments; allow a declaratory judgment remedy to determine whether investments in any entity are program-related investments; expand reporting requirements for for-profit entities that receive program-related investments; and allow public inspection of petitions seeking a determination of program-related investment status and annual information returns. The bill also includes several tax provisions that apply to rural renewal communities, which are low-income communities that: (1) have a population of at least 200 people but not more than 25,000 people, and are not located in a metropolitan area which has a population of 200,000 or more; or (2) are entirely within an Indian reservation.

With respect to such communities, the bill:

 allows tax credits for a portion of the costs of reducing lead, radon, or asbestos hazards in rural commercial structures; expands the new markets tax credit; allows expensing of certain depreciable business assets; reduces payroll taxes; and allows tax-preferred rural renewal community business start-up savings accounts. Reducing Excessive Government in Rural America Act of 2016 

Congress must consider legislation to reduce the regulatory cost to rural America by at least 10% over 10 years by repealing certain regulations. The legislation must be considered using expedited legislative procedures specified in the bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
