<bill session="114" type="h" number="5911" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:54Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Countering Violent Extremism Task Force Oversight Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security and Attorney General to submit a report on the Countering Violent Extremism Task Force, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Countering Violent Extremism Task Force Oversight Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001255" joined="2016-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000620" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001055" joined="2016-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-08-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-08-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Counterterrorism and Intelligence.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Intelligence and Counterterrorism" code="HSHM05" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Countering Violent Extremism Task Force Oversight Act

This bill requires the Department of Homeland Security and the Department of Justice to jointly submit to Congress an annual report on the Countering Violent Extremism Task Force.

Each report shall include an examination of how the task force:

 plans and coordinates countering violent extremism programs of the federal government; evaluates the effectiveness of such programs; plans and coordinates such programs that specifically address and counter the threat of radicalization of U.S. citizens or lawful permanent residents by foreign terrorists or foreign terrorist organizations through the Internet, social media, or other platforms; and plans and coordinates such programs that specifically address and counter the threat of lone wolf acts of terrorism conducted by U.S. citizens or lawful permanent residents who have been radicalized. Each such report also shall examine:

 the levels of funding, personnel, and agency resources that are devoted to the task force; problems and difficulties associated with the development, implementation, and coordination of such programs; a comparison of the task force with similar organizations and programs employed by U.S. allies and partners; and proposed policy recommendations for developing coordinated, coherent, cohesive whole-government countering violent extremism programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
