<bill session="114" type="s" number="923" updated="2018-06-02T06:44:57Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Healthy Relationships Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, to award grants on a competitive basis to public and private entities to provide qualified sexual risk avoidance education to youth and their parents.</title>
    <title type="display">Healthy Relationships Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000359"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000542" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2015-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001141" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000127" joined="2015-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="453"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
    <term name="Teenage pregnancy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Healthy Relationships Act of 2015

This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Health Resources and Services Administration to award grants for qualified sexual risk avoidance education for youth and their parents.

The unambiguous message that postponing sexual activity is the optimal sexual health behavior for youth must be the primary emphasis and context for each topic covered by the education. The education must be age appropriate, medically accurate, and evidence based.

The education must address specified topics, including:

 the benefits associated with personal responsibility, success sequencing (sequential progression through: completing school, securing a job, and marrying before bearing children), goal setting, healthy decision making, and a focus on the future; the research-based advantage of reserving sexual activity for marriage; the skills needed to resist the pervasive, sex-saturated culture; the foundational components of healthy relationships; and how to avoid sexual coercion, dating violence, and risk behaviors, such as drugs, alcohol, and the misuse of social media. Priority in awarding grants must be given to programs serving youth in middle school and high school that will promote parent-child communication regarding healthy sexual decision making.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
