<bill session="114" type="h" number="5522" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:36Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 to require that civil investigative demands be appealed to courts, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 to require that civil investigative demands be appealed to courts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000588"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5983"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill amends the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 regarding civil investigative demands made by the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) on a person in the course of an investigation. (Under current law, the CFPB may, before institution of any proceedings, serve a civil investigative demand on a person the CFPB has reason to believe may be in possession, custody, or control of any documentary material or tangible things, or may have any information, relevant to a violation of federal consumer financial law.)

The bill requires the recipient of such a demand to meet and confer with a CFPB investigator within 30 calendar days after receiving the demand to discuss and attempt to resolve all issues regarding compliance with it, unless the CFPB grants an extension the recipient requests.

The deadline after the service of any civil investigative demand by which the recipient may petition for an order modifying or setting the demand aside shall extend from the current maximum of 20 days to a maximum of 45 days.

The bill eliminates the right to appeal any final order of a U.S. district court regarding such a petition.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
