<bill session="115" type="hr" number="537" updated="2019-05-09T22:56:58Z">
  <state datetime="2017-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Promoting United States national security and foreign policy objectives through consolidation and strengthening of the rule of law and respect for human rights in the Republic of Azerbaijan.</title>
    <title type="display">Promoting United States national security and foreign policy objectives through consolidation and strengthening of the rule of law and respect for human rights in the Republic of Azerbaijan.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000522"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2017-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000034" joined="2018-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2018-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Africa, Global Health, Global Human Rights and International Organizations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Europe, Eurasia, and Emerging Threats.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Europe, Eurasia, Energy and the Environment" code="HSFA14" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Africa, Global Health, Global Human Rights and International Organizations" code="HSFA16" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Azerbaijan"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-09-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Affirms the importance of the U.S. partnership with the government of Azerbaijan in the areas of international security, European energy security, and economic development.

Calls on the U.S. government:

 in its diplomatic engagement and delivery of bilateral assistance, to prioritize as a matter of strategic importance its response to Azerbaijan's violations of universally recognized human rights, fundamental freedoms, and the rule of law to ensure the long-term sustainability of the U.S.-Azerbaijani bilateral partnership; to closely evaluate reporting to identify and impose travel and financial restrictions on Azerbaijan officials responsible for gross violations of internationally recognized human rights, pursuant to the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act; and to closely evaluate reporting to identify and impose travel restrictions on Azerbaijan officials responsible for severe violations of religious freedom, pursuant to the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998. Calls on the government of Azerbaijan to release all political prisoners and prisoners of conscience, rehabilitate their records, lift travel bans, and cease harassment, intimidation, and mistreatment of citizens engaged in political speech, independent journalism, and other forms of advocacy on behalf of government accountability, democratic values, and universally recognized human rights.

Supports the peaceful efforts of the people of Azerbaijan ito achieve democratic reform and exercise their fundamental freedoms.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
