<bill session="114" type="h" number="2320" updated="2019-01-09T21:26:16Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Improper Payments Coordination Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Federal Improper Payments Coordination Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide access to and use of information by Federal agencies in order to reduce improper payments, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Federal Improper Payments Coordination Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001182"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001286" joined="2015-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001103" joined="2015-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2015-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2015-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000754" joined="2015-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2015-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001071" joined="2015-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000591" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000796" joined="2015-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000810" joined="2015-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-07-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-10-20">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 114-299.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-10-20" calendar="Union" number="228">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 228.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="614"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-20T15:46:25Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">Federal Improper Payments Coordination Act of 2015

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Improper Payments Elimination and Recovery Improvement Act of 2012 to: (1) extend the availability of the Do Not Pay Initiative to the judicial and legislative branches and to the states; and (2) authorize the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to issue guidance that establishes privacy requirements that shall be incorporated into Do Not Pay Initiative access agreements with states and the judicial and legislative branches.

(Sec. 3) The Departments of Defense and State must submit, promptly and on a regular basis, relevant information on the deaths of individuals.

The OMB, in consultation with the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, the heads of other relevant federal, state, and local agencies, and Indian tribes and tribal organizations, as appropriate, shall issue guidance regarding implementation of the Initiative to the Department of the Treasury and each agency or component of an agency: (1) that operates or maintains a database of death records maintained by the Social Security Administration; or (2) for which the OMB determines improved data matching would be relevant, necessary, or beneficial.

(Sec. 4) Treasury must report to Congress on:

 data analytics performed as part of the Do Not Pay Business Center operated by Treasury for the purpose of detecting, preventing, and recovering improper payments through pre-award, post-award prepayment, and post-payment analysis; the metrics used in determining whether the analytic and investigatory efforts have reduced, or contributed to the reduction of, improper payments or improper awards; and the target dates for implementing the data analytics operations performed as part of the Do Not Pay Business Center.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-299</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
