<bill session="114" type="h" number="3587" updated="2019-02-14T23:30:53Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Dry Cask Storage Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to provide for the development of plans for dry cask storage of spent nuclear fuel, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Dry Cask Storage Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000179"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000556" joined="2015-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000375" joined="2015-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000480" joined="2015-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2015-10-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Environment and Climate Change" code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="945"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Dry Cask Storage Act of 2015

 Amends the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to require each licensee of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) to submit a plan for: (1) transfer (including on-going additional transfers) to spent nuclear fuel dry casks of any spent nuclear fuel stored by the licensee for at least seven years in spent nuclear fuel pools, and (2) configuration of the remaining spent nuclear fuel in the pool in a manner that minimizes the chance of a fire if there is a loss of water in the pool.

Requires the NRC to approve or disapprove the plan within 90 days after its submission.

Authorizes the NRC to make a grant to any licensee with an approved plan to assist in the cost of transferring spent nuclear fuel to dry casks under the plan.

Requires the emergency planning zone applicable to each civilian nuclear power reactor to be at least 10 miles in radius until all spent nuclear fuel at the reactor has been transferred to dry casks.

Directs the NRC to expand to 50 miles in radius the emergency planning zone applicable to each reactor not in compliance with an approved plan. Makes the licensee responsible for all coasts associated with expansion.

Requires the Department of the Treasury to transfer annually to the NRC, to pay the costs of the grants program, 10% of the interest generated during the preceding fiscal year from investments of the Nuclear Waste Fund.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
