<bill session="115" type="h" number="5846" updated="2019-04-18T16:23:39Z">
  <state datetime="2018-07-16T18:00:26-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-07-16T18:00:26-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Promoting Flood Risk Mitigation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Promoting Flood Risk Mitigation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Promoting Flood Risk Mitigation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Promoting Flood Risk Mitigation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Flood Risk Mitigation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Flood Risk Mitigation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study regarding the buyout practices of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000574"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2018-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000614" joined="2018-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000051" joined="2018-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-05-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27">
      <text>Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-06-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-07-16">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 115-820.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-07-16" calendar="Union" number="634">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 634.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-07-16T17:49:18-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Barletta moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-16T17:49:40-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6224-6226" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-16T17:49:42-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5846.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2018-07-16T18:00:26-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6224-6225" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-07-16T18:00:27-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-17">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="2862"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="6402"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-07-16T17:56:57Z" status="Passed House amended">Promoting Flood Risk Mitigation Act

(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to conduct a study to assess: (1) the efficacy of practices or programs under which the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) provides assistance to state and local governments to acquire flood-damaged properties committed to open space use in perpetuity (buyout practices), and (2) ways to streamline the buyout practices to provide more timely assistance.

The study must consider and analyze:

 current and future trends with respect to repetitive loss structures and severe repetitive loss structures that are insured under the National Flood Insurance Program; buyout practices, including the socioeconomic status of recipients of buyouts under buyout programs and examples of successful buyout programs, including best practices employed; administrative, financial, or temporal constraints that may impede the timely acquisition of properties under a buyout program; potential options, methods, and strategies to address such constraints; the ecological, financial, and flood risk reduction benefits that buyout practices provide; an assessment of how FEMA may use buyout programs to reduce future flood disaster recovery costs; and a cost-benefit analysis of mitigation and buy-out projects and programs. The GAO shall submit to Congress and FEMA a report on the buyout practices study and the feasibility of FEMA establishing an alternative buyout program.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-820</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
