<bill session="114" type="h" number="2110" updated="2019-01-29T22:16:11Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consumer Review Freedom Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the use of certain clauses in form contracts that restrict the ability of a consumer to communicate regarding the goods or services that were the subject of the contract.</title>
    <title type="display">Consumer Review Freedom Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2015-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2015-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000460" joined="2015-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2015-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2015-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2015-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2015-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001193" joined="2015-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Consumer Protection and Commerce" code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2044"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="First Amendment rights"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Consumer Review Freedom Act of 2015

Declares a provision of a form contract to be void from the inception if it: (1) prohibits or restricts a person who is a party to the contract from engaging in written, verbal, or pictorial reviews, or other similar performance assessments or analyses of, the products, services, or conduct of a business that is a party to the contract; (2) imposes penalties or fees against persons who engage in such communications; or (3) transfers or requires the individual to transfer any intellectual property rights in any such otherwise lawful communications about the person or the goods or services provided by the person or business. (Thus, bars certain contract provisions that prohibit consumers from commenting publicly about businesses.)

Sets forth exceptions under which a provision shall not be considered void under this Act if the provision prohibits disclosure of certain: (1) trade secrets or commercial or financial information, (2) personnel and medical files, or (3) law enforcement records.

Provides for this Act to be inapplicable to contracts establishing an employer-employee or independent contractor relationship.

Prohibits businesses from offering or entering into form contracts containing a provision that is considered void under this Act. Sets forth authority for the Department of Justice (DOJ) and state attorneys general to enforce such prohibition.

Requires DOJ to bring an action against any business that violates such prohibition for civil penalty of not more than $16,000 for each day that the business requires the use of such a form contract by a distinct person.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
