<bill session="113" type="h" number="978" updated="2018-06-05T16:08:52Z">
  <state datetime="2013-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Emergency Selective Service Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To deauthorize the Military Selective Service Act, including the registration requirement and the activities of civilian local boards, civilian appeal boards, and similar local agencies of the Selective Service System, except during a national emergency declared by the President, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">National Emergency Selective Service Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001077"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001032" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000591" joined="2013-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="Selective Service System"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-03-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">National Emergency Selective Service Act - Deauthorizes the Military Selective Service Act (requiring registration under the Selective Service System [System] for possible military induction) except during a period of national emergency declared by the President.

Provides for the suspension of local military selection boards, appeal boards, and other selective service system agencies and activities during non-emergency periods. Requires the Secretary of Defense (DOD), when System operations are suspended, to assume responsibility for the security of System databases.

Suspends sanctions against persons failing to register under the System, unless such failure occurs during a national emergency.

Permits the authorization of appropriations under the Military Selective Service Act only during periods of national emergency.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
