<bill session="115" type="s" number="3066" updated="2019-07-18T12:27:28Z">
  <state datetime="2018-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the General Education Provisions Act to allow the release of education records to facilitate the award of a recognized postsecondary credential.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reverse Transfer Efficiency Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reverse Transfer Efficiency Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Reverse Transfer Efficiency Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000805"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2018-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2018-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2018-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2018-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-06-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2986"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="6543"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="4508"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3774"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-06-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reverse Transfer Efficiency Act of 2018

This bill amends the General Education Provisions Act to allow the release of a transfer student's educational records from an institution of postsecondary education where a student earned credit for coursework to an institution of postsecondary education where the student was previously enrolled in order to apply the student's coursework and credits toward completion of a recognized postsecondary credential, such as an associate's degree. (In the case of a student who does not complete a bachelor's degree after transferring to a four-year institution from a two-year institution, the credits earned at the four-year institution may be applied towards a recognized postsecondary credential at the two-year institution.) Specifically, the bill allows the Department of Education to provide funding to an institution of postsecondary education that releases a student's records of postsecondary coursework and credits without the consent of the student or the student's parents if the student provides written consent prior to receiving the credential.

&#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
