<bill session="114" type="h" number="5788" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:46Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Coal Combustion Residuals Regulation Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to provide for the management and disposal of coal combustion residuals, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Improving Coal Combustion Residuals Regulation Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001180"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1734"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1803"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="2446"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Hydrology and hydrography"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Improving Coal Combustion Residuals Regulation Act of 2016

This bill amends subtitle D (Resource Conservation and Recovery Act of 1976) of the Solid Waste Disposal Act to establish a permit program for coal combustion residuals (coal ash) that states may elect to administer. The program outlines the criteria that a state must use if it chooses to adopt and enforce a permit program regulating the management and disposal of coal ash generated by electric utilities and independent power producers. The program applies to the disposal of coal ash into landfills or surface impoundments, sand or gravel pits, quarries, or lateral expansions of the structures. The structural criteria concern: (1) design, location, and integrity; (2) financial assurance; (3) groundwater and surface water protections; (4) closure procedures; and (5) air quality with respect to fugitive dust.

A state that chooses to adopt a coal ash program is given sole enforcement authority. The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) must implement a program for a state if: (1) a state's program fails to meet those criteria, or (2) a state does not implement a program.

The bill revises implementation of the EPA rule governing the disposal of coal ash, entitled "Hazardous and Solid Waste Management System; Disposal of Coal Combustion Residuals from Electric Utilities." The rule may be implemented only through the permit program established by the bill.

The agency implementing the permit program must ensure that certain information concerning the program is publicly available.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
