<bill session="114" type="s" number="937" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:51Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">State Grazing Management Authority Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into cooperative agreements with States to provide for State management of grazing permits and leases.</title>
    <title type="display">State Grazing Management Authority Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="1792"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">State Grazing Management Authority Act

Amends the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to require the Bureau of Land Management, upon the request of a state governor, to enter into 20-year cooperative agreements providing for a state to manage grazing allotments on eligible federal land in that state. Defines "eligible federal land" as public land that is subject to a grazing permit or lease issued by the Bureau, excluding a unit of the National Wilderness Preservation System or an area of critical environmental concern.

Prohibits any state from managing more than two allotments at any one time unless waived by the Bureau.

Requires such a cooperative agreement to assign to the state the Bureau's responsibilities with respect to the grazing allotments managed under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, including the responsibility for determining whether the following actions for those allotments qualify for a categorical exclusion under such Act:

 the conduct of vegetation projects; the conduct of pinyon or juniper treatments; and determinations with respect to the number of permitted animal unit months. Requires a cooperative agreement to provide for the state to develop a process to resolve disputes relating to a decision by the state with respect to management of an allotment.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
