<bill session="114" type="h" number="5233" updated="2019-01-09T21:26:32Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-25T17:18:17-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-05-25T17:18:17-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clarifying Congressional Intent in Providing for DC Home Rule Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To repeal the Local Budget Autonomy Amendment Act of 2012, to amend the District of Columbia Home Rule Act to clarify the respective roles of the District government and Congress in the local budget process of the District government, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Clarifying Congressional Intent in Providing for DC Home Rule Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001187"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001052" joined="2016-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-05-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 22 - 14.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-05-23">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 114-586.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-05-23" calendar="Union" number="456">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 456.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T17:26:24-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 744 Reported to House. The resolution provides for consideration of S. 2012 and H.R. 5233.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T13:43:17-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 744 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T15:46:18-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 744.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3208-3217" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T15:46:23-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for consideration of S. 2012 and H.R. 5233.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T15:47:04-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 5233.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T16:39:40-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Connolly moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Oversight and Government.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3215" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3215" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T16:40:15-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Connolly motion to recommit with instructions, pending reservation of a point of order. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the same back to the House forthwith with an amendment to allow the District of Columbia government to use local funds to prevent and treat the Zika virus. Subsequently, the reservation of a point of order was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T16:50:01-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3216" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T17:11:51-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 179 - 239 (Roll no. 247).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3216" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="248" datetime="2016-05-25T17:18:17-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 240 - 179 (Roll no. 248).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3208" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T17:18:19-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="114" relation="procedurally-related" number="744"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-25T18:14:31Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the House reported version is repeated here.)

Clarifying Congressional Intent in Providing for DC Home Rule Act of 2016

(Sec. 2) This bill repeals the Local Budget Autonomy Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Law 19-321) and restores previous law as though the Act had never been enacted.

(Sec. 3) The District of Columbia Home Rule Act is amended to declare that nothing in it shall be construed as creating a continuing appropriation of the General Fund of the District.

All funds provided for the District of Columbia shall be appropriated on an annual fiscal year basis through the federal appropriations process.

The District of Columbia Code is amended to declare that nothing in it shall be construed as authorizing the District of Columbia to make any change in law, regulation, or basic procedure and practice relating to the respective roles of Congress, the President, the Office of Management and Budget, and the Government Accountability Office in the preparation, review, submission, examination, authorization, and appropriation of the total budget of the District of Columbia government.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-586</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
