<bill session="114" type="s" number="1887" updated="2018-06-02T06:58:35Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect and Preserve International Cultural Property Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect and preserve international cultural property at risk due to political instability, armed conflict, or natural or other disasters, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Protect and Preserve International Cultural Property Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2016-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2016-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1493"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Archaeology and anthropology"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protect and Preserve International Cultural Property Act

Directs the Department of State to designate a Department employee at the Assistant Secretary level or above to serve concurrently as the U.S. Coordinator for International Cultural Property Protection to:

 coordinate and promote federal agency efforts to address international cultural property protection activities; support activities to assist countries that are the principal sources of trafficked cultural property to protect cultural heritage sites and to prevent cultural property looting and theft; develop strategies to reduce illegal trade and trafficking in international cultural property in the United States and abroad, including by reducing consumer demand for such trade; and Chair the Coordinating Committee on International Cultural Property Protection. Establishes a Coordinating Committee on International Cultural Property Protection to facilitate the Coordinator's work.

Directs the Department, through the U.S. Coordinator for International Cultural Property Protection, to report to Congress annually for seven years regarding activities of the U.S. Coordinator and the Coordinating Committee, the Department, the U.S. Agency for International Development, the Department of Defense, the Department of Homeland Security, and the Department of Justice to protect international cultural property.

Authorizes any agency involved in international cultural property protection activities to enter into agreements with the Smithsonian Institution to engage Smithsonian personnel temporarily to assist in such activities.

Directs the President to apply specified import restrictions with respect to any archaeological or ethnological material of Syria as if Syria were a State Party to the Convention on prohibiting and preventing the illicit import, export, and transfer of ownership of cultural property.

 Sets forth the conditions for termination of such restrictions.

 Authorizes the President to waive such import restrictions for specified cultural property if the President certifies to Congress that:

 the foreign owner or custodian of the specified cultural property has requested that such property be temporarily located in the United States for protection purposes, such property shall be returned upon request to the foreign owner or custodian, and the grant of a waiver will not contribute to illegal trafficking in cultural property or financing of criminal or terrorist activities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
