<bill session="114" type="h" number="4629" updated="2019-05-09T23:32:58Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To extend Federal recognition to the Muscogee Nation of Florida.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Muscogee Nation of Florida Federal Recognition Act</title>
    <title type="display">Muscogee Nation of Florida Federal Recognition Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001144"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indigenous Peoples of the United States" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-25T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Muscogee Nation of Florida Federal Recognition Act

This bill extends federal recognition to the Muscogee Nation of Florida, which makes its members eligible for the services and benefits provided to members of federally recognized Indian tribes.

 The service area of the tribe, for the purpose of delivering federal services to members, is the community of Bruce in Walton County, Florida, and an area in Florida in which members reside that is bordered on the west by the Escambia River and on the east by the St. Marks River.

The constitution and bylaws of the tribe must be the constitution and bylaws of the tribe's Tribal Council dated January 21, 2001, including amendments. The Department of the Interior, upon receipt of a written request of the Tribal Council, must hold a referendum for members to adopt a new constitution and bylaws.

The role and duties of the Tribal Council are specified.

The membership roll of the tribe must be determined in accordance with the membership criteria established by the ordinance of the tribe numbered 04-01-100 and dated February 7, 2004.

Interior may take land into trust on behalf of the tribe.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
