<bill session="114" type="s" number="2381" updated="2018-06-02T07:13:44Z">
  <state datetime="2015-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Puerto Rico Assistance Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide assistance and support to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</title>
    <title type="display">Puerto Rico Assistance Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2015-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2015-12-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4199"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-12-09T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Puerto Rico Assistance Act of 2015

TITLE I--TAXES

The bill provides for a reduction in employment and self-employment tax rates for qualified residents of Puerto Rico, American Samoa, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, and the Virgin Islands during a payroll tax holiday period beginning after December 31, 2015, and ending before January 1, 2021.

TITLE II--PUBLIC PENSIONS

The bill requires reports on: (1) the financial condition of Puerto Rico public pension plans, and (2) state and local government employee pension benefit plans.

The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide for annuity accumulation retirement plans for state and local government employees beginning after 2015.

TITLE III--PUERTO RICO FINANCIAL RESPONSIBILITY AND MANAGEMENT ASSISTANCE AUTHORITY

The bill establishes the Puerto Rico Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority to assist the Commonwealth government of Puerto Rico and its public corporations in achieving financial stability. The Authority shall initiate a control period for either the Commonwealth government or a public corporation by certifying that either such entity: (1) does not have sufficient revenue to meet is debt obligations, (2) has defaulted on a loan or other financial obligation, (3) is unable to meet payroll, (4) has a cash deficit, or (5) fails to make required pension payments. For each year in which the Commonwealth government or a public corporation is in a control period, the Governor of Puerto Rico or the emergency manager of a public corporation shall develop and submit to the Authority a financial plan and budget. A control period terminates when the Authority certifies that the Commonwealth government or its public corporations have adequate access to credit and have been solvent for a specified period.

The bill sets forth standards to promote the financial stability of the Commonwealth government and its public corporations.

The Authority may issue bonds at the request of the governor and pursuant to an act of the Legislative Assembly to raise revenue for the functioning of the Commonwealth government.

The bill establishes the Office of the Chief Financial Officer of Puerto Rico. During a control period the Chief Financial Officer shall assist the governor in preparing financial plans and budgets and shall oversee other financial operations of the Commonwealth government.

TITLE IV--ADDITIONAL REPORTS AND STUDIES

The bill requires: (1) a report on the exclusion of U.S. territories from participation in health care exchanges, and (2) recommendations on the manner in which the federal government should more equitably allocate resources across U.S. territories.

TITLE V--TRANSITION ASSISTANCE

The bill authorizes appropriations, to remain available through FY2016, for use by the Authority to assist the transition of Puerto Rico to financial, fiscal, economic, and health care stability, the cost of which shall be offset by reductions in funding for the Prevention and Public Health Fund.

TITLE VI--TECHNICAL ASSISTANCE

The Department of the Treasury must provide technical assistance to U.S. territories (including Puerto Rico) for improved accounting and disclosure practices.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
