<bill session="115" type="h" number="3824" updated="2019-04-18T16:15:25Z">
  <state datetime="2017-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Army to submit to Congress a report with respect to dams, reservoirs, lakes, and other water retention facilities in Texas, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Texas Flood Accountability Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Texas Flood Accountability Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Texas Flood Accountability Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000592"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2017-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000755" joined="2017-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001048" joined="2017-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000553" joined="2017-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000410" joined="2017-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2017-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000168" joined="2017-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2017-10-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-09-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7527"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8132"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-09-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Texas Flood Accountability Act of 2017

This bill requires the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers to submit to Congress and make publicly available a report with respect to dams, reservoirs, lakes, and other water retention facilities in Texas.

 The report shall include:

 for each such facility, the maximum water capacity that would necessitate an unplanned release of water, the water level at which the facility and each spillway of the facility will overflow, and plans to notify first responders, local officials, and communities of flood emergencies and the projected water levels during such emergencies; a description of steps taken by the Corps of Engineers to limit or prevent unplanned releases of water or overflows from such facilities; recommendations of the Corps for infrastructure improvements and dredging of existing facilities needed to limit or prevent such releases or overflows; plans to coordinate among such facilities during a flood emergency; and a list identifying the such facilities under the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission's jurisdiction, which shall include a description of the process for lowering water levels at each facility. The Corps may exclude information from the report for national security purposes.

Upon the Corps' request, a non-federal entity that owns, operates, or has jurisdiction over a covered facility shall provide the maximum water capacity that would necessitate an unplanned release of water, the water level at which the facility and each spillway of the facility will overflow, and plans to notify first responders, local officials, and communities of flood emergencies and the projected water levels during such emergencies. An entity shall not be eligible for federal financial assistance until it complies with such request.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
