<bill session="115" type="s" number="2824" updated="2019-04-18T16:43:04Z">
  <state datetime="2018-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 to establish in each State a network between agricultural producers and food banks to provide food to the needy and reduce food waste, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Farm to Food Bank Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Farm to Food Bank Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Farm to Food Bank Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-05-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural insurance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Fruit and vegetables"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Grain"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Seafood"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-05-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Farm to Food Bank Act of 2018 

This bill amends the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 to require the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish a program to allocate funding to states to support the establishment and administration of farm to food bank programs. A "farm to food bank program" is a program under which agricultural producers donate food products to a food bank, an association of food banks, or a food assistance network for free distribution to individuals in need.

The bill also amends the Federal Crop Insurance Act to require the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation to establish a procedure under which an insured crop that is donated by a producer does not qualify as a produced crop under a crop insurance claim.

USDA must coordinate with the Environmental Protection Agency to conduct a study to evaluate and determine methods of measuring food waste, standards for the volume of food waste, and causal factors for food waste.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
