<bill session="113" type="h" number="5874" updated="2016-10-25T16:17:53Z">
  <state datetime="2014-12-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Counterfeit Drug Enforcement Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tim Fagan's Law</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to increase criminal penalties for the sale or trade of prescription drugs knowingly caused to be adulterated or misbranded, to establish recall authority regarding drugs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Counterfeit Drug Enforcement Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000057"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-12-11T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Tim Fagan's Law or Counterfeit Drug Enforcement Act of 2014 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (FFDCA) to establish a criminal fine and/or imprisonment for a person who: (1) knowingly causes a prescription drug to be adulterated, misbranded, or misrepresented as an approved prescription drug and sells or trades the drug; or (2) purchases or trades for a drug knowing or having reason to know that the drug was knowingly adulterated, misbranded, or misrepresented. Requires a manufacturer of a drug to notify the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) within 48 hours after first receiving or becoming aware of information that reasonably suggests that such a violation may have occurred.

Deems a drug to be misbranded if it is not manufactured using technologies that HHS determines are technically feasible and assist in preventing such violations.

Authorizes additional appropriations for Food and Drug Administration (FDA) inspections, examinations, and investigations.

Requires HHS to educate the public and health care professionals on counterfeit drugs.

Directs HHS, upon a finding that a drug intended for human use may constitute a threat to the public health, to issue an order requiring the appropriate person (including the manufacturers, importers, distributors, or retailers of the drug) to cease distribution of the drug and to notify and instruct health professionals to cease administering, distributing, selling, or prescribing the drug. Requires HHS, after providing the person with an opportunity for an informal hearing, to amend the order to include a recall, if appropriate.

Requires HHS and the Attorney General to establish a procedure through which the FDA is authorized to issue subpoenas.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
