<bill session="114" type="s" number="1434" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:56Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Storage Promotion and Deployment Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to establish an energy storage portfolio standard, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Energy Storage Promotion and Deployment Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001046"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2015-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2015-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2015-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2015-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2015-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2015-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-09">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Energy Storage Promotion and Deployment Act of 2015

This bill amends the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to establish national energy storage standards for certain electric power suppliers (utilities) that sell at least 500,000 megawatt hours of electric energy annually. Each supplier must have energy storage devices that have the capacity to provide at least 1% of its annual average peak power demand by 2021 and 2% by 2025. Suppliers must also meet a secondary standard.

Energy storage devices include those used to store energy using pumped hydropower, compressed air, batteries or other electrochemical forms, thermal forms, flywheels, capacitors, and superconducting magnets.

The standards do not apply to rural electric cooperatives or government-owned suppliers.

An energy storage device placed in operation before January 1, 2009, may not be used to achieve compliance with the standards.

The Department of Energy may provide one-year waivers from the deadlines if achieving the standard by the deadline would present undue hardship to the supplier or its ratepayers.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
