<bill session="113" type="h" number="2777" updated="2016-10-25T16:06:07Z">
  <state datetime="2013-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Pay for Violent Offenders Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to authorize the Secretaries of the military departments to suspend the pay and allowances of a member of the Armed Forces who is held in confinement pending trial by court-martial or by civil authority for any sex-related offense or capital offense.</title>
    <title type="display">Stop Pay for Violent Offenders Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000567"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001051" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000583" joined="2013-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000672" joined="2013-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-07-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop Pay for Violent Offenders Act - Directs the Secretary of the military department concerned (Secretary concerned) to suspend all or a portion of the pay and allowances of a member of the Armed Forces who is being held in confinement pending trial by court-martial or by civil authority for any sex-related or capital offense.

Entitles such member to: (1) written notice of the suspension, (2) a reasonable time (at least seven days) to request a suspension waiver and to furnish supporting evidence, (3) representation by an attorney or other representative in making such request, and (4) a written response by the Secretary concerned and the reasons for any denial of such request.

Requires any member who is subsequently acquitted of any such charges to be paid the full amount of the withheld pay and allowances.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
