<bill session="114" type="h" number="2085" updated="2019-02-08T20:13:06Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to enter into negotiations with interested local water and power providers for the transfer of ownership, control, and operation of the New Melones Unit, Central Valley Project, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to enter into negotiations with interested local water and power providers for the transfer of ownership, control, and operation of the New Melones Unit, Central Valley Project, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000612"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000059" joined="2015-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001177" joined="2015-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000181" joined="2015-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water, Oceans, and Wildlife" code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Directs the Department of the Interior to: (1) enter into negotiations for the transfer of ownership, control, and operation of the New Melones Unit, Central Valley Project to interested local water and power providers within California; (2) report to specified congressional committees every six months on such negotiations, on actions Interior recommends the United States take to finalize an agreement for such transfer, and on the terms of any agreement reached; and (3) transfer such Unit in accordance with such an agreement.

Defines: (1) the "New Melones Unit, Central Valley Project" to mean all federal reclamation projects located within or diverting water from or to the watershed of the Stanislaus and San Joaquin rivers and their tributaries; and (2) "interested local water and power providers" to include the Calaveras County Water District, Central San Joaquin Water Conservation District, Modesto Irrigation District, Oakdale Irrigation District, Stockton East Water District, South San Joaquin Irrigation District, Tuolumne Utilities District, Turlock Irrigation District, and Union Public Utilities District.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
