<bill session="115" type="h" number="2419" updated="2019-04-18T16:08:31Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the process by which the Secretary of Veterans Affairs pays non-Department of Veterans Affairs health care providers for hospital care or medical services furnished to veterans pursuant to the laws administered by the Secretary.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the process by which the Secretary of Veterans Affairs pays non-Department of Veterans Affairs health care providers for hospital care or medical services furnished to veterans pursuant to the laws administered by the Secretary.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000603"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to ensure that payments made to non-VA health care providers, including payments under the Veterans Choice Program, comply with the Prompt Payment Act and the requirements set forth in this bill.

The bill: (1) prescribes payment schedules; (2) requires, with exceptions, claims to be submitted electroncially beginning January 1, 2019; and (3) requires the VA Chief Information Officer to establish by such date an electronic interface for health care providers to submit reimbursement claims.

The VA shall: (1) within 90 days after enactment of this bill, make necessary modifications to ensure prompt payment for hospital care or medical treatment furnished under the program, and (2) within 180 days after enactment of this bill, adjudicate all program claims submitted before such date by non-VA health care providers.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
