<bill session="114" type="h" number="5729" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:39Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Stop U.S. Support for State Sponsors of Terrorism Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the Secretary of the Treasury from issuing certain licenses in connection with the export or re-export of a commercial passenger aircraft to the Islamic Republic of Iran, to require annual reports by the Secretary of the Treasury and the Export-Import Bank on financing issues related to the sale or lease of such a commercial passenger aircraft or spare parts for such an aircraft, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Stop U.S. Support for State Sponsors of Terrorism Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000606"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Monetary Policy and Trade Prior to Introduction and Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 33 - 21.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-12-12">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 114-866, Part I.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Monetary Policy and Trade" code="HSBA20" name="House Financial Services" activity="Hearings"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5711"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5716"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-12T14:08:19Z" status="Reported to House amended, Part I">Stop U.S. Support for State Sponsors of Terrorism Act

(Sec. 2) This bill prohibits the Department of the Treasury from issuing a license for the export or re-export of commercial passenger aircraft to the Islamic Republic of Iran.

(Sec. 3) Treasury shall submit an annual report to Congress:

 stating whether any U.S. financial institution is involved with the sale or lease of commercial passenger aircraft or aircraft spare parts to Iran by a non-U.S. manufacturer, and whether any such involvement is with respect to such aircraft or spare parts comprising 10% or more U.S. content; and containing a description of the risks related to repayment, money laundering, and the financing of terrorism faced by U.S. financial institutions that are involved in such transactions. (Sec. 4) The Export-Import Bank shall report annually to Congress on the use of Bank assistance for such transactions.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-866</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
