<bill session="114" type="h" number="1821" updated="2019-05-09T23:15:18Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide certain protections from civil liability with respect to the emergency administration of opioid overdose drugs.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Opioid Overdose Reduction Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Opioid Overdose Reduction Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000015"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001105" joined="2015-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000613" joined="2015-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000570" joined="2015-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000297" joined="2015-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000560" joined="2015-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2016-04-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E501-502"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="707"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Opioid Overdose Reduction Act of 2015

This bill exempts individuals from liability for harm caused by the emergency administration of an opioid overdose drug under certain circumstances. (An opioid is a drug with effects similar to opium, such as heroin.) The individuals exempted from liability are:

 a health care professional who prescribes or provides an opioid overdose drug to an individual at risk of experiencing an opioid overdose or to another individual in a position to assist the individual, if the individual has been educated about opioid overdose prevention and treatment by the health care professional or as part of a government opioid overdose program; an individual who provides an opioid overdose drug for emergency administration to another individual authorized to receive it as part of an opioid overdose program; and an individual who administers an opioid overdose drug to another individual who appears to have suffered an opioid overdose if the individual obtained the drug from a health care professional or as part of an opioid overdose program and was educated by the professional or program in the proper administration of the drug. These exemptions are inapplicable if the harm was caused by gross negligence or reckless misconduct.

States can preempt these exemptions by providing additional protections from liability for individuals that administer opioid overdose drugs, or by enacting legislation making the Act not applicable to state civil action involving only citizens from that state.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
