<bill session="115" type="h" number="4823" updated="2019-04-18T16:19:42Z">
  <state datetime="2018-01-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-01-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-01-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 to include certain areas in the Central Texas Corridor.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Connecting the Rest to the West</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Connecting the Rest to the West</title>
    <title type="display">Connecting the Rest to the West</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001062"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-01-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Highways and Transit" code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="6111"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-01-18T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Connecting the Rest to the West

This bill amends the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 to include the following named areas as part of the high priority Central Texas Corridor of the National Highway System in Texas:

 certain routes in the corridor and the I-14 system in Texas, beginning in the vicinity of State Highway 338 in Odessa, Texas, running eastward concurrent with Interstate 20, connecting to State Highway 158 in the vicinity of Midland, Texas, then following State Highway 158 eastward to US 87 and then following US 87 southeastward, passing in the vicinity of San Angelo, and connecting to US 190 in the vicinity of Brady, Texas; US 83 southward from the vicinity of Eden, Texas, to a logical connection to Interstate 10 at Junction, Texas. The corridor shall not include the section of US 190 from I-10 in Pecos County to Brady in McCullough County, Texas.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
