<bill session="114" type="h" number="2187" updated="2018-09-07T15:11:25Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-01T18:48:04-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-02-01T18:48:04-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Investment Opportunities for Professional Experts Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Fair Investment Opportunities for Professional Experts Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Fair Investment Opportunities for Professional Experts Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Securities and Exchange Commission to revise its regulations regarding the qualifications of natural persons as accredited investors.</title>
    <title type="display">Fair Investment Opportunities for Professional Experts Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001183"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2015-12-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-16">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises Prior to Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-12-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 54 - 2.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 114-406.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-02-01" calendar="Union" number="309">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 309.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01T15:15:17-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Garrett moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01T15:15:30-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H378-379" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01T15:15:32-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2187.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01T15:28:32-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01T18:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H401" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="46" datetime="2016-02-01T18:48:04-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 347 - 8 (Roll no. 46).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H378" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01T18:48:04-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises" code="HSBA16" name="House Financial Services" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6427"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5983"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-01T12:58:24Z" status="Passed House amended">Fair Investment Opportunities for Professional Experts Act

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Securities Act of 1933 to add to the definition of accredited investor any natural person whose individual net worth, or joint net worth with his or her spouse, exceeds $1 million (adjusted every five years for inflation).

The person's net worth shall exclude:

 the person's primary residence; and as a liability any indebtedness secured by the primary residence, up to the estimated fair market value of the residence at the time of the sale of securities. Indebtedness secured by the person's primary residence in excess of the residence's estimated fair market value at the time of the sale of securities, however, shall be included in net worth as a liability.

An accredited investor shall also include any natural person:

 whose individual income exceeded $200,000 in each of the two most recent years, or whose joint income with spouse exceeded $300,000 in each of those years, and has a reasonable expectation of reaching the same income level in the current year; currently licensed or registered as a broker or investment adviser by the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Financial Industry Regulatory Authority (FINRA) (or an equivalent self-regulatory organization), or a state division responsible for licensing or registration of individuals in connection with securities activities; or whose demonstrable education or job experience qualifies as professional knowledge of a subject related to a particular investment, and whose education or job experience is verified by the FINRA or an equivalent self-regulatory organization.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-406</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
