<bill session="114" type="s" number="2121" updated="2018-06-02T07:10:29Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preserving American Access to Information Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to facilitate and enhance the declassification of information, including in the Legislative Branch, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Preserving American Access to Information Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-01T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Preserving American Access to Information Act 

This bill directs: (1)&#160;the President to take appropriate actions to enhance the authority and capacity of the National Declassification Center under Executive Order 13526, or any successor executive order, to promote a government-wide strategy for the declassification of information; (2) the National Declassification Center to provide for consultation between the Center's advisory panel and the public on a regular basis; (3) federal agencies to make efforts to identify and designate historically valuable records during the initial classification process to ensure preservation and timely access to such records following eventual declassification; (4) the Public Interest Declassification Board to submit reports to Congress on pilot programs to assess the feasibility and&#160;advisability of mechanisms to improve the current declassification capabilities of such agencies; and (5) the Public Interest Declassification Board to review the rules of the Senate and the House of Representatives regarding the declassification of classified Committee records and make recommendations to improve declassification efforts.

The bill requires federal agency heads that classify information to report to Congress on&#160;an assessment of the feasibility and advisability of: (1)&#160;replacing the&#160;agency's current classification system with a two-tiered system,&#160;and&#160;(2) declassifying records with classified Formerly Restricted Data.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
