<bill session="115" type="h" number="5089" updated="2019-04-18T16:20:35Z">
  <state datetime="2018-03-22T13:14:19-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-03-22T13:14:19-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve threat information sharing, integrated operations, and law enforcement training for transportation security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Strengthening Local Transportation Security Capabilities Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Strengthening Local Transportation Security Capabilities Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Strengthening Local Transportation Security Capabilities Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Strengthening Local Transportation Security Capabilities Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Local Transportation Security Capabilities Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Local Transportation Security Capabilities Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Strengthening Local Transportation Security Capabilities Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001300"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2018-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2018-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-02-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Protective Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-07">
      <text>Subcommittee on Transportation and Protective Security Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-03-07" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-03-19">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 115-604.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-03-19" calendar="Union" number="460">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 460.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-03-19T17:09:52-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bacon moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-19T17:10:05-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1673-1675" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1673" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-19T17:10:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5089.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-19T17:19:07-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-22T13:07:12-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2028-2029" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="129" datetime="2018-03-22T13:14:19-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 397 - 1 (Roll no. 129).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-03-22T13:14:20-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Transportation and Maritime Security" code="HSHM07" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="4474"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-03-22T11:13:22Z" status="Passed House amended">Strengthening Local Transportation Security Capabilities Act of 2018

(Sec. 3) This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to prioritize the assignment of officers and intelligence analysts from the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) and DHS's Office of Intelligence and Analysis, to locations with participating state, local, and regional fusion centers in jurisdictions with a high-risk surface transportation asset in order to enhance the security of such asset. A "surface transportation asset" includes facilities, equipment, or systems used to provide transportation services by: (1) a public transportation agency, (2) a railroad carrier, (3) an owner or operator of bus services or a bus terminal, or (4) other facilities as determined by DHS.

 Officers and intelligence analysts assigned to locations with participating state, local, and regional fusion centers shall participate in the generation and dissemination of transportation security intelligence products, with an emphasis on terrorist and other threats to surface transportation assets that: (1) assist state, local, and tribal law enforcement agencies in deploying their resources; (2) promote more consistent and timely sharing of threat information among jurisdictions; and (3) enhance DHS's situational awareness of such terrorist and other threats.

(Sec. 4) The TSA shall: (1) make available to public and private sector stakeholders a framework for establishing an integrated and unified operations center responsible for overseeing daily operations of a transportation facility that promotes coordination for responses to terrorism, serious incidents, and other purposes; and (2) report to the House Committee on Homeland Security and the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation on operations centers at transportation facilities at which the TSA has a presence.

(Sec. 5) DHS, may develop, through the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers, a training program to enhance the protection, preparedness, and response capabilities of law enforcement agencies with respect to terrorism and other serious incidents at a surface transportation asset.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-604</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
