<bill session="114" type="s" number="2317" updated="2018-06-02T07:12:11Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Minority-Serving Institution Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title III of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to strengthen minority-serving institutions.</title>
    <title type="display">Minority-Serving Institution Fairness Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2015-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2015-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="4098"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-19T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Minority-Serving Institution Fairness Act

This bill amends titles III (Institutional Aid) and V (Developing Institutions) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to permit an eligible minority-serving institution of higher education (IHE) to concurrently receive grant funds under more than one of the following programs: (1) the Strengthening Alaska Native and Native Hawaiian-Serving Institutions program; (2) the Strengthening Native American-serving, Nontribal Institutions program; (3) the Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-Serving Institutions program; and (4) the Hispanic-Serving Institutions program.

At least 35% of grant funds awarded under each program must be awarded to IHEs that are not eligible to concurrently receive funds under more than one program.

An eligible minority-serving IHE is a Hispanic-serving institution, Alaska Native-serving or Native Hawaiian-serving institution, Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institution, or a Native American-serving nontribal institution.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
