<bill session="114" type="h" number="1556" updated="2019-05-09T23:15:18Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To secure the Federal voting rights of non-violent persons when released from incarceration.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Civil Rights Voting Restoration Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Civil Rights Voting Restoration Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000808"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000911" joined="2015-05-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="12"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1459"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="772"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="457"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Civil Rights Voting Restoration Act of 2015

 Declares that the right of a U.S. citizen to vote in any election for federal office shall not be denied or abridged because the individual has been convicted of a non-violent criminal offense, unless, at the time of the election, the individual is serving a sentence in a correctional facility or a term of probation.

Restores the right to vote of an individual on probation: (1) on the date the term of probation ends, if such term is less than one year; or (2) one year after the date the individual begins serving the term of probation, if such term is one year or longer.

Directs the Attorney General to determine and establish a list of the criminal offenses under federal and state law that are non-violent criminal offenses.

Provides for enforcement of, and remedies for violations of, this Act.

Sets forth requirements for state and federal notification of individuals of their voting rights pursuant to this Act.

Prohibits a state, local government, or other person from receiving or using federal grant amounts to construct or improve a place of incarceration unless that person has in effect a program under which each incarcerated individual is notified, upon release, of his or her rights under this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
