<bill session="115" type="h" number="4974" updated="2019-04-18T16:20:14Z">
  <state datetime="2018-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to render overstaying a visa a criminal offense, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to render overstaying a visa a criminal offense, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001199"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="643"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-02-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to subject any alien who remains in the United States after any visa or status under which the alien is lawfully present has expired to: (1) a fine or imprisonment for up to six months, or both, for a first offense; and (2) a fine or imprisonment for up to two years, or both, for any subsequent offense.

 Such penalties shall be waived if the overstay was due to medical necessity, public safety, or national security.

An alien convicted of a first offense may not be admitted to the United States for 5 years or granted a visa for 10 years.

 An alien convicted of a subsequent offense may not be admitted to the United States at all or granted a visa.

 The bill expands the scope of an individual's right to counsel in immigration proceedings and appeals. The government, however, shall not bear the cost of counsel in such proceedings or appeals.

 The Department of State may share visa records and related information with a foreign government if in the national interests of the United States.

 The Department of Justice and the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall provide the State Department with access to National Crime Information Center files for visa adjudications involving a diplomat or government official.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
