<bill session="114" type="h" number="4397" updated="2018-06-02T04:52:38Z">
  <state datetime="2016-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rail Safety Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to provide for caches of emergency response equipment to be used in the event of an accident involving rail tank cars transporting hazardous material, crude oil, or flammable liquids.</title>
    <title type="display">Rail Safety Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000188"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000799" joined="2016-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-01-28T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Rail Safety Act

This bill directs the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to develop and preposition caches of emergency response equipment, which may include firefighting equipment and fire suppression agents, to facilitate the rapid deployment of resources needed to reduce damage to life, property, and the environment in the event of an accident involving rail tank cars transporting hazardous material, crude oil, or flammable liquids.

Such caches shall be strategically prepositioned along rail routes over which a high volume of high-hazard trains operate in a manner that lowers the response time of firefighters to fight fires involving flammable liquids and to prevent such fires from spreading. FEMA may collect fees from railroad carriers to develop and preposition the caches.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
