<bill session="115" type="h" number="6550" updated="2019-04-18T16:26:38Z">
  <state datetime="2018-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance the innovation, security, and availability of Federal Government cloud services by establishing the Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program within the Office of Management and Budget Office of Electronic Government and by establishing a risk management, authorization, and continuous monitoring process to enable the Federal Government to leverage cloud computing services using a risk-based approach consistent with the Federal Information Security Reform Act of 2014 and cloud-based operations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program Reform Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program Reform Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FedRAMP Authorization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FedRAMP Authorization Act</title>
    <title type="display">FedRAMP Authorization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001187" joined="2018-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-07-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-07-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program Reform Act of 2018 or the FedRAMP Authorization Act

This bill amends the E-Government Act of 2002 to establish the FedRAMP Program Management Office within the General Services Administration. The office shall be responsible for the Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program.

Additionally, the bill establishes the Joint Authorization Board which shall issue provisional authorizations to cloud service providers to operate within FedRAMP security guidelines.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
