<bill session="114" type="h" number="4082" updated="2018-06-02T04:49:31Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coordinating Transportation Services for Transportation Disadvantaged Individuals Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To coordinate transportation services for transportation-disadvantaged individuals.</title>
    <title type="display">Coordinating Transportation Services for Transportation Disadvantaged Individuals Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000806"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Highways and Transit" code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-19T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Coordinating Transportation Services for Transportation Disadvantaged Individuals Act of 2015

This bill establishes in the Department of Transportation (DOT) the New Interagency Transportation Coordinating Council on Access and Mobility to coordinate transportation services to transportation-disadvantaged individuals (those who require the use of public transportation but have difficulty accessing it due to disability, income level, age, or veteran status) in a manner that is cost effective and efficient and that minimizes the fragmentation and duplication of such services.

The Council shall:

 develop a strategic plan that identifies federal agency roles and responsibilities and measurable outcomes in coordinating such services; develop a joint cost-sharing policy among federal agencies with representatives on the Council that provides clear guidance to state and local governments regarding cost allocation; maintain an inventory of all federal programs that provide such services; and partner with State Transport Coordinating Commissions (STCCs) and aid them in coordinating such services. A state must establish an STCC to coordinate transportation for transportation-disadvantaged individuals. An STCC shall:

 compile information on transportation operations for and needs of such individuals; establish statewide objectives for coordinating transportation services for such individuals; develop written policies and procedures for the coordination of government funding for such individuals; identify and pursue the elimination of barriers to transportation services; establish an information clearinghouse; assist communities in developing transportation systems designed to serve such individuals; verify that purchasing procedures aid the coordination of such services; verify that purchasing agencies purchase all trips within transportation systems that serve such individuals, unless they use more cost-effective alternative providers; and develop a strategic plan that addresses the transportation problems and needs of such individuals over a five-year period. DOT must withhold 1% of the amount required to be apportioned to a state under specified federal-aid highway programs on the first day of each fiscal year beginning with FY2017 if the state does not meet this bill's requirements.

Each federal agency shall keep an accounting of expenditures directly related to services for transportation-disadvantaged individuals. No federal agency may make capital investments for the purpose of providing the services.

The bill terminates the Interagency Transportation Coordinating Council on Access and Mobility.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
