<bill session="113" type="s" number="1998" updated="2016-10-25T16:28:45Z">
  <state datetime="2014-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native Adult Education and Literacy Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Adult Education and Family Literacy Act to reserve funds for American Indian, Alaska Native, Native Hawaiian, and Tribal College or University adult education and literacy.</title>
    <title type="display">Native Adult Education and Literacy Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001265" joined="2014-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2014-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000818" joined="2014-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Adult education and literacy"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-02-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Native Adult Education and Literacy Act of 2014 - Amends the Adult Education and Family Literacy Act to include Tribal Colleges or Universities as eligible providers of services under that Act.

Directs the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to Tribal Colleges or Universities and Native Hawaiian educational organizations to develop and implement innovative, effective, and replicable programs designed to enhance life skills and transition individuals to employability and postsecondary education.

Requires grantees to have a multiyear strategy, including performance measures, for increasing the number of adult American Indians, Native Hawaiians, or Alaska Natives that attain a secondary school diploma or its recognized equivalent.

Includes among the activities that may be funded by a grant:

 adult education and literacy services, including workplace literacy services; family literacy services; English literacy programs, including limited English proficiency programs; opportunities for American Indians, Native Hawaiians, and Alaska Natives to qualify for a secondary school diploma or its recognized equivalent; and demonstration and research projects and professional development activities designed to develop and identify the most successful means of addressing the educational needs of American Indian, Native Hawaiian, and Alaska Native adults.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
