<bill session="115" type="s" number="3315" updated="2019-04-18T16:45:02Z">
  <state datetime="2018-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to allow for the taking of pinnipeds on the Columbia River and its tributaries to protect endangered and threatened species of salmon and other nonlisted fish species.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Predation Reduction of Salmon Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Predation Reduction of Salmon Act</title>
    <title type="display">Predation Reduction of Salmon Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001176"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2018-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2083"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-07-31T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Predation Reduction of Salmon Act

 This bill amends the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to authorize the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to issue permits allowing Washington, Oregon, and Idaho to kill sea lions in a portion of the Columbia River and certain tributaries in order to protect specified fish from sea lion predation. Specifically, the permits may be issued to protect: (1) endangered or threatened species of salmon, steelhead, or eulachon; and (2) species of lamprey or sturgeon that are listed as a species of concern. Those states may enter into memoranda of understanding with Indian tribes with legal or historic interests in the protection of the species in such area for deterrence and removal of sea lions.

Permits may be issued to kill sea lions only if the sea lions are part of a population that is not categorized as depleted or strategic.

The cumulative annual taking of sea lions each year under all such permits is limited to 10% of the annual potential biological removal level. In addition, the takings must be humane.

NOAA must suspend the issuance of the permits if, after five years, lethal removal authority is no longer necessary to protect fish from sea lion predation.

The Department of the Interior must study the effectiveness of the permits on the recovery of salmon and steelhead stocks.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
