<bill session="114" type="h" number="5966" updated="2018-06-02T05:30:06Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to convey certain locks and dams.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to convey certain locks and dams.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000558"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-08T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill deauthorizes the project for navigation at the Green River Locks and Dams 3, 4, 5, and 6 and Barren River Lock and Dam 1, Kentucky, and requires the associated lands and improvements to be disposed of as prescribed below.

All U.S. rights to:

 Green River Lock and Dam 3, located in Ohio County and Muhlenberg County, shall be conveyed to the Rochester Dam Regional Water Commission; Green River Lock and Dam 4, located in Butler County, shall be conveyed to Butler County; Green River Lock and Dam 5, located in Butler County and Warren County, shall be conveyed to Kentucky, a political subdivision thereof, or a tax-exempt non-governmental organization; and the portion of the Green River Lock and Dam 6, Edmonson County located on the right descending bank of the Green River, and Barren River Lock and Dam 1, located in Warren County, shall be conveyed to the Kentucky Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources. The Secretary of the Army shall transfer administrative jurisdiction over the portion of the Green River Lock and Dam 6 located on the left descending bank of the Green River to the Department of the Interior for inclusion in the Mammoth Cave National Park.

If the Secretary determines that such conveyed land ceases to be owned by the public, all right to the land shall revert to the United States.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
