<bill session="113" type="h" number="4772" updated="2016-10-25T16:13:42Z">
  <state datetime="2014-05-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RESPECT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Respecting Senior Performers as Essential Cultural Treasures Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 17, United States Code, to provide for the payment of royalties for the performance of sound recordings fixed before February 15, 1972, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">RESPECT Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001065"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001273" joined="2014-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2014-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2014-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000556" joined="2014-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001093" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2014-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000754" joined="2014-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000610" joined="2014-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000458" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000552" joined="2014-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000294" joined="2014-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000258" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000583" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000580" joined="2014-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2014-12-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="Sound recording"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-05-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Respecting Senior Performers as Essential Cultural Treasures Act or the RESPECT Act - Requires digital music services (certain services providing digital transmissions of music by Internet radio, cable, or satellite) that transmit sound recordings under the statutory license provided under federal copyright law to pay royalties for sound recordings fixed before February 15, 1972, in the same manner as they pay royalties for sound recordings protected by federal copyright that are fixed after such date. (Currently, sound recordings fixed before February 15, 1972, are governed by state laws and are not subject to federal copyright laws that require music services to pay a performance royalty for transmitting such recordings.)

Provides a remedy under which performance royalties for the transmission of such recordings may be recovered in a civil action in federal court if a digital music service fails to make such payments.

Prohibits an infringement action against a transmitting entity from being brought under a state law if the appropriate royalty is paid under this Act.

Declares that this Act does not confer federal copyright protection upon such recordings fixed before February 15, 1972 (sound recordings fixed before February 15, 1972, remain under applicable state laws notwithstanding the payment of royalties under federal statutory licensing requirements).

Terminates this Act on February 15, 2067.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
