<amendment session="113" chamber="h" number="964" updated="2016-10-25T12:44:13Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4899" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2014-06-26T09:46:43-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000615"/>
  <offered datetime="2014-06-26"/>
  <description>Page 51, after line 21, insert the following:    SEC.___. SOUTH ATLANTIC OUTER CONTINENTAL SHELF PLANNING AREA DEFINED.    For the purposes of this Act, the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (43 U.S.C. 1331 et seq.), and any regulations or 5-year plan issued under that Act, the term "South Atlantic Outer Continental Shelf Planning Area" means the area of the outer Continental Shelf (as defined in section 2 of that Act (43 U.S.C. 1331)) that is located between the northern lateral seaward administrative boundary of the State of Virginia and the southernmost lateral seaward administrative boundary of the State of Georgia.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment No. 3 printed in House Report 113-493 to direct the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management to include Virginia, North Carolina, South Carolina and Georgia into an administrative planning area for offshore leasing purposes.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2014-06-26T09:46:43-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Duncan (SC) amendment (A003) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26T09:40:58-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A003) offered by Mr. Duncan (SC).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5786-5787" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5786" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26"/>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26T09:40:58-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A003) offered by Mr. Duncan (SC).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5786-5787" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5786" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26T09:46:43-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26T09:46:43-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Duncan (SC) amendment (A003) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
