<bill session="114" type="hr" number="821" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:42Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Urging the Government of Gabon to respect democratic principles during the August 2016 presidential elections.</title>
    <title type="display">Urging the Government of Gabon to respect democratic principles during the August 2016 presidential elections.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000522"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2016-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000179" joined="2016-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001137" joined="2016-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000487" joined="2016-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Calls on the Gabonese government to:

 hold orderly, peaceful, free, and fair presidential elections in August 2016 in order to ensure stability and long-term growth of Gabon; guarantee fair and open participation of opposition parties; and guarantee the freedom of speech and assembly of all Gabonese citizens. Encourages continued efforts toward the consolidation of democracy through increased dialogue and concrete actions to address the constitutional and legal framework of electoral systems.

Expresses support for Gabonese organizations that work to further strengthen democratic processes.

Calls on: (1) the citizens of Gabon to fully and peacefully participate in the presidential elections; and (2) the United States and other international partners to help create an environment that facilitates open communication, guarantees free and fair elections, encourages voter participation, and fosters a robust civil society.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
