<bill session="115" type="h" number="1803" updated="2019-04-18T16:05:51Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Constitutional Government Review Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">10th Amendment Restoration Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">10th Amendment Restoration Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">10th Amendment Restoration Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000628"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000065" joined="2017-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">10th Amendment Restoration Act of 2017

This bill establishes the Constitutional Government Review Commission, which shall review the authorizing statute and statutory authority of each agency to determine if they should be repealed to eliminate federal powers not definitively delegated by the Constitution.

The commission, after completing any such review, shall: (1) recommend whether immediate repeal action is appropriate, (2) prepare an estimate of federal spending or revenue changes resulting from adoption of a repeal recommendation, and (3) prepare a recommendation for distributing any federal budget savings among the states for the administration of powers returned to the states as a result of adoption of a repeal recommendation.

Such a review may be initiated by the President, a Member of Congress, any federal, state, local, tribal, or regional government officer or employee, or any member of the public.

The bill requires the commission to report to Congress detailing its activities and recommendations for the repeal of statutes and the distribution of savings among the states.

The bill establishes procedures for the expedited congressional consideration of commission recommendations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
