<bill session="114" type="hr" number="896" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:34Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Recognizing the significance of the United States relationship with the Republic of Moldova and encouraging United States support for anti-corruption efforts and strengthening democratic institutions.</title>
    <title type="display">Recognizing the significance of the United States relationship with the Republic of Moldova and encouraging United States support for anti-corruption efforts and strengthening democratic institutions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000814"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000448" joined="2016-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000435" joined="2016-11-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5920"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Calls on the U.S. government and the European Union to ensure that free and fair presidential elections are held in Moldova on October 30, 2016.

Encourages the President and the Department of State to restrict assistance to Moldova, for so long as corruption within the government ranks persists, to only justice sector reform, anti-corruption efforts, and strengthening democratic institutions.

Urges executive branch agencies that have initiated investigations to pursue all available avenues to determine: (1) if the U.S. banking system, with involvement by U.S. citizens, was used to launder money as part of the Moldovan banking scandal; (2) if U.S. taxpayer dollars in the form of International Monetary Fund loans were directed to sanctioned entities; and (3) which members of the government of Moldova participated in or benefitted from the 2014 bank heist.

Requests that the United States consider imposing sanctions, including a ban on travel to the United States, economic sanctions, and the freezing of assets, if individuals or entities are found to have participated in the laundering of funds from U.S. sanctioned entities or governments.

Urges the establishment, through legislation or via authority under Presidential Proclamation 7750, of a list similar to the one created by the Magnitsky Act for Vladimir Plahotniuc and other government officials if they are found to have been involved in such crimes.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
