<bill session="113" type="s" number="1575" updated="2016-10-25T16:27:08Z">
  <state datetime="2013-10-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to correct inconsistencies in the definitions relating to Native Americans in the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to correct inconsistencies in the definitions relating to Native Americans in the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001265"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000243" joined="2013-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2013-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2013-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2013-10-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-10-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to define an "Indian" for purposes of title I (Quality, Affordable Health Care for All Americans) of that Act.

Includes within that definition an individual who is:

 a member of a federally-recognized Indian tribe; an Eskimo, Aleut, or other Alaska Native; considered by the Secretary of the Interior to be an Indian for any purpose, including eligibility for Indian health care services; a member of a tribe, band, or other organized group of Indians or who is a descendant, in the first or second degree, of any such member; determined to be an Indian under regulations promulgated by the Secretary; an urban center resident who fits any of the preceding categories; eligible for health services provided by the Indian Health Service (IHS); or of Indian descent and a member of an Indian community served by the IHS.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
