<bill session="115" type="s" number="646" updated="2019-04-18T16:33:56Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the enforcement of employment and reemployment rights of members of the uniformed services, to amend the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to improve the protection of members of the uniformed services, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Justice for Servicemembers and Veterans Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Justice for Servicemembers and Veterans Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Justice for Servicemembers and Veterans Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2017-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2017-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2017-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2017-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2017-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2631"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Lease and rental services"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Merit Systems Protection Board"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Justice for Servicemembers and Veterans Act of 2017

 This bill authorizes the Department of Justice (DOJ) to initiate an action for relief in a service member's employment or reemployment rights action with respect to: (1) a private or state employer, or (2) a state or private employer that is engaged in a pattern or practice to infringe upon such rights.

 The bill provides that: (1) a person may bring an action against a state, state instrumentality, or state officer or employee acting in his or her official capacity in U.S. district court or state court (currently, only in state court), and (2) the state employer shall not be immune from such action under the Eleventh Amendment or under any other doctrine of sovereign immunity.

No such state, instrumentality, officer, or employee that receives or uses federal financial assistance for a program or activity shall be immune under the Eleventh Amendment or under any other doctrine of sovereign immunity from suit in federal or state court for any employment rights violation related to such program or activity.

The bill expands judicial venues for an action against a private employer.

DOJ may issue civil investigative demands in the enforcement of employment and reemployment rights of members of uniformed services with respect to states and private employers.

Service-related disability coverage is extended.

The Servicemembers Civil Relief Act is amended to revise protective provisions for service members regarding: (1) default judgments, including the requirement that a court shall not enter a judgment until it appoints an attorney for the defendant; (2) termination of residential and motor vehicle leases upon relocation; (3) DOJ issuance of civil investigative demands; and (4) vacating or setting aside judgments.

 The bill provides for the portability of professional licenses of service members and their spouses who are relocated under military orders.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
