<bill session="115" type="h" number="2115" updated="2019-04-18T16:07:13Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To encourage State, local and tribal jurisdictions to implement and enforce appropriate and time-sensitive procedures to notify the next-of-kin or designated person upon the death or life-threatening emergency of an individual who is in the custody of law enforcement.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Family Notification of Death in Custody or Life-Threatening Emergency Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Family Notification of Death in Custody or Life-Threatening Emergency Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wakiesha's Law</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wakiesha&#8217;s Law</title>
    <title type="display">Wakiesha's Law</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001270"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000588" joined="2017-04-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-24T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Family Notification of Death in Custody or Life-Threatening Emergency Act of 2017 or Wakiesha's Law

This bill requires federal, state, and local law enforcement agencies to obtain identifying information about an individual in custody and contact information for the individual's next of kin or designated emergency contact. It establishes minimum standards with respect to notifying the next of kin or designated emergency contact following an individual's death or life-threatening emergency while in custody.

The Department of Justice must reduce by 10% the allocation of funds under the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant program for a state or local government that fails to comply.

The bill also amends the Death in Custody Reporting Act of 2013 to require a state or federal law enforcement agency to include, in its quarterly report on deaths in custody, additional information such as the date and time that death notification was provided and the date and time of each unsuccessful notification attempt.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
