<bill session="113" type="s" number="333" updated="2016-10-25T16:20:57Z">
  <state datetime="2013-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Access to Birth Control Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish certain duties for pharmacies to ensure provision of Food and Drug Administration-approved contraception, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Access to Birth Control Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000123"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000243" joined="2013-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2013-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2013-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="identical" number="728"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2625"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-02-14T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Access to Birth Control Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require pharmacies to comply with certain rules related to contraceptives, including: (1) providing a customer a contraceptive without delay if it is in stock; (2) immediately informing a customer if the contraceptive is not in stock and either transferring the prescription to a pharmacy that has the contraceptive in stock or expediting the ordering of the contraceptive and notifying the customer when it arrives, based on customer preference, except for pharmacies that do not ordinarily stock contraceptives in the normal course of business; and (3) ensuring that pharmacy employees do not take certain actions relating to a request for contraception, including intimidating, threatening, or harassing customers, interfering with or obstructing the delivery of services, intentionally misrepresenting or deceiving customers about the availability of contraception or its mechanism of action, breaching or threatening to breach medical confidentiality, or refusing to return a valid, lawful prescription.

Provides that a pharmacy is not prohibited from refusing to provide a contraceptive to a customer if: (1) it is unlawful to dispense the contraceptive to the customer without a valid, lawful prescription and no such prescription is presented; (2) the customer is unable to pay for the contraceptive; or (3) the employee of the pharmacy refuses to provide the contraceptive on the basis of a professional clinical judgment.

Provides that this Act does not preempt state law or any professional obligation of a state board that provides greater protections for customers.

Sets forth civil penalties and establishes a a private cause of action for violations of this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
