<bill session="114" type="s" number="3379" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:38Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve surface transportation and maritime security.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Surface Transportation and Maritime Security Act</title>
    <title type="display">Surface Transportation and Maritime Security Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2016-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2016-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Surface Transportation and Maritime Security Act

This bill requires the Transportation Security Administration (TSA)&#160;to assess, and implement a risk-based strategy to address, threats posed to surface transportation and maritime systems. The TSA shall establish the Surface Transportation and Maritime Security Advisory Committee to develop recommendations for improvements to surface transportation and maritime security.

In addition, the bill:

 allows the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to expand the TSA's explosives-detection canine-team program; requires the Government Accountability Office to study specified matters related to surface transportation; expands the permissible uses of railroad security improvement grants; requires the TSA to issue a decision on the use of a passenger vetting system by the National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak); requires the TSA to establish processes to improve background checks and terrorism vetting; requires DHS to commission an assessment of&#160;its transportation security card program and, if applicable, develop a corrective action plan; with respect to&#160;transportation security card&#160;applications, establishes priority for members of the Armed Forces; requires DHS to evaluate cargo-container scanning technologies; and revises other provisions related to transportation security.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
