<bill session="115" type="h" number="4303" updated="2019-04-18T16:17:44Z">
  <state datetime="2017-11-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-11-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-11-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to prohibit funding under the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance grant program and the Public Safety and Community Policing grant program to be provided to law enforcement agencies that use license plate readers unless certain conditions are met.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reasonable Policies on Automated License Plate Readers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reasonable Policies on Automated License Plate Readers Act</title>
    <title type="display">Reasonable Policies on Automated License Plate Readers Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001037"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-11-08T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Reasonable Policies on Automated License Plate Readers Act

This bill amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to make ineligible for funds under the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program and the Public Safety and Community Policing Grant Program a state or local law enforcement agency that uses an automated license plate reader without developing written and binding policies to limit the storage and sharing of data collected by the reader.

Additionally, the bill generally prohibits a federal law enforcement agency from using an automated license plate reader without developing written and binding policies to limit the storage and sharing of data collected by the reader.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
