<bill session="114" type="h" number="455" updated="2019-02-12T18:22:41Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-28T18:10:57-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-10-28T18:10:57-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Northern Border Security Review Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Northern Border Security Review Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Northern Border Security Review Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to conduct a northern border threat analysis, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Northern Border Security Review Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001271" joined="2015-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001038" joined="2015-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2015-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001150" joined="2015-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000602" joined="2015-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-06-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-07-28">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 114-232.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-07-28" calendar="Union" number="175">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 175.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-10-28T17:57:34-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Katko moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-28T17:57:48-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7316-7319" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-28T17:57:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 455.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2015-10-28T18:10:57-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7316-7317" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-10-28T18:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-29">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Border Security, Facilitation, and Operations" code="HSHM11" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="399"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1808"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4482"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2976"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-28T12:04:27Z" status="Passed House amended">Northern Border Security Review Act

(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to submit a northern border threat analysis of:

 current and potential terrorism and criminal threats posed by individuals and organized groups seeking to enter the United States through the northern border or to exploit vulnerabilities along such border; improvements needed at and between ports of entry along the northern border to prevent terrorists and instruments of terror from entering the United States and to reduce criminal activity, as measured by the total flow of illegal goods, illicit drugs, and smuggled and trafficked persons moved across such border; gaps in law, policy, cooperation between state, local, and tribal law enforcement, international agreements, or tribal agreements that hinder effective and efficient border security, counterterrorism, anti-human smuggling and trafficking efforts, and the flow of legitimate trade along the northern border; and whether additional preclearance and pre-inspection operations by the U.S. Customs and Border Protection at ports of entry along the northern border could help prevent terrorists and instruments of terror from entering the United States. For such analysis, DHS must consider and examine:

 technology needs and challenges; personnel needs and challenges; the role of state, local, and tribal law enforcement in general border security activities; the need for cooperation among federal, state, local, tribal, and Canadian law enforcement entities relating to border security; and the terrain, population density, and climate along the northern border.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-232</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
