<bill session="114" type="hr" number="477" updated="2019-05-09T22:56:58Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Recommending the designation of a Presidential Special Envoy to the Balkans to evaluate the successes and shortcomings of the implementation of the Dayton Peace Accords in Bosnia and Herzegovina, to provide policy recommendations, and to report back to Congress within one year.</title>
    <title type="display">Recommending the designation of a Presidential Special Envoy to the Balkans to evaluate the successes and shortcomings of the implementation of the Dayton Peace Accords in Bosnia and Herzegovina, to provide policy recommendations, and to report back to Congress within one year.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001063"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1468"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Europe, Eurasia, and Emerging Threats.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Europe, Eurasia, Energy and the Environment" code="HSFA14" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Bosnia and Herzegovina"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-09T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Reiterates support for the sovereignty, territorial integrity, and legal continuity of Bosnia and Herzegovina (BiH) within its internationally recognized borders, as well as the equality of its three constituent peoples and others within an integrated multi-ethnic country.

Welcomes steps taken by the government of BiH towards integration into the Euro-Atlantic community.

Emphasizes that BiH, as well as its internal political entities, work toward the creation of an effective state, and that the national government of BiH, as well as the institutions of the entities, are able to instill necessary reforms to fulfill European Union (EU) and North Atlantic Treaty Organization membership requirements.

Stresses the importance of privatization of the publicly owned enterprises through transparent international tenders prepared in close cooperation with the EU and the Office of the High Representative.

Commends the focus of the United States in support of a stronger civil society in BiH.

Believes that it is important that the United States: (1) works closely with the EU in implementing an accession process specifically made for BiH, and (2) supports countries of the region in fulfilling their obligations aimed at ending the refugee and internal-displacement situation in Southeast Europe.

Reiterates that: (1) a fully functional Federation of BiH entity is essential for the future of BiH as a stable state and therefore any envisaged reform should take into account protection of the constitutional rights of all, including Bosnian Croats; (2) constitutional reform in BiH should take the Dayton Peace Accords as its basis and advance the principles of political, economic, legal, and religious equality and tolerance; and (3) the United States should designate a Presidential Special Envoy to the Balkans.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
