<amendment session="113" chamber="h" number="966" updated="2016-10-25T16:44:14Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4899" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2014-06-26T11:47:15-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001036"/>
  <offered datetime="2014-06-26"/>
  <description>In title I, at the end of subtitle F (page 51, after line 21) add the following:    SEC.___. NOTICE OF RECEIPT OF ANY APPLICATION FOR A PERMIT THAT WOULD ALLOW THE CONDUCT OF ANY OFFSHORE OIL AND GAS WELL STIMULATION ACTIVITIES.    The Secretary of the Interior shall notify all relevant State and local regulatory agencies and publish a notice in the Federal Register, within 30 days after receiving any application for a permit that would allow the conduct of any offshore oil and gas well stimulation activities.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment No. 5 printed in House Report 113-493 to require the Secretary of the Interior to notify all relevant state and local regulatory agencies and publish a notice in the Federal Register, within 30 days after receiving any application for a permit that would allow the conduct of any offshore oil and gas well stimulation activities.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2014-06-26T11:47:15-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="362">
      <text>On agreeing to the Capps amendment (A005) Failed by recorded vote: 183 - 227 (Roll no. 362).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26T09:52:07-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A005) offered by Mrs. Capps.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5788-5789, H5800-5801" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5788" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26"/>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26T09:52:07-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A005) offered by Mrs. Capps.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5788-5789, H5800-5801" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5788" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26T11:47:15-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Capps amendment (A005) Failed by recorded vote: 183 - 227 (Roll no. 362).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26T11:47:15-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26T11:47:15-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
