<bill session="115" type="s" number="2640" updated="2019-04-18T16:42:32Z">
  <state datetime="2018-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require operators that provide online and similar services to educational agencies, institutions, or programs to protect the privacy and security of personally identifiable information, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE KIDS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE KIDS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safeguarding American Families from Exposure by Keeping Information and Data Secure Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safeguarding American Families from Exposure by Keeping Information and Data Secure Act</title>
    <title type="display">SAFE KIDS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2018-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-04-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2042" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-04-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Safeguarding American Families from Exposure by Keeping Information and Data Secure Act or the SAFE KIDS Act

 This bill prohibits an operator of a school's website from using personally identifiable information or material it acquired because of use of the site in order to target advertising to students from early childhood education through secondary school, or their parents, based on information obtained or inferred from students' online behavior, use of online applications, or such personally identifiable information. The bill exempts online advertisements that are based on a current visit or are in response to a student's request for more information or feedback, provided that information about students' online behavior is not collected or retained over time for the purpose of targeting subsequent advertisements.

 The bill prohibits operators from: (1) selling students' personal information to third parties; or (2) collecting student information to create a personal profile or for purposes unrelated to educational instruction, school collaboration, or administrative activities.

 The bill requires operators to implement information security procedures. It directs operators to delete certain student information that is not included in a student's education records: (1) within a reasonable time&#160;after a request through an educational agency, institution, or program, or&#160;from the student's parent; or (2) once the data has outlived the legitimate purpose for which it was collected.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
