<bill session="115" type="s" number="2920" updated="2019-04-18T16:43:26Z">
  <state datetime="2018-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to impose certain requirements under the Medicare program with respect to outlier prescribers of opioids.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Commit to Opioid Medical Prescriber Accountability and Safety for Seniors Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Commit to Opioid Medical Prescriber Accountability and Safety for Seniors Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Commit to Opioid Medical Prescriber Accountability and Safety for Seniors Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2018-08-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000461" joined="2018-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="5716"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3120"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-05-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Commit to Opioid Medical Prescriber Accountability and Safety for Seniors Act of 2018

This bill requires the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) to identify outlier prescribers of opioids under the Medicare prescription drug benefit and Medicare Advantage prescription drug plans. Specifically, the CMS must: (1) establish an opioid-prescription threshold for determining whether a prescriber is an outlier compared to other prescribers, based on specialty and geographic area; (2) use National Provider Identifiers (unique provider identification numbers currently included on claims for covered drugs) to identify outlier prescribers; and (3) annually notify identified outlier prescribers of their status and provide them with resources on proper prescribing methods. The CMS may also identify and notify outlier prescribers based on co-prescriptions of covered drugs that have adverse effects when used in combination with opioids. Persistent outlier prescribers are subject to additional requirements.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
