<bill session="113" type="h" number="980" updated="2018-06-05T16:08:53Z">
  <state datetime="2013-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CARE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coal Accountability and Retired Employee Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect the health care and pension benefits of our nation's miners.</title>
    <title type="display">CARE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001227" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001286" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2013-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2013-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000292" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000368" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000725" joined="2013-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001162" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000480" joined="2013-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000266" joined="2013-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000132" joined="2013-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="identical" number="468"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2918"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-03-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Coal Accountability and Retired Employee Act of 2013 or CARE Act - Amends the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to transfer specified excess funds derived from coal mine operator-paid reclamation fees to the trustees of the 1974 United Mine Workers of America (UMWA) Pension Plan for use solely to pay pension benefits required under such Plan.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to revise 1992 UMWA Benefit Plan eligibility requirements.

Makes eligible for health benefits from the 1992 UMWA Benefit Plan an individual who would be eligible to receive benefits from the 1974 UMWA Benefit Plan (with a specified exception) following a bankruptcy or other insolvency proceeding of a coal mine operator, but who does not receive from that operator or any related person health benefits at least equal to those received under the Multiemployer Health Benefit Plan of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977.

Prescribes a special rule to state that employer contributions to an employees' trust or annuity benefit plan providing supplemental benefits solely to participants in a pension plan are neither deductible nor nondeductible as such from the employer's gross income. Subjects such contributions, on the other hand, to the requirements for deduction as an allowable trade or business expense.

Treats a trust holding the assets of such a pension benefit plan as a tax-exempt organization.

Excludes from wages any payments made to, or on behalf of, an employee or his or her beneficiary under such a plan.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
