<bill session="114" type="sc" number="49" updated="2019-06-21T11:07:13Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-07">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-09-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A concurrent resolution supporting efforts to stop the theft, illegal possession or sale, transfer, and export of tribal cultural items of Indians, Alaska Natives, and Native Hawaiians in the United States and internationally.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PROTECT Patrimony Resolution</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protection of the Right of Tribes to stop the Export of Cultural and Traditional Patrimony Resolution</title>
    <title type="display">PROTECT Patrimony Resolution</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000039"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2016-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5177-5178" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-09-07" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hc" session="114" relation="unknown" number="122"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protection of the Right of Tribes to stop the Export of Cultural and Traditional Patrimony Resolution or the PROTECT Patrimony Resolution

Condemns the theft, illegal possession or sale, transfer, and export of tribal cultural items. Calls upon: (1) the Departments of the Interior, State, Commerce, Homeland Security, and Justice to consult with Native Americans in addressing this issue, to take affirmative action to stop these practices, and to secure repatriation of tribal cultural items; and (2) the Government Accountability Office to determine the scope of illegal trafficking in tribal cultural items and identify steps required to end such trafficking.

Expresses support for restrictions on the export of tribal cultural items.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
