<bill session="114" type="h" number="3244" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:21Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Innovative Care for Complex Cases Demonstration Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish a pilot program to improve care for the most costly Medicare fee-for-service beneficiaries through the use of comprehensive and effective care management while reducing costs to the Federal Government for these beneficiaries, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Providing Innovative Care for Complex Cases Demonstration Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001159"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001287" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001069" joined="2016-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000376" joined="2015-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000188" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000557" joined="2015-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001181" joined="2016-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000585" joined="2015-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2016-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001180" joined="2015-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2016-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2498"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Providing Innovative Care for Complex Cases Demonstration Act of 2015

This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to establish a pilot program to demonstrate improvements in patient care and cost savings for the highest-cost Medicare fee-for-service (FFS) beneficiaries through enrollment of such beneficiaries with participating organizations. The program shall be designed to provide comprehensive and integrated care management and services through a network of health care providers to meet the specialized needs of such beneficiaries. The Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) must design the program in such a manner as to preserve the operation of the Medicare prescription drug benefit.

A participating organization must meet the same requirements that apply to a Medicare Advantage (MA) organization. CMS must develop quality performance standards and, using an integrated care model, care management requirements for participating organizations.

For each individual enrolled under the program, CMS shall make a monthly capitated payment to the participating organization as would be made for an individual enrolled in an MA plan (excluding MA prescription drug plans), except that the amount of payment shall: (1) equal 98% of the projected cost under the Medicare FFS program for the highest-cost Medicare FFS beneficiaries; and (2) be adjusted to account for differences in costs among different geographic areas and among high-cost Medicare FFS beneficiaries, including outlier costs.

CMS must report to Congress on the performance of the program within two years of initial enrollment.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
