<bill session="113" type="h" number="5887" updated="2016-10-25T16:17:55Z">
  <state datetime="2014-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To repeal the provisions of the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2015, which amended the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to establish separate contribution limits for contributions made to national parties to support Presidential nominating conventions, national party headquarters buildings, and recounts.</title>
    <title type="display">To repeal the provisions of the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2015, which amended the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to establish separate contribution limits for contributions made to national parties to support Presidential nominating conventions, national party headquarters buildings, and recounts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000381"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-12-16T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971, as amended by the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2015, to repeal certain limits on separate contributions by persons or multicandidate political committees to political committees of a national political party which are not the authorized political committees of any candidate. Specifies those contributions used to defray expenses for:

 a presidential nominating convention; the construction, purchase, renovation, operation, and furnishing of party headquarters buildings; and the preparation for and the conduct of election recounts, contests, and other legal proceedings.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
