<bill session="114" type="s" number="2146" updated="2018-06-02T07:10:50Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-20">PROV_KILL:CLOTUREFAILED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-10-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Sanctuary Policies and Protect Americans Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to hold sanctuary jurisdictions accountable for defying Federal law, to increase penalties for individuals who illegally reenter the United States after being removed, and to provide liability protection for State and local law enforcement who cooperate with Federal law enforcement and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Stop Sanctuary Policies and Protect Americans Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2015-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2015-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2015-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2015-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2015-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2015-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2015-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2015-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2015-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2015-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2015-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2015-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2015-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2015-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000461" joined="2015-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2015-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-06">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-10-07" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="252">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 252.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7249" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7249" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed to the measure presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7249" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7249" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-19">
      <text>Motion to proceed to measure considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7290-7302" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-20">
      <text>Motion to proceed to measure considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7314-7323, S7323-7332" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote-aux how="roll" type="cloture" roll="280" datetime="2015-10-20" where="s" result="fail" state="PROV_KILL:CLOTUREFAILED">
      <text>Cloture on the motion to proceed to the measure not invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 54 - 45. Record Vote Number: 280.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7323" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7323" label="text"/>
    </vote-aux>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2193"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3100"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stop Sanctuary Policies and Protect Americans Act

This bill prohibits a sanctuary jurisdiction from receiving grants under the State Criminal Alien Assistance Program, the Community Oriented Policing Services Program, and the Community Development Block Grant Program. A sanctuary jurisdiction is a state or political subdivision that has a policy or practice in effect that: (1) prohibits or restricts information sharing about an individual's immigration status, or (2) prohibits compliance with a lawfully issued detainer request or notification of release request.

The Department of Justice (DOJ) must terminate grant funding 30 days after DOJ and the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) determine, notify, and publish the states and political subdivisions that are sanctuary jurisdictions.

A state or political subdivision that complies with a detainer is deemed to be an agent of DHS. The bill authorizes such agent to take actions to comply with the detainer. It also limits the liability of such agent if the actions taken complied with the detainer.

The bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to increase from two years to five years the maximum prison term for an alien who reenters after being denied admission, excluded, deported, or removed.

It establishes a 10-year maximum prison term for an alien who reenters after being denied admission, excluded, deported, or removed on 3 or more prior occasions.

It establishes a five-year mandatory minimum prison term for an alien who reenters after being removed following a conviction for an aggravated felony or following two or more prior convictions for illegal reentry.&#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
