<bill session="114" type="hc" number="181" updated="2018-06-02T01:15:45Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-10">PASSED:CONCURRENTRES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-12-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Directing the Secretary of the Senate to make a certain correction in the enrollment of S. 1635.</title>
    <title type="display">Directing the Secretary of the Senate to make a certain correction in the enrollment of S. 1635.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000435"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-12-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-07T17:28:55-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Ros-Lehtinen asked unanimous consent to consider as introduced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-07T17:28:55-05:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7327-7328" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="without objection" type="vote" datetime="2016-12-07T17:29:37-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7327-7328" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-12-07T17:29:38-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2016-12-10" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:CONCURRENTRES">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7128" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-12-12">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="procedurally-related" number="1635"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-10T21:31:52Z" status="Passed Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Directs the Secretary of the Senate to make corrections in the enrollment of S. 1635 to:

 authorize the Department of State to transfer certain FY2018 appropriations if necessary to implement the recommendations of the Benghazi Accountability Review Board or to prevent or respond to security situations and requirements; eliminate provisions limiting the amount of such transferred funds to 20% of any appropriation made available for FY2018 for the State Department under the heading "Administration of Foreign Affairs" and limiting to 10% the amount by which such a transfer may increase such appropriation; and modify the requirement that the President direct the U.S. Permanent Representative to the United Nations to call for an examination of the feasibility of establishing a stand-alone U.N. agency to investigate allegations of misconduct or criminal behavior to provide for that agency to replace the offices of inspectors general of relevant U.N. agencies (instead of the Office of Inspector General of the Department of State and the Broadcasting Board of Governors).</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
