<bill session="114" type="h" number="3298" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:19Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Post-Acute Care Value-Based Purchasing Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for value-based purchasing of post-acute care services under the Medicare program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Medicare Post-Acute Care Value-Based Purchasing Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000755"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000188" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000387" joined="2015-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-08-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Medicare Post-Acute Care Value-Based Purchasing Act of 2015

This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to: (1) modify market basket percentages for post-acute care (PAC) providers, and (2) establish a PAC value-based purchasing program under which PAC providers receive value-based incentive payments. PAC providers are skilled nursing facilities, inpatient rehabilitation facilities, home health agencies, and long-term care hospitals.

A market basket is an index that reflects inflation and is used to update payments and cost limits. Under current law, market basket percentage increases for PAC providers are generally based on the application of a formula based on costs from the preceding fiscal year, but for FY2018 these increases are fixed at 1%. The bill repeals these fixed increases, leaving FY2018 increases to instead be determined according to the existing formula.

With respect to the PAC value-based purchasing program, the bill: (1) requires the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid (CMS) to establish performance standards and scores by which to rank PAC providers; (2) specifies how CMS must calculate value-based incentive payments for each type of PAC provider in accordance with such ranking; (3) requires CMS to make specified annual adjustments to how incentive payments are calculated; and (4) establishes limits on administrative and judicial review.

Under current law, a value-based purchasing program for skilled nursing facilities has been established to begin in FY2019. The bill maintains this program but specifies that it must terminate in FY2025.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
