<amendment session="113" chamber="h" number="340" updated="2016-10-25T12:36:56Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2013-07-19T09:29:51-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000451"/>
  <offered datetime="2013-07-19"/>
  <description>Amendment blocks State or local education agencies from being eligible for funds should they facilitate the transfer of an employee if they know, or have probable cause to believe, that the employee has engaged in sexual misconduct with a minor. Agencies must also require employees be subjected to background checks in compliance with the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 23 printed in House Report 113-158 to provide a funding condition for a state or local educational agency to be eligible for funds, agency personnel cannot facilitate the transfer of an employee if they know, or have probable cause to believe, that the employee has engaged in sexual misconduct with a minor. Agencies must also require employees be subjected to background checks in compliance with the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2013-07-19T09:29:51-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Fitzpatrick amendment (A023) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-07-19T09:23:49-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A023) offered by Mr. Fitzpatrick.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4732-4734" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4732-4733" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-19"/>
    <action datetime="2013-07-19T09:29:51-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Fitzpatrick amendment (A023) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-19T09:29:51-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-19T09:23:49-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A023) offered by Mr. Fitzpatrick.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4732-4734" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4732-4733" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-19">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
