<bill session="115" type="hr" number="599" updated="2019-04-18T15:54:37Z">
  <state datetime="2017-11-13T18:59:06-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-11-13T18:59:06-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-11-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives with respect to United States policy towards Yemen, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives with respect to United States policy towards Yemen, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000389"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2017-11-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-11-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-01T13:55:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF BUSINESS - Mr. Newhouse asked unanimous consent that it be in order at any time to consider in the House, H.Res. 599; that the resolution be considered as read; that the previous question be considered as ordered on the resolution and the preamble to adoption without intervening motion or demand for division of the question except for one hour of debate; and that notwithstanding any previous order of the House, the provisions of section 7 of the War Powers Resolution (50 U.S.C. 1546) shall not apply to H.Con.Res. 81. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-13T16:53:09-05:00">
      <text>Consideration initiated pursuant to a previous order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-13T16:53:11-05:00">
      <text>Considered pursuant to a previous order.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9148-9155" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-13T16:53:35-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order, the House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.Res. 599.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-13T17:53:44-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to a previous  order of the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-13T17:54:24-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 599, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the resolution and by voice vote, announced that the ayes prevailed. Mr. Royce demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed the question agreeing to the resolution until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-13T18:31:38-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9155-9156" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="623" datetime="2017-11-13T18:59:06-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 366 - 30, 1 Present (Roll no. 623).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9148" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-11-13T18:59:07-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Saudi Arabia"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Yemen"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-11-13T16:13:26Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Expresses the urgent need for a political solution in Yemen consistent with United Nations Security Council Resolution 2216 or as otherwise agreed to by the parties.

 Denounces the conduct of activities in Yemen and areas affected by the conflict that are inconsistent with the laws of armed conflict, including the deliberate targeting of civilian populations or the use of civilian human shields.

Calls on all parties to the conflict to: (1) increase efforts to prevent civilian casualties and increase humanitarian access; and (2) allow for unobstructed access for humanitarian organizations, human rights investigators, medical relief personnel, and journalists.

 Supports the Saudi-led Arab Coalition's commitments to abide by their no-strike and restricted target list and improve their targeting capabilities.

 Condemns Iranian activities in Yemen in violation in such resolution and calls on all responsible countries to take necessary measures against Iran, including the interdiction of Iranian weapons to the Houthi rebels and the application of sanctions against Iran.

 Encourages other governments to join in providing the resources necessary to address the humanitarian crisis.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
