<bill session="114" type="s" number="3090" updated="2019-07-20T13:42:03Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish a demonstration program to provide integrated care for Medicare beneficiaries with end-stage renal disease, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Dialysis PATIENT Demonstration Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Patient Access To Integrated-care, Empowerment, Nephrologists and Treatment Demonstration Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="display">Patient Access To Integrated-care, Empowerment, Nephrologists and Treatment Demonstration Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2016-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2016-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2016-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="5506"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5942"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Organ and tissue donation and transplantation"/>
    <term name="Surgery and anesthesia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Dialysis PATIENT Demonstration Act of 2016 or the Patient Access to Integrated-care, Empowerment, Nephrologists and Treatment Demonstration Act of 2016

This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to establish a demonstration program for the provision of integrated care to Medicare beneficiaries with end-stage renal disease (ESRD).

Under the voluntary program, eligible participating providers may form organizations to&#160;offer&#160;ESRD integrated care models&#160;and serve as medical homes for program-eligible beneficiaries. Such a model: (1)&#160;shall cover medical and hospital services, other than hospice care, under Medicare; (2)&#160;must include benefits for transition into palliative care; and (3) may cover prescription drug benefits. An organization must offer at least one open network model but may also offer one or more preferred network models.

An organization shall return savings achieved under the models to program-eligible beneficiaries.

A beneficiary shall have the opportunity to: (1) opt out of the program, (2) make an assignment change into an open network model offered by a different organization, or (3) elect a preferred network model.

The bill establishes requirements regarding: (1) benefits for program-eligible beneficiaries who are also eligible for Medicaid benefits, (2) program quality and reporting, (2) ESRD integrated care strategy, (3) program operation and scope, (4) beneficiary notification, and (5) payment.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
