<bill session="114" type="h" number="2071" updated="2018-06-02T03:37:17Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Streets Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure the safety of all users of the transportation system, including pedestrians, bicyclists, transit users, children, older individuals, and individuals with disabilities, as they travel on and across federally funded streets and highways.</title>
    <title type="display">Safe Streets Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001163"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001284" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2015-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001106" joined="2015-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001107" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000619" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000293" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000372" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000564" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000057" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000292" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000295" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000287" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000554" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2015-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2015-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000585" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000129" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2015-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Highways and Transit" code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Access Board"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Safe Streets Act of 2015

 Requires each state to have in effect within two years a law, or each state department of transportation and metropolitan planning organization (MPO) an explicit policy statement, that requires all federally-funded transportation projects, with certain exceptions, to accommodate the safety and convenience of all users in accordance with certain complete streets principles.

Defines "complete streets principles" as federal, state, local, or regional level transportation laws, policies, or principles which ensure that the safety and convenience of all users of a transportation system, including pedestrians, bicyclists, public transit users, children, older individuals, motorists, freight vehicles, and individuals with disabilities, are accommodated in all phases of project planning and development.

Allows such law or policy to make project-specific exemptions from such principles only if: (1) affected roadways prohibit specified users by law from using them, the cost of a compliance project would be excessively disproportionate to the need, or the population, employment densities, traffic volumes, or level of transit service around a roadway is so low that the expected roadway users will not include pedestrians, public transportation, freight vehicles, or bicyclists; and (2) all such exemptions are properly approved.

Requires the Secretary of Transportation to establish a method for evaluating compliance by state departments of transportation and MPOs with complete streets principles.

Requires the Access Board to issue final standards for accessibility of new construction and alterations of pedestrian facilities for public rights-of-way.

Requires the Secretary to conduct research regarding complete streets to: (1) assist states, MPOs, and local jurisdictions in developing and implementing complete streets-compliant plans, projects, procedures, policies, and training programs; and (2) establish benchmarks for, and provide technical guidance on, implementing complete streets policies and principles.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
