<bill session="114" type="s" number="2300" updated="2018-06-02T07:12:03Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American SAFE Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Security Against Foreign Enemies Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require that supplemental certifications and background investigations be completed prior to the admission of certain aliens as refugees, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">American Security Against Foreign Enemies Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000293"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4038"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3999"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6071"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-18T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">American Security Against Foreign Enemies Act of 2015 or the American SAFE Act of 2015

This bill requires that, in addition to the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) screening, the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) shall take all actions necessary to ensure that each covered alien receives a background investigation before U.S. refugee admission.

A "covered alien" is any alien applying for U.S. refugee admission who:

 is a national or resident of Iraq or Syria, has no nationality and whose last habitual residence was in Iraq or Syria, or has been present in Iraq or Syria at any time on or after March 1, 2011. A covered alien:

 may not be admitted as a refugee until the FBI certifies to DHS and the Director of National Intelligence (DNI) that he or she has received a background investigation sufficient to determine whether the alien is a U.S. security threat; and may only be admitted to the United States after DHS, with the unanimous concurrence of the FBI and the DNI, certifies to Congress that he or she is not such a threat. The Inspector General of DHS shall conduct annual risk-based reviews of all certifications.

DHS shall report monthly to Congress on the total number of admission applications for which a certification was made and the number of covered aliens for whom such a certification was not made for the preceding month. The report shall include for each covered alien for whom a certification was not made the concurrence or nonconcurrence of each person whose concurrence was required by the certification.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
