<bill session="114" type="s" number="2944" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:50Z">
  <state datetime="2016-11-29">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-11-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Safety Officers' Benefits Improvement Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Public Safety Officers' Benefits Improvement Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Public Safety Officers' Benefits Improvement Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require adequate reporting on the Public Safety Officers' Benefit program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by senate">A bill to require adequate reporting on the Public Safety Officers' Benefits program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Public Safety Officers' Benefits Improvement Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2016-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2016-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2016-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2016-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2016-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2016-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2976-2977" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-06-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-06-09">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Grassley with amendments. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-06-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="513">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 513.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-11-29">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6571-6573" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6571-6572" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-29">
      <text>The committee amendments withdrawn by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6573" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2016-11-29" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-11-30">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-30T12:02:17-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5743"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s5114"/>
    <amendment number="s5113"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2016-11-29T14:56:32Z" status="Passed Senate amended">Public Safety Officers' Benefits Improvement Act of 2016

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to revise requirements for the Public Safety Officers' Benefits (PSOB) program. (The PSOB program provides death, disability, and education benefits to public safety officers and survivors of public safety officers who are killed or injured in the line of duty.)

It authorizes the Department of Justice's Bureau of Justice Assistance (BJA) to establish PSOB program rules, regulations, and procedures based on standards developed by another federal agency.

In determining a claimant's eligibility for death or disability benefits, the BJA must give substantial weight to evidence and facts presented by a state, local, or federal agency.

The BJA must also publish and update information on pending claims and report to Congress on submitted claims for death, disability, and educational benefits.

(Sec. 3) This section extends the age limitation for a PSOB claim for death, disability, or education benefits that is approved more than one year after the date on which it was filed.

(Sec. 4) The BJA must attempt to obtain necessary documentation to determine a claimant's eligibility for death, disability, or education benefits. If it cannot determine eligibility due to a lack of documentation from a third party (e.g., a public agency), then the BJA may abandon the claim only after it utilizes investigative tools, including subpoenas, to obtain the information.

(Sec. 5) The bill establishes a rebuttable presumption that a public safety officer acted properly at the time of injury or death and that no specified limitation (e.g., voluntary intoxication at the time of injury or death) bars the payment of death or disability benefits. The BJA may rebut the presumption by clear and convincing evidence to the contrary.

(Sec. 6) This bill's provisions apply to a claim that is pending on or submitted on or after enactment.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
