<bill session="113" type="s" number="2667" updated="2016-10-25T16:31:43Z">
  <state datetime="2014-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Iranian Sanctions Relief Certification Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the exercise of any waiver of the imposition of certain sanctions with respect to Iran unless the President certifies to Congress that the waiver will not result in the provision of funds to the Government of Iran for activities in support of international terrorism, to develop nuclear weapons, or to violate the human rights of the people of Iran.</title>
    <title type="display">Iranian Sanctions Relief Certification Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000360"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2014-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000291" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000461" joined="2014-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-07-24T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Iranian Sanctions Relief Certification Act of 2014 - Prohibits the President from exercising a waiver specified under this Act in connection with the extension of the terms of the Joint Plan of Action beyond July 20, 2014, unless the President certifies to Congress before the waiver takes effect and every 60 days thereafter that any funds made available to the government of Iran as a result of the waiver will not facilitate Iran's ability to:

 support any individual or entity designated for the imposition of sanctions for international terrorism, any foreign terrorist organization, including Hamas, Hezbollah, Palestinian Islamic Jihad, and the regime of Bashar al-Assad in Syria; advance the efforts of Iran or any other country to develop nuclear weapons or ballistic missiles; or commit any violation of the human rights of the people of Iran. (Defines the Joint Plan of Action as the Joint Plan of Action signed on November 24, 2013, by Iran and by France, Germany, the Russian Federation, China, the United Kingdom, and the United States.)</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
