<bill session="114" type="h" number="818" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:00Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing and Reducing Improper Medicare and Medicaid Expenditures Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PRIME Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act to curb waste, fraud, and abuse in the Medicare and Medicaid programs.</title>
    <title type="display">PRIME Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000580"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000369" joined="2015-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001287" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001293" joined="2015-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001273" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001294" joined="2015-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001255" joined="2015-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001284" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001286" joined="2015-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001083" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000754" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001106" joined="2015-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001107" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000619" joined="2015-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000620" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2015-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001051" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001055" joined="2015-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001047" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001059" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000295" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000188" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000368" joined="2015-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000563" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000554" joined="2015-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000565" joined="2015-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2015-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001190" joined="2015-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000168" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000594" joined="2015-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000593" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000585" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000586" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000587" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000583" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000435" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000593" joined="2015-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000487" joined="2015-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001148" joined="2015-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001165" joined="2015-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001175" joined="2015-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2015-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000806" joined="2015-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000809" joined="2015-02-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="861"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3718"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-09T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Preventing and Reducing Improper Medicare and Medicaid Expenditures Act of 2015 or the PRIME Act of 2015

Amends part D (Prescription Drug Benefits) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSAct) to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to prohibit sponsors of prescription drug plans from paying claims for prescription drugs that do not include the valid National Provider Identifier for the drug's prescriber.

Requires the Secretary's annual report to Congress on the use of recovery audit contractors under the Medicare Integrity Program to: (1) describe the types and financial cost of improper payment vulnerabilities identified by recovery audit contractors and how the Secretary is addressing them, and (2) assess the effectiveness of changes made to Medicare payment policies and procedures in order to address those vulnerabilities.

Requires the Secretary to address improper payment vulnerabilities in a timely manner, prioritized based on the risk to the Medicare program.

Authorizes the Secretary, under recovery audit contracts under both Medicare and Medicaid (SSAct title XIX), to retain a certain portion of the recovered amounts for a program management account for activities addressing problems that contribute to improper payments and fraud.

Requires the Secretary, under such contracts, to retain an additional 5% of the recovered amounts to be made available to the HHS Inspector General to investigate improper payments or audit internal controls associated with Medicare or Medicaid payments.

Directs the Secretary to develop a plan to revise the incentive program under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 for the reporting of fraud and abuse to encourage greater participation by individuals reporting Medicare fraud and abuse. Requires the plan to include certain recommendations for: (1) ways to enhance rewards for individuals reporting, and (2) extension of the incentive program to the Medicaid program.

Amends SSAct title XIX to cover the costs of equipment, salaries and benefits, and travel and training in appropriations for the Medicaid Integrity Program. Allows the Secretary to increase Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS) staff whose duties consist solely of protecting the integrity of the Medicare program by a number determined necessary to carry out the Program (currently, by 100).

Directs the Secretary to provide incentives for Medicare administrative contractors to reduce the improper payment error rates in their jurisdictions.

Requires imprisonment for up to 10 years or a fine of up to $500,000 ($1 million in the case of a corporation), or both, for knowingly, intentionally, and with the intent to defraud purchasing, selling, distributing, or arranging for the purchase, sale, or distribution of a Medicare, Medicaid, or CHIP beneficiary identification number or billing privileges under SSAct titles XVIII, title XIX, or title XXI (Children's Health Insurance Program) (CHIP).

Amends SSAct title IV part D (Child Support and Establishment of Paternity) with respect to the Federal Parent Locator Service to give the CMS Administrator access to information in the National Directory of New Hires to determine the eligibility of an applicant for, or enrollee in, the Medicare program or an applicable state health subsidy program under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA).

Requires the Secretary to disclose to the HHS Inspector General information on individuals and their employers in the National Directory of New Hires if the HHS Inspector General gives the Secretary their names and Social Security account numbers. Restricts the use of such information to: (1) determining the eligibility of an applicant for, or enrollee in, the Medicare program or an applicable state health subsidy program; or (2) evaluating the integrity of such programs. Sets forth rules for the use and disclosure of such information by state agencies.

Directs the Secretary to establish a plan to encourage and facilitate the participation of states in the Medicare-Medicaid Data Match Program (Medi-Medi Program). Revises Medi-Medi Data Match Program purposes.

Amends SSAct title XIX, as amended by PPACA, and SSAct XXI with respect to claims processing and detection of fraud within the Medicaid and CHIP programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
