<bill session="114" type="s" number="1921" updated="2018-06-02T06:58:53Z">
  <state datetime="2015-08-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-08-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-08-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Vaccinate America's Children through Complete Information &amp; Education Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to encourage States to adopt administrative procedures with respect to nonmedical exemptions for State immunization requirements.</title>
    <title type="display">Vaccinate America's Children through Complete Information &amp; Education Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001169"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-08-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-08-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-08-04T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Vaccinate America's Children through Complete Information &amp; Education Act of 2015

This bill amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to require a state to certify that it has established, in its pediatric vaccine distribution program, administrative procedures regarding nonmedical exemptions from state immunization requirements.

These procedures must include at least two of the following prerequisites for granting a nonmedical exemption:

 the child's parent or guardian shall discuss the consequences of nonvaccination with the child's primary care provider, as noted in the child's medical record; the child's parent or guardian shall read, sign, and submit to the state a form discussing the risks of nonvaccination; the child's parent of guardian shall submit to the state a notarized letter describing why the exemption is being sought; or all medical exemptions shall be granted for only a one-year period and shall be required to be renewed annually only if the child's parent or guardian wants the exemption to continue for another year. A state that does not comply with these requirements is subject to a monetary penalty.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
