<bill session="114" type="s" number="1018" updated="2018-06-02T06:45:37Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SWAT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Swatting Won't be Accepted or Tolerated Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase the penalty for fraudulent 9-1-1 calls that result in an emergency response from law enforcement agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SWAT Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000148"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Swatting Won't be Accepted or Tolerated Act of 2015 or the SWAT Act

Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) impose a term of imprisonment of up to eight years for making a false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or representation to a federal law enforcement agency that causes an emergency federal law enforcement response; and (2) require the court to order a defendant convicted of such an offense to reimburse any federal, state, or local government for up to $10,000 in expenses incurred in responding to that conduct.

Extends the requirement that a court order a person convicted of conveying false or misleading information indicating that conduct involving specified criminal violations has taken, is taking, or will take place (including violations regarding biological and chemical weapons, firearms, sabotage of nuclear facilities, importation of explosive materials, terrorism, and damaging or destroying pipeline facilities) to reimburse state and local governments and not-for-profit organizations for expenses incident to fire and rescue service provided in any emergency or investigative response to such conduct to also require reimbursement of law enforcement service and any such services provided by the federal government.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
