<bill session="114" type="s" number="1167" updated="2019-03-03T14:40:56Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modify the boundaries of the Pole Creek Wilderness, the Owyhee River Wilderness, and the North Fork Owyhee Wilderness and to authorize the continued use of motorized vehicles for livestock monitoring, herding, and grazing in certain wilderness areas in the State of Idaho.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Owyhee Wilderness Areas Boundary Modifications Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Owyhee Wilderness Areas Boundary Modifications Act</title>
    <title type="display">Owyhee Wilderness Areas Boundary Modifications Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000880"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2015-04-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 114-500.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-09-06">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski with an amendment. With written report No. 114-315.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-09-06" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="588">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 588.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="2171"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-06T15:08:32Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Owyhee Wilderness Areas Boundary Modifications Act 

(Sec. 2) This bill adjusts the boundaries of the North Fork Owyhee Wilderness, the Owyhee River Wilderness, and the Pole Creek Wilderness in Idaho to exclude certain land.

(Sec. 3) The holder of a grazing permit within the Pole Creek Wilderness and the Owyhee River Wilderness shall be allowed continued limited motorized use in those wilderness areas to support livestock operations if:

 the use occurred before the designation of the wilderness areas; and the Department of the Interior, as part of the minimum requirements analysis required by this bill, has authorized the permittee to conduct limited motorized use within the wilderness areas. Interior shall conduct a minimum requirements analysis for motorized use within those wilderness areas as part of the renewal process for the affected grazing permit.

As part of such analysis, Interior shall analyze the impacts of limited motorized use for livestock operations on vegetation, wildlife, and cultural resources within those wilderness areas.

Until the minimum requirements analysis is completed, Interior shall permit limited motorized use for livestock operations in those wilderness areas at not more than the level authorized.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-315</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
