<bill session="114" type="s" number="1021" updated="2019-03-03T14:40:26Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to award grants to establish, or expand upon, master's degree programs in orthotics and prosthetics, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wounded Warrior Workforce Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="display">Wounded Warrior Workforce Enhancement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2015-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2015-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2302-2303" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1904"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Allied health services"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Wounded Warrior Workforce Enhancement Act

Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to award grants to eligible institutions to: (1) establish a master's degree program in orthotics and prosthetics, or (2) expand upon an existing master's degree program in such area. Requires a grant priority for institutions in partnership with a medical center administered by the VA or a facility administered by the Department of Defense. Provides grant amounts of at least $1 million and up to $1.5 million. Defines as eligible institutions those either accredited by the National Commission on Orthotic and Prosthetic Education or demonstrating an ability to meet such accreditation requirements if receiving a grant.

Requires the Secretary to award a grant to an institution with orthotic and prosthetic research and education experience to: (1) establish the Center of Excellence in Orthotic and Prosthetic Education; and (2) improve orthotic and prosthetic outcomes for veterans, members of the Armed Forces, and civilians by conducting orthotic and prosthetic-based research.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
