<bill session="114" type="s" number="2508" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:39Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-27">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reduce sports-related concussions in youth, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Youth Sports Concussion Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Youth Sports Concussion Act</title>
    <title type="display">Youth Sports Concussion Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000039"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2016-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2016-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-12-06">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Thune without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-12-06" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="701">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 701.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="4460"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-06T14:19:13Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Youth Sports Concussion Act

 (Sec. 2) This bill expresses the sense of Congress that the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) and the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) should review the National Academies' report on sports-related concussions and future research in such area for any matter that may impact products under the CPSC's jurisdiction or inform the FTC's efforts to protect consumers.

(Sec. 3) The bill makes it unlawful to sell or offer for sale in interstate commerce, or import into the United States for such purposes, athletic sporting equipment for which the seller or importer makes any deceptive claim with respect to the safety benefits of such item.

Violations shall be treated as unfair or deceptive acts or practices under the Federal Trade Commission Act. The bill sets forth the enforcement authority of the FTC.

States may bring civil actions in federal court to obtain injunctive relief on behalf of state residents unless a civil or administrative action has already been instituted by the FTC. The FTC may intervene and appeal in state actions.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
