<bill session="114" type="h" number="4580" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:36Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Terrorist Release Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of State to submit an unclassified notice before the transfer of any individual detained at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, to the custody or control of the individual's country of origin, any other foreign country, or any other foreign entity, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Terrorist Release Transparency Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000487"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2589"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-23T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Terrorist Release Transparency Act

This bill expresses the sense of Congress that the people of the United States: (1) deserve to know who is being released from the detention facilities at U.S. Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, their countries of origin, their destinations, and the ability of the host nation to prevent recidivism; and (2) deserve transparency in the manner in which the Obama Administration complies with Executive Order 13492.

Not less than 15 days before a detained individual's transfer to the custody or control of the individual's country of origin, any other foreign country, or any other foreign entity, the Department of State shall submit to Congress an unclassified notice that includes:

 the name, country of origin, and country of destination of the individual; the number of individuals detained at Guantanamo previously transferred to the country to which the individual is proposed to be transferred; and the number of such individuals who have re-engaged in terrorist activity after being transferred to that country.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
