<bill session="114" type="h" number="1322" updated="2018-06-02T02:35:38Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Hiding Congressional Farm Subsidies Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Crop Insurance Act to require the public disclosure of crop insurance premium subsidies made on behalf of Members of Congress and their immediate families, Cabinet Secretaries and their immediate families, and entities of which any such individual or combination of such individuals is a majority shareholder, and to require the public disclosure of the underwriting gains earned by private insurance providers and the business expenses covered by the Federal Government.</title>
    <title type="display">Stop Hiding Congressional Farm Subsidies Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2015-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2015-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2015-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000188" joined="2015-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000480" joined="2015-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities and Risk Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="General Farm Commodities and Risk Management" code="HSAG16" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural insurance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-04T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop Hiding Congressional Farm Subsidies Act 

This bill amends the Federal Crop Insurance Act to require the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to publicly disclose crop insurance premium subsidies paid on behalf of Members of Congress and their immediate families, Cabinet Secretaries and their immediate families, or entities of which any of these individuals is a majority shareholder.

 USDA must publicly disclose for private insurance providers: (1) underwriting gains earned through participation in the federal crop insurance program; and (2) amounts paid for administrative and operating expenses, any federal portion of indemnities and reinsurance, and any other purpose.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
