<bill session="114" type="s" number="1839" updated="2018-06-02T06:58:09Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Servicemembers Self-Defense Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend titles 10 and 18, to permit members of the Armed Forces to possess firearms on military installations in accordance with applicable State law, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Servicemembers Self-Defense Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000603"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2359"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Servicemembers Self-Defense Act of 2015

This bill excludes lands and buildings owned or leased by the Department of Defense (DOD) from the the ban against possession of firearms and dangerous weapons on federal facilities with respect to a qualified member of the Armed Forces.

The possession of a concealed or open-carry firearm by a member of the Armed Forces on a military installation, if lawful under the laws of the state in which the installation is located, is not a violation of the Uniform Code of Military Justice.

DOD shall amend DOD Directive number 5210.56 to allow members of the Armed Forces to possess firearms for defensive purposes on DOD facilities and installations in a manner consistent with the laws of the state in which the facility or installation is located.

A qualified member of the Armed Forces carrying DOD-issued photographic identification may carry a concealed firearm that has been shipped or transported in interstate or foreign commerce. Such authorization shall not be construed to supersede or limit the laws of any state that: (1) permit private persons or entities to prohibit or restrict the possession of concealed firearms on their property; or (2) prohibit or restrict the possession of firearms on any state or local government property, installation, building, base, or park.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
