<bill session="114" type="s" number="2773" updated="2018-06-02T07:16:28Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GAP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gender Advancement in Pay Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to provide more effective remedies to victims of discrimination in the payment of wages on the basis of sex, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">GAP Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000368"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2016-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2016-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2016-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2016-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2016-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2016-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5237"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2070"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Gender Advancement in Pay Act or the GAP Act

This bill amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to expand exceptions to the prohibition against sex discrimination to include payments pursuant to a differential based on expertise, shift, or a business-related factor other than sex, including but not limited to education, training, or experience.

The statute of limitations under the Portal-to-Portal Act of 1947 for a charge of prohibited sex discrimination, or an action by or on behalf of an employee for such discrimination, shall be tolled until the earlier of: (1) the date on which the Equal Employment Commission or the Department of Justice brings an action or notifies the employee concerned with respect to the charge under the Civil Rights Act of 1964, or (2) 270 days after the charge is filed.

Nonretaliation prohibitions are extended to cover inquiring about, discussing, or disclosing the wages of an employee or of another employee, or declining to discuss or disclose the employee's wages, with specified exceptions. An employer shall be considered to have committed an unlawful act if the employer requires an employee to sign a contract or waiver that would prohibit the employee from disclosing information about the employee's wages.

Civil penalties are established for violation of prohibitions against sex discrimination.

The Department of Labor, together with the Department of Education, shall conduct a multistate study, through a grant to a nonprofit research institution, that includes strategies to increase the participation of women in high-wage, high-demand occupations and industries in which women are underrepresented.

The Government Accountability Office shall also conduct a multistate study to develop such strategies.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
