<bill session="114" type="s" number="2240" updated="2019-03-03T14:41:02Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the control and management of invasive species that threaten and harm Federal land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Land Invasive Species Control, Prevention, and Management Act</title>
    <title type="display">Federal Land Invasive Species Control, Prevention, and Management Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2015-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2015-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2015-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2015-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2015-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2015-11-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-28">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 114-501.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1485"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-04T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Federal Land Invasive Species Control, Prevention, and Management Act

Directs the Department of the Interior (respecting federal land administered through the Bureau of Indian Affairs, Bureau of Land Management, Bureau of Reclamation, National Park Service, or U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service) and the Department of Agriculture (USDA) (respecting federal land administered through the U.S. Forest Service) to plan and carry out activities on land directly managed by the department concerned to control and manage invasive species in order to inhibit or reduce their populations and to effectuate restoration or reclamation efforts.

Requires the department concerned to develop a strategic plan for the implementation of an invasive species program that endeavors to achieve an annual 5% net reduction of invasive species populations on land managed by that department.

Requires each strategic plan to be developed: (1) in coordination with eligible states, their political subdivisions, and federally recognized Indian tribes; and (2) according to the priorities established by at least one governor of an eligible state in which an ecosystem affected by an invasive species is located.

Requires the USDA and Interior to prioritize the use of the least costly option necessary to perform effectively, based on sound scientific data and other commonly used cost-effective benchmarks in an area.

Requires projects and activities carried out under this Act to be coordinated with affected local governments according to certain criteria regarding the development and revision of land use plans under the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
