<bill session="114" type="s" number="2141" updated="2018-06-02T07:10:45Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transparent Ratings on Usability and Security to Transform Information Technology Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TRUST IT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act with respect to health information technology.</title>
    <title type="display">TRUST IT Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2015-10-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Transparent Ratings on Usability and Security to Transform Information Technology Act of 2015 or the TRUST IT Act

This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to define "information blocking" and "interoperability" for health information technology (IT). Information blocking is preventing, discouraging, or interfering with the access, exchange, or use of electronic health information. Interoperability is the ability of health information systems to exchange information and use exchanged information.

The Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology (ONC) may publish information demonstrating how health IT meets the certification criteria of the voluntary health IT certification program. To be certified, health IT must meet security requirements, incorporate user-centered design, and achieve interoperability.

Entities seeking certification of health IT must attest to meeting requirements regarding information blocking, communication between users and a certification body, and interoperability. The ONC must: (1) recognize a council to establish a rating program to evaluate the interoperability, usability, and security of health IT; (2) publish ratings from that program; (3) convene stakeholders to develop reporting criteria for entities offering health IT; and (4) establish a process for certification bodies to collect confidential feedback.

The ONC may fine entities offering certified health IT that is rated less than satisfactory or entities that do not meet reporting requirements.

The ONC may decertify health IT. The ONC must establish a revolving fund to reimburse users of health IT that becomes decertified for the cost of new certified health IT. Such users are exempt for one year from Medicare payment adjustment under the program that incentivizes meaningful use of electronic health records.

The ONC must publish information on individuals' rights under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA).</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
