<bill session="115" type="hr" number="465" updated="2019-04-18T15:54:14Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that regular order should be restored in the House and Senate.</title>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that regular order should be restored in the House and Senate.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000127"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="unknown" number="343"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that:

 it should not be in order to consider a bill or resolution in the House unless each committee of referral had a hearing on it at which amendments were permitted, a vote was taken, and the committee filed a report on the measure; a conference report should not be filed in the House unless the conference committee held at least three meetings in which all committee members were allowed to be present, all items of difference between the chambers were addressed, voted on, and resolved by the full conference committee membership, and printed or electronic copies of the conference report and the accompanying joint explanatory statement were available to Members and Delegates for at least 48 hours before filing; both chambers should schedule simultaneous five-day work weeks in Washington and district work periods; and every bill brought to committee should be open to amendment and every bill brought to the floor of the House for a vote should be considered under an open rule.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
