<bill session="115" type="s" number="1069" updated="2019-04-18T16:35:53Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish pilot projects in order to provide timely and reliable information on the safety and effectiveness of cleared or approved devices.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medical Device Safety Monitoring Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medical Device Safety Monitoring Act</title>
    <title type="display">Medical Device Safety Monitoring Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2017-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2017-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="934"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2430"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-08T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Medical Device Safety Monitoring Act

This bill amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) to support pilot projects in order to provide timely and reliable information on the safety and effectiveness of marketed medical devices. The projects must: (1) be designed to generate safety and active surveillance data, (2) inform support for safety and active surveillance activities, (3) be coordinated with a system for evaluating medical device technology that operates under a board with representation from consumer groups and device manufacturers, and (4) use electronic health data.

The FDA may determine that a manufacturer's participation in a pilot project satisfies requirements regarding reporting or postmarket surveillance if the project captures adverse event information and the FDA has established procedures to publish safety information from the project.

Not later than January 31, 2021, the FDA must evaluate real world evidence pilot projects, such as the ones supported by this bill, for their ability to inform decision-making and efficiently generate evidence about the safety or effectiveness of medical devices.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
