<amendment session="114" chamber="s" number="1063" updated="2018-06-04T02:15:41Z">
  <amends type="sc" number="11" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2015-03-26">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <offered datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  <description>To establish a deficit-neutral reserve fund relating to ensuring all legally married same-sex spouses have equal access to the Social Security and veterans benefits they have earned and receive equal treatment under the law pursuant to the Constitution of the United States.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2015-03-26" how="roll" result="pass" roll="121">
      <text>Amendment SA 1063 as modified agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 57 - 43. Record Vote Number: 121.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Amendment SA 1063 proposed by Senator Enzi for Senator Schatz. (consideration: CR S1995-1997, S2005-2006; text: CR S1996; text as modified: CR S2005) To establish a deficit-neutral reserve fund relating to ensuring all legally married same-sex spouses have equal access to the Social Security and veterans benefits they have earned and receive equal treatment under the law pursuant to the Constitution of the United States.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26"/>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 1063 as modified agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 57 - 43. Record Vote Number: 121.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 1063 as modified agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 57 - 43. Record Vote Number: 121.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 1063 proposed by Senator Enzi for Senator Schatz.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1995-1997, S2005-2006" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1996" label="text"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2005" label="text as modified"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
