<bill session="114" type="s" number="1220" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:56Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Distribution Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the distribution of energy in the United States.</title>
    <title type="display">Energy Distribution Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2369"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1312"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Energy Distribution Act of 2015

This bill requires the Department of Energy (DOE) to collaborate with other federal agencies to improve the conceptual development of energy security, considering at a minimum:

 development of flexible, transparent, and competitive energy markets, including natural gas and oil markets; diversification of energy fuels, sources, and routes; and encouragement of indigenous sources of energy supply. DOE must: (1) lead an interagency effort to improve and coordinate data collection and analytical and modeling capabilities for energy distribution on shared energy infrastructure; and (2) coordinate the training of, and enhanced dialogue among, technical staff in federal agencies responsible for cross-border energy projects evaluation and implementation.

 The Energy Information Administration must collaborate with officials in Canada and Mexico to improve:

 the quality and transparency of North American energy data through reconciliation of data on energy trade flows among the U.S., Canada, and Mexico; the extension of energy mapping capabilities in those countries; and the development of common energy data terminology among the three nations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
