<bill session="114" type="h" number="5508" updated="2019-02-01T21:05:44Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Job Opportunity and Business Services Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">JOBS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act to remove certain restrictions on advertising and public relations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">JOBS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000371"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Investment" code="HSED13" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Job Opportunity and Business Services Act or the JOBS Act

This bill amends the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act to require the reports to the Department of Labor each state, local board, and any other recipient of funds under the Act is required to make to include information regarding programs and activities carried out under the Act pertaining to the advertising budget, and a description of the advertising, for which the funds received were used.

The bill also exempts from the prohibition against using funds received under the Act for lobbying purposes, and from specified other restrictions, the use of such funds for public relations and advertising costs for program outreach or activities otherwise related to carrying out the Act's purposes.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
