<bill session="114" type="h" number="2201" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:20Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Warren Weinstein Hostage Rescue Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Security Act of 1947 to establish a committee of the National Security Council on hostage recovery, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Warren Weinstein Hostage Rescue Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000620"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001083" joined="2015-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000605" joined="2015-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000065" joined="2015-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-01T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Warren Weinstein Hostage Rescue Act

This bill amends the National Security Act of 1947 to establish: (1) the Committee on Hostage Recovery within the National Security Council (NSC), and (2) the Interagency Fusion Cell on Hostage Recovery which shall execute the Committee's hostage retrieval strategies.

The Committee's functions shall include:

 coordinating retrieval of U.S. hostages among federal departments and agencies and among the United States and its allies; coordinating with the Interagency Fusion Cell on Hostage Recovery; developing hostage retrieval strategies and guidelines; developing information sharing policies and procedures; and developing a strategy to keep family members of U.S. hostages informed, and policies that do not compromise U.S. national security. It is the sense of Congress that the President should appoint a Special Advisor on Hostage Affairs who: (1) serves as the chair of the NSC Committee on Hostage Recovery; (2) has extensive foreign policy, counterterrorism, and hostage recovery experience; and; (3) serves (or the designee of the Special Advisor serves) as a primary liaison between the federal government and the family of a U.S. hostage.

Nothing in this Act shall be construed as authorizing the federal government to negotiate with a state sponsor of terrorism or a foreign terrorist organization.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
