<bill session="114" type="h" number="3768" updated="2019-01-09T21:26:16Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Senior Executive Service Taking Responsibility for Unilateral Station Transfers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SES TRUST Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to provide that rates of basic pay for members of the Senior Executive Service are determined on the basis of the position, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SES TRUST Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000911"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Senior Executive Service Taking Responsibility for Unilateral Station Transfers Act or the SES TRUST Act

This bill directs the appointing authority for each agency to periodically determine the annual rate of basic pay for each Senior Executive Service (SES) position within such agency. Any senior executive who transfers or otherwise moves to an SES position with the same or any other agency shall receive the rate of pay applicable to that position.

The Office of Personnel Management (OPM) must review any decision to reassign a senior executive to another SES position, within 30 days after such reassignment, to ensure that the decision was not based on an impermissible reason (defined as any reason other than performance of the senior executive or interests in the efficiency of the SES). If OPM determines that the reassignment was based on an impermissible reason, and the rate of basic pay applicable to such other position is lower than the rate provided under the previous position, the senior executive shall retain the higher rate of pay.

The bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to submit, semiannually, a report on covered senior executives who transfer from one SES position to another within the VA, including a justification for any increase or decrease in pay, and information on any incentives or relocation expenses, received by such person.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
