<bill session="115" type="s" number="2289" updated="2019-04-18T16:40:59Z">
  <state datetime="2018-01-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-01-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-01-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to create an Office of Cybersecurity at the Federal Trade Commission for supervision of data security at consumer reporting agencies, to require the promulgation of regulations establishing standards for effective cybersecurity at consumer reporting agencies, to impose penalties on credit reporting agencies for cybersecurity breaches that put sensitive consumer data at risk, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Data Breach Prevention and Compensation Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Data Breach Prevention and Compensation Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Data Breach Prevention and Compensation Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2018-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2018-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2018-01-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-01-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-12">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-01-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Data Breach Prevention and Compensation Act of 2018 

This bill creates the Office of Cybersecurity within the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) that, in part, must:

 supervise, evaluate, and regulate specified agencies' management of data security; examine agencies annually for compliance with regulations; investigate an agency in the event of a breach covered by the bill or suspected noncompliance with regulations, and report on any findings of such investigation; and coordinate with the National Institute of Standards and Technology and the National Cybersecurity and Communications Integration Center of the Department of Homeland Security. The office is authorized to: (1) investigate an agency's compliance with regulations regarding any data breach, and (2) enjoin an agency from violating specified regulations.

Specified consumer reporting agencies, in part, must:

 provide the office with information relating to security measures, demonstrate reasonable data protection measures, and notify the FTC of a covered breach. The bill establishes civil penalties for violations and directs the FTC to enforce compliance.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
