<amendment session="115" chamber="h" number="788" updated="2019-06-13T18:20:11Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2851" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2018-06-15T10:24:29-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000568"/>
  <offered datetime="2018-06-15"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 1 printed in Part A of House Report 115-751 to incorporate an inter-agency agreement transmitted to Congress by the Office of National Drug Control Policy (ONDCP), the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) and the U.S. Department of Justice (DOJ). Specifically, the amendment clarifies when the Attorney General can temporarily and permanently schedule a drug or substance to the newly created schedule A and prevents the Attorney General from permanently scheduling that drug or substance if the Secretary of HHS determines that there is not sufficient potential for abuse. The amendment also clarifies under what circumstances an applicant for a schedule A registration may continue to conduct research with such schedule A substance while their application is pending, among their research accommodations.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2018-06-15T10:24:29-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Griffith amendment (A001) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-06-15T10:15:28-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Griffith.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5215-5216" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5215" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-15"/>
    <action datetime="2018-06-15T10:15:28-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Griffith.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5215-5216" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5215" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-15T10:24:29-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-15T10:24:29-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Griffith amendment (A001) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-15">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
