<bill session="115" type="s" number="2689" updated="2019-04-18T16:42:41Z">
  <state datetime="2018-04-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-04-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-04-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide a taxpayer bill of rights for small businesses</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Taxpayer Bill of Rights Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Taxpayer Bill of Rights Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Small Business Taxpayer Bill of Rights Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2018-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2018-04-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-04-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2219-2222" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2219-2222" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-04-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Small Business Taxpayer Bill of Rights Act of 2018 

This bill modifies various tax enforcement procedures and requirements that affect small businesses and other taxpayers.

The bill modifies requirements regarding:

 awarding costs and fees to small businesses for administrative and court proceedings, the amounts of damages and penalties that are allowed for violating various tax laws, dispute resolution and appeal procedures, enforcing liens against principal residences, terminating Internal Revenue Service (IRS) employees for misconduct, reviews by the Department of the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration, and the release of an IRS levy due to economic hardship for business taxpayers. The bill also:

 allows a tax deduction for a portion of a taxpayer's expenses for certain audits, prohibits ex parte communications between officers in the IRS Office of Appeals and other IRS employees with respect to matters pending before the officers, establishes a 10-year term for the National Taxpayer Advocate, and repeals the requirement to submit a partial payment with an offer-in-compromise to settle a tax liability.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
