<bill session="114" type="h" number="4678" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:32Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Naval Station Guantanamo Bay Preservation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">United States Naval Station Guantanamo Bay Preservation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit modification, abrogation, abandonment, or other related actions with respect to United States jurisdiction and control over United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, without congressional action.</title>
    <title type="display">United States Naval Station Guantanamo Bay Preservation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000487"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001094" joined="2016-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2016-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000290" joined="2016-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000181" joined="2016-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000435" joined="2016-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000018" joined="2016-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000522" joined="2016-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000813" joined="2016-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000810" joined="2016-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000065" joined="2016-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-03-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-04-15">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Foreign Affairs. H. Rept. 114-496.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-15" calendar="Union" number="378">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 378.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-15T12:08:27Z" status="Reported to House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

United States Naval Station Guantanamo Bay Preservation Act

(Sec. 3) This bill prohibits any action to modify, abrogate, or replace the stipulations, agreements, and commitments contained in the Guantanamo Lease Agreements, or to impair or abandon the jurisdiction and control of the United States over United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, unless specifically authorized or otherwise provided by:

 a statute enacted on or after the enactment of this Act; a treaty ratified with the advice and consent of the Senate on or after enactment of this Act; or a modification of the Treaty Between the United States of America and Cuba signed at Washington, DC, on May 29, 1934, that is ratified with the advice and consent of the Senate on or after enactment of this Act. (Sec. 4) "Guantanamo Lease Agreements" means:

 the Agreement Between the United States of America and the Republic of Cuba for the Lease to the United States of Lands in Cuba for coaling and naval stations, signed by the President of the United States on February 23, 1903; and the Lease to the United States by the Government of Cuba of Certain Areas of Land and Water for Naval or Coaling Stations, signed by the President of the United States on October 2, 1903.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-496</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
