<bill session="114" type="h" number="2651" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:13Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Eliminating Disparities in Diabetes Prevention, Access, and Care Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to prevent and treat diabetes, to promote and improve the care of individuals with diabetes, and to reduce health disparities, relating to diabetes, within racial and ethnic minority groups, including the African-American, Hispanic American, Asian American, Native Hawaiian and Other Pacific Islander, and American Indian and Alaskan Native communities.</title>
    <title type="display">Eliminating Disparities in Diabetes Prevention, Access, and Care Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000197"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001064" joined="2016-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000385" joined="2015-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2015-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000580" joined="2015-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000413" joined="2015-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5475"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Behavioral sciences"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-04T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Eliminating Disparities in Diabetes Prevention, Access, and Care Act of 2015

This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to require the National Institutes of Health to: (1) expand, intensify, and support activities regarding prediabetes and diabetes, particularly type 2, in minority populations; (2) award grants for a mentoring program for health care professionals to be more involved in weight counseling, obesity research, and nutrition; (3) provide for the participation of minority health professionals in diabetes-focused research programs; and (4) award grants for programs to establish a pipeline from high school to professional school that will increase minority representation in diabetes-focused health fields.

The Diabetes Mellitus Interagency Coordinating Committee must report on federal activities regarding prediabetes and diabetes in minority populations and prepare a plan to address prediabetes and diabetes in minority populations.

The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention must conduct and support research and public health activities regarding diabetes in minority populations. The Division of Diabetes Translation must educate the public on diabetes in minority populations and educate minority populations on diabetes. The National Diabetes Education Program must educate specific minority populations through culturally and linguistically appropriate information campaigns.

The Health Resources and Services Administration must educate health professionals on diabetes in minority populations.

The Indian Health Service must: (1) conduct and support research and other activities regarding diabetes; and (2) coordinate the collection of data on clinically and culturally appropriate diabetes services.

The Department of Health and Human Services must arrange for the National Academy of Medicine (formerly known as the Institute of Medicine) to update its report entitled "Unequal Treatment: Confronting Racial and Ethnic Disparities in Health Care."</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
