<bill session="114" type="s" number="949" updated="2018-06-02T06:45:03Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Taxpayer Bill of Rights Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide a taxpayer bill of rights for small businesses.</title>
    <title type="display">Small Business Taxpayer Bill of Rights Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2015-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2015-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="1828"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Federal appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Small Business Taxpayer Bill of Rights Act of 2015 

 Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow businesses with average annual gross receipts of not more than $50,000 that prevail in an administrative or court proceeding involving the determination, collection, or refund of tax, interest, or penalty to recover their costs incurred in such proceedings; (2) increase the amount of civil damages against Internal Revenue Service (IRS) officers or employees for reckless, intentional, or negligent disregard of internal revenue laws and extend from two to five years the period for bringing a claim for damages; (3) increase the penalties against federal officers or employees for unlawful acts in connection with internal revenue laws and for unauthorized disclosures or inspections of tax returns; and (4) allow a taxpayer whose interest abatement claim does not exceed $50,000 to elect to bring a small tax case petition in U.S. Tax Court.

Prohibits ex parte communications between officers in the IRS Office of Appeals and other IRS employees with respect to matters pending before such officers and employees.

Authorizes new alternative dispute resolution procedures for taxpayer disputes with the IRS.

Extends to three years: (1) the period in which taxpayer property that has been wrongfully levied upon may be returned, and (2) the period for bringing suit against the United States for a wrongful tax levy.

Authorizes the waiver of the fee for establishing an installment agreement for payment of tax for certain low-income taxpayers who agree to make electronic debit payments.

 Allows a taxpayer seeking review of a claim for innocent spouse relief or of a collection case in U.S. Tax Court a 60-day suspension of the period for filing a petition for such review when the U.S. Bankruptcy Court has issued an automatic stay in a bankruptcy case involving the taxpayer's claim.

Allows de novo review in U.S. Tax Court of any determination by the IRS with respect to a claim for equitable innocent spouse relief.

Prohibits the IRS Office of Appeals from considering or deciding any new issue in an internal appeal that is not within the scope of the initial determination made in a taxpayer's case.

Prohibits the imposition of a tax lien against a taxpayer's principal residence unless a written determination is made that all other property of the taxpayer, if sold, is insufficient to pay the tax liability and the lien will not create an economic hardship for the taxpayer.

Requires the termination of an IRS employee for disproportionate scrutiny of an organization applying for tax-exempt status based on the ideology expressed in the name or purpose of the organization;

Authorizes a court to issue a declaratory judgment with respect to the initial or continuing classification of a tax-exempt social welfare organization;

Requires the Inspector General for Tax Administration of the Department of the Treasury to: (1) review any IRS criteria for selection of tax returns for examination or audit, assessment or collection of deficiencies, criminal investigation or referral, refunds for amounts paid, or any heightened scrutiny or review to determine whether such criteria discriminates against taxpayers on the basis of race, religion, or political ideology; and (2) consult with the IRS on recommended amendments to such criteria.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
