<bill session="115" type="h" number="2977" updated="2019-04-18T16:11:36Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reduce a portion of the annual pay of Members of Congress for the failure to adopt a concurrent resolution on the budget which does not provide for a balanced budget, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Balanced Budget Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Balanced Budget Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="display">Balanced Budget Accountability Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000584"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="98"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Balanced Budget Accountability Act

This bill requires the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), upon adoption by a chamber of Congress of a concurrent budget resolution for a fiscal year, to determine and submit to the Speaker of the House of Representatives or the President pro tempore of the Senate a certification as to whether that chamber has adopted a balanced budget.

 "Balanced budget" means a concurrent budget resolution providing that for FY2027 and each succeeding fiscal year to which the resolution applies total outlays do not exceed total receipts and are not more than 18% of the gross domestic product for such fiscal year.

 If OMB does not certify that a chamber has adopted a balanced budget for FY2018 before July 28, 2017, the payroll administrator of each chamber must deposit in an escrow account all payments for compensation of Members of Congress serving in that chamber otherwise required beginning on such date. Such deposits shall be released to such Members on the earlier of: (1) the day on which OMB certifies that the chamber has adopted a balanced budget for FY2018, or (2) the last day of the 115th Congress.

 The same requirements shall apply for FY2019 if OMB does not certify that a chamber has adopted a balanced budget for FY2019 before April 16, 2018.

If OMB does not certify that a chamber has adopted a balanced budget for FY2020, or any succeeding fiscal year, before April 16 of the prior fiscal year, each Member of that chamber shall be paid $1 annually for pay periods beginning on April 16 of the prior fiscal year and ending on the earlier of:

 the date on which OMB certifies that the chamber has adopted a balanced budget for such fiscal year, or the last day of the same calendar year in which such period begins. This bill requires legislation in the House and Senate that increases revenue to be agreed upon only by an affirmative vote of three-fifths of the Members of that chamber.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
