<bill session="114" type="h" number="5777" updated="2019-02-13T17:31:23Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">King Cove Road Land Exchange Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the exchange of Federal land and non-Federal land in the State of Alaska for the construction of a road between King Cove and Cold Bay.</title>
    <title type="display">King Cove Road Land Exchange Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="3204"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">King Cove Road Land Exchange Act

This bill declares that, if the state of Alaska offers to convey to the Department of the Interior 43,093 acres of state-owned land, Interior shall convey to Alaska, in exchange, 206 acres of federal land within the Izembek National Wildlife Refuge and 131 acres of federal land within the Izembek Wilderness, for purposes of: (1) designating a road corridor through the refuge, and (2) constructing a single-lane gravel road along the road corridor.

The values of the federal and nonfederal lands to be exchanged shall be equal.

Interior and Alaska shall select an appraiser to conduct appraisals of the federal and nonfederal lands in accordance with nationally recognized appraisal standards.

The bill requires the route of the road corridor to follow a specified southern road alignment.

The bill states that the exchange of the federal and nonfederal lands and the road to be constructed under this bill shall not constitute a major federal action requiring environmental impact review under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
