<bill session="114" type="s" number="794" updated="2019-06-14T05:36:52Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend whistleblower protections for defense contractor employees to employees of contractors of the elements of the intelligence community.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to extend whistleblower protections for defense contractor employees to employees of contractors of the elements of the intelligence community.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001170"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Select Committee on Intelligence.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SLIN" name="Senate Intelligence" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Extends whistleblower protections to employees of contractors, subcontractors, or grantees of elements of the intelligence community who disclose information regarding such an element, or its activities, if the employee complies with procedures to report urgent concerns to Congress by first submitting the information to an appropriate agency Inspector General under the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 or the Inspector General Act of 1978. (Currently, employees of contractors of the intelligence community are excluded from certain whistleblower protections that are provided to employees of&#160;contractors of the&#160;Department of Defense and other federal agencies.)

Requires courts that receive&#160;a disclosure of information required by executive order to be kept classified (in the interests of national defense or the conduct of foreign affairs) to treat the information in a manner consistent with the interests of the national security of the United States, including through the use of summaries or ex parte submissions if the element of the intelligence community concerned advises the court that such procedures are warranted.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
