<bill session="113" type="h" number="3828" updated="2016-10-25T16:10:00Z">
  <state datetime="2014-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Notification of Your Eldercare Rights Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, to draft disclosures describing the rights and liabilities of customers of domestic care services and require that such services provide such disclosures to customers in any contract for such services.</title>
    <title type="display">Notification of Your Eldercare Rights Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001090"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Workforce Protections" code="HSED10" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Service industries"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-01-09T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Notification of Your Eldercare Rights - Directs the Secretary of Labor to: (1) draft disclosures which describe the rights and liabilities of customers and providers of domestic care services; (2) require that any provider of domestic care services give such disclosures to each customer before entering into a contract with the customer; and (3) disclose to the customer whether the individual or individuals who will provide such services are employees of the provider of domestic care services or independent contractors.

Makes it unlawful for any provider of domestic care services to enter into contract with a customer without first providing the disclosure document required by this Act.

Prescribes penalties for violations of this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
