<bill session="114" type="h" number="1673" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:19Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enterprise Secondary Reserve Taxpayer Protection and Government Accountability Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992 to establish a secondary reserve fund for a housing enterprise under conservatorship to protect taxpayers against loss in the event of a housing downturn, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Enterprise Secondary Reserve Taxpayer Protection and Government Accountability Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001243"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Enterprise Secondary Reserve Taxpayer Protection and Government Accountability Act of 2015

This bill amends the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992 to direct the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency to: (1) establish for any government sponsored enterprise (GSE, including the Federal National Mortgage Association [Fannie Mae] and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation [Freddie Mac]) operating in conservatorship a secondary reserve fund, and (2) deposit in it from any GSE revenues an amount equal to its required minimum capital level.

The GSE must hold secondary reserve fund amounts in escrow until the Director uses them according to this Act or until the fund is abolished.

The Director shall: (1) decide whether to use funds held in the secondary reserve of a GSE operating in conservatorship if the GSE's losses will exceed other available amounts, and (2) abolish any secondary reserve upon dissolution of the GSE's conservatorship.

Any amounts remaining in a secondary reserve upon abolishment shall revert first to meet the GSE's capital requirements and then to its earnings.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
