<bill session="114" type="h" number="2319" updated="2019-01-09T21:26:34Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Electronic Message Preservation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Electronic Message Preservation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 44, United States Code, to require preservation of certain electronic records by Federal agencies, to require a certification and reports relating to Presidential records, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Electronic Message Preservation Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000984"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2016-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-09-19">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 114-757.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-09-19" calendar="Union" number="589">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 589.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="National Archives and Records Administration"/>
    <term name="Presidential administrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-19T13:18:36Z" status="Reported to House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Electronic Message Preservation Act of 2015 

 (Sec. 2) This bill requires the Archivist of the United States to promulgate regulations governing federal agency preservation of electronic messages that are federal records and to periodically review and amend, as necessary, such regulations. Such regulations, at a minimum, shall: (1) require the electronic capture, management, and preservation of such electronic records in accordance with the Federal Records Act; (2) require such records to be retrievable through electronic searches; and (3) include timelines for federal agency compliance with the regulations that ensure compliance not later than December 31, 2016.

The Archivist shall promulgate regulations not later than two years after the enactment of this Act that: (1) establish mandatory minimum functional requirements for electronic records management systems and a process to ensure that such systems meet the functional requirements; and (2) include requirements for the capture, management, and preservation of other electronic records. The bill defines "electronic records management system" as software designed to manage electronic records, including by categorizing and locating records, ensuring that records are retained as long as necessary, identifying records that are due for disposition, and ensuring the storage, retrieval, and disposition of records.

Federal agency heads must report to the Archivist on agency compliance with the regulations promulgated by this Act and make such reports publicly available on the agency's website.

(Sec. 3) The bill requires the Archivist to: (1) establish standards for the management of electronic presidential records during a President's term of office, including records management controls necessary for the capture, management, and preservation of electronic messages and for ensuring that electronic messages are readily accessible for retrieval through electronic searches; (2) certify annually whether electronic records management controls established by a President meet the requirements of the Presidential Records Act; and (3) report annually to specified congressional committees on the status of such certification.

The Archivist must report to Congress one year after the conclusion of a President's term of office on: (1) the volume and format of electronic presidential records deposited into the presidential archival depository, and (2) whether electronic records management controls of a President met the requirements of this Act and the Presidential Records Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-757</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
