<bill session="114" type="s" number="1769" updated="2018-06-02T06:57:40Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">African Elephant Conservation and Legal Ivory Possession Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the African Elephant Conservation Act to conserve elephants while appropriately regulating ivory in the United States.</title>
    <title type="display">African Elephant Conservation and Legal Ivory Possession Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000360" joined="2015-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="697"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2406"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Art, artists, authorship"/>
    <term name="Crimes against animals and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Materials"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">African Elephant Conservation and Legal Ivory Possession Act of 2015

This bill revises and reauthorizes the African Elephant Conservation Act through FY2020.

Raw or worked ivory may be imported or exported under that Act and the Endangered Species Act of 1973 if: (1) the ivory is for a museum; (2) the ivory was lawfully importable into the United States on February 24, 2014, regardless of when it was acquired; or (3) the worked ivory was previously lawfully possessed in the United States.

This bill authorizes: (1) commerce in African elephant ivory or in products containing African elephant ivory that have been lawfully imported or crafted in the United States; and (2) the importation of a sport-hunted African elephant trophy if the trophy was taken from certain elephants populations that at the time were not necessarily threatened with extinction, but may have become so unless trade was closely controlled. Interior may station one U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service law enforcement officer in each African country that has a significant population of African elephants to assist local wildlife rangers in protecting the elephants and facilitating the apprehension of individuals who illegally kill them or assist in killing them.

The President may embargo any products from a country if it is a significant transit or destination point for illegal ivory trade.

In providing financial assistance under the African Elephant Conservation Act, Interior must prioritize projects for facilitating the acquisition of equipment and training to wildlife officials in ivory-producing countries to be used in anti-poaching efforts.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
