<bill session="114" type="h" number="1214" updated="2019-02-13T17:31:13Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-16T19:16:44-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-09-16T19:16:44-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Forest Small Tracts Act Amendments Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">National Forest Small Tracts Act Amendments Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">National Forest Small Tracts Act Amendments Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Tracts Act to expand the authority of the Secretary of Agriculture to sell or exchange small parcels of National Forest System land to enhance the management of the National Forest System, to resolve minor encroachments, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">National Forest Small Tracts Act Amendments Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000369"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2015-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2015-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000364" joined="2015-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30">
      <text>Subcommittee on Federal Lands Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-04-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-06-08">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 114-140, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-08">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-06-08" calendar="Union" number="100">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 100.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-09-16T15:40:55-04:00">
      <text>Mr. McClintock moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-16T15:41:28-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5995-5996" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-16T15:41:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1214.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-16T15:45:59-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-16T18:32:11-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6003-6004" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="495" datetime="2015-09-16T19:16:44-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 403 - 0 (Roll no. 495).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5995" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-09-16T19:16:44-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-17">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Conservation and Forestry" code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1712"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2012"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2647"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-16T13:57:49Z" status="Passed House amended">National Forest Small Tracts Act Amendments Act of 2015

(Sec. 2) Amends the Small Tracts Act (the Act) to permit the sale, exchange, or interchange under such Act of National Forest System (NFS) lands the sale or exchange of which is not practicable under any other authority of the Department of Agriculture (USDA) which have a value determined to be not more than $500,000.

Includes as those lands permitted to be sold, exchanged, or interchanged under the Act:

 parcels of 40 acres or less which are determined to be physically isolated, to be inaccessible, or to have lost their National Forest character; parcels of 10 acres or less which are not eligible for conveyance under such Act, but which are encroached upon by permanent habitable improvements for which there is no evidence that the encroachment was intentional or negligent; and parcels used as a cemetery, a landfill, or a sewage treatment plant under a special use authorization issued by the USDA. Allows the sale, exchange, or interchange of a cemetery that is expected to reach capacity within 10 years to include, in the USDA's sole discretion, up to 1 additional acre abutting the permit area to facilitate the expansion of that cemetery.

Requires any proceeds under this Act to be deposited in the special fund established under the Sisk Act and made available for:

 the acquisition of land or interests in land for administrative sites for the NFS in the state from which the amounts were derived; the acquisition of land or interests in land for inclusion in the NFS in that state, including those which enhance opportunities for recreational access; the performance of deferred maintenance on administrative sites for the NFS in that state or other deferred maintenance activities in that state which enhance opportunities for recreational access; and the reimbursement of the USDA for costs incurred in preparing a competitive sale conducted under the authority of the Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-140</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
