<bill session="114" type="h" number="981" updated="2019-02-08T20:13:06Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Red Snapper Regulatory Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act to improve the Gulf of Mexico Red Snapper fishery by providing flexibility for fishing managers and stability for fisherman, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Red Snapper Regulatory Reform Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001289"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000055" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001255" joined="2015-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001274" joined="2015-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001103" joined="2015-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000601" joined="2015-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000609" joined="2015-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000591" joined="2015-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000575" joined="2015-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001176" joined="2015-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001189" joined="2015-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water, Oceans, and Wildlife" code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-13T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Red Snapper Regulatory Reform Act 

This bill amends the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act to revise requirements on fishing and fisheries in the Gulf of Mexico.

The bill repeals a requirement that red snapper fishery management plans, plan amendments, or regulation submitted by the Gulf of Mexico Fishery Management Council contain catch limits.

State jurisdiction over fisheries in the Gulf of Mexico is expanded to nine nautical miles.

The Gulf States Marine Fisheries Commission must conduct all fishery stock assessments for fisheries managed under the Council's Reef Fish Management Plan. Stock assessments must: (1) incorporate fisheries survey information collected by universities; (2) use state, university, and private assets to conduct surveys; (3) incorporate surveys conducted on natural and artificial reefs; and (4) emphasize constituent and stakeholder participation in the development of the assessment.

The program created to improve the quality and accuracy of information generated by the Marine Recreational Fishery Statistics Survey must take into consideration all fishery effort data collection activities undertaken by the marine resources division of each relevant state of the Council.

Members of the Council are no longer appointed by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
