<bill session="113" type="h" number="5755" updated="2016-10-25T16:17:26Z">
  <state datetime="2014-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safer American Streets Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To withhold certain highway funds from a State that uses an automated traffic enforcement system on a Federal-aid highway.</title>
    <title type="display">Safer American Streets Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000937"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001280" joined="2014-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Highways and Transit" code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-11-20T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Safer American Streets Act - Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT), for FY2015 and subsequent fiscal years, to withhold 10% of a state's apportionment of specified federal-aid highway program funds for any state or municipal government that employs an automated traffic enforcement system on a federal-aid highway.

Prohibits:

 the Mayor of the District of Columbia from using an automated traffic enforcement system to detect a moving infraction, and the use of any information obtained through such a system as proof of an infraction in an administrative adjudication. Repeals title IX of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Temporary Amendment Act of 1996 (relating to automated traffic enforcement in the District of Columbia).</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
