<bill session="114" type="h" number="5391" updated="2018-08-16T22:36:56Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-27T15:27:43-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-09-27T15:27:43-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gains in Global Nuclear Detection Architecture Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Gains in Global Nuclear Detection Architecture Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Gains in Global Nuclear Detection Architecture Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to enhance certain duties of the Domestic Nuclear Detection Office, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Gains in Global Nuclear Detection Architecture Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000588"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-06-08" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-07-01">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 114-652.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-01" calendar="Union" number="504">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 504.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-09-27T15:16:33-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Ratcliffe moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-27T15:16:49-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5952-5954" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-27T15:16:50-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5391.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2016-09-27T15:27:43-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5952" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-09-27T15:27:45-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6381"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-27T13:40:49Z" status="Passed House amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the House reported version is repeated here.)

Gains in Global Nuclear Detection Architecture Act

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Domestic Nuclear Detection Office, in conducting research and development to generate and improve technologies to detect and prevent the illicit entry, transport, assembly, or potential use within the United States of a nuclear explosive device or fissile or radiological material, to:

 develop and maintain documentation that provides information on how the Office's research investments align with gaps in the enhanced global nuclear detection architecture and with research challenges identified by the Director, and that defines in detail how the Office will address such research challenges; document the rational for prioritizing and selecting research topics; and develop a systematic approach for evaluating how the outcomes of the Office's individual research projects collectively contribute to addressing its research challenges.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-652</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
