<bill session="113" type="h" number="5283" updated="2016-10-25T16:15:45Z">
  <state datetime="2014-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Land-Based Marine Debris Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish national goals for the reduction and recycling of municipal solid waste, to address the growing problem of marine debris, to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to promulgate regulations to attain those goals, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Land-Based Marine Debris Reduction Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000030" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2014-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Environment and the Economy" code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-07-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Land-Based Marine Debris Reduction Act - Declares national goals of: (1) no increase in the generation of solid waste sent to landfills, (2) recycling of at least 50% of the municipal solid waste stream by the end of 2020 and 65% by the end of 2030, and (3) no increase in the flow of marine debris into the ocean.

Requires the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to report on: (1) municipal solid waste generation, waste management methods, and progress in meeting the goals; (2) leakage paths of marine debris into the ocean; and (3) landfill closures.

Directs the EPA to develop a list of categories of commonly used products and packaging that are discarded into the municipal solid waste stream and determine with respect to the products or packaging in each category: (1) the percentage of recovered materials used in their manufacture; (2) the source reduction and recovery efficiency; (3) the percentage that is recycled upon discard and the percentage that is littered; and (4) the life cycle environmental effects associated with them, compared to alternatives.

Requires the EPA to identify categories to be targeted for regulatory action. Authorizes regulations requiring manufacturers to use recovered materials in the product or packaging.

Directs the EPA and the Department of Commerce to develop a voluntary system of packaging standards with respect to materials contained within the packaging and the recyclability of the packaging upon discard. Requires the standard to provide that packaging that meets the standards be eligible to use a label indicating compliance for promotional and educational purposes.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
