<bill session="114" type="h" number="6110" updated="2019-02-14T23:34:27Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Allow State Sovereignty Upon Refugee Entry (ASSURE) Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 412(a)(2) of the Immigration and Nationality Act to require ratification of a plan with respect to a refugee by the legislature of a State before the refugee may be initially placed or resettled in the State, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Allow State Sovereignty Upon Refugee Entry (ASSURE) Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000605"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001269" joined="2016-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001274" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000552" joined="2016-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000566" joined="2016-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-10-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Citizenship" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Allow State Sovereignty Upon Refugee Entry (ASSURE) Act

This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to set forth requirements for programs for domestic resettlement of, and assistance to, refugees.

Before initial placement or resettlement of a refugee in a state, and before any assistance under such Act is provided to a refugee in a state, the Office of Refugee Resettlement must submit to the state legislature, and the state must enact, a plan covering that refugee, which includes:

 the costs to the state for housing, providing benefits to, and education of, the refugee; vaccination and health records, and the criminal history, of the refugee; any ties to a terrorist organization; whether the refugee is affiliated with groups listed as unindicted co-conspirators in the case of United States of America v. Holy Land Foundation for Relief and Development; records of the refugee found in the Department of State's Consular Lookout and Support System; and records from the refugee interview conducted by U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services. If such plan is signed into law, the state may enter contracts to carry out programs for domestic resettlement of, and assistance to, covered refugees. The state shall be reimbursed by the federal government for expenses incurred.

The Department of Justice and the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) shall ensure that every Identity History Summary provided by the FBI includes: (1) the subject's immigration or citizenship status, and (2) any violation of federal immigration laws that has been adjudicated regarding the subject.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
