<bill session="115" type="s" number="1550" updated="2019-05-17T18:16:46Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the authority of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to hire and retain physicians and other employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Veterans Affairs Quality Employment Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Veterans Affairs Quality Employment Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Department of Veterans Affairs Quality Employment Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001202"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2017-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2017-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2017-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1367"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="114"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Department of Veterans Affairs Quality Employment Act of 2017

This bill provides that the annual determination of the Veterans Health Administration (VHA) staff shortages shall include shortages for five clinical and five non-clinical occupations for each network. (Such determination currently includes the five occupations for which there are the largest Department of Veterans Affairs [VA]-wide shortages.)

The bill establishes in the VA an executive management fellowship program to provide eligible employees of: (1) the Veterans Benefits Administration (VBA) and the VHA with private sector training and experience, and (2) a private-sector entity with VA training and experience.

The VA shall:

 conduct an annual performance plan for each political appointee that is similar to the plan conducted for VA career senior executive employees; establish a single database that lists each vacant VA position that is critical, difficult to fill, or both, and each vacant mental health position; prescribe regulations to allow for excepted service appointments of qualifying students and recent graduates; provide VHA human resources with training on employee recruitment and retention; establish a promotional track system for employees who are technical experts to advance without being required to transition to management positions; develop a program to transition military medical people into VHA employment; develop a plan to hire qualified directors for each medical center without a permanent director; develop a standardized VA exit survey; and ensure that a recruiter for each Veterans Integrated Service Network visits, at least annually, each allopathic and osteopathic teaching institution with a graduate medical education program within the network to recruit individuals to be appointed to VHA positions. The VA may non-competitively appoint a qualified former career or career conditional employee to any VA position within the competitive service that is one grade higher than the position most recently occupied by the employee.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
