<bill session="114" type="s" number="466" updated="2018-06-02T06:33:26Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Quality Care for Moms and Babies Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Quality Care for Moms and Babies Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XI of the Social Security Act to improve the quality, health outcomes, and value of maternity care under the Medicaid and CHIP programs by developing maternity care quality measures and supporting maternity care quality collaboratives.</title>
    <title type="display">Quality Care for Moms and Babies Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000770"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2015-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2015-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2015-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2015-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2015-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2015-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2015-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-06-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-07-30">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Reported by Senator Hatch with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 114-100.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-07-30" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="179">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 179.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4695"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-30T13:24:57Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Quality Care for Moms and Babies Act

(Sec. 2) This bill amends title XI of the Social Security Act (SSAct) to direct the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to:

 identify and publish a recommended core set of maternal and infant quality measures for women and children in the same manner as it identifies and publishes a core set of child health quality measures; publish an initial core set of any such measures applicable to mothers and infants eligible under SSAct titles XIX (Medicaid) and XXI (State Children's Health Insurance Program) (CHIP); develop a standardized format for reporting information based on the initial core set and create procedures to encourage states to use these measures to report voluntarily information regarding the quality of health care for Medicaid and CHIP eligible mothers and infants; establish a Maternal and Infant Quality Measurement Program; and publish recommended changes to the initial core set of measures that shall reflect the results of the testing, validation, and consensus process for their development. Any entity awarded a grant or contract by HHS to develop emerging and innovative evidence-based measures under the Maternal and Infant Quality Measurement Program shall work to advance eMeasures aligned with those developed under the Pediatric Quality Measures Program and the Medicaid Quality Measurement Program.

The Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality shall adapt the Consumer Assessment of Healthcare Providers and Systems program surveys of providers, facilities, and health plans to ensure that the adapted surveys are effective in measuring aspects of care that childbearing women and newborns experience.

States with an approved Medicaid or CHIP plan or waiver shall report annually to HHS regarding state specific maternal and infant quality of care measures applied.

(Sec. 3) HHS may make grants to eligible entities to support:

 the development of new state and regional maternity and infant care quality collaboratives; expanded activities of existing collaboratives; and maternity and infant care initiatives within established state and regional quality collaboratives that are not focused exclusively on maternity care. An online, open-access clearinghouse shall be established to make protocols, procedures, reports, tools, and other resources of individual collaboratives available to collaboratives and other entities working to improve maternity and infant care quality.

(Sec. 4) The consensus-based entity regarding performance measurement with which HHS must contract shall facilitate increased coordination and alignment between the public and private sector with respect to quality and efficiency measures.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-100</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
