<bill session="113" type="h" number="4898" updated="2016-10-25T16:14:14Z">
  <state datetime="2014-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Access to Veteran-Centered Community Care Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide hospital care and medical services in non-Department facilities for veterans waiting longer than 14 days for an appointment in a Department facility, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Access to Veteran-Centered Community Care Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000018" joined="2014-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-06-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Access to Veteran-Centered Community Care Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to: (1) determine that a VA facility is not capable of furnishing the care or services required if a veteran has been waiting for 14 days or longer for an appointment to receive hospital care or medical services, including primary care, in such a facility; and (2) ensure that such care or services are provided to such a veteran at a non-VA facility under contract with the VA.

Requires: (1) any referral of a veteran who, in the course of receiving hospital care or medical services in a non-VA facility, is referred to another non-VA facility for specialty care, to be submitted to the Secretary; and (2) the Secretary, if he or she does not reject such referral during the 72-hour period following its submittal, to ensure that such specialty care is provided to the veteran at a non-VA facility under contract with the VA.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
