<bill session="114" type="h" number="216" updated="2018-06-02T02:03:42Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-24T14:18:14-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-03-24T14:18:14-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Veterans Affairs Budget Planning Reform Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Department of Veterans Affairs Budget Planning Reform Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of Veterans Affairs Budget Planning Reform Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to submit to Congress a Future-Years Veterans Program and a quadrennial veterans review, to establish in the Department of Veterans Affairs a Chief Strategy Officer, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Department of Veterans Affairs Budget Planning Reform Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000911"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2015-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000382" joined="2015-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001144" joined="2015-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2015-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-27">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-02-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-03-23">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 114-48.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-03-23" calendar="Union" number="31">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 31.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-03-23T16:39:32-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Miller (FL) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-23T16:39:44-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1822-1824" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-23T16:39:46-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 216.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-23T16:49:31-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-24T14:11:24-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1869-1670" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="134" datetime="2015-03-24T14:18:14-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 420 - 0 (Roll no. 134).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 3/23/2015 H1822-1824" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-03-24T14:18:14-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-24T13:40:44Z" status="Passed House amended">Department of Veterans Affairs Budget Planning Reform Act of 2015

(Sec. 2) Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to submit annually to Congress a Future-Years Veterans Program (Program) reflecting estimated expenditures and proposed appropriations included in the budget for that fiscal year.

Requires the Program to: (1) set forth a five-year VA plan to address the U.S. commitment to veterans and the resources necessary to meet that commitment; (2) be included in VA's annual budget submission to the Congress, starting with the FY2020 budget submission; and (3) be published on a publicly available VA website.

Requires the Secretary, in 2019 and quadrennially thereafter, to conduct a review of the strategy for meeting such commitment and resources requirement (Quadrennial Veterans Review) which shall include a comprehensive examination of U.S. policies and strategies for veterans, including recommendations regarding the long-term strategy and priorities for veterans programs, services, and benefits, and guidance on VA programs, assets, budget, and policies.

Requires each Review to be coordinated with the Program.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) report to Congress regarding each Review, and (2) publish each Review on a public ally available VA website.

Directs the Secretary to establish an Independent Veterans Review Panel for each year in which a Review is conducted which shall review the process by which the review is formulated and submit a related report to Congress.

Directs the Secretary to provide annually to the appropriate VA officials written policy guidance for the preparation and review of the planning and program recommendations and budget proposals of the VA elements of such officials.

(Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary to designate a Chief Strategy Officer to: (1) advise the Secretary on long-range VA strategy and implications, and (2) develop and execute the Program.

(Sec. 4) States that: (1) no additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act, and (2) this Act shall be carried out using funds otherwise available to VA.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-48</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
