<bill session="114" type="h" number="4735" updated="2019-02-12T19:45:27Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Architect of the Capitol Administrative Operations Improvement Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a working capital fund for the Architect of the Capitol, to permit the Architect of the Capitol to use certain funds to operate a shuttle service for Members and employees of Congress to travel to and from the House Office Buildings, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Architect of the Capitol Administrative Operations Improvement Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001227"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Architect of the Capitol"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="U.S. Capitol"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Architect of the Capitol Administrative Operations Improvement Act of 2016

This bill establishes in the Treasury a Working Capital Fund for the Architect of the Capitol (AOC), whose amounts shall be available for:

 appropriate, efficient, and economical common agency services, activities, equipment, and other common costs; and construction, capital repairs, renovations, rehabilitation, maintenance of real property, and similar agency expenses, on a reimbursable basis within the AOC. The Fund shall consist of, among other things, appropriations as well as:

 the reasonable value of stocks of supplies, equipment, and other assets and inventories on order that the AOC transfers to the Fund, minus related liabilities and unpaid obligations; receipts from the sale or exchange of property held in the Fund; all miscellaneous receipts compensating the AOC for loss or damage to any government property under its jurisdiction or care, including the U.S. Botanic Garden; and reimbursements and transfers from certain other accounts. The Fund shall be reimbursed from available AOC accounts for supplies, materials, services, and related expenses, at rates which will approximate the full cost of operations, including:

 accrual of employee leave and benefits; depreciation of plant, property, and equipment; and overhead. The AOC may use certain appropriations for the purchase or rental, maintenance, and operation of passenger motor vehicles to provide shuttle service for Members and employees of Congress to and from the House Office Buildings.

Available balances of expired AOC appropriations shall be available to the AOC for reimbursing the Department of Labor for any unemployment compensation payments for former AOC employees, without regard to the fiscal year for which the obligation to make such payments is incurred.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
