<bill session="114" type="h" number="4977" updated="2018-06-02T05:01:50Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VA Scheduling Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to ensure that each medical facility of the Department of Veterans Affairs complies with requirements relating to scheduling veterans for health care appointments, to improve the uniform application of directives of the Department, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">VA Scheduling Accountability Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000813"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-29">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3956"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">VA Scheduling Accountability Act

This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to ensure that the director of each VA medical facility annually certifies to the VA that the facility is in full compliance with all provisions of law and regulations relating to scheduling appointments for veterans hospital care and medical services, including pursuant to Veterans Health Administration Directive 2010-027 (regarding scheduling of outpatient clinic appointments and ensuring staff competency). The VA may not waive any applicable provision of such laws or regulations.

If unable to make such certification, a director shall provide the VA with an explanation of noncompliance and a description of compliance actions being taken.

The VA shall ensure that its directives and policies apply uniformly to each VA office or facility.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
