<bill session="115" type="h" number="3112" updated="2019-04-18T16:12:08Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title II of the Social Security Act to provide an option to claim a delayed retirement credit in a partial lump sum, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Choice for Social Security Retirees Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Choice for Social Security Retirees Act</title>
    <title type="display">Providing Choice for Social Security Retirees Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001172" joined="2017-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Social Security" code="HSWM01" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Providing Choice for Social Security Retirees Act

This bill amends title II (Old Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to allow an individual who is entitled to OASDI benefits to claim a delayed-retirement credit in a partial lump sum.

Under current law, an individual's OASDI benefits are increased by a&#160;two-thirds of 1% for each month in which the individual, after attaining full retirement age but prior to attaining age 70,&#160;delays claiming those benefits. The bill allows an individual who delays claiming&#160;OASDI benefits to instead opt to receive a smaller percentage increase (one-half of 1%) for each applicable month,&#160;plus a one-time lump sum payable at the time of the individual's entitlement to the benefits. The amount of this lump sum shall equal the sum of the present values of one-sixth of 1% of the amount of the individual's monthly benefits for each month in the individual's life-expectancy period.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
