<bill session="114" type="h" number="5181" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:38Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Countering Foreign Propaganda and Disinformation Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To counter foreign disinformation and propaganda, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Countering Foreign Propaganda and Disinformation Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000378"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001296" joined="2016-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2016-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000451" joined="2016-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000558" joined="2016-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000057" joined="2016-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2016-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2016-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000563" joined="2016-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2016-05-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2016-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2016-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000473" joined="2016-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2016-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2692"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3274"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Countering Foreign Propaganda and Disinformation Act of 2016

This bill expresses the sense of Congress that:

 foreign governments, including the governments of the Russian Federation and China, use disinformation and other propaganda tools to undermine the national security objectives of the United States and key allies and partners; the U.S. government should develop a comprehensive strategy to counter foreign disinformation and propaganda and assert leadership in developing a fact-based strategic narrative; and an important element of this strategy should be to promote an independent press in countries that are vulnerable to foreign disinformation. The Department of State shall establish a Center for Information Analysis and Response to:

 lead and coordinate the collection and analysis of information on foreign government information warfare efforts; establish a framework for the integration of critical data and analysis on foreign propaganda and disinformation efforts into the development of national strategy; and develop and synchronize government initiatives to expose and counter foreign information operations directed against U.S. national security interests and advance fact-based narratives that support U.S. allies and interests. When selecting participants for U.S. educational and cultural exchange programs, special consideration shall be given to students and community leaders from populations and countries deemed vulnerable to foreign propaganda and disinformation campaigns.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
