<amendment session="114" chamber="h" number="754" updated="2018-11-09T00:02:53Z">
  <amends type="h" number="22" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2015-11-03T17:01:43-05:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001185"/>
  <offered datetime="2015-11-03"/>
  <description>Amendment requires a report to Congress on the Internet of Things (IoT) and its potential to improve transportation services to the elderly and persons with disabilities as well as assist local, state and federal transportation planners in achieving better inefficiencies and cost effectiveness, while protecting privacy and security of persons who use IoT technology.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 21 printed in Part B of House Report 114-325 to provide a report on the Internet of Things (IoT) and its potential to improve transportation services to the elderly and persons with disabilities as well as assist local, state and federal transportation planners in achieving better inefficiencies and cost effectiveness, while protecting privacy and security of persons who use IoT technology.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2015-11-03T17:01:43-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Sewell (AL) amendment (A021) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-11-03T16:58:55-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A021) offered by Ms. Sewell (AL) to the Rules amendment (A001).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7595-7597" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7595" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-03"/>
    <action datetime="2015-11-03T17:01:43-05:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-03T17:01:43-05:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Sewell (AL) amendment (A021) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-03T16:58:55-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A021) offered by Ms. Sewell (AL) to the Rules amendment (A001).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7595-7597" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7595" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-03">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
