<bill session="114" type="s" number="3350" updated="2018-08-16T23:01:12Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clarification of Treatment of Electronic Sales of Livestock Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921, to clarify the duties relating to services furnished in connection with the buying or selling of livestock in commerce through online, video, or other electronic methods, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Clarification of Treatment of Electronic Sales of Livestock Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000567"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2016-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5883"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Clarification of Treatment of Electronic Sales of Livestock Act of 2016

 This bill amends the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921 to expand the definition of "marketing agency" to include any person who engages in the business of buying or selling livestock, on a commission or other fee basis, through the use of online, video, or other electronic methods. The term "marketing agency" does not include a person whose annual average of online, video, or electronic sales of livestock, on a commission or other fee basis, is less than $250,000.

 The bill also permits electronic funds transfers and other expeditious payment methods that the Department of Agriculture determines to be appropriate to be used as options for meeting prompt payment requirements for livestock purchases.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
