<bill session="114" type="h" number="2570" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:10Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-17T17:32:51-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-06-17T17:32:51-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Value Based Insurance Design for Better Care Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VBID for Better Care Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Strengthening Medicare Advantage through Innovation and Transparency for Seniors of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a demonstration program requiring the utilization of Value-Based Insurance Design to demonstrate that reducing the copayments or coinsurance charged to Medicare beneficiaries for selected high-value prescription medications and clinical services can increase their utilization and ultimately improve clinical outcomes and lower health care expenditures.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act with respect to the treatment of patient encounters in ambulatory surgical centers in determining meaningful EHR use, establish a demonstration program requiring the utilization of Value-Based Insurance Design to demonstrate that reducing the copayments or coinsurance charged to Medicare beneficiaries for selected high-value prescription medications and clinical services can increase their utilization and ultimately improve clinical outcomes and lower health care expenditures, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Strengthening Medicare Advantage through Innovation and Transparency for Seniors of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001273"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2015-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001159" joined="2015-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2015-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-17T17:25:15-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Brady (TX) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-17T17:25:32-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4479-4481" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-17T17:25:35-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2570.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2015-06-17T17:32:51-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4479-4480" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-06-17T17:32:54-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-17T17:32:57-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-18">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2581"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1396"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Surgery and anesthesia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-17T04:00:00Z" status="Passed House amended">Strengthening Medicare Advantage through Innovation and Transparency for Seniors Act of 2015

(Sec. 2) This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSAct) with respect to criteria for qualifying as a meaningful user of electronic health records (meaningful EHR user). For any payment year after 2015 any patient encounter of an eligible professional occurring at an eligible ambulatory surgical center shall not be treated as one in determining whether an eligible professional qualifies as a meaningful EHR user.

(Sec. 3) HHS shall establish a three-year demonstration program to test the use of value-based insurance design methodologies under the eligible Medicare Advantage (MA) plans offered by MA organizations under Medicare part C.

"Value-based insurance design methodology" is one for identifying specific prescription medications, and clinical services payable under Medicare, for which copayments, coinsurance, or both would improve the management of specific chronic clinical conditions because of the high value and effectiveness of such medications and services for such specific chronic clinical conditions, as approved by HHS.

 HHS may expand the duration and scope of the demonstration program to an appropriate extent if specified requirements are met.

(Sec. 4) Payment amounts are prescribed for infusion drugs and biologicals furnished through durable medical equipment (DME) on or after January 1, 2017.

(Sec. 5) It is the sense of Congress that HHS:

 has incorrectly interpreted the determination of blended benchmark amounts as prohibiting the provision of any Medicare quality incentive payments with respect to MA plans that exceed the payment benchmark cap for the area served by those plans; and should immediately apply quality incentive payments with respect to such MA plans without regard to limits. (Sec. 6) $220 million shall be available to the Medicare Improvement Fund during and after FY2020.

(Sec. 7) DME competitive acquisition programs shall not cover infusion drugs and biologicals.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
