<bill session="114" type="hc" number="152" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:30Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of Congress that the United States and the international community should support the Republic of Iraq and its people to recognize a province in the Nineveh Plain region, consistent with lawful expressions of self-determination by its indigenous peoples.</title>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of Congress that the United States and the international community should support the Republic of Iraq and its people to recognize a province in the Nineveh Plain region, consistent with lawful expressions of self-determination by its indigenous peoples.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000449"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000055" joined="2016-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001105" joined="2016-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000625" joined="2016-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000448" joined="2016-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001052" joined="2016-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000563" joined="2016-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000373" joined="2016-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2016-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000522" joined="2016-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000130" joined="2016-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000804" joined="2016-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-09T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Expresses the sense of Congress that:

 the return of the displaced indigenous peoples of the Nineveh Plain, including those in Iraq, to their ancestral homeland should be a policy priority of United States and the international community; their fundamental human rights should be fully restored upon their return to their homeland; the indigenous communities of Iraq's Nineveh Plain region have a right to security and self-determination within the federal structure of Iraq; the United States, the Counter ISIL Coalition, the international community, the government of Iraq, and the Kurdish regional government should remain committed to liberation, economic revitalization, and prosperity of that region; the United States, the international community, international observers, the government of Iraq, and the Kurdish regional government should be committed to the territorial integrity and security of the Nineveh Plain; and the United States, the Counter ISIL Coalition, the international community, and international observers should be committed to working with the national and regional governments of Iraq toward a sustainable security settlement in the Nineveh Plain. Expresses the sense of Congress that the United States and the international community should:

 make the peaceful resolution of questions pertaining to Iraq's disputed internal boundaries a priority; work with the national and regional governments of Iraq to oversee the peaceful reintegration of the indigenous peoples of the Nineveh Plain to their ancestral homeland; work with the national and regional governments of Iraq, including the Kurdish regional government, to establish the Nineveh Plain as an undisputed territory, politically represented by the indigenous peoples and communities of the region; and be committed to supporting the Iraqi government in implementing the decision to create a Nineveh Plain Province and support the new provincial administration to attain its full potential.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
