<amendment session="115" chamber="h" number="651" updated="2019-06-13T18:11:45Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5515" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2018-05-23T16:44:46-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000179"/>
  <offered datetime="2018-05-23"/>
  <description>Amendment authorizes financial and visa sanctions against perpetrators of ethnic cleansing of the Rohingya by the Burmese military and security forces; limits U.S. military and security assistance with Burma until reforms take place; incentivizes reform of the Burmese gemstone sector; and requires a determination of what crimes the Burmese military committed, including genocide.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 43 printed in House Report 115-702 to authorize financial and visa sanctions against perpetrators of ethnic cleansing of the Rohingya by the Burmese military and security forces; limit U.S. military and security assistance with Burma until reforms take place; incentivize reform of the Burmese gemstone sector which is notoriously dominated by the military; and require a determination of what crimes the Burmese military committed, including genocide.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2018-05-23T16:44:46-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="227">
      <text>On agreeing to the Engel amendment (A018) Agreed to by recorded vote: 382 - 30 (Roll no. 227).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T15:31:20-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A018) offered by Mr. Engel.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4663-4666, H4671-4672" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4663-4666" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23"/>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T15:31:20-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A018) offered by Mr. Engel.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4663-4666, H4671-4672" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4663-4666" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T16:44:46-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T16:44:46-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T16:44:46-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Engel amendment (A018) Agreed to by recorded vote: 382 - 30 (Roll no. 227).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
