<bill session="114" type="s" number="2918" updated="2018-06-02T07:18:41Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 5, United States Code, to clarify the eligibility of employees of a land management agency in a time-limited appointment to compete for a permanent appointment at any Federal agency, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend title 5, United States Code, to clarify the eligibility of employees of a land management agency in a time-limited appointment to compete for a permanent appointment at any Federal agency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2016-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4906"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4909"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Temporary and part-time employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill allows otherwise eligible employees of a land management agency serving under a time-limited appointment in the competitive service to compete for a permanent appointment in the competitive service: (1) at that agency when the agency is accepting applications from individuals within the agency's workforce under merit promotion procedures, or (2) at any agency when the agency is accepting applications from individuals outside its own workforce under its merit promotion procedures.

A former employee of a land management agency who served under a time-limited appointment and who otherwise meets applicable requirements shall be deemed a time-limited employee of the agency from which the former employee was most recently separated.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
