<bill session="113" type="s" number="2999" updated="2016-10-25T16:32:57Z">
  <state datetime="2014-12-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Reauthorization Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize and improve the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Reauthorization Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000802"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2014-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hereditary and development disorders"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-12-11T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Reauthorization Act of 2014 - Amends the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to:

 reauthorize such Act for FY2015-FY2019; include as one of the purposes of such Act the support of a trauma-informed continuum of programs to address the needs of at-risk youth and youth who come into contact the the justice system; require states to implement plans to ensure fairness and reduce racial and ethnic disparities in the detention of juveniles; enhance requirements for separating juveniles from sight or sound contact with adult lock-ups; terminate, three years after the enactment of this Act, the authority of a court to issue an order detaining juveniles who have not been charged with adult criminal offenses (status offenders) in secure detention or correctional facilities ; require the Administrator of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention to report annually on policies and procedures to eliminate dangerous practices and unreasonable use of restraints in the detention of juveniles; expand requirements for state plans for juvenile justice and delinquency prevention to include community-based alternatives to the detention of juveniles in correctional facilities; provide technical assistance to states and local governments for achieving compliance with the requirements of this Act; and authorize the Administrator to make incentive grants to states and local governments to increase the use of evidence-based or promising prevention and intervention programs for juveniles who enter the criminal justice system and for the recruitment and training of professional personnel. Amends the Incentive Grants for Local Delinquency Prevention Programs Act of 2002 to include mentoring programs in delinquency prevention grant programs.

Requires the Comptroller General (GAO) to conduct: (1) a comprehensive evaluation of the performance of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention; and (2) a comprehensive audit and evaluation of selected grant recipients, including a review of internal controls to prevent fraud, waste, and abuse.

Requires states, as a condition of receiving juvenile accountability block grants, to provide assurances of compliance with the core requirement of the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 applicable to the detention and confinement of juveniles.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
