<bill session="115" type="s" number="2010" updated="2019-06-17T18:49:15Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-10-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to extend the FISA Amendments Act of 2008 for 8 years, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">FISA Amendments Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">FISA Amendments Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FISA Amendments Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">FISA Amendments Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001135"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-10-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-25">
      <text>Select Committee on Intelligence. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Burr. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-10-25" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="252">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 252.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-11-07">
      <text>By Senator Burr from Select Committee on Intelligence filed written report. Report No. 115-182. Additional and Minority views filed.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Legislative Interest"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SLIN" name="Senate Intelligence" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-10-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">FISA Amendments Reauthorization Act of 2017

This bill amends the FISA Amendments Act of 2008 to extend the Act through December 31, 2025.

The bill prohibits the intelligence community from intentionally acquiring a communication about a non-U.S.&#160;entity if the communication contains a reference to&#160;the entity but&#160;is not from or directed to that entity (this kind of communications collecting is called abouts collection) unless the Department of Justice (DOJ) and the Office of the Director of National Intelligence (ODNI)&#160;submit to Congress a written notice of the intent to implement the authorization of such communications collection.&#160;The notice triggers a 30-day congressional review period that requires Congress to pass specific legislation in order to prohibit the authorization of such communications collection. Information obtained about a U.S. person through an abouts collection can only be used against that U.S. person for specified criminal proceedings.

The bill allows the FISA court's amici curiae (lawyers who argue against the government's&#160;FISA requests)&#160;to participate in matters pertaining to abouts collection.

DOJ and the ODNI must&#160;create procedures and keep records pertaining to queries, which&#160;are searches done&#160;with data the government already acquired and use a specific search term for the purpose of discovering or retrieving content or metadata.&#160;

The bill exempts the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board from certain open meetings laws.

The penalty for the unauthorized removal of classified documents or materials is increased to up to 10 years in prison.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-182</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
