<bill session="114" type="s" number="2419" updated="2018-06-02T07:14:00Z">
  <state datetime="2015-12-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Educator Preparation Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve quality and accountability for educator preparation programs.</title>
    <title type="display">Educator Preparation Reform Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2015-12-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8795-8796" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="4471"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee performance"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-12-17T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Educator Preparation Reform Act

This bill amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to add as purposes of teacher quality partnership grants: (1) recruiting profession ready individuals, including minorities and individuals from other occupations, as teachers, principals, and other educators; and (2) meeting the staffing needs of high-need local education agencies and high-need schools through close partnerships with educator preparation programs within institutions of higher education.

An eligible partnership that receives a partnership grant shall use grant funds to carry out a program for the pre-baccalaureate or post-baccalaureate preparation of teachers, a teaching residency program (as in current law) or a principal residency program, or a combination of such programs.

An eligible partnership carrying out a principal residency program must perform specified activities for high-need schools.

The bill revises requirements for teacher residency programs and prescribes requirements for the establishment of principal residency programs.

An eligible partnership that receives a partnership grant may carry out, instead of a leadership development program, effective educator development programs for other educators besides teachers and principals.

The bill revises requirements for state reporting on the quality of teacher preparation.

As a condition for receiving funds under this Act or under title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965, a state must conduct an assessment to identify at-risk (as well as low-performing) teacher preparation programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
