<bill session="115" type="s" number="362" updated="2019-04-18T16:32:53Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide that 6 of the 12 weeks of parental leave made available to a Federal employee shall be paid leave, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Employees Paid Parental Leave Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Employees Paid Parental Leave Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Federal Employees Paid Parental Leave Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2017-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2017-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2017-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="6275"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1022"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Government Accountability Office (GAO)"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-13T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Federal Employees Paid Parental Leave Act of 2017

This bill allows executive branch employees to substitute any available paid leave for any leave without pay for either: (1) the birth of a child, or (2) the placement of a child for adoption or foster care. It makes available for any of the 12 weeks of leave an employee is entitled to for such purposes: (1) six administrative weeks of paid parental leave in connection with the birth or placement involved, and (2) any accumulated annual or sick leave.

 The bill authorizes the Office of Personnel Management to promulgate regulations to increase the amount of paid parental leave to a total of 12 administrative workweeks. Such regulations must consider certain factors, including benefit and cost to the federal government.

The personnel management system for employees of the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) shall include family and medical leave (including paid parental leave) for any leave without pay. The bill amends the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 and the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 to allow the same substitution for covered congressional employees, Government Accountability Office (GAO) employees, and Library of Congress employees. Service in the National Guard or the Reserves by executive branch employees, TSA employees, congressional employees, and GAO or Library of Congress employees shall count as service for purposes of determining eligibility to take or substitute leave as allowed under this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
