<bill session="114" type="h" number="2273" updated="2019-02-08T20:13:44Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-05T20:16:43-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-07-05T20:16:43-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Colorado River Storage Project Act to authorize the use of the active capacity of the Fontenelle Reservoir.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to amend the Definite Plan Report for the Seedskadee Project to enable the use of the active capacity of the Fontenelle Reservoir.</title>
    <title type="display">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to amend the Definite Plan Report for the Seedskadee Project to enable the use of the active capacity of the Fontenelle Reservoir.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000571"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-02-03" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-03-14">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 114-450.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-03-14" calendar="Union" number="345">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 345.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-07-05T20:14:04-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Lummis moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-05T20:14:17-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4251-4252" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-05T20:14:18-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2273.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2016-07-05T20:16:43-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4251" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-07-05T20:16:56-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-05T20:16:58-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-06" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="546">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 546.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water, Oceans, and Wildlife" code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="1305"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2902"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-05T14:47:49Z" status="Passed House amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on March 14, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

(Sec. 1) This bill authorizes the Department of the Interior, in cooperation with the state of Wyoming, to amend the Definite Plan Report for the Seedskadee Project authorized under the Colorado River Storage Project Act to provide for the study, design, planning, and construction activities that will enable the use of all active storage capacity of Fontenelle Dam and Reservoir, including the placement of sufficient riprap on the upstream face of the Dam to allow such storage capacity to be used for authorized Project purposes.

Interior may enter into: (1) any contract, grant, cooperative agreement, or other agreement that is necessary to carry out this Act; and (2) contracts with Wyoming for division of any additional active capacity made available under this Act.

Interior shall enter into a cooperative agreement with Wyoming for planning, design, related preconstruction activities, and construction of any modification of the Fontenelle Dam under this Act, which shall specify the responsibilities of Interior and Wyoming regarding: (1) completing the planning and final design of such modification, (2) any environmental and cultural resource compliance activities required for such modification, and (3) the construction of such modification. As a condition of providing additional storage, Wyoming shall provide to Interior funds for any work carried out to do so.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-450</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
