<bill session="114" type="s" number="1476" updated="2018-06-02T06:54:39Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Police Reporting Information, Data, and Evidence Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PRIDE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require States to report to the Attorney General certain information regarding shooting incidents involving law enforcement officers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">PRIDE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000711"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2015-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2016-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2015-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2015-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2015-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2015-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2016-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2016-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="3481"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-02T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Police Reporting Information, Data, and Evidence Act of 2015 or the PRIDE Act

Directs the Attorney General to make grants to states and Indian tribes that: (1) demonstrate that the use-of-force policy for their law enforcement officers is publicly available; and (2) report information on any incident involving the shooting of a civilian by a law enforcement officer or the shooting of an officer by a civilian and on any incident in which the use of force by an officer against a civilian, or the use of force by a civilian against an officer, results in serious bodily injury or death. Requires such information to include:

 the gender, race, ethnicity, and age of each individual who was shot, injured, or killed; the date, time, and location of the incident; whether the civilian was armed and, if so, the type of weapon; the type of force used against the officer, the civilian, or both; the number of officers and civilians involved; and a brief description regarding the circumstances surrounding the incident. Authorizes a grant to be used for:

 the cost of complying with such reporting requirements; the cost of establishing necessary systems required to investigate and report incidents; public awareness campaigns designed to gain information from the public on use of force against police officers; and use of force training for law enforcement agencies and personnel. Directs the Attorney General: (1) to publish an annual report containing the information reported, and (2) in coordination with the Federal Bureau of Investigation, to issue guidance on best practices relating to establishing standard data collection systems that capture such information.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
