<bill session="114" type="h" number="1463" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:18Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SEC Revolving Door Restriction Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to provide for a one-year employment restriction for ex-employees of the Securities and Exchange Commission seeking to work for companies against which the Commission brought enforcement actions that were participated on by such ex-employees, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SEC Revolving Door Restriction Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000562"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2015-03-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-19T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">SEC Revolving Door Restriction Act of 2015

This bill amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to subject to federal criminal penalties for bribery, graft, and conflicts of interest an ex-employee of the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) who, within one year after ending employment with the SEC, works for any company or individual against whom the SEC brought an enforcement action (or a related waiver) within the previous 18 months and the ex-employee participated in that action.

Any employee who seeks to work for such a company or individual must first receive an ethics opinion from the SEC on whether permission to do so should be granted.

Non-professional SEC staff are exempt from this employment prohibition.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
