<bill session="115" type="s" number="1350" updated="2019-04-18T16:37:06Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Labor Relations Act with respect to the timing of elections and pre-election hearings and the identification of pre-election issues, and to require that lists of employees eligible to vote in organizing elections be provided to the National Labor Relations Board.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Workforce Democracy and Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Workforce Democracy and Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="display">Workforce Democracy and Fairness Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000360"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2017-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2017-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2017-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000444" joined="2017-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2017-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2017-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2017-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2017-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2017-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000355" joined="2017-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2017-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2017-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2017-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2017-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001202" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2017-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2017-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2017-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2775"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2776"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="National Labor Relations Board (NLRB)"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Workforce Democracy and Fairness Act

This bill amends the National Labor Relations Act to require a waiting period of at least 14 days after a petition is filed by an employer or employee relating to collective bargaining rights before the National Labor Relations Board (NLRB) may begin an investigative hearing into questions of representation affecting commerce. A hearing must be non-adversarial and the hearing officer must identify any relevant and material pre-election issues and create a full record.

The bill requires the NLRB, in cases where it finds that a question of representation affecting commerce exists, to: (1) direct an election by secret ballot as soon as practicable but not before 35 calendar days after the filing of an election petition, and (2) certify election results after it has ruled on each pre-election issue not resolved before the election and any additional issue pertaining to the conduct or results of that election.

The bill also requires the NLRB, not earlier than seven days after a final determination of the appropriate bargaining unit, to acquire from the employer a list of all employees eligible to vote in the election, which shall: (1) be made available to all parties; and (2) include the employees' names and one additional form of personal contact information (e.g., telephone number, email address, or mailing address) chosen by the employee in writing.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
