<bill session="114" type="h" number="1681" updated="2018-06-02T02:39:23Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VA Construction, Accountability, and Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To extend the authorization for the major medical facility project to replace the Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Center in Denver, Colorado, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to enter into an agreement with the Army Corps of Engineers to manage the construction of such project, to transfer the authority to carry out future major medical facility projects of the Department from the Secretary to the Army Corps of Engineers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">VA Construction, Accountability, and Reform Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001077"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000197" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000593" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000583" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000470" joined="2015-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" code="HSVR08" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="997"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="593"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">VA Construction, Accountability, and Reform Act

This bill authorizes the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to carry out the major medical facility project to replace the VA Medical Center in Denver, Colorado (Aurora Project).

 The Secretary may not pay any bonus during FY2015-FY2016. If the Aurora Project is not completed by September 30, 2016, the Secretary may not pay any bonus until the date on which the Secretary certifies to Congress that such Project is fully operational. The aggregate amount of subsequent fiscal year bonuses is capped through FY2024.

 The Secretary shall enter into an agreement with the Secretary of the Army for the Army Corps of Engineers to carry out the design, contract, construction management, and other similar services for the Aurora Project.

The bill prohibits the VA Secretary from carrying out a major medical facility project and requires the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, to carry out all major medical facility projects for the VA.

 The Government Accountability Office shall review the Secretary's management of the Aurora Project.

 The Secretary must notify Congress at least 120 days (currently, at least 30 days) before obligating funds for major medical facility projects that exceed authorized amounts.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
