<bill session="114" type="h" number="3340" updated="2019-02-13T17:58:24Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-14T15:41:38-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-04-14T15:41:38-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Financial Stability Oversight Council Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Financial Stability Oversight Council Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Financial Stability Oversight Council Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To place the Financial Stability Oversight Council and the Office of Financial Research under the regular appropriations process, to provide for certain quarterly reporting and public notice and comment requirements for the Office of Financial Research, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Financial Stability Oversight Council Reform Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000294"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001282" joined="2015-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000458" joined="2015-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000548" joined="2015-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000569" joined="2015-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001156" joined="2015-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001189" joined="2015-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001182" joined="2015-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000606" joined="2015-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000592" joined="2015-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000611" joined="2015-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000593" joined="2015-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000487" joined="2015-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2015-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000470" joined="2015-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000816" joined="2015-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-21">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit Prior to Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-04">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-11-04" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 33 - 24.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-03-23">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 114-473.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-03-23" calendar="Union" number="359">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 359.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-04-12T20:23:24-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 671 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3340 and H.R. 3791. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 3340 and H.R. 3791.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-14T13:48:01-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 671.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1699-1710" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-14T13:48:21-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 3340 and H.R. 3791.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-14T13:48:22-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 3340, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-14T14:54:39-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 671, the House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Royce Part A amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-14T15:05:36-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Moore moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Financial Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1708" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1708" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-14T15:06:24-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Moore motion to recommit with instructions, pending reservation of a point of order. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment providing for consideration of H. Con. Res. 125, establishing the congressional budget for the United States Government for FY 2017.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-14T15:12:59-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hensarling raised a point of order against the motion to recommit with instructions. Mr. Hensarling stated that the amendment contained provisions not germane to the bill. Sustained by the Chair.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1708" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-14T15:13:19-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Moore appealed the ruling of the chair. The question was then put on sustaining the ruling of the chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-14T15:13:35-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hensarling moved to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the chair</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1709" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-14T15:35:20-04:00">
      <text>On motion to table the appeal of the ruling of the Chair Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 239 - 176 (Roll No. 145).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="146" datetime="2016-04-14T15:41:38-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 239 - 179 (Roll no. 146).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1699" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-04-14T15:41:39-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-18">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Consumer Protection and Financial Institutions" code="HSBA15" name="House Financial Services" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="114" relation="unknown" number="671"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Financial Stability Oversight Council"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h973"/>
    <amendment number="h972"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2016-04-14T12:45:38Z" status="Passed House amended">Financial Stability Oversight Council Reform Act 

This bill amends the Financial Stability Act of 2010 to make the budgets of the Financial Stability Oversight Council (FSOC) and the Office of Financial Research (OFR) subject to the annual appropriations process and to establish requirements for reports and a public notice and comment period.

(Sec. 2) The budgets of the FSOC and the OFR are funded by assessments on financial institutions which are deposited into the Financial Research Fund and, under current law, are immediately available to be spent. This bill requires the funding from the Financial Research Fund to be made available by appropriations Acts.

(Sec. 3) The OFR must submit quarterly reports to Congress regarding its:

 finances; workforce; and actions taken to achieve the goals, objectives, and performance measures of the office. (Sec. 4) The OFR must provide a public notice and comment period of at least 90 days before issuing any proposed report, rule, or regulation.

(Sec. 5) The bill expands the duties of the OFR to include:

 publishing an annual work plan; consulting with other federal departments and agencies with relevant expertise prior to preparing any public report with respect to a specified entity, class of entities, or financial product or service; and developing and implementing a cybersecurity plan. The Government Accountability Office must annually audit the cybersecurity plan and its implementation.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-473</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
