<bill session="115" type="h" number="6126" updated="2019-04-18T16:24:45Z">
  <state datetime="2018-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to provide support to State and local governments in their efforts to counter violent extremist threats.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PREVENT Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PREVENT Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Radical Extremist's Violent Endeavors Now and Tomorrow Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Radical Extremist&#8217;s Violent Endeavors Now and Tomorrow Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">PREVENT Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000371"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Counterterrorism and Intelligence.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Intelligence and Counterterrorism" code="HSHM05" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-06-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Preventing Radical Extremist's Violent Endeavors Now and Tomorrow Act of 2018 or the PREVENT Act of 2018

This bill expands the duties of the Office for State and Local Government Coordination in the Department of Homeland Security to include, for purposes of countering violent extremist threats: (1) providing training from specially trained clinical social workers, psychologists, religious, community leaders, and law enforcement personnel to assist local efforts at securing the homeland; and (2) in coordination with the Federal Bureau of Investigation, providing to state and local governments specialists, analysts, and agents trained to counter terrorism to assist local efforts at responding to such threats.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
