<bill session="114" type="h" number="1644" updated="2018-11-21T20:17:11Z">
  <state datetime="2016-01-12T17:00:27-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-01-12T17:00:27-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STREAM Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Transparent Regulatory and Environmental Actions in Mining Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">STREAM Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Supporting Transparent Regulatory and Environmental Actions in Mining Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">STREAM Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Supporting Transparent Regulatory and Environmental Actions in Mining Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to ensure transparency in the development of environmental regulations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Supporting Transparent Regulatory and Environmental Actions in Mining Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001195"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001282" joined="2015-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001295" joined="2015-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000266" joined="2015-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001094" joined="2015-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2015-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000619" joined="2015-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000459" joined="2015-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2015-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000568" joined="2015-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000558" joined="2015-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000297" joined="2015-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000292" joined="2015-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000289" joined="2015-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000295" joined="2015-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000376" joined="2015-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000388" joined="2015-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2015-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2015-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000566" joined="2015-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2015-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001177" joined="2015-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001180" joined="2015-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001189" joined="2015-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000189" joined="2015-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000600" joined="2015-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000395" joined="2015-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000592" joined="2015-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000598" joined="2015-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000364" joined="2015-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000467" joined="2015-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000470" joined="2015-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000821" joined="2015-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2015-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000018" joined="2015-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-09-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 23 - 12.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-09-10">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-01">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 114-277.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-10-01" calendar="Union" number="209">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 209.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-01-11T18:50:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 583 Reported to House. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 1644, S.J. Res. 22 and H.R. 3662. The resolution also provides for proceedings during the period from January 14, 2016, through January 22, 2016.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-12T14:30:36-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 583.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H308-323" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-12T14:30:41-05:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 1644, S.J. Res. 22 and H.R. 3662. The resolution also provides for proceedings during the period from January 14, 2016, through January 22, 2016.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-12T14:31:09-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 583 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-12T14:31:10-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Erik Paulsen to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-12T14:31:33-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1644.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-12T15:37:32-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 583, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lamborn amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-12T15:41:44-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 583, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kildee amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-12T15:47:15-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Kildee amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Kildee demanded a recorded voted and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-12T15:47:49-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 583, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cartwright amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-12T15:59:05-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Cartwright amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Cartwright demanded a recorded voted and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-12T15:59:56-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 583, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Sewell amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-12T16:05:28-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Sewell amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Sewell demanded a recorded voted and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-12T16:37:45-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1644.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-12T16:38:20-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H321" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-12T16:38:31-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H315-316" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-12T16:40:10-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Kildee moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H321-322" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H321" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-12T16:40:23-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kildee motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to insert language stating that either an imminent or long-term threat to human life or increase the incidence or prevalence of lung cancer, heart or kidney disease, birth defects, or heavy metal contaimination in communities in the vicinities of mountaintop removal cola mining projects.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-12T16:48:02-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H322" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-12T16:54:28-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 186 - 237 (Roll no. 41).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="42" datetime="2016-01-12T17:00:27-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 235 - 188 (Roll no. 42).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-01-12T17:00:28-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-19">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="114" relation="unknown" number="583"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h908"/>
    <amendment number="h907"/>
    <amendment number="h906"/>
    <amendment number="h905"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2016-01-12T12:01:24Z" status="Passed House amended">Supporting Transparent Regulatory and Environmental Actions in Mining Act or the STREAM Act

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to direct the Department of the Interior to make publicly available online and in the Federal Register, 90 days before publication, any draft, proposed, supplemental, final, or emergency rule, or any environmental analysis, economic assessment, policy, or guidance, and each scientific product upon which Interior has relied in developing the rule, the analysis, or the assessment.

A scientific product is any product that:

 employs the scientific method for inventorying, monitoring, experimenting, studying, researching, or modeling purposes; is relied upon by Interior in developing any rule, environmental analysis, economic assessment, policy, or guidance; and is not protected under copyright laws. For scientific products receiving federal funds Interior must also make publicly available the raw data used for them (any computational process or quantitative or qualitative data not protected by copyright or containing personally identifiable information, sensitive intellectual property, trade secrets, or business-sensitive information).

If Interior fails to make publicly available any scientific product for longer than six months, it must withdraw the rule, environmental analysis, or economic assessment policy or guidance. This requirement shall not apply if a delay in the publication of a rule will pose an imminent and severe threat to human life.

(Sec. 3) Interior shall arrange with the National Academy of Sciences for its Board on Earth Sciences and Resources to conduct a detailed, comprehensive study of the effectiveness of the "Surface Coal Mining and Reclamation Operations Permanent Regulatory Program; Stream Buffer Zones and Fish, Wildlife, and Related Environmental Values" Final Rule in protecting perennial and intermittent streams through the use of stream buffer zones. The study shall include suggestions and recommendations for increasing the effectiveness of the rule if it finds regulatory inefficiencies.

Appropriations for the study are authorized for FY2016-FY2017.

 Until one year after publication of the Board's report to Congress, Interior may not issue any proposed or final regulations under the Act that relate either to stream buffer zones or to stream protection.

(Sec. 4) The Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 is further amended to declare that nothing in it authorizes Interior to take any action that duplicates, implements, interprets, enforces, or determines compliance with specified mining, environmental, or fish and wildlife law.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-277</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
