<bill session="114" type="s" number="2114" updated="2018-06-02T07:10:27Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to correct inconsistencies in the definitions relating to Native Americans in the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to correct inconsistencies in the definitions relating to Native Americans in the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2015-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2015-10-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5475"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-01T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill amends title I (Quality, Affordable Health Care for All Americans) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to add a definition of &#8220;Indian.&#8221; This definition includes individuals of Indian descent who are members of an Indian community served by the Indian Health Service and individuals considered by the Department of Health and Human Services to be Indian for purposes of eligibility for Indian health care services, including California Indians, Eskimos, Aleuts, or other Alaska Natives.

Individuals included in the above definition are eligible for special monthly enrollment periods on health insurance exchanges and elimination of cost-sharing under individual health coverage for those whose income is not more than 300% of the poverty line. (Currently, only members of Indian tribes are eligible for these benefits.)

Indians are exempted from the penalty for not maintaining minimum essential health coverage.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
