<bill session="113" type="h" number="3660" updated="2016-10-25T16:09:26Z">
  <state datetime="2013-12-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alerting Local Leaders and Ensuring Responsible Guidelines for Youth Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ALLERGY Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require local educational agencies to implement a policy on allergy bullying in schools.</title>
    <title type="display">ALLERGY Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000210" joined="2013-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2013-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001187" joined="2013-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2013-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000599" joined="2013-12-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Allergies"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-12-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Alerting Local Leaders and Ensuring Responsible Guidelines for Youth Act or the ALLERGY Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to condition each local educational agency's (LEA's) receipt of funds under the ESEA on the LEA establishing and implementing a policy on allergy bullying that requires its schools to:

 educate students, school personnel, and parents about allergy bullying and about such bullying being against school rules; clearly define what the punishment or response may be for violating the rule against allergy bullying, which may include a therapeutic response, where appropriate; encourage each victim of allergy bullying to report such bullying to school personnel; and remain in compliance with the requirements of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act and the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 in carrying out these requirements. Requires the LEAs to submit an annual written certification to their state that they have established and implemented such policy.

Defines "allergy bullying" as unwanted, aggressive behavior by a student toward another student with an allergy, including: (1) a real or perceived imbalance of power due to such other student's allergy; and (2) actions such as making threats, spreading rumors, making physical or verbal attacks, and excluding such other student from a group on purpose.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
