<bill session="115" type="s" number="1374" updated="2019-04-18T16:37:12Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend the principle of federalism to State drug policy, provide access to medical marijuana, and enable research into the medicinal properties of marijuana.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CARERS Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CARERS Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Compassionate Access, Research Expansion, and Respect States Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Compassionate Access, Research Expansion, and Respect States Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">CARERS Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3556-3557" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1820"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="1764"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="2920"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alternative treatments"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Compassionate Access, Research Expansion, and Respect States Act of 2017 or the CARERS Act of 2017

This bill amends the Controlled Substances Act to provide that the Act's regulatory controls and administrative, civil, and criminal penalties do not apply to a person who produces, possesses, distributes, dispenses, administers, tests, recommends, or delivers medical marijuana in compliance with state law.

The bill also:

 excludes "cannabidiol" (CBD) from the definition of "marijuana"; limits the concentration of delta-9-tetrahydrocannabinol (THC) in CBD to 0.3 percent on a dry weight basis; and deems marijuana grown or processed to make CBD, in accordance with state law, to comply with the THC concentration limit unless the Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA) determines state law to be unreasonable. The bill directs the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to terminate the Public Health Service's interdisciplinary review process that is used to evaluate applications for medical marijuana research. The DEA must license manufacturers and distributors of marijuana for medical research; HHS must register practitioners to conduct research; and the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) must authorize VA health care providers to provide recommendations and opinions to veterans regarding participation in their states' marijuana programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
