<bill session="114" type="s" number="3336" updated="2019-03-03T14:41:17Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-10">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-12-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="amended by senate">A bill to provide installation reutilization authority for arsenals, depots, and plants.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide arsenal installation reutilization authority.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to provide installation reutilization authority for arsenals, depots, and plants.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2016-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2016-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2016-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2016-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-05">
      <text>Senate Committee on Armed Services discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-05">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6684" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2016-12-05" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-12-05">
      <text>Senate vitiated previous passage.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6688, S6716" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-05">
      <text>Senate vitiated previous discharge from the Senate Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-10">
      <text>Senate Committee on Armed Services discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-10">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7102-7103" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2016-12-10" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7102-7103" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-12-12">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-12T15:06:23-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-12T16:50:45-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6153"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Military command and structure"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s5129"/>
    <amendment number="s5128"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2016-12-10T20:19:57Z" status="Passed Senate amended">(Sec. 1) This bill authorizes the Army, in the case of a military manufacturing arsenal, depot, or plant (a government-owned, government-operated defense plant of the Army that manufactures weapons, weapon components, or both), to authorize leases of and contracts for non-excess military property for a term of up to 25 years if it determines that such a lease or contract will promote the national defense or be in the public interest for the purpose of:

 helping to maintain the viability of such arsenal, depot, or plant and any military installations on which it is located; eliminating, or at least reducing, the cost of government ownership of the arsenal, depot, or plant; and leveraging private investment at the arsenal, depot, or plant through long-term facility use contracts, property management contracts, leases, or other agreements that support and advance the preceding purposes. The Army may delegate such authority to the commander of the major subordinate command of the Army responsible for the arsenal, depot, or plant, or if part of a larger military installation, the installation as a whole. The commander may approve such a lease or contract on a case-by-case or class basis. Any lease or contract approved utilizing such authority is subject to a 90-day hold period so that the Army real property manager may review it. If such manager disapproves of it, the agreement shall be null and void upon transmittal to the delegating authority of a written disapproval, including a justification, within the hold period. If no such disapproval is transmitted within such period, the agreement shall be deemed approved.

 If, by 60 days after receiving a disapproval, the delegating authority submits a new contract or lease that addresses the manager's concerns, it shall be deemed approved unless the manager transmits a disapproval within 30 days of submission.

 The authority under this bill shall terminate at the close of September 30, 2019.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
