<bill session="114" type="h" number="3773" updated="2018-06-02T04:46:16Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect Riders of Metrorail Public Transportation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, relating to the authority of the Secretary of Transportation under the public transportation safety program.</title>
    <title type="display">Protect Riders of Metrorail Public Transportation Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000147"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001105" joined="2015-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000290" joined="2015-10-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1487"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Highways and Transit" code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="22"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3763"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Protect Riders of Metrorail Public Transportation Act of 2015

This bill authorizes the Department of Transportation (DOT), in carrying out the public transportation safety program, to:

 conduct inspections, investigations, audits, examinations, and testing of the equipment, facilities, rolling stock, and operations of the public transportation system of a recipient of financial assistance; make reports and issue directives with respect to the safety of a recipient's system; subpoena and depose any employee of a recipient or of a state safety oversight agency, subject to certain administrative requirements, in conjunction with an accident investigation or an investigation into a pattern or practice of conduct negatively affecting public safety; and investigate public transportation accidents and incidents and provide guidance to recipients regarding their prevention. DOT may also administer state safety oversight activities for a rail fixed guideway system operating in more than two states, if the state safety oversight agency overseeing the system has become incapable of providing adequate safety oversight, until the states involved develop a state safety oversight program that DOT certifies as meeting specified criteria.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
