<bill session="115" type="h" number="5661" updated="2019-04-18T16:22:58Z">
  <state datetime="2018-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve access by Indian tribes to support from the Schools and Libraries Universal Service Support program (E-rate) of the Federal Communications Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tribal Connect Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tribal Connect Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Tribal Connect Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000570"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2018-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000580" joined="2018-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001190" joined="2018-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000171" joined="2018-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2205"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Libraries and archives"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates and fees"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-04-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Tribal Connect Act of 2018

This bill amends the Communications Act of 1934 to expand the Schools and Libraries Universal Service Support (E-rate) program to include support for Indian tribal libraries that are eligible for support under the Library Services and Technology Act (LSTA), without regard to whether the libraries are eligible for assistance from state library administrative agencies under the LSTA. The E-rate program provides discounted telecommunications services to certain schools and libraries.

The Federal Communications Commission must establish a Tribal Anchor Institution Program to provide E-rate support to tribes for institutions that are not schools or libraries, such as community centers. E-rate support may be provided to institutions designated by tribes if: (1) the tribes do not have existing libraries that are eligible for E-rate support; (2) the institutions are exclusively owned by the tribes; and (3) the institutions intend to deliver publicly available Internet access to students, teachers, librarians, and community members for educational purposes.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
