<bill session="114" type="h" number="2544" updated="2019-04-11T15:41:45Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the USEC Privatization Act to require the Secretary of Energy to issue a long-term Federal excess uranium inventory management plan, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Excess Uranium Transparency and Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="display">Excess Uranium Transparency and Accountability Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001248" joined="2015-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2015-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000460" joined="2015-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000636" joined="2015-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2016-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000588" joined="2015-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001172" joined="2015-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy" code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="1428"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Excess Uranium Transparency and Accountability Act 

This bill amends the USEC Privatization Act governing uranium transfers and sales to require the Department of Energy (DOE) to issue, beginning January 1, 2017, and at least once every 10 years afterwards, a long-term excess uranium inventory management plan that details how all forms of excess DOE uranium inventories will be managed for a minimum period of 10 years.

This management plan must outline DOE steps that will: (1) minimize the impact of DOE's transferring, selling, or otherwise providing uranium upon the domestic uranium mining, conversion, and enrichment industries; and (2) ensure that the federal government maximizes for itself the potential value of uranium.

DOE may provide from its stockpile up to 2100 and up to 2700 metric tons of uranium in any form (currently, only natural and low-enriched uranium) for the periods calendar 2016-2023 and beginning January 1, 2024, respectively.

 Before making any determination that the sale of the material will not have an adverse material impact on the domestic uranium mining, conversion, or enrichment industry, DOE shall publish the proposed determination in the Federal Register pursuant to a rulemaking.

Any market analysis prepared by or for DOE as part of the determination process shall be subject to a peer review process consistent with Office of Management and Budget guidelines.

Beginning on January 1, 2021, the requirement for a DOE determination of no adverse material impact on the domestic uranium industry shall be waived for transferring, selling, or otherwise providing uranium if it has been identified in an updated long-term federal excess uranium inventory management plan.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
