<bill session="113" type="h" number="2735" updated="2016-10-25T16:05:58Z">
  <state datetime="2013-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PLANT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Lands Against Narcotics Trafficking Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the United States Sentencing Commission with respect to penalties for the unlawful production of a controlled substance on Federal property or intentional trespass on the property of another that causes environmental damage.</title>
    <title type="display">PLANT Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000369" joined="2013-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2014-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001094" joined="2014-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000030" joined="2013-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2013-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2013-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against animals and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-07-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Lands Against Narcotics Trafficking Act of 2013 or the PLANT Act - Directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to review and amend the federal sentencing guidelines to ensure that they provide for additional penalties applicable to persons convicted of Controlled Substances Act offenses of manufacturing, distributing, dispensing, or possessing with intent to distribute a controlled substance or a counterfeit substance while on federal property or intentionally trespassing on the property of another, if the offense involves:

 the use of a poison, chemical, or hazardous substance for the unlawful production of a controlled substance that: (1) creates a serious hazard to humans, wildlife, or domestic animals; (2) degrades or harms the environment or natural resources; or (3) pollutes an aquifer, spring, stream, river, or body of water; the diversion, redirection, obstruction, draining, or impoundment of an aquifer, spring, river, or body of water for the unlawful production of a controlled substance; or the substantial removal of vegetation or clear cutting of timber for the unlawful production of a controlled substance.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
