<bill session="115" type="h" number="2767" updated="2019-04-18T16:09:59Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Act to require senior procurement executives, procurement center representatives, and the Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization to assist small business concerns participating in the Small Business Innovation Research Program and the Small Business Technology Transfer Program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stimulating Innovation through Procurement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stimulating Innovation through Procurement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Stimulating Innovation through Procurement Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001202"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Research and Technology" code="HSSY15" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2763"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Stimulating Innovation through Procurement Act of 2017

This bill amends the Small Business Act to require:

 the Small Business Administration (SBA) to coordinate with the senior procurement executives of federal agencies participating in a Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) Program or a Small Business Technology Transfer (STTR) Program to assist small businesses participating in such programs with commercializing research before the business is awarded a federal contract; the SBA to modify its policy directives to require procurement center representatives to assist small businesses participating in SBIR or STTR programs with researching solicitations for federal contracts and submitting bids; and each Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization to assist small businesses participating in SBIR or STTR programs with researching solicitations for federal contracts and submitting bids.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
