<bill session="114" type="s" number="3289" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:37Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit scheduled passenger air transportation between the United States and Cuba until a study has been completed regarding security measures and equipment at Cuba's airports and certain agreements have been established with the Government of Cuba, to amend title 49, United States Code, to clarify the role of the Secretary of Homeland Security regarding security standards at foreign airports, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cuban Airport Security Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="display">Cuban Airport Security Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2016-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5728"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Service animals"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Cuban Airport Security Act of 2016

This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to report to Congress on specified aspects of security measures at Cuban airports that: (1) are served by U.S. aircraft operators, or (2) serve as last point of departure locations for foreign air carriers. The Government Accountability Office shall submit to Congress an audit of the report.

The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) shall establish agreements with the Government of Cuba to allow:

 the Federal Air Marshal Service to conduct missions on regularly scheduled passenger air flights between the United States and Cuba, and TSA inspectors to access all areas of last point of departure airports in Cuba to assess security. No agreement dated on or after January 1, 2016, to expand air flights between the United States and Cuba may be permitted until: (1)&#160;the required report and audit have been submitted, (2)&#160;the required agreements have been established, and (3) specified hiring and training requirements have been met.

DHS, rather than the Department of Transportation, shall: (1)&#160;assess the effectiveness of security standards at foreign airports, and (2) take other specified actions if an airport fails to maintain effective security measures.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
