<bill session="114" type="sr" number="535" updated="2018-06-02T06:21:24Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-06">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-12-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding the trafficking of illicit fentanyl into the United States from Mexico and China.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding the trafficking of illicit fentanyl into the United States from Mexico and China.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2016-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000461" joined="2016-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5171-5172" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-12-06" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-12-07">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Corker with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and with an amended preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-12-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="707">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 707.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-07T16:06:01Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Expresses the sense of the Senate that:

 the use of illicit fentanyl in the United States and the resulting overdose deaths are a public health crisis; the trafficking of illicit fentanyl into the United States, especially by transnational criminal organizations, is a problem that requires close cooperation between the U.S. government and the governments of Mexico and China; and all three such countries have a shared interest in, and responsibility for, stopping the production of illicit fentanyl and its trafficking into the United States. Calls for the United States to:

 support the efforts by the governments of Mexico and China to stop such production and trafficking; take further measures to reduce and prevent heroin and fentanyl consumption through enhanced enforcement to reduce the illegal supply and increased use of evidence-based prevention, treatment, and recovery services; and use its broad diplomatic and law enforcement resources, in partnership with the governments of China and Mexico, to stop such production and trafficking.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
