<bill session="114" type="s" number="1293" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:55Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Department of Energy as the lead agency for coordinating all requirements under Federal law with respect to eligible clean coal and advanced coal technology generating projects, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to establish the Department of Energy as the lead agency for coordinating all requirements under Federal law with respect to eligible clean coal and advanced coal technology generating projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001069"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2015-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-09">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="601"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill designates the Department of Energy (DOE) as the lead agency to coordinate all federal requirements under the Clean Air Act, the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, the Endangered Species Act of 1973, the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, and the Safe Drinking Water Act regarding clean coal and advanced coal technology generating projects which:

 install and operate an advanced carbon capture and storage technology or carbon capture utilization and storage technology at a new or existing steam generating unit; or increase the efficiency of converting coal to either a useful energy, or to a feedstock for the manufacture of other products. DOE is also required to establish a schedule for all federal authorizations with respect to such projects, including:

 setting binding intermediate milestones and deadlines to ensure expeditious completion of all proceedings and final action on all pertinent federal authorizations, requiring all permit decisions and related environmental reviews to be completed within one year after the date on which a complete application for each environmental review is submitted, and coordinating state permitting and environmental requirements.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
