<bill session="115" type="s" number="2165" updated="2019-04-18T16:40:30Z">
  <state datetime="2017-11-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-11-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-11-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide additional disaster recovery assistance for the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and the United States Virgin Islands, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Puerto Rico and Virgin Islands Equitable Rebuild Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Puerto Rico and Virgin Islands Equitable Rebuild Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Puerto Rico and Virgin Islands Equitable Rebuild Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2017-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2017-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2017-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001075" joined="2017-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2017-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2018-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2017-11-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-11-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="261"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2404"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2530"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2531"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2026"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2263"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="4782"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-11-28T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Puerto Rico and Virgin Islands Equitable Rebuild Act of 2017

This bill provides for additional disaster-recovery assistance and other assistance to Puerto Rico and the U.S. Virgin Islands&#160;with respect to&#160;infrastructure, health care, agriculture, education, economic development, and environmental remediation,&#160;among other sectors. Specifically, regarding both territories, the bill:

 provides for the use of certain emergency assistance to rebuild electric grids; establishes several grant programs to&#160;promote energy efficiency and renewable energy; subject to specified oversight requirements, increases funding for transportation infrastructure, telecommunications systems, housing, and community development; increases&#160;funding for the Medicaid and Medicare programs; temporarily increases social-services block-grant allotments; increases&#160;funding for, and otherwise revises, rural and agricultural programs; increases funding for the Department of Veterans Affairs; provides for aid to the Head Start program, elementary and secondary education programs, and higher education programs; increases funding for training and employment services; modifies provisions concerning the earned-income tax credit, the child tax credit, and unemployment assistance; increases funding for economic and community development programs; increases funding for environmental remediation; and otherwise modifies provisions related to emergency funding and disaster-recovery assistance. In addition, the bill:

 extends Medicaid waiver authority to all territories, provides for Medicaid disproportionate share hospital allotments to the territories, and otherwise revises the Medicaid and Medicare programs with respect to the territories; extends participation in the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program to all territories; modifies provisions concerning the application of certain workers' protections in Puerto Rico; and requires the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to submit to Congress a long-term disaster-relief plan&#160;with respect to&#160;Puerto Rico and the U.S Virgin Islands.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
