<bill session="114" type="s" number="1405" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:54Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Severe Fuel Supply Emergency Response Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require a coordinated response to coal fuel supply emergencies that could impact electric power system adequacy or reliability.</title>
    <title type="display">Severe Fuel Supply Emergency Response Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000457"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-09">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Severe Fuel Supply Emergency Response Act of 2015

This bill amends the Federal Power Act to direct the Department of Energy (DOE) to lead a coordinated federal response to severe fuel supply emergencies. A severe fuel supply emergency is a coal supply deficiency reported to DOE that has the potential to affect at least 500 megawatts of electricity generation or 100,000 electricity customers.

 DOE's duties are to:

 promptly investigate the circumstances of the emergency; notify the Surface Transportation Board and the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) of the existence of the emergency; convene a meeting with the Board, FERC, and, as appropriate, the Electric Reliability Organization and affected Regional Entities and Reliability Coordinators; and submit in writing to the Board and to FERC, and publicize on the DOE website, recommendations for actions by either the Board or FERC to alleviate the emergency and to prevent future recurrences.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
