<bill session="114" type="s" number="2630" updated="2018-06-02T07:15:30Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pay Stub Disclosure Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to require certain disclosures be included on employee pay stubs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Pay Stub Disclosure Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000457"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2016-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2016-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2016-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2016-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4376"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Pay Stub Disclosure Act

This bill amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to require each employer to provide an initial disclosure to each employee who is not subject to exemption from minimum wage and maximum hour requirements within 15 days after: (1) the employee is hired, or (2) specified information in the initial disclosure changes.

The information specified in that initial disclosure shall include:

 the pay rate and form of compensation; the name of the employer and any other name used by the employer to conduct business; and the physical address and telephone number of the employer's main office or principal place of business, and a mailing address if different from the first one. The bill specifies additional disclosures that must be in each pay stub, including the pay period covered, the employee's name, the total hours worked by the employee, benefits, allowances, and reimbursements.

The bill also prescribes the form of the pay stub as well as employer notice requirements.

An employer shall keep records of the information disclosed in an employee's pay stub for three years from each stub's issuance.

In the event that an employee who is not subject to minimum wage and maximum hourexemptions requests an inspection of his or her records, the employer shall provide copies of them for up to three years before the request.

The bill prescribes civil penalties for employer failure to comply with this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
