<bill session="114" type="h" number="5663" updated="2019-04-11T15:42:42Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 to deliver high-quality career and technical education opportunities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Critical Thinking, Collaboration, Communication, and Creativity for Careers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Four C's for Careers Act</title>
    <title type="display">Four C's for Careers Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001106"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000565" joined="2016-07-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Critical Thinking, Collaboration, Communication, and Creativity for Careers Act or the Four C's for Careers Act

This bill amends the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 to revise requirements for the local use of funds received by eligible recipients under the Act to support their career and technical education programs.

The bill requires such funds to be used by eligible recipients to support career and technical education programs that:

 train career guidance and academic counselors to use labor market information in assisting students with postsecondary education and career planning; and support public-private partnerships designed to provide students with the credentials and skills required to secure employment in relevant fields; and if determined appropriate by the local educational agency, support programs that coordinate and integrate academic and career and technical education content and specified work-based learning opportunities. Funds may be used to assess resources required for promoting greater engagement and coordination with business and industry.

An eligible agency, with input from eligible recipients, may identify in its state plan, the acquisition of critical thinking, collaboration, communication, and creativity skills as additional indicators of performance for the career and technical education activities authorized under the Act.

State plans shall describe how eligible agencies will improve the critical thinking, communications, collaboration, and creativity skills of the students participating in their career and technical education programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
