<bill session="114" type="h" number="2738" updated="2018-06-02T04:27:55Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Highways Bettering the Economy and Environment Pollinator Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 23, United States Code, to encourage and facilitate efforts by States and other transportation rights-of-way managers to adopt integrated vegetation management practices, including enhancing plantings of native forbs and grasses that provide habitats and forage for Monarch butterflies, native bees, and other native pollinators, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Highways Bettering the Economy and Environment Pollinator Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000324"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001296" joined="2016-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2015-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2015-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000612" joined="2015-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000293" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000449" joined="2015-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2015-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2015-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2015-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2015-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2015-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001175" joined="2015-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000131" joined="2015-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Highways and Transit" code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Horticulture and plants"/>
    <term name="Insects"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Highways Bettering the Economy and Environment Pollinator Protection Act

 This bill authorizes as an eligible project cost for the construction of a federal-aid highway the cost of improving habitat and forage for pollinators (i.e., bees, birds, bats, Monarch and other butterflies) on rights-of-way adjacent to such highways.

The Department of Transportation, in conjunction with willing states, shall carry out programs that encourage:

 integrated vegetation management practices on roadsides and other transportation rights-of-way, including reduced mowing; the development of habitat and forage for pollinators through planting of native forbs and grasses, including noninvasive, native milkweed species; research and demonstration projects on economic and environmental benefits and best practices for integrated vegetation management, reduced mowing, and planting of native forbs and grasses for pollinator habitat, forage, and migratory way stations for Monarch butterflies and other migrating pollinators; and participation in such activities by representatives of transportation landscape management, pollinator health, agriculture, horticulture, and other affected communities. Federal funds may be used for the provision of habitat, forage, and migratory way stations for Monarch butterflies, other native pollinators, and honey bees that is related to a federally-funded highway project.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
