<bill session="114" type="h" number="5810" updated="2019-04-11T15:42:42Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a national, evidence-based, and comprehensive home study assessment standard for the evaluation of prospective foster parents and adoptive parents and provide funding to States to adopt this standard.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Adoption and Foster Care Home Study Act</title>
    <title type="display">National Adoption and Foster Care Home Study Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001270" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000559" joined="2016-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000581" joined="2016-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">National Adoption and Foster Care Home Study Act

This bill amends the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act to direct a state receiving from the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) a community-based formula grant for the prevention of child abuse and neglect to establish a demonstration program through which the state:

 adopts a specific evidence-based, uniform, national home study program for the evaluation of prospective foster parents and adoptive parents; and furnishes HHS with data gathered through operation of the program. HHS shall establish a national registry of home study reports filed by home study practitioners using an HHS-developed methodology meeting specified criteria. This registry must be accessible to state foster care and adoption agencies, or a designated entity as determined by the lead agency in the state, to assist with the selection of prospective foster parents and adoptive parents.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
