<bill session="114" type="s" number="913" updated="2019-03-03T14:40:55Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide an investment tax credit for waste heat to power technology.</title>
    <title type="display">An original bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide an investment tax credit for waste heat to power technology.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Hatch. With written report No. 114-23.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-04-14" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="46">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 46.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Lighting, heating, cooling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-14T15:11:21Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

(Sec. 1) This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an energy tax credit for investment in waste heat to power property. The property cannot have a capacity in excess of 50 megawatts.

The bill defines "waste heat to power property" as property: (1) comprising a system which generates electricity through the recovery of a qualified waste heat resource; and (2) that is placed in service before January 1, 2017. "Qualified waste heat resource" is defined as: (1) exhaust heat or flared gas from an industrial process that does not have as its primary purpose the production of electricity, and (2) a pressure drop in any gas for an industrial or commercial process.

The bill provides for a formula to limit the basis of any waste heat to power property for purposes of calculating the credit.

The amendments made by this section apply to taxable years ending after the enactment date of this Act.

(Sec. 2) The bill also increases from 30% to 35% the rate of the continuous levy on payments made after 180 days after the enactment date of this Act&#160;to Medicare providers and suppliers for unpaid taxes.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-23</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
