<bill session="114" type="h" number="3332" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:43Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Law Enforcement Torture Prevention Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide a criminal penalty for torture committed by law enforcement officers and others acting under color of law.</title>
    <title type="display">Law Enforcement Torture Prevention Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000096"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2015-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Law Enforcement Torture Prevention Act of 2015

 This bill amends the federal criminal code to impose a prison term of up to 10 years on any person who, acting under color of law, commits, or attempts or conspires to commit, torture. If death results from such torture, the offender shall be imprisoned for any term of years or for life.

"Torture" is defined to mean intentionally inflicting severe pain or suffering, whether physical or mental, on a person for such purposes as obtaining from that person or another person information or a confession, punishing that person, or intimidating or coercing that person or another person, or for any reason based on discrimination, but does not include pain or suffering arising only from, inherent in, or incidental to lawful sanctions.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
