<bill session="114" type="s" number="1317" updated="2018-06-02T06:53:26Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lifetime Income Disclosure Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to require a lifetime income disclosure.</title>
    <title type="display">Lifetime Income Disclosure Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2015-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="2317"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4067"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3471"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Lifetime Income Disclosure Act 

 Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to require the quarterly pension benefit statement furnished to a participant or beneficiary with the right to direct the investment of assets in his or her account under an individual account plan to include a lifetime income disclosure at least once during any 12-month period.

Requires such lifetime income disclosure to set forth the lifetime income stream equivalent of the participant's or beneficiary's total benefits accrued. Defines a lifetime income stream equivalent of the total benefits accrued as the monthly annuity payment the participant or beneficiary would receive if those total accrued benefits were used to provide lifetime income streams to a qualified joint and survivor annuitant.

Directs the Secretary of Labor to:

 issue a model lifetime income disclosure, written in a manner which can be understood by the average plan participant; and prescribe assumptions that plan administrators may use in converting total accrued benefits into lifetime income stream equivalents. Declares that no plan fiduciary, plan sponsor, or other person shall have any liability under ERISA solely by reason of the provision of lifetime income stream equivalents derived in accordance with such assumptions and related rules and including explanations contained in the model lifetime income disclosure.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
