<bill session="114" type="s" number="2486" updated="2018-06-02T07:14:29Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Electronic Warfare Capabilities Enhancement Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance electronic warfare capabilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Electronic Warfare Capabilities Enhancement Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000360"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2016-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2016-02-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4851"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2943"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Military command and structure"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Electronic Warfare Capabilities Enhancement Act of 2016

This bill permits the use of appropriations authorized for electromagnetic spectrum warfare systems and electronic warfare in order to develop and field electromagnetic spectrum warfare systems and electronic warfare capabilities.

The Bob Stump National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2003 is amended to include electronic warfare programs in the rapid acquisition authority program.

Electronic warfare is military action involving the use of electromagnetic and directed energy to control the electromagnetic spectrum or to attack the enemy, and includes electromagnetic spectrum warfare, which encompasses military communications and sensing operations that occur in the electromagnetic operational domain.

The Department of Defense shall delegate to the senior electronic warfare executive the authority to review and validate all Joint Capabilities Integration and Development System documents for electronic warfare acquisition programs.

The Electronic Warfare Executive Committee shall submit to the congressional defense committees a strategic plan with measurable and timely objectives to achieve its mission according to specified metrics.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
