<bill session="114" type="h" number="35" updated="2018-08-16T22:57:30Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-07T14:04:59-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-01-07T14:04:59-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Low-Dose Radiation Research Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Low-Dose Radiation Research Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To increase the understanding of the health effects of low doses of ionizing radiation.</title>
    <title type="display">Low-Dose Radiation Research Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001059"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001275" joined="2015-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2015-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000563" joined="2015-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2015-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000244" joined="2015-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000583" joined="2015-01-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-07T13:56:24-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (TX) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-07T13:56:34-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H82-83" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-07T13:56:35-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 35.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2015-01-07T14:04:59-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H82" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-01-07T14:05:01-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-08">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-09">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1806"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cell biology and embryology"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Radiation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-07T13:26:11Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Low-Dose Radiation Research Act of 2015

Requires the Director of the Department of Energy (DOE) Office of Science to carry out a research program on low dose radiation to enhance the scientific understanding of and reduce uncertainties associated with the effects of exposure to low dose radiation.

Requires the Director to enter into an agreement with the National Academies to conduct a study assessing the current status and development of a long-term strategy for low dose radiation research.

Requires such study to:

 identify current scientific challenges for understanding the long-term effects of ionizing radiation, assess the status of current low dose radiation research, formulate overall scientific goals for the future of low-dose radiation research, recommend a long-term strategic and prioritized research agenda to address scientific research goals for overcoming the identified scientific challenges in coordination with other research efforts, define the essential components of a research program that would address this research agenda within the universities and the National Laboratories, and assess the effectiveness of such a program. Directs the Secretary of Energy to deliver to Congress a five-year research plan that responds to the study's findings and recommendations and identifies and prioritizes research needs.

Makes DOE's limitation on human research inapplicable to research under this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
