<bill session="114" type="h" number="480" updated="2018-11-09T00:08:24Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Housing America's Workforce Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide incentives for employer-provided employee housing assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Housing America's Workforce Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000081"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-22T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Housing America's Workforce Act of 2015

 Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow employers a business-related tax credit for up to 50% (100% for small business employers) of the qualified housing expenses paid for the benefit of their employees. Defines "qualified housing expenses" to include homeownership assistance and rental assistance. Limits the amount of such credit to the lesser of $10,000 or 6% of an employee's home purchase price, or up to $5,000 for rental assistance. Excludes from employee gross income the value of employer-paid housing assistance.

Authorizes the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to award grants in FY2015-FY2017, on a competitive basis, to nonprofit housing organizations or local governments for certain costs, including operating costs and technical assistance costs, of employer-assisted housing programs. Requires the Secretary to establish a national clearinghouse, including a website, to provide information about employer-assisted housing programs to federal, state, and local governments and other interested entities.

Directs the Comptroller General to conduct a study of employer-assisted housing programs and provide the Secretary with an interim report by January 1, 2018, and final report by December 31, 2019.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
