<bill session="115" type="s" number="2256" updated="2019-04-18T16:40:52Z">
  <state datetime="2017-12-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-12-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-12-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend expiring provisions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tax Extender Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tax Extender Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Tax Extender Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2017-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2017-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2017-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2017-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2017-12-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-12-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1892"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1551"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2010"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2091"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2543"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3683"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="4857"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="122"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="666"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1535"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1663"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="407"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="110"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="721"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1403"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3761"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-12-20T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Tax Extender Act of 2017 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend various expiring tax deductions, credits, and rules.

The bill extends tax credits relating to:

 Indian employment, railroad track maintenance, mine rescue team training, qualified zone academy bonds, American Samoa economic development, nonbusiness energy property, new fuel cell motor vehicles, two-wheeled plug-in electric vehicles, alternative fuel vehicle refueling property, second generation biofuel producers, biodiesel and renewable diesel, Indian coal facilities, facilities producing energy from renewable resources, energy efficient new homes, and alternative fuels. The bill extends and modifies the tax credits for:

 residential energy property, investments in energy property, production from advanced nuclear power facilities, and carbon dioxide sequestration. The bill also extends provisions relating to:

 the tax exclusion for the discharge of principal residence indebtedness; the treatment of mortgage insurance premiums as qualified residence interest; deductions for tuition and related expenses, income attributable to domestic production activities in Puerto Rico, and energy efficient commercial buildings; depreciating or expensing various types of property; timber gains; empowerment zones; the cover over of rum excise taxes to Puerto Rico and the Virgin Islands; sales or dispositions to implement electric restructuring policies for electric utilities; and the oil spill liability trust fund.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
