<amendment session="114" chamber="s" number="652" updated="2018-06-04T02:15:43Z">
  <amends type="sc" number="11" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2015-03-25">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <offered datetime="2015-03-25"/>
  <description>To make college more affordable for middle-class families by allowing borrowers with outstanding Federal and private student loans to refinance at the equivalent interest rates that were offered to Federal student loan borrowers during the 2013-2014 school year and to fully offset the cost of such a program by requiring millionaires to pay at least a 30 percent effective Federal tax rate.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2015-03-25" how="roll" result="fail" roll="86">
      <text>Amendment SA 652 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 46 - 53. Record Vote Number: 86.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Amendment SA 652 proposed by Senator Reed for Senator Warren. (consideration: CR S1839-1840, S1840-1842, S1842-1844) To make college more affordable for middle-class families by allowing borrowers with outstanding Federal and private student loans to refinance at the equivalent interest rates that were offered to Federal student loan borrowers during the 2013-2014 school year and to fully offset the cost of such a program by requiring millionaires to pay at least a 30 percent effective Federal tax rate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25"/>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 652 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 46 - 53. Record Vote Number: 86.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Senate amendment not agreed to: Amendment SA 652 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 46 - 53. Record Vote Number: 86.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 652 proposed by Senator Reed for Senator Warren.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1839-1840, S1840-1842, S1842-1844" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
