<bill session="114" type="h" number="3039" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:18Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PROTECT US Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Retaliation Options against Those Engaging in Cyberattacks Targeting the United States Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To impose penalties on state-sponsors of cyberattacks, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">PROTECT US Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001274"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001103" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000546" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000583" joined="2015-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Financial Services, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Financial Services, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Financial Services, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Financial Services, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Trade" code="HSWM04" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets and economic espionage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Providing Retaliation Options against Those Engaging in Cyberattacks Targeting the United States Act or PROTECT US Act

This bill directs the President to submit to Congress a list of countries designated as state-sponsors of cyberattacks.

 A country shall be so designated if the President determines that the United States or a U.S. person has been targeted in a cyber-enabled activity originating from or directed by a person located in a foreign country, and such activity is likely to result in or have contributed to a threat to U.S. national security or foreign policy, or harmed U.S. economic health or financial stability or a U.S. person, or has the purpose or effect of:

 harming or compromising the provision of services by a computer or network of computers that support the United States or a U.S. person in a critical infrastructure sector; compromising the provision of services by the United States or a U.S. person in a critical infrastructure sector; disrupting the availability of a computer or network of computers owned or operated by the United States or a U.S. person; or causing a misappropriation of funds or economic resources, trade secrets, personally identifiable information, or financial information of the United States or a U.S. person. The President may impose a trade-related penalty and take other actions, including assistance limitations, trade embargoes, and cyber counter attacks, with respect to a designated country.

A country may be removed from the list of state-sponsors of cyberattacks if: (1) the President determines that it no longer meets the requirements for the designation, or (2) Congress enacts a law providing for such removal.

A country that has been removed from the list by Congress may not be added back to the list by the President until at least one year after removal.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
