<bill session="114" type="s" number="731" updated="2018-06-02T06:41:00Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Social Security Expansion Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance Social Security benefits and ensure the long-term solvency of the Social Security program.</title>
    <title type="display">Social Security Expansion Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1391"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5367"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5830"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Social Security Expansion Act

 Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act to:

 increase the primary insurance amount for all eligible beneficiaries, beginning in 2021; revise computation of cost-of-living adjustments to use the Consumer Price Index for Elderly Consumers; increase the special minimum primary insurance amount for lifetime low earners based on years in the workforce. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) apply employment and self-employment taxes to remuneration up to the contribution and benefit base and to remuneration in excess of $250,000; and (2) increase the tax on investment gain from 3.8% to 10% of the lesser of net investment income for such taxable year or the excess (if any) of the modified adjusted gross income for such taxable year, over the threshold amount, with 62% of such tax allocated to the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and 9% allocated to the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
