<bill session="114" type="h" number="3030" updated="2018-06-02T04:37:01Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-02">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Baudette Coast Guard Housing Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Baudette Coast Guard Housing Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Commandant of the Coast Guard to convey certain property from the United States to the City of Baudette, Minnesota.</title>
    <title type="display">Baudette Coast Guard Housing Conveyance Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000258"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-02">
      <text>Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-02">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-03-02" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-03-23">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 114-466.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-03-23" calendar="Union" number="355">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 355.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" code="HSPW07" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-23T13:26:37Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">Baudette Coast Guard Housing Conveyance Act

(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Coast Guard to convey specified federal land (including buildings, structures, utilities, and miscellaneous facilities) in Baudette, Minnesota, to the city of Baudette, upon payment to the United States of the property's fair market value.

The fair market value of the covered property must be:

 determined by a real estate appraiser selected by the city, and licensed to practice in Minnesota; and subject to the approval of the Coast Guard, considering specified requirements regarding use of the property. Any proceeds received by the United States from a conveyance under this Act shall be deposited in the Coast Guard Housing Fund.

As a condition of any conveyance under this Act, the Coast Guard shall require that all interest in and to the covered property revert to the United States if any part of the property ceases being used for:

 affordable housing or a related purpose, or infrastructure providing a public benefit approved by the city. The authority to convey the covered property shall expire four years after this Act's enactment.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-466</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
