<bill session="113" type="hr" number="206" updated="2016-10-25T15:54:45Z">
  <state datetime="2013-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that Congress and the States should investigate and correct abusive, unsanitary, and illegal abortion practices.</title>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that Congress and the States should investigate and correct abusive, unsanitary, and illegal abortion practices.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000458"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001273" joined="2013-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2013-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000448" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000292" joined="2013-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000186" joined="2013-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001188" joined="2013-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E624-625"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="sr" session="113" relation="identical" number="133"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-05-08T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that Congress and states should gather information about and correct: (1) abusive, unsanitary, and illegal abortion practices; and (2) the interstate referral of women and girls to facilities engaged in dangerous or illegal second- and third-trimester procedures.

Declares that Congress has the responsibility to: (1) investigate, and conduct hearings on, abortions performed near, at, or after viability and public policies regarding such abortions; and (2) evaluate the extent to which such abortions involve violations of the natural right to life of infants who are born alive or are capable of being born alive and therefore are entitled to equal protection under the law.

Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) there is a compelling government interest in protecting the lives of unborn children beginning at least from the stage at which substantial medical evidence indicates that they are capable of feeling pain, which is separate from the compelling governmental interest in protecting the lives of unborn children beginning at the stage of viability, and neither governmental interest is intended to replace the other; and (2) governmental review of public policies and outcomes relating to these issues is long overdue and is an urgent priority that must be addressed.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
