<bill session="114" type="s" number="3088" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:39Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide a deadline for compliance with an alternate safety compliance program and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to provide a deadline for compliance with an alternate safety compliance program and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001198"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2016-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2016-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-06-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-11-15">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Thune with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 114-372.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-11-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="665">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 665.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-11-15T13:42:57Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">(Sec.1)This bill revises the requirements of the U.S. Coast Guard's alternate safety compliance program for certain fishing vessels.

Specifically, the bill delays the date when vessels must comply with the program. Vessels must comply by the later of January 1, 2021, or the end of the three-year period after the Coast Guard issues a final rule establishing the program.The bill also requires vessels that are built before July 1, 2012, to comply with the program. Currently, vessels built before July 1, 2013, must comply.Additionally, a vessel built before July 1, 2012 that undergoes a major conversion after such date must comply with the program.

If the requirements of the program change after establishment, the Coast Guard must provide at least a three-year grace period for vessels to be in compliance with such requirements.

(Sec. 2) The Coast Guard must: (1) publish and disseminate a policy to standardize coordination, outreach, and design of the alternate safety compliance program; and (2) publish a public memorandum for the fishing, shipbuilding, and maritime industry and the public including guidance, timelines, and opportunities for public engagement.

(Sec. 4) The Coast Guard must report to Congress by June 1, 2018, on the progress of the design and implementation of the alternate safety compliance program.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-372</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
