<bill session="114" type="h" number="5941" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:27Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keep Taxpayer Dollars Safe from Terrorists Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for congressional review of transfers of funds from Executive agencies to state sponsors of terrorism, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Keep Taxpayer Dollars Safe from Terrorists Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001248" joined="2016-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000577" joined="2016-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000546" joined="2016-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000569" joined="2016-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000603" joined="2016-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000244" joined="2016-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000017" joined="2016-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5983"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Keep Taxpayer Dollars Safe from Terrorists Act of 2016

This bill prohibits an executive agency from transferring funds to a state sponsor of terrorism without prior written notice to Congress (with an exception for humanitarian assistance).

An intended transfer shall not take effect if Congress enacts a joint resolution disapproving the transfer.

An intended transfer shall not take effect until the latest of:

 the date occurring 60 days after Congress receives such written notice; in the case of a presidential veto of a joint resolution of disapproval, the earlier of the date on which either chamber fails to override the veto or the date occurring 30 session days after Congress received the veto; or the date the transfer otherwise would have taken effect (unless a joint resolution of disapproval is enacted). The bill provides a special rule for a written notice of transfer submitted within 60 legislative days before Congress adjourns.

The bill sets forth congressional procedures for such a joint resolution of disapproval.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
