<bill session="114" type="s" number="2283" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:38Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that small business providers of broadband Internet access service can devote resources to broadband deployment rather than compliance with cumbersome regulatory requirements.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Small Business Broadband Deployment Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Broadband Deployment Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Small Business Broadband Deployment Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2016-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2015-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2016-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2016-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7969" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7969-7970" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-06-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-12-06">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Thune with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-12-06" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="698">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 698.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-12-09">
      <text>By Senator Thune from Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation filed written report. Report No. 114-401. Additional views filed.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2666"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4596"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-06T14:17:06Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Small Business Broadband Deployment Act of 2016

(Sec. 2) This bill exempts any small business broadband Internet access service provider with not more than 250,000 subscribers from the enhancements to the transparency rule of the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) under which any person providing broadband Internet access service must disclose publicly accurate information regarding the network management practices, performance, and commercial terms of its broadband Internet access services sufficient for:

 consumers to make informed choices regarding their use; and content, application, service, and device providers to develop, market, and maintain Internet offerings. The FCC shall:

 report to Congress, within 180 days of enactment of this bill, its recommendations (including supporting data) on whether the exception should be made permanent, and whether the definition of "small business," for purposes of the exception, should be modified; and within 180 days after such report, commence a rulemaking proceeding to implement the recommendations. This small business exception shall terminate after the later of: (1) three years after enactment of this bill; or (2) the date on which the FCC adopts rules in its rulemaking proceeding for implementing its recommendations.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-401</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
