<bill session="114" type="h" number="1709" updated="2019-02-14T23:30:52Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to provide for the assessment and management of the risks of drought to drinking water, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to provide for the assessment and management of the risks of drought to drinking water, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001166"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001036" joined="2015-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2015-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2015-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001163" joined="2015-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2015-03-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Environment and Climate Change" code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="212"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="460"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4653"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6116"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to direct the Environmental Protection Agency to develop and submit to Congress a strategic plan for assessing and managing risks associated with drought to drinking water provided by public water systems.

The plan must include steps and time lines to:

 evaluate the risks posed by drought to drinking water provided by public water systems; establish a comprehensive list of the effects of drought on drinking water that may have an adverse effect on human health; summarize the known adverse human health effects, factors that cause drought, and factors that exacerbate the effects of drought on drinking water provided by public water systems; determine whether to establish guidance for quantifying the effects of drought on drinking water and for determining the frequency of monitoring necessary to detect the effects; recommend feasible treatment options to mitigate such effects, including procedures, equipment, and source water protection practices; and enter into cooperative agreements with, and provide technical assistance to, affected states and public water systems to manage risks associated with the effects of drought on drinking water.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
