<bill session="114" type="s" number="2399" updated="2019-03-03T14:41:02Z">
  <state datetime="2015-12-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-12-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for emissions reductions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Climate Protection and Justice Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Climate Protection and Justice Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Lighting, heating, cooling"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-12-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Climate Protection and Justice Act of 2015

 This bill amends the Clean Air Act to address greenhouse gas emissions. Specifically, the bill:

 states as U.S. policy greenhouse gas emission targets for 2020, 2030, 2040, and 2050 that will result in reducing the emissions 80% below 1990 levels by 2050; establishes a fee for manufacturing, producing, or importing certain carbon polluting substances (coal, petroleum, and natural gas) that increases over time; establishes the Interagency Climate Council to evaluate whether the targets are being met; requires the Environmental Protection Agency to issue regulations to ensure the targets are met if the council finds the targets are not being met; requires those fees to be deposited in the Carbon Fee Rebate Fund established by this bill; establishes the Carbon Fee Rebate Program, which will distribute proceeds from the fees to eligible U.S. residents; establishes a Climate Justice Resiliency Grant Program to fund projects that mitigate climate impacts on communities that are unable to afford the management or mitigation of those impacts; expands the definition of solid waste under the Clean Air Act and applies air pollution emission limits to those wastes; and establishes a fee on carbon pollution-intensive goods imported into the United States, requires the fees to be deposited in the Carbon Equivalency Fee Fund established by this bill, and requires the fund to be used for certain purposes, including improving industrial energy efficiency. The bill provides funding for the Weatherization Assistance Program, the Energy Efficiency and Conservation Block Grant Program, and the Rural Energy for America Program.

 The bill revises the Food Security Act of 1985 by providing incentives for farmers to use no-till cultivation practices and sustainable fertilizer application practices.

 The bill revises the Federal Power Act to enable access on the electric grid for demand response programs (programs that enable customers to reduce or shift their power use during peak demand periods).</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
