<bill session="114" type="s" number="3330" updated="2018-06-02T07:48:05Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accountability to Safeguard Veterans from Violent Crimes Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reduce the benefits of employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs who are medical professionals and were convicted of violent crimes against veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Accountability to Safeguard Veterans from Violent Crimes Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000934"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2016-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="473"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1994"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3595"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6062"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="290"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2921"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Accountability to Safeguard Veterans from Violent Crimes Act of 2016

This bill prohibits the covered service of an individual who is removed (or who retires before being removed) from a specified medical professional position in the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) and who is convicted of committing a crime of violence against a veteran while employed in such position from being taken into account for purposes of calculating a federal retirement annuity for such individual.

"Covered service" means the period of service beginning on the date the VA determines such individual engaged in activity that gave rise to the removal action and ending on the date such individual is removed from or leaves VA employment. An individual whose annuity is reduced pursuant to this bill shall be entitled to be paid so much of such individual's lump-sum credit as is attributable to such period of covered service.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
