<bill session="114" type="h" number="4743" updated="2019-02-14T22:54:55Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-16T18:51:37-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-05-16T18:51:37-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Cybersecurity Preparedness Consortium Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">National Cybersecurity Preparedness Consortium Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">National Cybersecurity Preparedness Consortium Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a National Cybersecurity Preparedness Consortium, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security to work with cybersecurity consortia for training, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">National Cybersecurity Preparedness Consortium Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2016-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000399" joined="2016-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001073" joined="2016-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000588" joined="2016-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000583" joined="2016-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2016-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Security Technologies.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-28">
      <text>Subcommittee on Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Security Technologies Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-05-13">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 114-565.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-05-13" calendar="Union" number="438">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 438.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-05-16T17:30:39-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Ratcliffe moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-16T17:30:52-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2409-2411" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-16T17:30:54-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4743.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-16T17:43:07-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-16T18:31:21-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2415-2416" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="194" datetime="2016-05-16T18:51:37-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 394 - 3 (Roll no. 194).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2409" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-05-16T18:51:38-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-17">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Innovation" code="HSHM08" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3295"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-16T15:29:57Z" status="Passed House amended">National Cybersecurity Preparedness Consortium Act of 2016

(Sec. 2) This bill authorizes the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to work with a consortium, including the National Cybersecurity Preparedness Consortium, to support efforts to address cybersecurity risks and incidents, including threats or acts of terrorism.

Such a consortium must be composed primarily of nonprofit entities, including academic institutions, that develop, update, and deliver cybersecurity training in support of homeland security.

DHS may work with such a consortium to assist its national cybersecurity and communications integration center to:

 provide training to state and local first responders and officials, develop curriculums, and provide technical assistance; conduct cross-sector cybersecurity training and simulation exercises, including for state and local governments, critical infrastructure owners and operators, and private industry; help states and communities develop cybersecurity information sharing programs; and help incorporate cybersecurity risk and incident prevention and response into existing state and local emergency plans and continuity of operations plans. In selecting a consortium, DHS must consider: (1) any prior experience conducting cybersecurity training and exercises for state and local entities, and (2) the geographic diversity of its members to cover different regions across the United States.

DHS must conduct outreach to universities and colleges regarding opportunities to support efforts to address cybersecurity risks and incidents.

DHS's authority to carry out this bill terminates five years after its enactment.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-565</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
