<bill session="114" type="h" number="4793" updated="2019-02-13T17:31:19Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Everglades Land Acquisition Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to acquire land south of Lake Okeechobee, Florida, for the purpose of flood damage reduction and water storage, treatment, and conveyance purposes, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Everglades Land Acquisition Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001102"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Everglades"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Everglades Land Acquisition Act of 2016

This bill directs the Department of the Interior to carry out, south of Lake Okeechobee, Florida, land acquisition projects for flood damage reduction and water storage, treatment, and conveyance purposes.

The bill prohibits Interior from paying more than the land's fair market value.

Upon the acquisition of such land, Interior, in consultation with the Army Corps of Engineers, shall provide for:

 the restoration of the acquired land for flood damage reduction and water storage, treatment, and conveyance purposes; and the utilization of the land in conjunction with projects that implement the Comprehensive Everglades Restoration Plan. Interior may transfer or sell the land acquired under this Act to the Army Corps of Engineers, the state of Florida, a political subdivision of the state, or a nonprofit conservation organization.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
