<bill session="114" type="s" number="2142" updated="2018-06-02T07:10:45Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Workplace Democracy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Labor Relations Act to establish an efficient system to enable employees to form, join, or assist labor organizations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Workplace Democracy Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2015-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2015-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2015-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2015-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2015-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2015-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2015-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2015-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2015-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2015-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2015-10-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="3690"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2398"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5000"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="National Labor Relations Board (NLRB)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Workplace Democracy Act

This bill amends the National Labor Relations Act to require the National Labor Relations Board (NLRB) to certify without an election an individual or labor organization as the exclusive representative of the employees in a unit appropriate for bargaining if a majority of the employees has signed valid authorizations designating the individual or labor organization specified in a properly filed petition as their bargaining representative and no other individual or labor organization is currently certified or recognized as the exclusive representative of any of the employees in the unit.

The NLRB shall develop guidelines and procedures for the designation by employees of a bargaining representative.

Deadlines are prescribed for critical turns in collective bargaining to establish an initial agreement upon the request of an individual or labor organization that has been newly organized or certified as a representative. The first meeting shall convene within 10 days after the employer receives a request. Either party to a negotiation may, 90 days after commencement, notify the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service of the existence of a dispute and request mediation. The Service shall refer the dispute to an arbitration board if the parties are not brought to agreement within 30 days after the request for mediation.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
