<bill session="114" type="h" number="4394" updated="2019-02-08T20:13:12Z">
  <state datetime="2016-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">OCEAN Research Partnerships Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Opportunities in Cooperative Education And New Research Partnerships Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize and amend the National Sea Grant College Program Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">OCEAN Research Partnerships Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001036" joined="2016-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2016-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2016-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-01-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water, Oceans, and Wildlife" code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1900"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="764"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2328"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3282"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Seafood"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-01-25T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Opportunities in Cooperative Education And New Research Partnerships Act or the OCEAN Research Partnerships Act

This bill amends the National Sea Grant College Program Act to revise and reauthorize through FY2021 the National Sea Grant College Program.

The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) must award Dean John A. Knauss Marine Policy Fellowships. Currently, NOAA has discretion in awarding such fellowships. These fellowships support the placement of graduate students in fields related to ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes resources in positions with the executive and legislative branches.

In placing marine policy fellows in the legislative branch, NOAA must give priority to positions in: (1) offices or committees of Congress that have jurisdiction over NOAA; and (2) offices of Members of Congress that have a demonstrated interest in ocean, coastal, or Great Lakes resources.

The bill authorizes through FY2021 grants for university research on: (1) the biology, prevention, and control of aquatic nonnative species; (2) oyster diseases, oyster restoration, and oyster-related human health risks; (3) the biology, prevention, and forecasting of harmful algal blooms; and (4) sustainable aquaculture techniques and technologies. The bill also authorizes through FY2021 grants for: (1) fishery extension activities conducted by sea grant colleges or sea grant institutes to enhance existing core program funding, and (2) priority issues identified in the National Sea Grant Program's strategic plan.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
