<bill session="115" type="h" number="7024" updated="2019-04-18T16:28:05Z">
  <state datetime="2018-10-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-10-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a Federal standard in order to improve the Nation's resilience to current and future flood risk.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Flood Management Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Flood Management Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Federal Flood Management Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000606"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001107" joined="2018-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000625" joined="2018-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2018-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000132" joined="2018-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000797" joined="2018-10-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-10-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-10-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1798"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-10-02T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Flood Management Act of 2018

This bill directs executive agencies, including military departments, to reduce the risk of flood losses, minimize flood impacts, and restore and preserve natural floodplains. Agencies must also: (1) evaluate the effects of an action taking place in a floodplain, (2) ensure planning programs and budget requests incorporate flood hazard considerations, and (3) indicate their compliance with this bill to the Office of Management and Budget when making a request for a new authorization or appropriation. The bill sets forth characteristics to be used in determining whether an agency action impacts a floodplain. The Mitigation Framework Leadership Group must reassess annually the implementation of these requirements, and provide recommendations to the Water Resources Council.

An agency undertaking a federally funded project must comply with federal flood risk management standards, including construction guidelines, flood-proofing measures, and elevation techniques. Projects may be exempted if compliance would not be in the interest of national security, a project is in response to an emergency, or the standard is demonstrably inappropriate.

An agency facilitating a financial transaction in an area subject to a base flood (a base flood has a 1% chance of being equaled or exceeded in any year) has a duty to inform any private party of the hazards.

Agencies must report on their compliance with this bill to the Council on Environmental Quality.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
