<bill session="114" type="h" number="6473" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:34Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To express the sense of Congress that information security is critical to the economic security of the United States and to direct the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information to submit to Congress a report on the costs of information security.</title>
    <title type="display">To express the sense of Congress that information security is critical to the economic security of the United States and to direct the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information to submit to Congress a report on the costs of information security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000031"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-12-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill expresses the sense of Congress that information security is critical to U.S. economic security and should be protected to promote economic growth.

The National Telecommunications and Information Administration&#160;must report on the costs to the U.S. economy of protecting information and systems from unauthorized access, use, disclosure, disruption, modification, or destruction to provide information integrity, confidentiality, timely and reliable access, and authentication through digital credentials.

The report must estimate the cost of: (1) security for computers, networks, software, storage systems, data transmission, equipment, and support services; (2) measures to mitigate and hedge against compromises of information systems; and (3) economic loss or harm caused by such compromises.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
