<bill session="114" type="h" number="5336" updated="2018-06-02T05:14:48Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Taxpayer-Funded Travel Transparency Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require Members of the House of Representatives to post information on their official public websites on the costs of trips taken by Members for which expenses were paid by the Department of Defense, the Department of State, or other offices of the House of Representatives, to direct the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives to maintain an online clearinghouse on its official public website of all such information for all Members, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Taxpayer-Funded Travel Transparency Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000291"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="House Committee on House Administration"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Taxpayer-Funded Travel Transparency Act of 2016

This bill requires each Member of the House of Representatives to post on the Member's official public website, and to furnish to the Committee on House Administration:

 a description of each trip taken by the Member for which transportation, lodging, or related expenses were paid by the Department of Defense (DOD), the Department of State, or an office of the House; and the amounts paid by DOD, State, or the office for such expenses. These reporting requirements shall not apply with respect to a trip taken by a Member for which expenses were paid by that Member's Representational Allowance.

The Committee on House Administration shall maintain on its official public website a clearinghouse of all of the travel and expenses information furnished to the Committee by all House members.

In the case of a trip taken by a Member of the House for which DOD or the State Department pays transportation, lodging, or related expenses, the respective department shall:

 determine the costs of the transportation, lodging, and related expenses paid; and furnish the Member with a written statement of those expenses within 10 days after completion of the trip. The respective department may waive the written statement of expenses requirement if furnishing the statement may affect national security.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
