<bill session="114" type="h" number="5861" updated="2019-02-13T17:31:24Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish terms and conditions under which the Secretary of the Interior shall convey, for fair market value, certain properties in the Lake Roosevelt National Recreation Area in the State of Washington to the permittees of those properties, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To establish terms and conditions under which the Secretary of the Interior shall convey, for fair market value, certain properties in the Lake Roosevelt National Recreation Area in the State of Washington to the permittees of those properties, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001159"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill requires the Department of the Interior to give permittees of specified federal land (including improvements) located along Sherman Creek and Rickey Point in Lake Roosevelt National Recreation Area in the state of Washington the first option to purchase such property for fair market value.

Interior shall offer to sell for fair market value:

 all interest of the United States in and to each property; and easements for vehicular access to it, access to and use of one dock for it, and access to and use of all boathouses, ramps, retaining walls, and other improvements for which access is provided in the permit. Interior shall also:

 solicit sealed bids for each property, and sell each property to the bidder who submits the highest bid at or above its fair market value. The cost of a conveyance of a property, including the costs of required appraisals, shall be paid by:

 Interior, for a sale to a permittee, from revenues of that sale; and the purchaser, for a sale to any person other than the permittee. Revenues from sales of federal lands under this bill shall be made available, without further appropriation, for conveyance costs and for deferred maintenance activities in the recreation area.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
