<bill session="114" type="s" number="905" updated="2018-06-02T06:44:50Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to increase the limitation on eligibility for the alternative tax for certain small insurance companies.</title>
    <title type="display">An original bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to increase the limitation on eligibility for the alternative tax for certain small insurance companies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Hatch. With written report No. 114-16.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-04-14" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="39">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 39.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1788"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Transfer and inheritance taxes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-14T15:01:37Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

(Sec. 1) This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to expand the eligibility of certain small insurance companies (other than life insurance companies) for the alternative corporate income tax by increasing the premium limitation used to determine such eligibility to $2.2 million (from $1.2 million), with an annual inflation adjustment to such increased amount after 2015. This increase is applicable to taxable years beginning after the enactment of this Act.

The Department of the Treasury must submit to the Senate Finance Committee by February 11, 2016, a report on the abuse of captive insurance companies for estate planning purposes, including legislative recommendations for addressing any such abuses.

(Sec. 2) This bill also increases from 30% to 45% the rate of the continuous levy on payments made after 180 days after the enactment of this Act to Medicare providers and suppliers for unpaid taxes.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-16</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
