<bill session="113" type="s" number="1637" updated="2016-10-25T16:27:22Z">
  <state datetime="2013-10-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United We Stand to Hire Veterans Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to better connect current and former members of the Armed Forces with employment opportunities by consolidating duplicative Federal Government Internet websites into a single portal, to conserve resources by merging redundant and competing programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">United We Stand to Hire Veterans Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001183"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2013-10-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="identical" number="3405"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-10-31T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">United We Stand to Hire Veterans Act - Requires the Secretary of Labor, in conjunction with the Secretaries of Defense (DOD) and Veterans Affairs (VA), to consolidate government Internet portals on employment for current and former members of the Armed Forces into one comprehensive portal for the purposes of connecting members who are seeking employment with employers who want to employ them.

Authorizes the Secretaries, in order to expedite implementation of such consolidated portal, to carry out pilot projects to evaluate the feasibility and advisability of various portal options by continuing or modifying existing programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
