<bill session="113" type="s" number="128" updated="2016-10-25T16:20:09Z">
  <state datetime="2013-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Campus Sexual Violence Elimination Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to improve education and prevention related to campus sexual violence, domestic violence, dating violence, and stalking.</title>
    <title type="display">Campus Sexual Violence Elimination Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001265" joined="2013-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2013-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2013-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2013-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2013-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2013-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2013-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2013-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2013-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2013-01-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="identical" number="812"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="11"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="47"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-01-24T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Campus Sexual Violence Elimination Act - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require institutions of higher education (IHEs) to include in their annual security report policies encouraging the accurate and prompt reporting of all crimes to campus police and appropriate law enforcement agencies when crime victims elect to, or are unable to, report the crimes.

Requires that report to include: (1) data on the occurrence of certain violent crimes that are motivated by the victim's nationality; and (2) statistics concerning the occurrence of domestic violence, dating violence, and stalking incidents reported to campus security authorities or local police.

Requires schools to protect victim confidentiality when reporting criminal threats to the campus community.

Directs IHEs to include in their annual security report a statement of policy regarding their programs to prevent domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking and the procedures they follow when such an offense is reported.

Requires an IHE's policy regarding those offenses to include:

 education that promotes awareness of the offenses; possible sanctions or protective measures imposed following disciplinary action; procedures victims should follow after such an offense occurs; institutional disciplinary procedures; information about how the IHE will protect victim confidentiality; the written notification of students and employees concerning on-campus and community services available for victims; and the written notification of victims regarding their options for, and assistance in, changing academic, living, transportation, and working situations, regardless of whether or not they choose to report the crime. Requires students and employees who report having been the victim of such an offense to their IHE, whether it occurred on or off campus, to receive a written notification of their rights and options under the IHE's policy.

Directs the Secretary of Education to seek the counsel of the Attorney General and Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) regarding the development, and dissemination to IHEs, of best practices for preventing and responding to incidents of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
