<bill session="114" type="h" number="3943" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:19Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Physician Assistant Education Public Health Initiatives Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide loan repayment incentives for physician assistants, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Physician Assistant Education Public Health Initiatives Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001270"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001251" joined="2015-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000216" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000287" joined="2016-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2015-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Physician Assistant Education Public Health Initiatives Act of 2015

This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to enter into contracts to repay the student loans of physician assistants who agree to serve as: (1) faculty members for physician assistant education programs; or (2) physician assistants in health professional shortage areas, in medically underserved areas, or at health centers serving medically underserved populations.

The bill extends through FY2021 programs that: (1) award grants to health professional schools to provide need-based scholarships, (2) repay the student loans of health professionals from disadvantaged backgrounds who agree to serve as faculty members at health professional schools, (3) support fellowships to increase the number of underrepresented minority faculty members at health professional schools, and (4) award grants to health professional schools to assist individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds.

Support provided by HHS for the development, operation, expansion, and improvement of primary care training programs is revised and extended through FY2021.

HHS must award grants to nonprofit organizations to increase research on physician assistant education.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
