<bill session="113" type="h" number="5304" updated="2016-10-25T16:15:50Z">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Audiology Patient Choice Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for treatment of audiologists as physicians for purposes of furnishing audiology services under the Medicare program, to improve access to the audiology services available for coverage under the Medicare program and to enable beneficiaries to have their choice of a qualified audiologist to provide such services, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Audiology Patient Choice Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000290"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2014-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="5360"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Hearing, speech, and vision care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-07-31T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Audiology Patient Choice Act of 2014 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to revise the coverage of audiology services to treat as physicians qualified audiologists authorized by the state and acting within the scope of their license to furnish such services.

Enables Medicare beneficiaries to choose a qualified audiologist without regard to any requirement to be under the care of (or referred by) a physician or other health care practitioner, or that services be provided under the supervision of a physician or other health care practitioner.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
