<bill session="115" type="h" number="3479" updated="2019-04-18T16:13:55Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve border security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Secure Miles with All Resources and Technology Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Secure Miles with All Resources and Technology Act</title>
    <title type="display">Secure Miles with All Resources and Technology Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001073"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2017-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2017-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000581" joined="2017-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000386" joined="2017-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000387" joined="2017-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000588" joined="2017-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000598" joined="2017-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000129" joined="2017-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000066" joined="2017-10-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-08-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Border Security, Facilitation, and Operations" code="HSHM11" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Communications and Technology" code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="4796"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Secure Miles with All Resources and Technology Act

This bill amends the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 to direct the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to deploy the most practical and effective technology available (such as radar, tunnel detection technology, unmanned aerial vehicles, and sensors) to achieve situational awareness and operational control along the U.S. border.

DHS shall submit to Congress a comprehensive southern border strategy, which shall include: (1) a list of known physical barriers, technologies, tools, and other devices to achieve situational awareness and operational control of the border and their related cost estimates; and (2) information from federal, state, local, and private sources.

DHS shall begin eradicating the carrizo cane plant and salt cedar along the Rio Grande River.

The Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended to establish Operation Stonegarden in DHS to provide border security grants to law enforcement agencies: (1) in a state bordering Canada or Mexico or a maritime border state or territory, and (2) involved in an ongoing U.S. Customs and Border Protection operation coordinated through a sector office.

DHS shall establish a two-year grant program to improve emergency communications in the southern border region for individuals who: (1) reside or work in a southern border state, and (2) are at greater risk of violence due to border proximity and a lack of residential or business cellular and LTE network service. Such grants may be used to purchase satellite telephone communications systems and services that provide access to 9-1-1 service and that are equipped with Global Positioning System receivers.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
