<bill session="114" type="h" number="5593" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:41Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Veterans Credit Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act and the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act to delay the inclusion in consumer credit reports and to establish requirements for debt collectors with respect to medical debt information of veterans due to inappropriate or delayed Veterans Choice Program billing payments, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Protecting Veterans Credit Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000620"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000490" joined="2016-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2016-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001047" joined="2016-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2016-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001059" joined="2016-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2016-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000382" joined="2016-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2016-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000170" joined="2016-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000603" joined="2016-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000576" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2016-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2016-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2016-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000130" joined="2016-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000813" joined="2016-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2016-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3258"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Veterans Credit Act of 2016

 This bill amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to exclude from a consumer report: (1) for one year, information related to a veteran's choice medical program (program) debt; and (2) information related to a fully paid or settled program debt that had been characterized as delinquent, charged off, or in collection.

The Consumer Credit Protection Act is amended to provide a mechanism for veterans to dispute the inclusion of program debt already on a credit report. A consumer reporting agency shall, within 30 days after receiving notice of such dispute, delete such information from the veteran's file and notify the furnisher and the veteran.

Within five days after the initial communication with a veteran, a debt collector shall, unless the appropriate information is contained in the initial communication or the veteran has paid the debt, send the veteran a written notice containing specified debt-related information, including information concerning debt amount, creditors, the insurance company involved, and the hospital or medical care provider.

If a veteran notifies the debt collector within such one-year period that the program debt is disputed or that the veteran requests the name and address of the original creditor, the debt collector shall cease collection until debt verification or the name and address of the original creditor is obtained.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
