<bill session="114" type="h" number="152" updated="2019-02-13T17:31:09Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Corolla Wild Horses Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Corolla Wild Horses Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to enter into an agreement to provide for management of the free-roaming wild horses in and around the Currituck National Wildlife Refuge.</title>
    <title type="display">Corolla Wild Horses Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000255"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-03-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Subcommittee on Federal Lands Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-20">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 114-84.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-04-20" calendar="Union" number="62">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 62.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1204"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Seashores and lakeshores"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-20T12:58:57Z" status="Reported to House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Corolla Wild Horses Protection Act

 Directs the Department of the Interior to enter into an agreement with the Corolla Wild Horse Fund, Currituck County, North Carolina, and the state of North Carolina to provide for the management of free-roaming wild horses in and around the Currituck National Wildlife Refuge.

Requires that such agreement: (1) allow a herd of between 110 and 130 free-roaming wild horses in and around the Refuge; (2) provide for cost-effective management of such horses while ensuring that natural resources within the Refuge are not adversely impacted; (3) provide for the introduction of a small number of free-roaming wild horses from the herd at Cape Lookout National Seashore as is necessary to maintain the genetic viability of the herd in and around the Refuge; and (4) require such Fund to pay the costs of inspecting the health of the horses, maintaining records, coordinating the removal and placement of such horses, and administering a viable population control plan for the horses.

Prohibits the removal of any horse from the Seashore for introduction at the Refuge except with the approval of the Foundation for Shackleford Horses Inc. and consistent with the memorandum of understanding between the National Park Service and the Foundation and the management plan for the Shackleford Banks Horse Herd.

 Declares that nothing in this Act shall be construed as creating liability of the United States for any damages caused by the free-roaming wild horses to any person or property located inside or outside the boundaries of the Refuge.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-84</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
