<bill session="114" type="s" number="3151" updated="2018-06-02T07:47:07Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CAREER Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cutting Administrative Red-tape for Education and Employment Reinvestment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance investment in education and employment programs by eliminating duplication, cutting red tape, and increasing flexibility, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">CAREER Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000461"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Adult education and literacy"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational guidance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Cutting Administrative Red-tape for Education and Employment Reinvestment Act or the CAREER Act

This bill addresses educational and employment training programs for certain individuals including:

 training for adults, training for disadvantaged youth, vocational rehabilitation and referral services for individuals with disabilities, training for Native Americans, and training to reintegrate criminal offenders. The Department of Labor must assist in the development of a nationwide system of public labor exchange services that are provided through state and local workforce investment boards. Labor must provide funding to the boards to assist with training adults and disadvantaged youths, including providing services to promote literacy, attain education, and assist with job search and placement.Additionally, Labor must provide funding to states to carry out vocational rehabilitation and referral services for individuals with disabilities so that those individuals may prepare for and engage in employment.

The bill also provides training for Native Americans to develop skills, be competitive in the workforce, and promote economic and social development.

The bill amends the Second Chance Act of 2007 to make youth offenders eligible to receive grants from Labor for certain transitional services, including being reintegrated into society and obtaining and retaining employment.

The bill replaces several provisions related to educational and employment programs for adults, youths, disabled individuals, and Native Americans.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
