<bill session="114" type="s" number="2663" updated="2018-06-02T07:15:41Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reforming CFPB Indirect Auto Financing Guidance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to nullify certain guidance of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection and to provide requirements for guidance issued by the Bureau with respect to indirect auto lending.</title>
    <title type="display">Reforming CFPB Indirect Auto Financing Guidance Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000934"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-07">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 114-520.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1737"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5983"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reforming CFPB Indirect Auto Financing Guidance Act 

 This bill declares without force or effect Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) Bulletin 2013-02 (Indirect Auto Lending and Compliance with the Equal Credit Opportunity Act), published March 21, 2013.

 The Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 is amended to direct the CFPB, when proposing and issuing guidance primarily related to indirect auto financing, to:

 provide for a public notice and comment period before issuing the guidance in final form; make publicly available all information relied on by the CFPB; redact any information exempt from disclosure under the Freedom of Information Act; consult with the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Trade Commission, and the Department of Justice; and study the costs and impacts of the guidance to consumers and women-owned, minority-owned, veteran-owned, and small businesses, including consumers and small businesses in rural areas.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
