<bill session="114" type="h" number="6481" updated="2018-09-27T13:55:30Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Urban Agriculture Production Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote and enhance urban agricultural production and agricultural research in urban areas, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Urban Agriculture Production Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2016-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing and promotion"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Fruit and vegetables"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Materials"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-08T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Urban Agriculture Production Act of 2016

This bill requires the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish an urban agriculture outreach program to award grants to support outreach activities for: (1) infrastructure, (2) land acquisition and conversion, (3) education and training, (4) technical and financial assistance to farmers or ranchers in urban areas, and (5) other activities that support urban agriculture. USDA must give preference to grants for activities in historically underserved communities.

The bill amends the Department of Agriculture Reorganization Act of 1994 to expand the purpose and duties of USDA's Office of Advocacy and Outreach to include activities on behalf of urban farmers or ranchers.

USDA must award grants, on a competitive basis, for scientific and community-based participatory research related to urban agriculture. The bill provides specified funds for the grants and requires USDA to give priority to outreach activities to be carried out in historically underserved communities.

The bill amends the Farmer-to-Consumer Direct Marketing Act of 1976 to: (1) establish a program to provide loans and loan guarantees for projects or activities to establish, expand, and promote direct producer-to-consumer marketing and assist in the development of local food business enterprises; and (2) extend and provide additional funding for the Farmers' Market Promotion Program.

The bill amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to extend the Seniors Farmers' Market Nutrition Program and provide additional funding.

The bill amends the Census of Agriculture Act of 1997 to require additional USDA reporting on farmers' markets and agricultural production in urban areas.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
