<bill session="113" type="h" number="3349" updated="2016-10-25T16:08:09Z">
  <state datetime="2013-10-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Innovation Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the permanent funding of the United States Patent and Trademark Office, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Innovation Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000714"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000266" joined="2013-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001093" joined="2013-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2013-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000617" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000610" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000448" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000056" joined="2013-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2013-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000294" joined="2013-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2013-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001179" joined="2013-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2013-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000588" joined="2013-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000409" joined="2013-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000207" joined="2013-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2013-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2146"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-10-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Innovation Protection Act - Establishes in the Treasury the United States Patent and Trademark Office Public Enterprise Fund (Public Enterprise Fund) to be used as a revolving fund by the Director of the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) without fiscal year limitation.

Requires to be credited to or deposited in the Public Enterprise Fund: (1) appropriations for defraying the costs of USPTO activities; (2) fees collected under federal patent and trademark laws; and (3) any unobligated balances remaining in the Patent and Trademark Office Appropriation Account and in the Patent and Trademark Fee Reserve Fund. (Thus, replaces the Patent and Trademark Office Appropriation Account, eliminates the Patent and Trademark Fee Reserve Fund, and provides a source of permanent funding for the USPTO.)

Requires fees collected by the Director to remain available to the Director until expended.

Makes the Public Enterprise Fund available to cover: (1) ordinary and reasonable administrative, operating, and other expenses incurred by the Director for the continued operation of USPTO services, programs, activities, and duties relating to patents and trademarks; and (2) expenses incurred pursuant to obligations, representations, or other commitments of the USPTO.

Requires the Director, on an annual basis, to: (1) report to Congress with operation and spending plans, including financial details and staff levels broken down by each major activity; (2) provide for an independent audit of USPTO financial statements; and (3) submit a budget to the President.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
