<bill session="114" type="s" number="1340" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:56Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coal Oversight and Leasing Reform Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COAL Reform Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Mineral Leasing Act to improve coal leasing, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">COAL Reform Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-09">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Coal Oversight and Leasing Reform Act of 2015 or the COAL Reform Act of 2015

This bill amends the Mineral Leasing Act to repeal the requirement that the Department of the Interior offer under a deferred bonus lease payment system at least 50% of total acreage offered for coal leasing in any one year.

 Any independent consultants used by Interior for lease sales shall be subject to a nondisclosure agreement and any other confidentiality requirements.

Licensees must certify the accuracy of exploration data they submit.

A proposed lease sale may not be held until Interior determines, and includes in a formal appraisal report, the fair market value of the coal to be extracted.

Interior must: (1) make publicly available appraisal reports, individual and total lease sales, high bids, royalty payments, and related revenues; and (2) find that a proposed coal leasing modification would not result in revenue reduction.

The total area of coal leasing modifications is reduced from 960 to 160 acres.

Interior shall prepare, periodically revise, and maintain a coal leasing program consisting of a schedule of proposed lease sales indicating the size, timing, and location of leasing activity that will best meet national needs for the five-year period following approval or reapproval of the program.

 Annual lease rentals must be for at least $100 per acre, adjustable every 5 years.

Lease terms are reduced from 20 to 10 years. A lease which is not producing in commercial quantities shall be terminated at the end of 5 years.

The minimum lease royalty is increased from 12.5% of the value of the coal to 18.75%.

BLM shall promulgate regulations for inspections and enforcement of coal operations, including oversight of state inspection and enforcement programs by its Washington, D.C. office. BLM may also assess civil penalties for noncompliance.

There shall be a moratorium on new coal lease sales until this Act has been implemented.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
