<bill session="115" type="s" number="827" updated="2019-04-18T16:34:47Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the sealing or expungement of records relating to Federal nonviolent criminal offenses, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Record Expungement Designed to Enhance Employment Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Record Expungement Designed to Enhance Employment Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REDEEM Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REDEEM Act</title>
    <title type="display">REDEEM Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000603"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2017-04-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="901"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="329"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="511"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1906"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Record Expungement Designed to Enhance Employment Act of 2017 or the REDEEM Act 

This bill creates a mechanism by which certain eligible individuals may file a petition to seal federal criminal records with respect to covered nonviolent offenses. If an individual is eligible for such a sealing order, the court must notify the person in writing of their potential eligibility. The bill establishes a set of rules and procedures for assessing a sealing petition. If granted, the offense, criminal proceeding, conviction, or sentence shall be treated as if it never occurred.

A judge shall issue a sealing order three years after the date on which a person is adjudicated delinquent for a juvenile nonviolent offense if certain conditions are met.

The use of room confinement (defined as involuntary placement of a juvenile alone in a cell) for discipline, other than a temporary response to a juvenile's behavior that presents harm to others, is prohibited.

The bill removes possession and use of controlled substance as a disqualifying activity under federal welfare laws. Further, the prohibition from access to federal welfare benefits for drug-related offenses shall not apply to persons who, among other things, have completed a certified substance abuse treatment program.

When awarding grants under the Community-Oriented Policing Services (COPS) program, the Department of Justice (DOJ) may give preference to states that have laws similar to this bill's provisions.

DOJ shall establish and enforce procedures to ensure the prompt release of accurate records exchanged for employment-related purposes through the records system created by this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
