<bill session="113" type="s" number="2010" updated="2016-10-25T16:28:48Z">
  <state datetime="2014-06-18">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bureau of Reclamation Conduit Hydropower Development Equity and Jobs Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Bureau of Reclamation Hydropower Development Equity and Jobs Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Water Conservation and Utilization Act to authorize the development of non-Federal hydropower and issuance of leases of power privileges at projects constructed pursuant to the authority of the Water Conservation and Utilization Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Bureau of Reclamation Hydropower Development Equity and Jobs Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001261"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-284.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Landrieu with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 113-229.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-31" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="516">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 516.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water and Power" code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1963"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-07-31T13:14:41Z" status="Reported to Senate amended">Bureau of Reclamation Hydropower Development Equity and Jobs Act - Amends the Water Conservation and Utilization Act (WCUA) to: (1) authorize the Secretary of the Interior (acting through the Bureau of Reclamation) to enter into leases of power privileges for electric power generation in connection with any project constructed pursuant to such Act, using the processes, terms, and conditions applicable to the lease under the Reclamation Project Act of 1939; and (2) grant the Secretary authority over any project constructed pursuant to such Act in addition to and alternative to any existing authority relating to a particular project.

Specifies that no findings required as prerequisites for construction of a water conservation or utilization project under WCUA shall be required for such a lease.

Requires: (1) all right, title, and interest in and to installed power facilities constructed by non-federal entities pursuant to such a lease, and any direct revenues derived from such lease, to remain with the lessee; and (2) lease charges to be credited to the project from which the power is derived.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 113-229</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
