<bill session="115" type="sr" number="354" updated="2019-04-18T16:30:03Z">
  <state datetime="2017-12-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding the courageous work and life of Argentinian prosecutor Alberto Nisman, and calling for a swift and transparent investigation into his tragic death in Buenos Aires on January 18, 2015.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding the courageous work and life of Argentinian prosecutor Alberto Nisman, and calling for a swift and transparent investigation into his tragic death in Buenos Aires on January 18, 2015.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2017-12-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-12-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7933-7934" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="unknown" number="704"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Argentina"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-12-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Offers condolences to the family of Argentinian prosecutor Alberto Nisman. Recognizes his dedication to the investigation of the bombing of the Argentine Israelite Mutual Association (AMIA) in Buenos Aires, Argentina.

Applauds Argentine President Mauricio Macri for calling for an independent investigation into Mr. Nisman's death and encourages the public release of the results. Recognizes the work of the Argentine National Gendarmerie in reviewing evidence to produce credible findings.

Commends the government of Argentina for exemplifying the rule of law and the importance of an independent justice system.

Urges the President of the United States to: (1) offer technical assistance to the government of Argentina in investigating Mr. Nisman's death and the AMIA bombing, and (2) continue to monitor Iran's activities in Latin America and the Caribbean.

Expresses concern about: (1) Iran's terrorist networks in Argentina and the Western Hemisphere, and (2) attempts by former Argentine President Cristina Fernandez de Kirchner and her government to discredit Mr. Nisman and raise unfounded hypotheses on his AMIA findings and the circumstances of his death.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
