<bill session="114" type="s" number="3249" updated="2018-06-02T07:47:38Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keeping Our Commitment to Ending Veteran Homelessness Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to extend authorities relating to homeless veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Keeping Our Commitment to Ending Veteran Homelessness Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2016-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2048"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2082"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Keeping Our Commitment to Ending Veteran Homelessness Act of 2016

This bill extends through FY2017 authority for the following Department of Veterans Affairs programs:

 homeless veterans reintegration programs; the homeless women veterans and homeless veterans with children reintegration program; referral and counseling services for certain veterans at risk of homelessness; treatment and rehabilitation services for seriously mentally ill and homeless veterans, including a program to provide homeless veterans with benefits and services at certain locations; housing assistance for homeless veterans; financial assistance for supportive services for very low-income veteran families in permanent housing; and the grant program for homeless veterans with special needs. Extends through December 31, 2017, authority for the Advisory Committee on Homeless Veterans.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
