<bill session="115" type="sr" number="348" updated="2019-04-18T16:30:01Z">
  <state datetime="2017-12-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-12-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-12-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution reaffirming the strategic partnership between the United States of America and the Federal Democratic Republic of Ethiopia and encouraging inclusive governance in the Federal Democratic Republic of Ethiopia.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution reaffirming the strategic partnership between the United States of America and the Federal Democratic Republic of Ethiopia and encouraging inclusive governance in the Federal Democratic Republic of Ethiopia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000024"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2017-12-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-12-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7820-7821" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Ethiopia"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-12-04T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reaffirms the U.S. commitment to support the government of Ethiopia to:

 provide training and resources to counter terrorism and violent extremism and address security concerns in the Horn of Africa, bolster trade and investment in the private sector between the United States and Ethiopia, continue support to strengthen higher education and promote health through the exiting mechanisms, and continue humanitarian assistance with the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) to the people affected by the drought. Calls on the Department of State to engage with the Ethiopian government in strengthening the bilateral Working Group on Democracy, Governance and Human Rights, and provide support in the implementation of the National Human Rights Action Plan.

Condemns the violence that resulted in the death of over 500 Ethiopians.

Calls on the government of Ethiopia to:

 hold accountable all personnel responsible for the death and destruction that took place as a result of violent protests in the Oromia and Amhara regions, respect the right to freedom of peaceful assembly and guarantee freedom of the press and mass media, and engage in open and transparent consultations relative to its development strategy. Calls on the USAID to: (1) continue to lead efforts to work with the Ethiopian government to improve democracy and governance, and (2) assist the government and people of Ethiopia in capacity building in all areas.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
