<bill session="114" type="h" number="2990" updated="2019-02-14T22:59:19Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accelerating Individuals into the Workforce Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Accelerating Individuals into the Workforce Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the conduct of demonstration projects to test the effectiveness of subsidized employment for TANF recipients.</title>
    <title type="display">Accelerating Individuals into the Workforce Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000613"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000585" joined="2016-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-05-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-06-28">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 114-646.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-06-28" calendar="Union" number="498">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 498.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Worker and Family Support" code="HSWM03" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-28T12:58:36Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">Accelerating Individuals into the Workforce Act 

(Sec. 2) This bill amends part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF) of title IV of the Social Security Act to direct the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to make grants to states to conduct demonstration projects designed to implement and evaluate strategies that provide wage subsidies to enable low-income individuals to enter into and retain employment.

A state may use a grant to subsidize a recipient's wages for only 12 months and for no more than 50% of the wages received.

An eligible recipient of such a subsidy may be either a TANF recipient or a noncustodial parent of a minor child receiving TANF assistance, but must also be unemployed and have an income less than 200% of the poverty line.

A state must ensure that a subsidy recipient does not displace an individual on layoff or an employee whose employment has been terminated to make a vacancy for the subsidy recipient. A state must also establish a grievance procedure for resolving complaints of alleged violations of this nondisplacement requirement.

HHS shall reserve specified funds for FY2017 to carry out this program, 15% of which must fund programs offering career pathway training services under the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act. (Career pathways programs combine education, training, and other services aligned with the skill needs of industries in the economy of the state or regional economy involved in order to help an individual enter or advance within a specific occupation or occupational cluster.)</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-646</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
