<bill session="113" type="h" number="1613" updated="2016-10-25T16:35:02Z">
  <state datetime="2013-06-27T15:05:35-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-06-27T15:05:35-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Outer Continental Shelf Transboundary Hydrocarbon Agreements Authorization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Outer Continental Shelf Transboundary Hydrocarbon Agreements Authorization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Outer Continental Shelf Transboundary Hydrocarbon Agreements Authorization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to provide for the proper Federal management and oversight of transboundary hydrocarbon reservoirs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Outer Continental Shelf Transboundary Hydrocarbon Agreements Authorization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000615"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000369" joined="2013-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001280" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001262" joined="2013-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2013-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000560" joined="2013-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000329" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2013-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2013-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001187" joined="2013-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001190" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000592" joined="2013-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000596" joined="2013-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000018" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000937" joined="2013-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000812" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000796" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2013-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Foreign Affairs, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-18">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-18">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Terrorism, Nonproliferation, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Western Hemisphere.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-15">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-05-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 25 - 16.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-101, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Affairs discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06">
      <text>Committee on Financial Services discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-06-06" calendar="Union" number="70">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 70.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-06-25T21:12:39-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 274 Reported to House. Resolution provides for 3 separate measures and for proceedings during the period from June 29, 2013 through July 5, 2013.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27T12:56:00-04:00">
      <text>AMENDMENT MODIFICATION AUTHORITY - Mr. Sessions asked unanimous consent that during the consideration of H.R. 1613 and H.R. 2231 pursuant to H.Res. 274, amendment numbered 1 printed in part A of House Report 113-131 and amendments numbered 5 and 10 printed in part B of that report be modified. Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4096-4097" label="(consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4097" label="text of certain modified House amendments"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27T12:56:22-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 274.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4096-4108" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4097-4098" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27T12:56:27-04:00">
      <text>Resolution provides for 3 separate measures and for proceedings during the period from June 29, 2013 through July 5, 2013.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27T12:57:01-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 1613.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27T13:44:48-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 274, the House proceeded with 10 minutes of the Grayson amendment No. 1, as modified.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27T13:54:13-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Grayson amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27T13:54:44-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair announced that further proceedings on H.R. 1613 had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27T14:09:20-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to clause 1(c) of rule 19, further consideration of H.R. 1613 resumed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27T14:09:22-04:00">
      <text>Before the House recessed, the Chair had declared that the noes had prevailed by voice vote on the Grayson amendment. Mr. Grayson demanded the yeas and nays.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27T14:09:40-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4105-4108" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27T14:41:36-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Garcia moved to recommit with instructions to Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4106" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="text CR H4106"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27T14:41:59-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Garcia motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to require that, prior to the commencement of drilling operations authorized under this bill, the Secretary of the Interior ensure that requirements are met for well safety, blowout protection, and risk assessment. The amendment would also require increased fines for every day in which a well is found to be in violation of these requirements and give the Secretary authority to collect these fines and also to increase their maximum amounts.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27T14:50:36-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4107" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27T14:58:49-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 194 - 232 (Roll no. 292).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="293" datetime="2013-06-27T15:05:35-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 256 - 171 (Roll no. 293).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27T15:05:36-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-08">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-01">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 113-104.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Western Hemisphere" code="HSFA07" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Terrorism,  Nonproliferation, and Trade" code="HSFA18" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="812"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="113" relation="unknown" number="274"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Bahamas"/>
    <term name="Bermuda"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h233"/>
    <amendment number="h232"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2013-06-27T12:48:01Z" status="Passed House amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on June 6, 2013. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Outer Continental Shelf Transboundary Hydrocarbon Agreements Authorization Act - Title I: Amendment to the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act - (Sec. 101) Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (OCSLA) to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to implement any agreement for the management of transboundary hydrocarbon reservoirs entered into by the President and approved by Congress.

Prescribes procedures for submission of such agreements to Congress.

Authorizes the Secretary to implement the terms of the Agreement between the United States of America and the United Mexican States Concerning Transboundary Hydrocarbon Reservoirs in the Gulf of Mexico, signed at Los Cabos, February 20, 2012 (the Agreement), including: (1) approving unitization agreements and related arrangements for the exploration, development, or production of oil and natural gas from transboundary reservoirs or geological structures; (2) making available, subject to the agreement's confidentiality protections, information pertaining to such activities that may be considered confidential, privileged, or proprietary; and (3) ensuring that only the operator, lessee, or inspection staff at the Bureau of Safety and Environmental Enforcement have authority to stop work on such activities on any production site attached to the U.S. seabed.

Exempts from resources extraction reporting requirements under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 any actions taken by a public company in accordance with a transboundary hydrocarbon agreement.

Prohibits this Act from being construed as: (1) authorizing the Secretary to participate in any negotiations, conferences, or consultations with Cuba regarding exploration, development, or production of hydrocarbon resources in the Gulf of Mexico along the U.S. maritime border with Cuba (including the area known as the "Eastern Gap"); or (2) affecting U.S. sovereign rights and jurisdiction over the outer Continental Shelf which appertains to it.

Title II: Approval of Transboundary Hydrocarbon Agreement - (Sec. 201) Approves the Agreement.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 113-101</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
