<bill session="114" type="s" number="2104" updated="2018-06-02T07:10:21Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preserving Medicare Advantage for all Medicare Beneficiaries Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide relief to Medicare Advantage plans with a significant number of dually eligible or low-income subsidy beneficiaries and to prevent the termination of two star plans.</title>
    <title type="display">Preserving Medicare Advantage for all Medicare Beneficiaries Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000449"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2015-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2015-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2015-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Preserving Medicare Advantage for all Medicare Beneficiaries Act of 2015

This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to: (1) temporarily prohibit the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid from terminating a Medicare Advantage (MA) plan contract solely because the MA plan fails to achieve a certain minimum quality rating, provided that the MA plan achieves a quality rating of at least two out of five stars; and (2) establish a demonstration project to provide funds to MA organizations for the development or expansion of programs or services to improve health care delivery and outcomes for enrollees of low socioeconomic status.

To qualify for demonstration project funding, an MA plan must meet specified requirements with respect to quality ratings and the percentage of plan enrollees either eligible for a low-income subsidy or dually eligible for Medicare and Medicaid. MA organizations receiving funds under the demonstration project must use those funds to target improvement by the MA plan with respect to certain quality rating measures.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
