<bill session="115" type="h" number="2444" updated="2019-05-09T23:15:26Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To create an alternative prosecutor for certain Federal offenses.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TRUMP Special Counsel Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TRUMP Special Counsel Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Trusted, Reliable, Unquestioned Method of Procedure for Special Counsel Appointment, Limitations, and Powers Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Trusted, Reliable, Unquestioned Method of Procedure for Special Counsel Appointment, Limitations, and Powers Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">TRUMP Special Counsel Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Trusted, Reliable, Unquestioned Method of Procedure for Special Counsel Appointment, Limitations, and Powers Act of 2017 or the TRUMP Special Counsel Act 

This bill requires the Attorney General to appoint a special counsel when the Attorney General determines that the investigation or prosecution of a person or matter would present a conflict of interest for the Department of Justice (DOJ) or other extraordinary circumstances exist. Extraordinary circumstances exist in any criminal investigation of the President, Vice President, and their spouses or children, or which involves the activities of agents or entities under the control of a foreign state acting in concert with agents associated with the President or Vice President.

The jurisdiction of a special counsel is established by the Attorney General, who shall include a specific factual statement of the matter to be investigated. The special counsel's jurisdiction also includes the authority to investigate and prosecute federal crimes committed with the intent to interfere with the investigation.

A special counsel may request the assignment of appropriate DOJ employees to assist him or her. If necessary, the special counsel may request that additional personnel be hired or assigned from outside DOJ.

The special counsel shall exercise, within the scope of his or her jurisdiction, the full power and independent authority to exercise all investigative and prosecutorial functions of any U.S. Attorney.

The special counsel and staff shall be subject to disciplinary action for misconduct under the same standards as other employees of DOJ.

At the conclusion of the special counsel's work, the special counsel must provide the Attorney General with a confidential report explaining prosecution or declination decisions.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
