<bill session="113" type="h" number="4376" updated="2016-10-25T16:12:09Z">
  <state datetime="2014-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Retirement Security Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify safe harbor requirements applicable to automatic contribution arrangements, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Retirement Security Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001259"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-02">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" code="HSED02" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="identical" number="1970"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2171"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="5875"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1145"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-04-02T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Retirement Security Act of 2014 - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1)&#160;prescribe final regulations to permit employers to participate in&#160;multiple employer pension benefit plans, (2) promulgate regulations or other guidance to simplify and clarify rules relating to the timing of participant notices required under tax-preferred pension plans and the automatic escalation rules, and (3) modify the 1040EZ tax return form to allow taxpayers to claim the tax credit for retirement savings (saver's credit) on such form.

Amends the Employee Retirement&#160;Income Security Act of 1974&#160;(ERISA) and the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to employer pension benefit plans, to: (1)&#160;allow employers to maintain a tax-exempt multiple employer pension benefit plan even if the employers&#160;sponsoring the plan share no common interest, (2) modify requirements for secure deferral arrangements with respect to nondiscrimination and employer matching contributions, and&#160;(3) allow employers with not more than 100 employees a business-related tax credit to cover increased matching contributions required by this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
