<bill session="113" type="h" number="1144" updated="2018-06-05T16:10:31Z">
  <state datetime="2013-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alabama-Coushatta Tribe of Texas Equal and Fair Opportunity Settlement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To restore an opportunity for tribal economic development on terms that are equal and fair, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Alabama-Coushatta Tribe of Texas Equal and Fair Opportunity Settlement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000937"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001271" joined="2013-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001097" joined="2014-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000010" joined="2014-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000410" joined="2013-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2013-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000599" joined="2014-01-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2923"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-03-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Alabama-Coushatta Tribe of Texas Equal and Fair Opportunity Settlement Act - Amends the Alabama-Coushatta Tribes of Texas Restoration Act to delete a provision prohibiting the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe of Texas from conducting gaming activities on its lands if those gaming activities are prohibited by Texas.

Approves and ratifies any prior invalid transfer of land or natural resources within Texas from, by, or on behalf of the Tribe or any predecessor in interest or any of its members.

Extinguishes any aboriginal title held by the Tribe, or any predecessor in interest or any of its members, to the land or natural resources the transfer of which is approved and ratified by this Act.

Extinguishes any claim by or on behalf of the Tribe, or any predecessor in interest or any of its members, against Texas or the United States regarding the transferred or aboriginal lands or natural resources.

Requires the United States and the Tribe to execute and file with the U.S. District Court for the Eastern District of Texas a motion for entry of final judgment in accordance with the terms of this Act of pending litigation regarding the government's failure to discharge its fiduciary duty to the Tribe.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
