<bill session="114" type="s" number="2635" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:37Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance the ability of the United States to carry out icebreaking in the polar regions and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coast Guard Icebreaker Recapitalization Act</title>
    <title type="display">Coast Guard Icebreaker Recapitalization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2016-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2016-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Coast Guard Icebreaker Recapitalization Act

This bill authorizes the U.S. Coast Guard to renovate and reactivate the Coast Guard Cutter Polar Sea, a heavy icebreaker, for an additional 7 to 10 years of service life.

The Coast Guard must submit a polar icebreaker recapitalization plan to Congress within 90 days. The plan must include:

 the number of heavy and medium polar icebreakers required in the polar regions, the vessel details required for the design of heavy polar icebreakers, the specific appropriations required for the acquisition of each icebreaker, and a description of any polar icebreaking capacity gaps that exist based on the current fleet and procurement outlook. The bill requires the Government Accountability Office to submit to Congress, within six months, a report on the international funding models used to sustain the icebreaking fleets of foreign countries in the polar regions or other areas. The report must include:

 an analysis of icebreaking activity carried out by foreign countries, an overview of the fees used to compensate foreign countries for icebreaking escorts, the impact of escort fees in the polar regions on the shipping industry, the effectiveness of escort fees in funding foreign icebreaking vessels, and policy recommendations for funding U.S. polar icebreaking vessels.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
