<bill session="113" type="h" number="3483" updated="2016-10-25T16:08:39Z">
  <state datetime="2013-11-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Individual Liberties and States' Rights Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide exceptions from the firearm prohibitions otherwise applicable in relation to marijuana if its possession is lawful under State law.</title>
    <title type="display">Protecting Individual Liberties and States' Rights Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000598"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000409" joined="2013-11-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-11-14T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Individual Liberties and States' Rights Act - Amends the federal criminal code to modify the definition of a "crime punishable by imprisonment for a term exceeding one year" for purposes of firearms prohibitions to specifically exclude any offense pertaining to marijuana that occurs in a state if the conduct constituting the offense is lawful under the law of the state.

Provides that the prohibition against knowingly selling or otherwise disposing of a firearm or ammunition to any person who is an unlawful user of or addicted to a controlled substance, and the prohibition against such a person transporting, possessing, or receiving a firearm or ammunition in interstate or foreign commerce, shall not apply with respect to a sale or other disposition to, or the transportation, possession, or receipt by, a person if: (1) the controlled substance is marijuana, (2) the possession of marijuana is lawful under the law of the state, and (3) the person is a resident of the state.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
