<bill session="114" type="hj" number="31" updated="2019-05-09T23:15:17Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States regarding the permissible sources of funding for elections for public office and State ballot measures.</title>
    <title type="display">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States regarding the permissible sources of funding for elections for public office and State ballot measures.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001166"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="First Amendment rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-11T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Constitutional Amendment

This joint resolution proposes a constitutional amendment specifying individual citizens or public election financing or voter education systems as the only sources of funding to directly or indirectly support or oppose campaigns for election to public office or state ballot measures.

The amendment requires Congress, the states, and local jurisdictions to establish limits on the amount of contributions individuals may make with respect to a single campaign for election to public office. States and local jurisdictions shall establish limits on the amount of contributions individuals may make with respect to a ballot measure. The total of combined contributions to the principal campaign committee of a candidate from citizens who are not eligible to vote for the candidate is limited to the total of combined contributions from citizens who are eligible to vote for the candidate.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
