<bill session="113" type="h" number="3357" updated="2016-10-25T16:08:10Z">
  <state datetime="2013-10-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Early Childhood Education Professional Improvement Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Education to make grants to States to improve the knowledge, credentials, compensation, and professional development of early childhood educators working with children in early childhood education programs.</title>
    <title type="display">Early Childhood Education Professional Improvement Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001188"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000598" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2013-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2013-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2013-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2014-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000808" joined="2013-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6915"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-10-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Early Childhood Education Professional Improvement Act of 2013 - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award grants to states to:

 provide scholarships that enable preschool teachers employed in an early childhood education program to pursue a bachelor's degree in early childhood education or a closely related field; support preschool teachers employed in an early childhood education program to attain a credential, licensure, or endorsement that demonstrates competence in early childhood education if their bachelor's degree is not in that or a closely related field; increase the compensation of teachers who are making progress toward a degree in early childhood education or who have attained that degree; and provide ongoing professional development opportunities to preschool teachers and teacher assistants employed in an early childhood education program. Requires each state that desires a grant to include a description of its comprehensive early childhood professional development system in its application.

Requires grant recipients to maintain their fiscal effort for the activities supported by the grant funds for a fiscal year at levels equal to or greater than their fiscal effort for such activities during the preceding fiscal year.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
