<amendment session="114" chamber="h" number="509" updated="2018-11-08T23:28:54Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2596" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2015-06-16T14:41:16-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000057"/>
  <offered datetime="2015-06-16"/>
  <description>Amendment requires the Director of National Intelligence to provide reports to the congressional intelligence and defense committees on the cyber threat trends identified by the Cyber Threat Intelligence Integration Center, an assessment of collaborative efforts between federal agencies, and recommendations to improve those collaborative efforts. Reports are due not later than 10 months after the date of enactment and annually thereafter for 3 years.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 2 printed in House Report 114-155 to require the Director of National Intelligence to provide report to the congressional intelligence and defense committees on the cyber threat trends identified by the Cyber Threat Intelligence Integration Center, an assessment of collaborative efforts between federal agencies, and recommendations to improve those collaborative efforts.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2015-06-16T14:41:16-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Israel amendment (A002) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-06-16T14:36:29-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Israel.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4405-4406" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4405" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-16"/>
    <action datetime="2015-06-16T14:36:29-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Israel.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4405-4406" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4405" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-16T14:41:16-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Israel amendment (A002) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-16T14:41:16-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-16">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
