<bill session="114" type="sr" number="118" updated="2019-04-11T15:42:25Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution amending rule XXXI of the Standing Rules of the Senate, to provide for timely consideration of nominations.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution amending rule XXXI of the Standing Rules of the Senate, to provide for timely consideration of nominations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001176"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2052" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amends Rule XXXI (Executive Session - Proceedings on Nominations) of the Standing Rules of the Senate to make a covered nomination eligible for expedited consideration, if it has been on the Executive Calendar for more than 14 calendar days.

Excludes from coverage by this resolution the nomination of an individual:

 to serve as a justice, including Chief Justice, of the U.S. Supreme Court, or to one of several specified positions entitled to expedited procedures under S. Res. 116 (112th Congress). Deems the covered nomination confirmed by the Senate unless at least 10 Senators have submitted written requests that it be considered by the full Senate in executive session before the end of the 14-day period.

Makes a covered nomination (other than to serve as a judge or justice appointed to hold office during good behavior, or to a position at level I of the Executive Schedule [Cabinet Secretaries and certain others]) eligible for expedited consideration, under similar requirements.

Requires the Senate to proceed to executive session and begin consideration of a nomination:

 24 hours after the majority leader provides notice that it is eligible for expedited consideration; and 48 hours after the majority leader provides such notice of an individual to serve as a judge or justice appointed to hold office during good behavior, or to a position at level I of the Executive Schedule. Limits expedited consideration of a covered nomination to:

 four hours, evenly divided in the usual form, for a nomination to serve as a judge of a circuit court of the United States or a nomination to a position at level I of the Executive Schedule; and two hours, evenly divided in the usual form, for any other covered nomination.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
