<bill session="115" type="s" number="3372" updated="2019-04-18T16:45:20Z">
  <state datetime="2018-08-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-08-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-08-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require asylum officers to conduct credible fear screenings before admitting aliens seeking asylum into the United States, to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish an alternatives to detention pilot program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Asylum Abuse Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Asylum Abuse Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="display">Asylum Abuse Reduction Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000024"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-08-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-08-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-08-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Asylum Abuse Reduction Act 

This bill provides that if an alien seeking asylum attempts to enter the United States from Canada or Mexico at a land port of entry without a valid visa or appropriate entry documents the inspecting immigration officer:

 may not admit the alien, and shall advise the alien to schedule an asylum hearing at a U.S. embassy or consulate in Canada or Mexico. Such alien may not be admitted into the United States unless the asylum officer has conducted an in-person interview and concluded that the alien:

 has been persecuted in his or her country of origin because of race, religion, nationality, social group membership, or political opinion; or would be subject to torture upon return. The bill requires each federal judicial district to appoint at least one magistrate or district court judge who, upon a showing of probable cause, shall issue an arrest warrant for an alien under a final removal order who has failed to leave the United States.

The Department of Homeland Security shall establish an alternative to detention pilot program in which aliens may be released to the supervision of a qualified organization that has contracted with the federal government to facilitate such aliens' compliance with all stages of the immigration proceedings. An alien who fails to comply with program requirements may be subjected to arrest, detention, and expedited removal.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
