<bill session="114" type="h" number="4524" updated="2019-04-11T15:42:42Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Social Security Act to provide for mandatory funding, to ensure that the families that have infants and toddlers, have a family income of not more than 200 percent of the applicable Federal poverty guideline, and need child care have access to high-quality infant and toddler child care by the end of fiscal year 2026, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Child Care Access to Resources for Early-learning Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Child CARE Act</title>
    <title type="display">Child CARE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000373" joined="2016-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001281" joined="2016-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001292" joined="2016-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000216" joined="2016-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2016-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000462" joined="2016-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2016-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000263" joined="2016-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2016-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001188" joined="2016-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2016-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2016-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000480" joined="2016-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000187" joined="2016-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Worker and Family Support" code="HSWM03" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2539"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Child Care Access to Resources for Early-learning Act or the Child CARE Act 

This bill amends part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF) of title IV of the Social Security Act to make appropriations through FY2021 to the Department of Health and Human Services for allotments to states to:

 expand access to high-quality child care for infants and toddlers from low-income families who do not receive child care funded through the Child Care and Development (CCD) Fund, and increase the quality of such care for infants and toddlers who do receive child care funded through the CCD Fund. The state shall reserve at least 80% of funds for direct services provided through grants, contracts, or certificates, to expand access to high-quality child care for infants and toddlers and to increase parental options for and access to such care.

The state shall use the cost of a mandatory triennial high-quality child care study to ensure that for all infant and toddler child care slots: (1) the child care is of sufficient quality, (2) the care providers are supported along a career pathway to achieve higher levels of training and education, and (3) the provider rates are sufficient.

The state shall also ensure that all infant and toddler child care providers participating in CCD Fund-supported activities meet certain quality standards by the end of FY2026.

The state shall: (1) identify underserved geographic areas and special populations; and (2) develop and implement a plan to increase the availability of high-quality child care in such areas and populations, especially those that are hard-to-serve.

The state shall reserve certain funds to carry out specified activities to increase the quality of child care programs for infants and toddlers in eligible families.

An Indian tribe or tribal organization that receives a grant through an allotment for Indian and Native Hawaiian Child Care shall use the grant funds to provide, by the end of FY2026, access to high-quality, culturally and linguistically appropriate child care for infants and toddlers for eligible families in the tribal community.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
