<bill session="114" type="h" number="1517" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:04Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SMOKE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Selling and Marketing to Our Kids E-Cigarettes Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide greater clarity in the regulation of electronic nicotine delivery systems, including electronic cigarettes, cigars, cigarillos, pipes, and hookahs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SMOKE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001175"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001097" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2015-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2015-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000581" joined="2015-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2015-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2015-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2015-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-19T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop Selling and Marketing to Our Kids E-Cigarettes Act or the SMOKE Act

Amends the Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to define "electronic nicotine delivery system" (e-cigarette) and "e-liquid" (solution used in an e-cigarette). Gives the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) authority to regulate e-cigarettes and e-liquids as tobacco products.

Amends the Federal Cigarette Labeling and Advertising Act to include e-cigarettes and e-liquids in the definition of cigarettes, thereby: (1) requiring warning labels to appear on packaging and advertising, and (2) prohibiting advertising in electronic media regulated by the Federal Communications Commission.

Requires the FDA to study the effects of flavorings added to e-cigarettes and e-liquids, including whether flavorings appeal to children or help adults quit smoking. Requires, upon completion of the study, the FDA to consider restricting the use of flavorings.

Directs the FDA to require child-proof packaging for e-cigarettes and e-liquids.

Directs the FDA to set nicotine dosage and concentration limits for e-cigarettes and e-liquids, respectively, and allows for exceptions.

Prohibits advertisement, promotion, or marketing of e-cigarettes and e-liquids in a manner that increases their use by minors. Sets forth authority for: (1) the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to enforce violations as an unfair or deceptive act or practice, and (2) states to bring civil actions on behalf of residents threatened or adversely affected by a violation. Allows the FTC to intervene and appeal in state actions.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
