<bill session="114" type="h" number="2958" updated="2019-02-01T21:05:40Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Dine College Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To fulfill the United States Government's trust responsibility to serve the higher education needs of the Navajo people and to clarify, unify, and modernize prior Din&#233; College legislation.</title>
    <title type="display">Dine College Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000368"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2015-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Investment" code="HSED13" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Dine College Act of 2015

Authorizes Dine College to receive federal funding and resources for its operation, improvement, and growth, including to:

 provide higher education programs and vocational and technical education for citizens of the Navajo Nation and others; preserve and protect the Navajo language, philosophy, and culture for citizens of the Navajo Nation and others; provide Navajo communities and people with employment and training opportunities; provide economic development and community outreach for Navajo communities and people; and provide a safe learning, working, and living environment for students, employees, and the public. Authorizes appropriations to Dine College to pay for its operation and maintenance. Allows such funds to be treated as non-federal, private funds for purposes of any provision of federal law that requires that non-federal or private funds of the College be used in a project for a specific purpose. Directs the Department of the Interior to fund the operation and maintenance of the College separately from tribal colleges and universities recognized and funded by the Tribally Controlled College or University Assistance Act of 1978.

Directs: (1) an inventory prepared by the College identifying repairs, alterations, and renovations to facilities required to meet health and safety standards and other factors to be submitted to Interior by January 31, 2016; (2) Interior to conduct a detailed survey of all capital projects and facility needs of the College and to report to specified congressional committees by October 31, 2016; and (3) Interior to use the College's inventory as baseline data to inform the survey. Authorizes the College to use funds provided under this Act to undertake any renovations and repairs to the infrastructure of the College identified in the survey.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
