<bill session="114" type="h" number="5747" updated="2018-11-09T00:09:33Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">S.O.S. Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title II of the Social Security Act to improve solvency and stability for future generations.</title>
    <title type="display">S.O.S. Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000587"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001271" joined="2016-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000754" joined="2016-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2016-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000589" joined="2016-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000592" joined="2016-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001192" joined="2016-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Social Security" code="HSWM01" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="20"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">S.O.S. Act of 2016

This bill amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to increase the contribution and benefit base for 2017 through 2019.

 The bill revises the computation of primary insurance amounts to include surplus average indexed monthly earnings (AIME) in determining them, adjust surplus earnings for purposes of determining the surplus AIME, and reduce the third bend point factor.

The retirement age shall increase past 67 years by certain formulae.

Cost-of-living adjustments shall involve the Chained Consumer Price Index for all Urban Consumers published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor.

 The bill formulates a minimum monthly insurance benefit, and establishes an increased benefit for beneficiaries on account of long-term eligibility, starting 20 years after they become eligible for monthly OASDI benefits.

 The bill revises a certain formula to increase benefit computation years for purposes of calculating primary OASDI insurance amounts.

 This bill amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to make it out of order in the House of Representatives or the Senate to consider any:

 budget resolution that sets forth totals for any fiscal year regarding the Social Security Trust Funds that are less than the totals of the Social Security Trust Funds for that fiscal year as calculated in accordance with a current services baseline, or spending or tax legislation that would cause any totals to be less than the Funds totals for the covered fiscal year. The bill declares that this latter point of order shall not apply to Social Security reform legislation.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
