<amendment session="115" chamber="h" number="632" updated="2019-07-16T21:20:05Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2018-05-18T10:40:09-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001074"/>
  <offered datetime="2018-05-18"/>
  <description>In title XI, at the end of subtitle F insert the following:    SEC. XX. DEPREDATION PERMITS FOR BLACK VULTURES.    (a) In General- The Secretary of the Interior, in conjunction with the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, may issue depredation permits to livestock farmers, authorizing takings of black vultures otherwise prohibited by Federal law to prevent such vultures from taking livestock during the calving season. ***.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 30 printed in House Report 115-679 to allow the Secretary of the Interior, in conjunction with the Director of the US Fish and Wildlife Service, to issue depredation permits to livestock farmers authorizing the taking of black vultures otherwise prohibited by law to prevent damage to livestock during calving season.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2018-05-18T10:40:09-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Hollingsworth amendment (A047) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-05-18T10:32:42-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A047) offered by Mr. Hollingsworth.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4224-4225" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4224" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-18"/>
    <action datetime="2018-05-18T10:32:42-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A047) offered by Mr. Hollingsworth.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4224-4225" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4224" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-18T10:40:09-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-18T10:40:09-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Hollingsworth amendment (A047) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-18">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
