<bill session="114" type="s" number="2102" updated="2018-09-07T15:13:11Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Standard Merger and Acquisition Reviews Through Equal Rules Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Clayton Act and the Federal Trade Commission Act to provide that the Federal Trade Commission shall exercise authority with respect to mergers only under the Clayton Act and only in the same procedural manner as the Attorney General exercises such authority.</title>
    <title type="display">Standard Merger and Acquisition Reviews Through Equal Rules Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000577"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2015-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000542" joined="2016-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2016-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2015-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2015-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-07">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary Subcommittee on Antitrust, Competition Policy and Consumer Rights. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-09">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary Subcommittee on Antitrust, Competition Policy and Consumer Rights. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Antitrust, Competition Policy and Consumer Rights" code="SSJU01" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="2745"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Standard Merger and Acquisition Reviews Through Equal Rules Act of 2015

This bill amends the Clayton Act with respect to actions brought by the Attorney General for violations of antitrust laws. The Federal Trade Commission (FTC) is required, but only under the Clayton Act, to exercise the same authority and procedures of the Attorney General specified in the Act with respect to the prohibition against acquisition by one corporation of the stock of another (merger) that may substantially lessen competition or tend to create a monopoly.

The Federal Trade Commission Act (FTCA) is amended to exclude proposed mergers, acquisitions, joint ventures, or similar transactions from FTC proceedings, except in cases where the FTC approves an agreement with the parties to the transaction that contains a consent order.

Jurisdiction is granted to the U.S. district courts to issue writs of mandamus commanding compliance with the FTCA or any FTC order, if the FTC applies to such courts with respect to any activity related to consummation of a merger, acquisition, joint venture, or similar transaction that results in an unfair method of competition.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
