<bill session="114" type="h" number="4943" updated="2019-01-09T21:10:16Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tribal Tax and Investment Reform Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to treat Indian tribal governments in the same manner as State governments for certain Federal tax purposes, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Tribal Tax and Investment Reform Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000188"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000290" joined="2016-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2016-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" code="HSED02" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1542"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="835"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3365"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Tribal Tax and Investment Reform Act of 2016

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) to include Indian tribal governments in an annual allocation of a national tax-exempt bond volume cap. The bill repeals provisions that limit an Indian tribal government's eligibility to issue tax-exempt bonds or to be exempt from specified excise taxes to transactions involving the exercise of an essential government function customarily performed by state and local governments.

The bill amends the IRC and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to treat employee benefit or pension plans maintained by Indian tribes and domestic relations orders issued pursuant to tribal law in the same manner as plans maintained by states and domestic relations orders issued pursuant to state law.

The bill treats tribal charities and foundations in the same manner as charities and foundations funded and controlled by other governmental entities for purposes of the tax-exempt status of, and deduction for contributions to, such organizations.

The bill amends the Social Security Act to give Indian tribes or tribal organizations access to the Federal Parent Locator Service if they are eligible for a grant to operate a child support enforcement program. It makes those tribes and tribal organizations eligible to participate in the program that collects past-due support from individual tax refunds.

An Indian tribal government may determine whether a child has special needs for the purpose of the tax credit for the adoption of a child with special needs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
