<bill session="115" type="h" number="4182" updated="2019-06-17T18:20:23Z">
  <state datetime="2017-11-30T16:52:44-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-11-30T16:52:44-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to modify probationary periods with respect to positions within the competitive service and the Senior Executive Service, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Ensuring a Qualified Civil Service Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">EQUALS Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Ensuring a Qualified Civil Service Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">EQUALS Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring a Qualified Civil Service Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring a Qualified Civil Service Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">EQUALS Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">EQUALS Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">EQUALS Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001108"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001071" joined="2017-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000583" joined="2017-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001187" joined="2017-10-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-10-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-02">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-11-02" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 19 - 17.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-11-16">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 115-415.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-11-16" calendar="Union" number="307">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 307.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-11-28">
      <text>Supplemental report filed by the Committee on Oversight and Government, H. Rept. 115-415, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-29T17:19:29-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 635 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4182 and H.R. 1699. Resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 4182 under a structured rule, with one hour of general debate, and one motion to recommit with or without instructions. Resolution also provides for consideration of H.R. 1699 under a closed rule, with one hour of general debate, and one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-30T15:18:13-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 635.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9547-9559" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H9553-9554" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-30T15:18:18-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4182 and H.R. 1699. Resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 4182 under a structured rule, with one hour of general debate, and one motion to recommit with or without instructions. Resolution also provides for consideration of H.R. 1699 under a closed rule, with one hour of general debate, and one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-30T15:18:59-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 635 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-30T15:19:01-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Michael K. Simpson to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-30T15:19:11-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 4182.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-30T15:49:49-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 635, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hastings amendment no. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-30T15:57:37-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hastings amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Comer demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-30T15:59:35-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 635, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gianforte amendment no. 3, as modified.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-30T16:03:05-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 635, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Connolly amendment no. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-30T16:10:32-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Connolly amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Connolly demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-30T16:11:24-05:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on adoption of amendments, which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-30T16:45:27-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 4182.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-30T16:45:48-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-30T16:46:14-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="648" datetime="2017-11-30T16:52:44-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 213 - 204 (Roll no. 648).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-11-30T16:52:46-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-01">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="unknown" number="635"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Employee performance"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h491"/>
    <amendment number="h490"/>
    <amendment number="h489"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2017-10-31T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Ensuring a Qualified Civil Service Act of 2017 or the EQUALS Act of 2017

This bill requires the probationary period before an appointment in the competitive civil service or an initial appointment as a supervisor or manager becomes final to last for two years. The two-year probationary period applies to any position that requires formal training or a license, and any other position not requiring formal training or a license.

Each agency must ensure that: (1) an announcement of a vacant position and an offer of appointment clearly state the terms and conditions of the probationary period,&#160;(2) an individual who is&#160;required to complete a probationary period receives timely notice of requirements to successfully complete the probationary period, (3) a supervisor or manager of an individual who is required to complete the probationary period receives notification not less than 30 days before the end of the probationary period, and&#160;(4) certification of such successful completion is made.

The bill increases from one to two years: (1) the probationary period after which an individual's appointment as a career appointee in the Senior Executive Service becomes final, and (2) the continuous employment requirement for coverage under adverse action procedures for misconduct.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-415</report>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-415,Part 2</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
