<bill session="114" type="h" number="384" updated="2019-05-09T23:15:17Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend titles 5 and 28, United States Code, to require annual reports to Congress on, and the maintenance of databases on, awards of fees and other expenses to prevailing parties in certain administrative proceedings and court cases to which the United States is a party, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Open Book on Equal Access to Justice Act</title>
    <title type="display">Open Book on Equal Access to Justice Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2015-01-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="556"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3279"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-14T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Open Book on Equal Access to Justice Act

Amends the Equal Access to Justice Act and the federal judicial code to require the Chairman of the Administrative Conference of the United States to report to Congress annually on the amount of fees and other expenses awarded to prevailing parties other than the United States in certain administrative proceedings and civil action court cases (excluding tort cases) to which the United States is a party, including settlement agreements. Requires that such reports: (1) describe the number, nature, and amount of the awards, the claims involved in the controversy, and any other relevant information that may aid Congress in evaluating the scope and impact of such awards; and (2) be made available to the public online.

Directs the Chairman to create and maintain online a searchable database containing specified information with respect to each award, including the name of the agency involved, the name of each party to whom the award was made, the amount of the award, and the basis for finding that the position of the agency concerned was not substantially justified.

Directs the head of each agency, including the Attorney General, to provide the Chairman all information requested to comply with such requirements.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
