<bill session="114" type="s" number="691" updated="2018-06-02T06:40:45Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nuclear Waste Informed Consent Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Nuclear Regulatory Commission to obtain the consent of affected State and local governments before authorizing the construction of a nuclear waste repository.</title>
    <title type="display">Nuclear Waste Informed Consent Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000146"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2015-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1387" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="1364"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1825"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Nuclear Waste Informed Consent Act

This bill prohibits the Nuclear Regulatory Commission from authorizing construction of a nuclear waste repository unless the Secretary of Energy has entered into an agreement to host the repository with the following entities:

 the governor of the state in which the repository is proposed to be located, each affected unit of local government, any unit of general local government contiguous to the affected unit if spent nuclear fuel or high-level radioactive waste will be transported through that unit of general local government for disposal at the repository, and each affected Indian tribe. Furthermore, any agreement to host the repository must meet the following conditions:

 it must be written and signed by all parties, it must be binding on the parties, and it shall not be amended or revoked except by mutual agreement of the parties.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
