<bill session="113" type="s" number="2374" updated="2016-10-25T16:30:17Z">
  <state datetime="2014-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Creating Higher Education Affordability Necessary to Compete Economically Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Middle Class CHANCE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve college affordability.</title>
    <title type="display">Middle Class CHANCE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000550"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2014-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2014-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000361" joined="2014-06-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="identical" number="4902"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-05-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Creating Higher Education Affordability Necessary to Compete Economically Act or the Middle Class CHANCE Act - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to increase the maximum Federal Pell Grant for award year 2014-2015 and adjust it each subsequent award year to account for changes in the Consumer Price Index.

Directs the Secretary of Education to award an additional Pell Grant to an eligible student who: (1) has received a Pell Grant for an award year, and (2) is enrolled in a program of study for one or more additional payment periods during the same award year that are not otherwise covered by the Pell Grant.

Limits the total amount of the Pell Grants awarded to such student for the award year to 150% of the maximum Pell Grant for such award year.

Raises, from 12 semesters to 15 semesters, the period during which a student may receive Federal Pell Grants.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
