<bill session="114" type="s" number="1406" updated="2018-06-02T06:54:13Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Saving Access to Compounded Medications for Special Needs Patients Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to pharmacy compounding.</title>
    <title type="display">Saving Access to Compounded Medications for Special Needs Patients Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000127"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Saving Access to Compounded Medications for Special Needs Patients Act

This bill amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to allow drugs to be compounded (manufactured at a small scale) and distributed to practitioners for treatment of, or administration to, patients of that practitioner. Currently, drugs may be compounded only for identified individual patients. (Compounded drugs do not need to meet certain requirements for drugs regarding manufacturing, labeling, or FDA approval.)

Compounded drugs must comply with United States Pharmacopeia standards.

A memorandum of understanding (MOU) between the FDA and a state regarding compounded drugs no longer must address interstate distribution of inordinate amounts of compounded drugs. Such an MOU must not create an unfunded mandate on a state. (Compounders in states that do not have an MOU with the FDA may not distribute more than 5% of their orders out of state.)</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
