<bill session="114" type="h" number="1888" updated="2019-02-08T20:13:07Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fluke Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for an equitable management of summer flounder based on geographic, scientific, and economic data and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Fluke Fairness Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Z000017"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water, Oceans, and Wildlife" code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1107"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Fluke Fairness Act 

This bill directs the Mid-Atlantic Fishery Management Council to submit for approval by the Department of Commerce a modified fishery management plan for the commercial and recreational management of summer flounder, or an amendment to the plan, that:

 is based on the best scientific information available; reflects changes in the distribution, abundance, and location of summer flounder in establishing distribution of the commercial and recreational catch quotas; considers regional, coastwide, or other management measures that comply with national standards under the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act; and prohibits the allocation of catch quotas on a state-by-state basis using historical landings data that does not reflect the status of the summer flounder stock, based on the most recent scientific information. Commerce must prepare and approve a plan if the Council fails to submit the modifications or amendments.

The Government Accountability Office must assess and report on whether the subsequent implementation of the approved plan or amendment complies with national standards.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
