<bill session="114" type="h" number="2060" updated="2019-02-20T18:37:51Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States-Mexico Economic Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote economic partnership and cooperation between the United States and Mexico, particularly in the areas of academic exchange, entrepreneurship, and infrastructure integration.</title>
    <title type="display">United States-Mexico Economic Partnership Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001063"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Western Hemisphere.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Western Hemisphere, Civilian Security and Trade" code="HSFA07" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">United States-Mexico Economic Partnership Act

This bill authorizes the President to expand U.S.-Mexico academic exchange programs at the secondary, post-secondary, and post-graduate levels.

It is the sense of Congress that such programs should reflect the goals of the 100,000 Strong in the Americas Initiative and should seek to double the number of students studying in each other's country within five years.

Priority should be given to strengthening ties between communities and academic institutions in those portions of the United States and Mexico that are within 100 kilometers of the international boundary between those countries (covered region).

The President is authorized to establish programs to support cooperation, training, and mentoring of entrepreneurs in the covered region.

It is the sense of Congress that such programs should seek to provide not less than 100 grants of not more than $25,000 each for program participants.

The President is authorized to promote U.S.-Mexico energy infrastructure coordination and cooperation through programs to support vocational-level education, internships, and exchanges between the two countries, particularly in the region in which the Eagle Ford Shale is located and in proximity to the covered region.

It is the sense of Congress that such programs should seek to provide education, internships, and exchanges for at least 1,000 program participants.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
