<bill session="114" type="h" number="5711" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:38Z">
  <state datetime="2016-11-17T12:02:23-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-11-17T12:02:23-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">No U.S. Financing for Iran Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">No Ex-Im Assistance for Terrorism Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the Secretary of the Treasury from authorizing certain transactions by a U.S. financial institution in connection with the export or re-export of a commercial passenger aircraft to the Islamic Republic of Iran.</title>
    <title type="display">No U.S. Financing for Iran Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001058"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2016-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Monetary Policy and Trade Prior to Introduction and Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 33 - 21.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-11-14">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 114-810.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-11-14" calendar="Union" number="634">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 634.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-11-14T19:31:58-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 921 Reported to House. The rule provides for one hour of general debate on H.R. 5711 and H.R. 5982.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-16T17:47:46-05:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Huizenga (MI) asked unanimous consent that the question of adopting a motion to recommit on H.R. 5711 be subject to postponement as though under Clause 8 of Rule 20. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-16T17:47:55-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 921.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6255-6265" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6255-6256" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-16T17:48:00-05:00">
      <text>The rule provides for one hour of general debate on H.R. 5711 and H.R. 5982.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-16T17:49:26-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 5711.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-16T18:53:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 921, the House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Huizenga (MI) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-16T19:02:10-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Swalwell (CA) moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Financial Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6264" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6264" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-16T19:02:59-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to add a section to prohibit the Secretary of the Treasury from authorizing a transaction described under section 101 by a U.S. financial institution if such institution is engaged in business with a foreign entity that has been found to have engaged in or authorized cyber attacks targeting any election held in the United States.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-16T19:09:17-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the motion to recommit with instructions, the Chair put the question on adopting the motion and by voice vote, announced that the nays had prevailed. Mr. Swalwell (CA) demanded the yeas and nays, and pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the motion to recommit with instructions until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-17T11:49:56-05:00">
      <text>The Chair announced that the unfinished business and pursuant to a previous order of the House, the question was on adoption of a motion to recommit with instructions, which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-17T11:49:57-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6288-6289" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-17T11:56:37-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 181 - 235 (Roll no. 586).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6288-6289" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="587" datetime="2016-11-17T12:02:23-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 243 - 174 (Roll no. 587).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-11-17T12:02:24-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Monetary Policy and Trade" code="HSBA20" name="House Financial Services" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5716"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5729"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="114" relation="unknown" number="921"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1480"/>
    <amendment number="h1479"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2016-11-17T15:39:08Z" status="Passed House amended">No U.S. Financing for Iran Act

TITLE I--IRAN FINANCING PROHIBITION

(Sec. 101) This bill prohibits the Department of the Treasury from authorizing U.S. financial institution transactions in connection with the export or re-export of commercial passenger aircraft to the Islamic Republic of Iran.

(Sec. 102) Any transaction authorized by Treasury before enactment of this bill is revoked.

TITLE II--NO EX-IM ASSISTANCE FOR TERRORISM

No Ex-Im Assistance for Terrorism Act

(Sec. 202) This bill amends the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 to prohibit the Export-Import Bank from guaranteeing, insuring, extending credit, or participating in the extension of credit in connection with the export of U.S. goods or services sought by:

 the Government of Iran, an entity owned or controlled by it, an entity created under Iranian law, or a foreign subsidiary of such an entity; an entity involving the Government of Iran, owned or controlled by the Government of Iran, created under Iranian law, or a foreign subsidiary of such an entity; or a non-U.S. entity that, in the last five-years, has leased or sold aircraft to the Government of Iran, or a subsidiary or controlling parent of such a non-U.S. entity. The Bank must cancel approved financing if it finds that such financing has facilitated the export, sale, or lease of an aircraft to the Government of Iran or a related entity and must seek immediate recovery of any amount it has provided in connection with the transaction.

TITLE III--SUNSET

(Sec. 301) This bill shall cease to be effective 30 days after the President certifies to Congress that the Government of Iran has ceased support for acts of international terrorism.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-810</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
