<bill session="114" type="s" number="230" updated="2019-06-21T11:07:09Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-30">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the conveyance of certain property to the Yukon Kuskokwim Health Corporation located in Bethel, Alaska.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to provide for the conveyance of certain property to the Yukon Kuskokwim Health Corporation located in Bethel, Alaska.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2015-04-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-02-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-05-11">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Barrasso without amendment. With written report No. 114-38.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-05-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="78">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 78.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4656-4657" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2015-06-25" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4656-4657" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25T18:00:29-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25T18:28:32-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-16T16:16:13-04:00">
      <text>Mr. McClintock moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-16T16:16:40-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6002-6003" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-16T16:16:42-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 230.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote2" datetime="2015-09-16T16:21:21-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6002" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-09-16T16:21:22-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2015-09-21">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2015-09-30" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="114-56" type="public" datetime="2015-09-30">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 114-56.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="521"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2077"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2015-10-01T03:59:58Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on June 25, 2015. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

 (Sec. 1) Directs the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to convey to the Yukon Kuskokwim Health Corporation in Bethel, Alaska, all interest of the United States in certain property (including all land and appurtenances) containing 22.98 acres, for use in connection with health and social services programs.

States that this conveyance by warranty deed shall supersede and render of no future effect any quitclaim deed to the property executed by HHS and the Corporation.

Declares that this conveyance: (1) shall be made by warranty deed; and (2) shall not require any consideration from the Corporation for the property, impose any obligation, term, or condition on the Corporation, or allow for any U.S. reversionary interest in the property. (Sec. 3) Shields the Corporation from being liable for soil, surface water, groundwater, or other contamination resulting from the disposal, release, or presence of environmental contamination (including oil or petroleum products, hazardous substances, hazardous materials, hazardous waste, pollutants, toxic substances, solid waste, or any other environmental contamination or hazard under any federal or Alaska law).

Accords to HHS any easement or access to the conveyed property as may be necessary to satisfy any retained obligations and liability.

Requires the HHS to be in compliance with requirements under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 respecting certain deeds for the transfer of U.S. owned real property on which any hazardous substance was stored for one year or more, disposed of, or known to have been released.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-38</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
