<bill session="114" type="h" number="925" updated="2019-05-09T23:32:57Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote conservation, improve public land, and provide for sensible development in Douglas County, Nevada, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Douglas County Conservation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Douglas County Conservation Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000369"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001070" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001055" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2015-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indians, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water, Oceans, and Wildlife" code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indigenous Peoples of the United States" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="472"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4688"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-12T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Douglas County Conservation Act of 2015

Directs the Forest Service to convey approximately 67 acres of certain Forest Service land (Lake Tahoe-Nevada State Park) to the state of Nevada to be used for the conservation of wildlife or natural resources or for a public park.

Directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to make publicly available a prospectus to solicit one or more concessionaires for the approximately 125 acres of land identified as the Round Hill Pines Resort and the approximately 448 acres of land identified as the Zephyr Shoals.

 Directs the Forest Service for National Forest System land and the Department of Interior for land managed by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) to convey approximately 7,990 acres of specified federal land to Douglas County, Nevada, to be used for flood control or any other public purpose. Prohibits such land from being disposed of by the county.

Directs the Forest Service or Interior, as appropriate, to conduct one or more sales of specified public lands in the county to qualified bidders, with the option for the state or county to obtain the land for public purposes before the land is offered for sale. Amends the Southern Nevada Public Land Management Act of 1998 to specify the disposition of funds from a sale.

Transfers all interest of the United States in the approximately 1,016 acres of certain federal land which shall be held in trust for the Washoe Tribe of Nevada and California, and which shall become part of the Tribe's reservation. Prohibits the conduct of certain gaming on such land. Designates approximately 12,330 acres of specified federal land managed by the BLM, to be known as the Burbank Canyons Wilderness, as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System.

Releases the approximately 1,065 acres of public land in the Burbank Canyons Wilderness study area not designated as wilderness by this Act from further study for designation as wilderness.

Authorizes USDA to transfer from the Forest Service to Douglas County, Nevada, certain lands or interests in Forest Service land which are unsuitable for Forest Service administration or necessary for a public purpose.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
