<bill session="115" type="s" number="2126" updated="2019-07-18T05:27:21Z">
  <state datetime="2017-11-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 to provide a temporary exemption for low-revenue issuers from certain auditor attestation requirements.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fostering Innovation Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fostering Innovation Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Fostering Innovation Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000476"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2017-11-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-11-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-26">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 115-354.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3978"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="6147"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1645"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="10"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-11-15T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fostering Innovation Act of 2017

This bill amends the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 to establish a temporary exemption&#160;from the requirement that each registered public accounting firm that prepares or issues an audit report for an issuer of securities (other than an emerging growth company) shall attest to, and report on, the internal control assessment made by the management of the issuer. Specifically, this requirement shall not apply with respect to an audit report prepared for an issuer that:

 ceased to be an emerging growth company on the last day of its fiscal year following the five-year period beginning on the date of its first sale of common equity securities, had average annual gross revenues of less than $50 million as of its most recently completed fiscal year, and is not a large accelerated filer. An issuer shall&#160;cease to be eligible for the&#160;exemption at the earliest of: (1) the last day of the fiscal year following the&#160;10-year period beginning on the date of its&#160;first sale of common equity securities, (2) the last day of the fiscal year in which its average annual gross revenues exceed $50 million, or (3) when the issuer becomes a large accelerated filer.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
