<bill session="114" type="h" number="1885" updated="2019-01-09T21:26:02Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing Access to Rural Postal Services Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 39, United States Code, to cap rural post office closures at no more than 5 percent of total closures in any given year, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Securing Access to Rural Postal Services Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001172"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000369" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000449" joined="2015-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2015-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2015-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="U.S. Postal Service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Securing Access to Rural Postal Services Act of 2015

Prohibits the U.S. Postal Service (USPS), in any calendar year, from closing, consolidating, or suspending the operations of more than 5% of the postal facilities operating as of the first day of such calendar year and that were within specified cost ascertainment groupings as of June 23, 2011, except as specifically authorized by law.

Defines "postal facility" as a post office, post office branch, post office classified station, or other facility operated by the USPS, the primary function of which is to provide retail postal services.

Requires the USPS to conduct nonbinding surveys on proposed post office closings or consolidations to allow customers an opportunity to indicate their preference between or among such a closing or consolidation and one or more alternative options. Directs the USPS, if such a closure or consolidation is necessary, to provide access to postal services through the alternative preferred by survey participants and, if the preferred alternative is unable to be provided or is cost prohibitive, permits the USPS to provide alternative access through different means and requires the USPS to notify customers with a written explanation.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
