<bill session="114" type="h" number="5471" updated="2018-08-16T22:35:56Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-16T13:39:22-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-06-16T13:39:22-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Countering Terrorist Radicalization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Countering Terrorist Radicalization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To combat terrorist recruitment in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Countering Terrorist Radicalization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001157"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001103" joined="2016-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000625" joined="2016-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000460" joined="2016-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000459" joined="2016-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001073" joined="2016-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000386" joined="2016-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000375" joined="2016-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2016-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000583" joined="2016-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001197" joined="2016-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001150" joined="2016-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000601" joined="2016-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2016-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16T09:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. McCaul moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16T09:16:02-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3919-3925" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16T09:16:04-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5471.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16T10:15:07-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16T13:28:16-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3953" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="333" datetime="2016-06-16T13:39:22-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 402 - 15 (Roll no. 333).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3919-3920" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16T13:39:24-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="3072"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4401"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4407"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4820"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-16T14:45:44Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Countering Terrorist Radicalization Act

TITLE I--AMPLIFYING LOCAL EFFORTS TO ROOT OUT TERROR

(Sec. 101) This bill authorizes the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to provide training at state and major urban area fusion centers for the purpose of administering community awareness briefings and related activities in furtherance of its efforts to counter violent extremism, identify and report suspicious activities, and increase awareness of and more quickly identify terrorism threats, including the travel or attempted travel of individuals from the United States to support a foreign terrorist organization abroad. (A "fusion center" serves as a focal point within the state and local environment for the receipt, analysis, gathering, and sharing of threat-related information between the federal government and state, local, tribal, territorial and private sector partners.)

(Sec. 102) The bill directs DHS to assess its efforts to support countering violent extremism at the state, local, tribal, and territorial levels. Such assessment shall:

 catalog such efforts; review cooperative agreements between DHS and such governments relating to countering violent extremism; and evaluate DHS plans and any potential opportunities to better support such governments that are in furtherance of DHS's countering violent extremism objectives and consistent with all relevant constitutional, legal, and privacy protections. (Sec. 103) DHS shall notify Congress of the number of employees of state, local, tribal, and territorial governments with security clearances sponsored by DHS, including a detailed list of the agencies that employ such employees, the level of clearance held, and whether such employees are assigned as representatives to fusion centers.

TITLE II--COUNTERMESSAGING TERRORIST ORGANIZATIONS

(Sec. 201) DHS shall incorporate the public testimonials of former extremists into its efforts to combat terrorist recruitment. Such efforts may include: (1) counter-messaging of foreign terrorist organization communications, and (2) related community engagement and public education efforts.

TITLE III--COUNTERTERRORISM ADVISORY BOARD

(Sec. 301) This title amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish in DHS a board to coordinate and integrate DHS's intelligence, activities, and policy related to its counterterrorism mission and functions. The board shall: (1) meet on a regular basis to discuss intelligence and coordinate ongoing threat mitigation efforts and departmental activities, and (2) advise the Secretary of DHS on the issuance of terrorism alerts. The Secretary shall appoint a Coordinator for Counterterrorism within DHS to serve as the chair of the board.

TITLE IV--PROHIBITION ON NEW FUNDING

(Sec. 401) No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
