<bill session="114" type="s" number="2882" updated="2018-06-02T07:18:26Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ozone Standards Implementation Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to facilitate efficient State implementation of ground-level ozone standards, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Ozone Standards Implementation Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001047"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2016-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2016-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2016-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000444" joined="2016-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2016-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2016-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2016-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001141" joined="2016-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000127" joined="2016-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-22">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works Subcommittee on Clean Air and Nuclear Safety. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Clean Air and Nuclear Safety" code="SSEV10" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4000"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4775"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Ozone Standards Implementation Act of 2016

This bill amends the Clean Air Act by revising the National Ambient Air Quality Standards (NAAQS) program.

The bill delays the implementation of the ozone NAAQS that were published in 2015. The bill extends until: (1) October 26, 2024, the deadline for states to submit designations to implement the 2015 ozone NAAQS; and (2) October 26, 2025, the deadline for the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to designate state areas as attainment, nonattainment, or unclassifiable areas with respect to the 2015 ozone NAAQS. States must submit a state implementation plan (SIP) by October 26, 2026, to implement, maintain, and enforce the 2015 ozone NAAQS.

The bill also changes the review cycle for criteria pollutant NAAQS from a 5-year review cycle to a 10-year review cycle. The EPA may not complete its next review of ozone NAAQS before October 26, 2025.

Prior to establishing or revising NAAQS, the EPA must obtain advice from its scientific advisory committee regarding potential adverse public health, welfare, social, economic, or energy effects which may result from attaining and maintaining NAAQS.

The EPA must publish regulations and guidance for implementing NAAQS concurrently with the issuance of a new or revised standard. New or revised NAAQS must not apply to preconstruction permits for constructing or modifying a major emitting facility or major stationary source of air pollutants until those regulations and guidance have been published.

The bill revises requirements concerning SIPs for extreme ozone nonattainment areas and particulate matter nonattainment areas.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
