<bill session="114" type="h" number="4021" updated="2019-04-11T15:42:42Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To award grants to encourage State educational agencies, local educational agencies, and schools to utilize technology to improve student achievement and college and career readiness, the skills of teachers and school leaders, and the efficiency and productivity of education systems at all levels.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancing Education Through Technology Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Enhancing Education Through Technology Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000808"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="451"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-16T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Enhancing Education Through Technology Act of 2015

This bill amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to modify grant funding related to education technology and innovation.

The Department of Education shall award matching grants to states to strengthen state and local technological infrastructure and professional learning that supports digital learning.

Grant funds are allocated among states in proportion to each state's share of school improvement funds under the ESEA.

States must use at least 90% of their grant funds to award subgrants to local educational agencies (LEAs), which shall use: (1) at least 40% of those funds to support the acquisition of technology that addresses their technology infrastructure and access needs; and (2) at least 40% of those funds to provide digital age professional learning opportunities for teachers, principals, school leaders, paraprofessionals, library and media personnel, specialized instructional support personnel, technology coordinators, and administrators.

To carry out grant and subgrant activities, including the purchase of technology, states may form purchasing consortia with other states, and LEAs may form purchasing consortia with other LEAs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
