<bill session="114" type="s" number="1789" updated="2018-06-02T06:57:47Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-08">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States-Jordan Defense Cooperation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">United States-Jordan Defense Cooperation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve defense cooperation between the United States and the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan.</title>
    <title type="display">United States-Jordan Defense Cooperation Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2015-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2015-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2015-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2015-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2015-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2015-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2015-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2015-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2015-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2015-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2015-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2015-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2015-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2015-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2015-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-10-08" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-10-27">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Corker without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-10-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="281">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 281.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="907"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Jordan"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-27T15:28:57Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

United States-Jordan Defense Cooperation Act of 2015

(Sec. 2) Specifies the findings of Congress that:

 as of January 22, 2015, the United States has provided over $3 billion in assistance to respond to the Syria humanitarian crisis, of which nearly $467 million has been provided to Jordan; as of January 2015, according to the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees, there were 621,937 registered Syrian refugees in Jordan, 83.8% of whom lived outside refugee camps; in 2000 the United States and Jordan signed a free-trade agreement that went into force in 2001; in 1996 the United States granted Jordan major non-NATO ally status; and Jordan is suffering from the Syrian refugee crisis and the threat of the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL). (Sec. 3) Urges that U.S. policy should be to:

 support Jordan in its response to the Syrian refugee crisis, provide necessary assistance to support the basic needs of the assimilated Syrian refugees, cooperate with Jordan to combat the terrorist threat from ISIL or other terrorist organizations, and help secure the border between Jordan and Syria and Iraq. (Sec. 4) Expresses the sense of Congress that expeditious consideration of certifications of letters of offer to sell defense articles, defense services, design and construction services, and major defense equipment to Jordan is fully consistent with U. S. security and foreign policy interests and the objectives of world peace and security.

(Sec. 5) Amends the Arms Export Control Act to include Jordan among the countries eligible for certain streamlined defense sales for three years.

(Sec. 6) Authorizes the Department of State to enter into a Memorandum of Understanding with Jordan to increase economic support funds and military cooperation, including joint military exercises, personnel exchanges, support for international peacekeeping missions, and enhanced strategic dialogue.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
