<bill session="115" type="h" number="2493" updated="2019-04-18T16:08:53Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to require individuals nominated or appointed to Senate-confirmed positions or to positions of a confidential or policymaking character to disclose certain types of contributions made or solicited by, or on behalf of, the individuals.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Conflicts from Political Fundraising Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Conflicts from Political Fundraising Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Conflicts from Political Fundraising Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000610"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2017-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2017-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2017-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001168" joined="2017-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2017-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001170" joined="2017-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="1184"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1880"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Office of Government Ethics"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Conflicts from Political Fundraising Act of 2017

This bill amends the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to revise financial disclosure requirements for federal personnel, including: (1) the disclosure of contributions made or solicited by, or on behalf of, individuals nominated or appointed to high level executive positions or to positions of a confidential or policymaking character to political action committees and tax-exempt social welfare or business organizations; and (2) the disclosure of certain gifts to appointees, their spouses, or dependent children.

The Office of Government Ethics shall, upon request, provide to the Chairman or Ranking Member of a House or Senate committee or subcommittee with jurisdiction over the agency to which an individual has been nominated or appointed to a covered position (certain Executive Schedule or Senior Executive Service positions) or is serving in a covered position, each financial disclosure report filed by such individual and any ethics agreement entered into between the agency and the individual.

The office shall issue rules on how an executive branch agency shall address conflicts of interest identified in disclosures through ethics agreements between the agency and its appointees.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
