<bill session="114" type="h" number="4506" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:39Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Know Before You Go Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to help health care consumers comparison shop for medical services based on quality and cost.</title>
    <title type="display">Know Before You Go Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000449"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-09T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Know Before You Go Act of 2016

This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to permit health insurers to include, for plan year accounting purposes, activities related to a transparency tool as activities that improve health care quality. (An insurer must provide a rebate to enrollees if the insurer spends less than a certain percentage of premium revenues on clinical services and activities that improve health care quality.) A transparency tool is a website and telephone support that provides quality of care and cost sharing comparisons among in-network providers.

Such accounting for a plan year is permitted only for insurers that have: (1) significantly increased the percentage of enrollees using a transparency tool compared to the previous year, (2) provided cost sharing estimates for episodes of care upon request, and (3) made available a list of high deductible health plans offered by the insurer to each individual seeking coverage from the insurer.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
