<bill session="114" type="h" number="3498" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:44Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Human Cloning Prohibition Act of 2105 [sic]</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit human cloning.</title>
    <title type="display">Human Cloning Prohibition Act of 2105 [sic]</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000563" joined="2015-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Cell biology and embryology"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Human Cloning Prohibition Act of 2105 

This bill amends the federal criminal code to prohibit human cloning for reproductive and research purposes.

Specifically, the bill makes it a crime for any public or private person or entity to:

 perform, attempt to perform, or participate in an attempt to perform human cloning; or ship, receive, or import a product of human cloning for any purpose. It defines "human cloning" as asexual reproduction by replacing a fertilized or unfertilized egg nucleus with a human somatic (body) cell nucleus to produce a living organism with a human or predominantly human genetic constitution.

A person or entity convicted of a human cloning offense is subject to a fine, up to 10 years in prison, or both. A person or entity who profits from such offense is also subject to a civil penalty of at least $1,000,000.

This bill does not restrict scientific research using nuclear transfer or other cloning techniques to produce molecules, DNA, cells other than human embryos, tissues, organs, plants, or animals other than humans.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
