<amendment session="114" chamber="h" number="918" updated="2019-02-13T19:55:16Z">
  <amends type="h" number="3700" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2016-02-02T16:50:48-05:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000288"/>
  <offered datetime="2016-02-02"/>
  <description>Amendment sought to provide affirmative permission for housing providers who administer U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development funds to report on-time rental payment data for their tenants to credit reporting agencies without requiring and managing individual written consent agreements. Amendment also sought to direct HUD to retain tenant privacy so the furnished information would not specifically note that tenants receive HUD assistance.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment No. 11 printed in House Report 114-411 to provide affirmative permission for housing providers who administer U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development funds to report on-time rental payment data for their tenants to credit reporting agencies without requiring and managing individual written consent agreements; and to direct HUD to retain tenant privacy so the furnished information would not specifically note that tenants receive HUD assistance.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2016-02-02T16:50:48-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="fail">
      <text>On agreeing to the Ellison amendment (A010) Failed by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02T16:43:09-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A010) offered by Mr. Ellison.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H473-474" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H473" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02"/>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02T16:50:48-05:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02T16:50:48-05:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Ellison amendment (A010) Failed by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02T16:43:09-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A010) offered by Mr. Ellison.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H473-474" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H473" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
