<bill session="115" type="h" number="4361" updated="2019-04-18T16:17:58Z">
  <state datetime="2017-11-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-11-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-11-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the use of macroeconomic analysis in estimating the budgetary effects of major revenue legislation.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accurate Budgeting Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accurate Budgeting Act</title>
    <title type="display">Accurate Budgeting Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001189"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-11-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-11-09T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Accurate Budgeting Act 

This bill amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to require the Joint Committee on Taxation to incorporate a macroeconomic impact analysis in estimates of the budgetary effects of major revenue legislation to the extent that it is practicable.

The macroeconomic impact analysis, commonly referred to as dynamic scoring, includes:

 the changes in economic output, employment, interest rates, capital stock, and tax revenues expected to result from the proposal; revenue feedback (changes in revenue resulting from changes in economic growth as a result of the proposal); and the assumptions and data used for the estimate. The bill also amends the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010 (PAYGO) to require estimates of the budgetary effects of major revenue legislation prepared for purposes of PAYGO requirements to incorporate a macroeconomic impact analysis to the extent that it is practicable.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
