<bill session="114" type="s" number="3396" updated="2018-06-02T07:48:27Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require an Air Force report on perfluorooctanoic acid (PFOA) and perfluorooctane sulfonates (PFOS) contamination at certain military installations and require reparation for identified contaminated sites and affected areas.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to require an Air Force report on perfluorooctanoic acid (PFOA) and perfluorooctane sulfonates (PFOS) contamination at certain military installations and require reparation for identified contaminated sites and affected areas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000148"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill requires the Department of the Air Force, in collaboration with the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), to report on perfluorooctanoic acid and perfluorooctane sulfonates contamination at Stewart Air National Guard Base, Newburgh, Plattsburgh, Hoosick Falls, and Petersburgh, New York, and any other appropriate sites.

The report shall include:

 an accelerated time line and status on the inspection and cleanup at Stewart Air National Guard Base, Newburgh, Plattsburgh, Hoosick Falls, and Petersburgh; an update on Air Force efforts to notify everyone potentially impacted by the contamination; an assessment of the Air Force's role, if any, in the new contaminations; a summary of Air Force support for the EPA regarding the latest contaminations; and a proposal requiring financial compensation for cleanup, water accessibility interim programs, and water source filtration initiatives in the event the Air Force is responsible for the contamination.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
