<bill session="114" type="s" number="1606" updated="2018-06-02T06:56:11Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Digital Learning Equity Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to support the development, implementation, and evaluation of innovative strategies and methods to increase out-of-school access to digital learning resources for eligible students in order to increase student and educator engagement and disseminate evidence-based strategies to relevant stakeholders and the public.</title>
    <title type="display">Digital Learning Equity Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000383"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2015-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3582"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Digital Learning Act of 2015

This bill amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish a digital learning equity demonstration program that awards grants for developing, implementing, and evaluating strategies and methods to increase students' home access to the Internet and digital learning resources. This may include such practices as: (1) providing a targeted distribution of technology, such as a modem, that provides out-of-school Internet access to eligible students; (2) educating and training students, parents, and educators regarding the appropriate use of that technology outside of the classroom; and (3) evaluating the effectiveness of relevant strategies and methods.

The Director of the Institute of Education Sciences must complete and publicly disseminate the finding of a national study on the educational trends and behaviors associated with access to digital learning resources outside of the classroom.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
