<bill session="114" type="h" number="3390" updated="2018-11-09T00:09:07Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Qualifying Renewable Chemical Production or Investment Tax Credit Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide credits for the production of renewable chemicals and investments in renewable chemical production facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Qualifying Renewable Chemical Production or Investment Tax Credit Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000096"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000373" joined="2015-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001106" joined="2016-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000451" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000015" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000127" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001156" joined="2016-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2271"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Chemistry"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Materials"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Qualifying Renewable Chemical Production or Investment Tax Credit Act of 2015

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a business-related tax credit for the production of renewable chemicals. The bill defines "renewable chemical" as any chemical that: (1) is produced in the United States from renewable biomass; (2) is sold or used for the production of chemical products, polymers, plastics, or formulated products or as chemicals, polymers, plastics, or formulated products; (3) has a biobased content of 95% or higher; (4) is the product of, or reliant upon, biological or thermal conversion of renewable biomass; (5) is not sold or used for the production of any food, feed, or fuel; and (6) is not a combination of certain specified renewable chemicals.

The bill also allows a tax credit for investment in renewable chemical production facilities.

The bill requires the Department of the Treasury to establish a program to allocate renewable chemical tax credit amounts to eligible taxpayers and imposes an aggregate limit on the amount of credits that may be allocated to not more than $500 million during the 5-year period after enactment of this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
