<amendment session="114" chamber="s" number="78" updated="2019-02-27T14:40:24Z">
  <amends type="s" number="1" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2015-01-22">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000575"/>
  <offered datetime="2015-01-21"/>
  <description>To express the sense of the Senate regarding the conditions for the President entering into bilateral or other international agreements regarding greenhouse gas emissions without proper study of any adverse economic effects, including job losses and harm to the industrial sector, and without the approval of the Senate.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2015-01-22" how="roll" result="fail" roll="20">
      <text>Amendment SA 78, under the order of 1/22/15, not having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, was not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 51 - 46. Record Vote Number: 20.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-01-22">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S372, S390-391, S396" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S390-391" label="text as modified"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-21">
      <text>Amendment SA 78 proposed by Senator Murkowski for Senator Blunt to Amendment SA 2. (consideration: CR S338; text: CR S338) To express the sense of the Senate regarding the conditions for the President entering into bilateral or other international agreements regarding greenhouse gas emissions without proper study of any adverse economic effects, including job losses and harm to the industrial sector, and without the approval of the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-21"/>
    <action datetime="2015-01-21">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 78 proposed by Senator Murkowski for Senator Blunt to Amendment SA 2.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S338" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S338" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-22">
      <text>Senate amendment not agreed to: Amendment SA 78, under the order of 1/22/15, not having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, was not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 51 - 46. Record Vote Number: 20.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-22">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 78, under the order of 1/22/15, not having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, was not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 51 - 46. Record Vote Number: 20.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-21">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
