<bill session="114" type="s" number="1642" updated="2018-06-02T06:56:38Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Savings Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Water Supply Cost Savings Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reduce Federal, State, and local costs of providing high-quality drinking water to millions of people in the United States residing in rural communities by facilitating greater use of cost-effective alternative systems, including well water systems, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Savings Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001236"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2015-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2016-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2015-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1160"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3533"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2848"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hydrology and hydrography"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Water Supply Cost Savings Act or the Savings Act 

This bill requires the Environmental Protection Agency and the Department of Agriculture to: (1) update their programs that provide drinking water technical assistance by including information on cost-effective, innovative, and alternative drinking water delivery systems; and (2) disseminate information on the cost effectiveness of alternative drinking water delivery systems, including wells and well systems, to communities and nonprofit organizations seeking federal funding for drinking water systems serving 500 or fewer persons.

In applications for a grant or loan from the federal government or a state that is using federal assistance for drinking water systems serving 500 or fewer persons, applicants must self-certify that they have considered as an alternative drinking water supply, drinking water delivery systems sourced by publicly-owned individual, shared, and community wells.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
