<bill session="115" type="hr" number="1020" updated="2019-04-18T15:55:47Z">
  <state datetime="2018-07-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Waiving a requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII with respect to consideration of certain resolutions reported from the Committee on Rules, and providing for consideration of motions to suspend the rules.</title>
    <title type="display">Waiving a requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII with respect to consideration of certain resolutions reported from the Committee on Rules, and providing for consideration of motions to suspend the rules.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000250"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-07-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-24">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 115-873, by Mr. Sessions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-24T21:35:12-04:00">
      <text>The resolution waives a requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII with respect to consideration of certain resolutions reported from the Committee on Rules, and provides for consideration of motions to suspend the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-07-24" state="REPORTED" calendar="House" number="175">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 175.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-07-26T10:27:41-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1027, H. Res. 1020 is laid on the table.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-07-24T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Waives a specified requirement of Rule XIII (Calendar and Committee Reports) to allow consideration of any resolution reported from the Committee on Rules through the legislative day of July 27, 2018 (relating to a measure authorizing appropriations for the Department of Defense), on the same day it is presented to the House.

Makes it in order at any time on the legislative day of July 26, 2018, or July 27, 2018, for the Speaker of the House to suspend the rules as though under Rule XV (Business in Order on Special Days), relating to such a measure.

Authorizes the Committee on Appropriations at any time before 3 p.m. on Thursday, August 2, 2018, to file privileged reports to accompany measures making appropriations for FY2019.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-873</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
