<bill session="114" type="h" number="3936" updated="2018-06-02T04:48:06Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-21T17:35:08-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-06-21T17:35:08-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VET Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veteran Engagement Teams Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">VET Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Veteran Engagement Teams Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program under which the Secretary carries out Veteran Engagement Team events where veterans can complete claims for disability compensation and pension under the laws administered by the Secretary, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Veteran Engagement Teams Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001106"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2016-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001107" joined="2016-01-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000451" joined="2015-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2016-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000600" joined="2016-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000813" joined="2016-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-13">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-21T17:26:17-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Roe (TN) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-21T17:26:42-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4010-4012" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-21T17:26:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3936.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2016-06-21T17:35:08-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4010" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-06-21T17:35:10-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4782"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-21T14:15:50Z" status="Passed House amended">Veteran Engagement Teams Act or the VET Act

(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), beginning not later than October 1, 2016, to carry out a three-year pilot program under which the VA shall carry out Veteran Engagement Team events to assist veterans in completing VA disability and pension claims.

Such events shall be carried out:

 during the first year, at least once a month within the jurisdiction of each of 10 VA regional offices, including at least 2 regional offices in each of the 5 districts of the Veterans Benefits Administration; during each of the second and third years, at least once a month within the jurisdiction of each of 15 VA regional offices, including at least 3 regional offices in each district; at different locations within each regional office's jurisdiction and at least 50 miles from any regional office; during the sponsoring regional office's normal business hours; and with a sufficient number of physicians (to be available for opinions only), veteran service and rating representatives, and other appropriate claims personnel to initiate, update, and finalize the completion and adjudication of claims. Amounts shall be paid to a VA employee for event work only from amounts otherwise available for the employee's salary. No additional appropriations are authorized for such payments.

The VA shall: (1) collect and analyze event-satisfaction information from attending veterans, and (2) report annually to Congress on event implementation.

The VA may not permanently transfer any Veterans Health Administration physician to staff an event.

(Sec. 3) The Veterans Access, Choice, and Accountability Act of 2014 is amended to reduce the aggregate amount of awards and bonuses that may be paid by the VA in FY2017.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
