<bill session="115" type="s" number="1815" updated="2019-04-18T16:39:01Z">
  <state datetime="2017-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require data brokers to establish procedures to ensure the accuracy of collected personal information, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Data Broker Accountability and Transparency Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Data Broker Accountability and Transparency Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Data Broker Accountability and Transparency Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2017-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2017-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2017-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2017-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-09-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="6548"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-09-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Data Broker Accountability and Transparency Act of 2017

This bill prohibits data brokers from obtaining or causing to be disclosed personal information relating to any person by making a false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or representation, including by providing any document that the broker knows or should know to: (1) be forged, counterfeit, lost, stolen, or fraudulently obtained; or (2) contain a false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or representation.

The bill defines "data broker" as a commercial entity that collects, assembles, or maintains personal information concerning an individual who is not a customer or an employee of that entity in order to sell or provide third-party access to the information. 

Data brokers must establish procedures to ensure the accuracy of the personal information they collect, assemble, or maintain, and provide individuals a cost-free means to review their personal or identifying information.

 Individuals may dispute the accuracy of their personal information with a written request that the data broker make a correction.





 Data brokers must provide individuals with a reasonable means of expressing a preference to exclude their information from being used, shared, or sold for marketing purposes.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
