<bill session="114" type="s" number="3013" updated="2019-06-21T11:07:13Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize and implement the water rights compact among the Confederated Salish and Kootenai Tribes of the Flathead Indian Reservation, the State of Montana, and the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Salish and Kootenai Water Rights Settlement Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="display">Salish and Kootenai Water Rights Settlement Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-29">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 114-401.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Salish and Kootenai Water Rights Settlement Act of 2016

This bill authorizes, ratifies, and confirms&#160;a specified water rights settlement entered into by the United States, Montana, and the Confederated Salish and Kootenai Tribes of the Flathead Reservation of Montana. Specified claims of the tribes against the United States are waived and released.

The Department of the Interior shall allocate specified amounts of storage water in Hungry Horse Reservoir for use by the tribes.

In addition, the bill: (1) establishes provisions related to the development of hydroelectric power within the reservation; (2) requires the Bureau of Reclamation to carry out specified activities related to the Flathead Indian Irrigation Project; (3) establishes, for purposes of carrying out the bill,&#160;the Selis-Qlispe Ksanka Settlement Trust Fund and the Salish and Kootenai Compact Fund; and (4) confirms certain instream flow water rights of the tribes.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
