<bill session="114" type="h" number="3089" updated="2019-01-09T21:26:12Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-28T15:49:52-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-09-28T15:49:52-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GONE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Grants Oversight and New Efficiency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">GONE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Grants Oversight and New Efficiency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">GONE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Grants Oversight and New Efficiency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To close out expired grants, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">GONE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000798"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001103" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000581" joined="2015-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-07-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-09-18">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 114-264.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-09-18" calendar="Union" number="200">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 200.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-09-28T15:43:04-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Walberg moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-28T15:43:22-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6271-6272" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-28T15:43:26-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3089.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2015-09-28T15:49:52-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6271" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-09-28T15:49:54-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-29">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1115"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-28T15:05:53Z" status="Passed House amended">Grants Oversight and New Efficiency Act or the GONE Act

(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to instruct the head of each federal agency (excluding Congress, U.S. courts, and the governments of U.S. territories or possessions and the District of Columbia), in coordination with the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), to submit to Congress and HHS, not later than December 31 of the first calendar year beginning after enactment of this Act, a report that: (1) lists each covered grant held by such agency; (2) provides the total number of covered grants, including the number of grants by time period of expiration, with zero dollar balances, and with undisbursed balances; (3) describes the challenges leading to delays in grant closeout; and (4) for the 30 oldest covered grants, explains why each covered grant has not been closed out. Agencies may use existing multiagency data systems to prepare their reports. Agency heads who are unable to submit all required information must include an explanation in their reports of why the information was not available, including any shortcomings with and plans to improve existing grant systems, including data systems.

Agencies must provide notice to HHS within one year after the agency head submits the report required by this Act, specifying whether grant awards associated with all of the covered grants have been closed out.&#160;HHS must compile and report to Congress on such notices not later than 90 days after all of the required notices have been provided, or by March 31 of the calendar year following the first calendar year beginning after enactment of this Act, whichever is sooner. The Inspector General of each agency with more than $500 million in grant funding must conduct a risk assessment to determine if an audit or review of the agency's grant closeout process is warranted. The OMB must submit to Congress a report on recommendations for legislation to improve accountability and oversight in grants management, including the timely closeout of a covered grant.

The bill defines "covered grant" to mean a grant in a federal agency cash payment management system held by the U.S. government for which: (1) the grant award period of performance, including any extensions, has been expired for at least two years; and (2) the grant has not been closed out.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-264</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
