<bill session="114" type="s" number="669" updated="2018-06-02T06:40:40Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Iran Congressional Oversight Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for consideration of legislation to respond to a violation by Iran of an arrangement relating to its nuclear program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Iran Congressional Oversight Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000711"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2015-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000174" joined="2015-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2015-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2015-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2015-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2015-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-04T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Iran Congressional Oversight Act of 2015

This bill directs the President, during the period which the Joint Plan of Action or a successor arrangement with Iran is in effect, to report Congress at least once every 90 days regarding Iran's compliance with the Joint Plan of Action or a successor arrangement. (The Joint Plan of Action: (1) means the November 2013 Joint Plan of Action signed by Iran and the P5-plus-1 countries, and (2) includes all implementing materials and agreements related to it.)

Each report shall include a presidential determination and certification, made in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence, on whether Iran has complied with or violated the terms of the Joint Plan of Action or a successor arrangement.

Congress may initiate expedited consideration of legislation to reinstate waived or suspended sanctions if a report is accompanied by a presidential certification that Iran has violated the Joint Plan of Action or any successor arrangement.

It is in order during the 30-day period beginning on the date on which a report is received by Congress for the Senate to move to proceed to the consideration of legislation to further respond to an Iranian violation of the Joint Plan of Action or any successor arrangement. The following shall apply:

 all points of order against the legislation are waived; the motion to proceed is not debatable; the motion is not subject to a motion to postpone; a motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to shall not be in order; and if a motion to proceed to the consideration of the legislation is agreed to, the legislation shall remain the unfinished business until disposed of. If the United States is a party to a comprehensive long-term arrangement with Iran relating to its nuclear program under which the United States commits to lifting sanctions imposed pursuant to a provision of law included in a duly enacted Act of Congress, that provision shall remain in effect until repealed by an Act of Congress or terminated pursuant to another provision of law.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
