<bill session="115" type="s" number="3791" updated="2019-04-18T16:46:59Z">
  <state datetime="2018-12-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to create a Carbon Dividend Trust Fund for the American people in order to encourage market-driven innovation of clean energy technologies and market efficiencies which will reduce harmful pollution and leave a healthier, more stable, and more prosperous nation for future generations.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Innovation and Carbon Dividend Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Energy Innovation and Carbon Dividend Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000444" joined="2018-12-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-12-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="7173"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-12-19T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Energy Innovation and Carbon Dividend Act of 2018 

This bill imposes a fee on the carbon content of fuels, including crude oil, natural gas, coal, or any other product derived from those fuels that will be used so as to emit greenhouse gases into the atmosphere.

The fee is imposed on the producers or importers of the fuels and is equal to the greenhouse gas content of the fuel multiplied by the carbon fee rate. The rate begins at $15 in 2019, increases by $10 each year, and is subject to further adjustments based on the progress in meeting specified emissions reduction targets. The bill also imposes a specified fee on fluorinated greenhouse gases.

The bill includes:

 exemptions for fuels used for agricultural or nonemitting purposes, rebates for facilities that capture and sequester carbon dioxide, and border adjustment provisions that require certain fees or refunds for carbon-intensive products that are exported or imported. The fees must be deposited into a Carbon Dividend Trust Fund and used for administrative expenses and dividend payments to U.S. citizens or lawful residents. The fees must be decommissioned when emissions levels and monthly dividend payments fall below specified levels.

The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) must evaluate the effectiveness of the fees at reducing emissions. If the targets specified in this bill have been met or exceeded, the EPA may review certain regulations related to the fuels and fluorinated greenhouse gases on which the fees have been imposed.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
