<bill session="114" type="h" number="1826" updated="2019-02-08T20:13:08Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fishing Economy Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Fishing Economy Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001177"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2015-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E496"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water, Oceans, and Wildlife" code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2012"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Fishing Economy Improvement Act

This bill revises and reauthorizes through FY2021 the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (MSA).

In managing highly migratory species that frequent the exclusive economic zone adjoining U.S. territories, the Department of Commerce must ensure participation of the territories.

If funds in the Western Pacific Sustainable Fisheries Fund are attributable to a particular U.S. territory, they must be sent to the territory instead of the Western Pacific Council.

Fishery management plans must include descriptions of subsistence or small scale traditional fishing.

The bill makes permanent the authority of Washington, Oregon, and California to adopt and enforce state laws governing fishing and processing in the exclusive economic zone adjacent to their state in any Dungeness crab (Cancer magister) fishery for which there is no fishery management plan in effect under the MSA.

The bill provides for the use of electronic monitoring of fisheries and public participation in the fishery management process by requiring certain meetings be broadcasted online.

Commerce must publish a plan within a year for implementing and conducting the cooperative research and management program.

The Fisheries Conservation and Management Fund is renamed the Zeke Grader Fisheries Conservation and Management Fund.

Commerce must: (1) implement a real-time reporting and data collection program for the Gulf of Mexico red snapper fishery using available technology, and (2) develop a schedule of stock surveys and stock assessments for the Gulf of Mexico Region and the South Atlantic Region for the next five years and every 5-year period thereafter.

Commerce must: (1) establish partnerships with states to develop best practices for implementing state programs that collect data on recreational fisheries, and (2) provide grants to states to improve implementation of those programs.

Commerce may make grants to support programs that address certain needs of fishing communities.

Commerce is given 90 days to determine if a fishery resource disaster exists for fisheries that originate within the Central Valley Project service area.

Commerce must enter into an agreement with the United States Digital Service for the Service to make recommendations to modernize and streamline the fishery data collection, processing, analysis, and storage systems of the National Marine Fisheries Service.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
