<bill session="115" type="s" number="3215" updated="2019-04-18T16:44:39Z">
  <state datetime="2018-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, to require the development of a bus operations safety risk reduction program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bus Operator and Pedestrian Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bus Operator and Pedestrian Protection Act</title>
    <title type="display">Bus Operator and Pedestrian Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000128"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2018-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2018-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2018-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="6016"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-07-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Bus Operator and Pedestrian Protection Act

This bill requires the Department of Transportation (DOT) to require public transportation safety grant recipients who operate fixed route bus service to: (1) develop a risk reduction program for bus operations to improve safety by reducing the number and rates of accidents, injuries, assaults on bus operators, and fatalities; (2) submit the program, including the implementation plan required by this bill, to DOT for review and approval; and (3) implement the program and implementing plan approved by DOT.

The bill amends the Fixing America's Surface Transportation Act (FAST Act) to direct DOT to issue a final rule regarding the protection of public transportation operators from the risk of assault.

The recipient of a public transportation grant shall report to DOT, for inclusion in the National Transit Database, any information on each assault on an operator.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
