<bill session="114" type="s" number="2182" updated="2018-06-02T07:11:07Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-10-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cut, Cap, and Balance Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to cut, cap, and balance the Federal budget.</title>
    <title type="display">Cut, Cap, and Balance Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000603"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-19">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-10-20" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="274">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 274.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-19T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Cut, Cap, and Balance Act of 2015 

This bill amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to establish FY2016 spending limits of $2.832 trillion for new budget authority and $2.884 trillion for outlays. Spending for Social Security, Medicare, Veterans Benefits and Services, Net Interest, and Military Personnel is exempt from the limits.

The chairs of the congressional budget committees may make specified adjustments to the limits for legislation that designates amounts for Overseas Contingency Operations/ Global War on Terrorism.

The bill amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to limit total annual spending for FY2016-FY2025 to a specified percentage of projected annual gross domestic product (GDP), which begins at 19.9% for FY2016 and decreases each year until it reaches 18% for FY2021-FY2025.

The bill enforces the spending limits using automatic spending cuts known as sequestration and specifies exemptions.

The Department of the Treasury may not exercise additional borrowing authority in subsequent legislation until a balanced budget amendment to the Constitution is submitted to the states that: (1) requires that total outlays not exceed total receipts, (2) contains a spending limitation as a percentage of GDP, and (3) requires tax increases be approved by a two-thirds vote in both houses of Congress.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
