<bill session="114" type="h" number="1754" updated="2019-02-20T18:31:55Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TSA Loose Change Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to direct the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security (Transportation Security Administration) to transfer unclaimed money recovered at airport security checkpoints to nonprofit organizations that provide places of rest and recuperation at airports for members of the Armed Forces and their families, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">TSA Loose Change Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001144"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Transportation and Maritime Security" code="HSHM07" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">TSA Loose Change Act

 Directs the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security (Transportation Security Administration [TSA]) to transfer annually, based on requests for proposals, unclaimed money recovered at airport security checkpoints to nonprofit organizations that operate multiple airport centers throughout the United States to provide places of rest and recuperation for Armed Forces members and their families. (Currently, such moneys are retained by the TSA for civil aviation security.)

Amends the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2005 to repeal the requirement that the TSA Administrator report annually to Congress on how unclaimed money is being used to provide civil aviation security. Requires the Administrator, instead, to report on the amount of money transferred to nonprofit organizations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
