<bill session="113" type="h" number="2702" updated="2016-10-25T16:05:52Z">
  <state datetime="2013-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Child Left Inside Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 regarding improving environmental literacy to better prepare students for postsecondary education and careers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">No Child Left Inside Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001168"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000210" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001036" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000380" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2013-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000984" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000598" joined="2013-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000482" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000030" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000451" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000556" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001032" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000057" joined="2014-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000379" joined="2013-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000382" joined="2013-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000559" joined="2014-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000565" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001166" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001149" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000933" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000187" joined="2013-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000593" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000523" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001170" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001175" joined="2014-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000266" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000465" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000062" joined="2013-10-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="identical" number="1306"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-07-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">No Child Left Inside Act of 2013 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to direct the Secretary of Education to award grants to states and, through them, competitive subgrants to eligible partnerships to support the implementation of state environmental literacy plans that include environmental education standards and teacher training.

Includes in the eligible partnerships a local educational agency (LEA) and at least one institution of higher education, another LEA, an elementary or secondary school, or a government or nonprofit entity experienced in environmental literacy.

Requires use of the subgrants for one or more of the following activities:

 providing targeted, job-embedded professional development that improves teachers' environmental content knowledge and pedagogical skills; establishing and operating environmental education summer workshops or institutes for teachers; developing or redesigning more rigorous environmental education curricula; designing programs that prepare teachers to provide environmental education mentoring and training to other teachers in their school; establishing and operating programs to bring teachers and students into contact with working professionals in environmental fields; creating initiatives that incorporate environmental education within teacher training programs or accreditation standards; and promoting the integration of outdoor environmental education lessons into the regular school curriculum and schedule. Authorizes the Secretary to award competitive matching grants to eligible partnerships for one or more of the following activities:

 developing and implementing state curriculum frameworks for environmental education that meet challenging state academic content and achievement standards for environmental education, replicating or disseminating information about proven and tested model environmental education programs, and developing and implementing new approaches to advancing environmental education and the adoption and use of environmental education content standards. Amends part B (Mathematics and Science Partnerships) of title II of the ESEA to: (1) include nonprofit environmental education organizations and government science, environmental, or natural resource management agencies among the entities eligible to participate in part B partnerships; and (2) allow the use of part B funds to train teachers to use environmental education to enhance student understanding of science and mathematics.

Amends part B (21st Century Community Learning Centers) of title IV of the ESEA to include environmental literacy activities among the before and after school activities that such program funds at community learning centers.

Directs the Secretary to:

 request all federal departments and agencies to provide information on any environmental literacy assistance program that they operate, sponsor, or support; make that information searchable and accessible through the Department of Education's website and cross-referenced with the United States Green Ribbon School application information; coordinate environmental literacy activities between the Department of Education, the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), the Department of the Interior, and the Department of Commerce; and appoint an advisory panel of stakeholders to advise and support interagency environmental literacy planning and assessment activities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
