<bill session="115" type="s" number="1983" updated="2019-06-17T18:49:09Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-10-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a process to review foreign investment to determine the economic effect of the investment on the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Foreign Investment Review Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Foreign Investment Review Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">United States Foreign Investment Review Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2017-10-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-10-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2998-2999" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-18">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-25">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 115-160.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Hearings"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-10-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">United States Foreign Investment Review Act of 2017

This bill amends the Trade Act of 1974 to require each party to a covered transaction to submit a written notification to the Department of Commerce of such transaction. "Covered transaction" is defined as any merger, acquisition, takeover, or investment, or the establishment of a new entity, by or with any person, that is proposed or pending after this bill's enactment that could result in foreign control of any individual or entity engaged in interstate commerce in the United States valued at: (1) $50 million or more, in the case of a transaction involving a state-owned enterprise; and (2) $1 billion or more, in the case of any other transaction.

Upon receiving such notification, Commerce must: (1) review the transaction to determine its economic effect on the United States, considering specified economic factors; and (2) based on the results of the review, take appropriate action.

The bill prohibits the expenditure of funds to encourage investment in the United States by any foreign state-owned enterprise that does not operate according to market considerations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
