<bill session="114" type="s" number="1241" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:55Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhanced Grid Security Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the modernization, security, and resiliency of the electric grid, to require the Secretary of Energy to carry out programs for research, development, demonstration, and information-sharing for cybersecurity for the energy sector, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Enhanced Grid Security Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000127"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-09">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2012"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2089"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Enhanced Grid Security Act of 2015

This bill designates the Department of Energy (DOE) as the lead Sector-Specific Agency for cybersecurity for the energy sector (this action comports with the presidential policy directive entitled "Critical Infrastructure Security and Resilience" dated February 12, 2013).

 DOE shall:

 develop advanced cybersecurity applications and technologies for the energy sector; advance the security of field devices and third-party control systems; leverage electric grid architecture as a means to assess risks to the energy sector, including by implementing an all-hazards approach to communications infrastructure, control systems architecture, and power systems architecture; perform pilot demonstration projects with the energy sector to gain experience with new technologies; and develop workforce development curricula for energy sector-related cybersecurity. DOE shall also implement within the energy sector cybertesting and cyberresilience programs that target:

 DOE emergency response capabilities, cooperation with the intelligence communities for energy sector-related threat collection and analysis, enhancing the tools of DOE and the Electricity Sector Information Sharing and Analysis Center (ES-ISAC) for monitoring the status of the energy sector, expanding industry participation in ES-ISAC, and technical assistance to small electric utilities to assess cybermaturity posture. DOE must develop an advanced energy security program that secures diverse energy networks in order to increase the functional preservation of the electric grid operations or natural gas and oil operations in the face of natural and human-made threats and hazards, including electric magnetic pulse and geomagnetic disturbances.

DOE shall study alternative management structures and funding mechanisms to expand industry membership and participation in ES-ISAC.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
