<bill session="114" type="h" number="286" updated="2019-05-09T23:32:58Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To extend the Federal recognition to the Little Shell Tribe of Chippewa Indians of Montana, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Little Shell Tribe of Chippewa Indians Restoration Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Little Shell Tribe of Chippewa Indians Restoration Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Z000018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2016-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indigenous Peoples of the United States" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="35"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3764"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-12T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Little Shell Tribe of Chippewa Indians Restoration Act of 2015

 Extends federal recognition to the Little Shell Tribe of Chippewa Indians of Montana. Makes the Tribe and each member eligible for all services and benefits provided by the United States to Indians and federally recognized Indian tribes, without regard to the existence of a reservation for the Tribe or the location of the residence of any member on or near an Indian reservation.

Considers the federal service area of the Tribe to be the area comprised of Blaine, Cascade, Glacier, and Hill Counties, Montana.

 Directs the Tribe, as a condition of receiving recognition, services, and benefits pursuant to this Act, to submit to the Secretary of the Interior a membership roll consisting of the name of each individual enrolled as a member of the Tribe. Requires the Tribe to maintain such membership roll.

Directs the Secretary to acquire, for the benefit of the Tribe, trust title to 200 acres of land within the Tribe's service area to be used for a tribal land base.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
