<bill session="115" type="hr" number="642" updated="2019-04-18T15:54:44Z">
  <state datetime="2017-12-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-12-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-12-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Prohibiting the use of the Members' Representational Allowance of a Member of the House of Representatives to pay awards, settlements, or other compensation in connection with allegations of sexual harassment or sexual misconduct by the Member or the employees of the Member's office, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Prohibiting the use of the Members' Representational Allowance of a Member of the House of Representatives to pay awards, settlements, or other compensation in connection with allegations of sexual harassment or sexual misconduct by the Member or the employees of the Member's office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000813"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-12-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="House Committee on House Administration"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-12-01T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Prohibits the Members' Representational Allowance of a Member of the House of Representatives from being used to pay awards, settlements, or other compensation in connection with allegations of sexual harassment or sexual misconduct by the Member or any individual whose compensation is paid from the allowance.

Requires an individual for whom such allowance was used to pay such compensation before the adoption of this resolution to repay the Treasury the amount of such compensation using personal funds.

Requires the Committee on House Administration, within 30 days after it approves a settlement entered into under the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 by the office of a Member of the House in connection with a violation involving sexual harassment or sexual misconduct, to publish and post on its public website:

 a description of the violation involved, the office and the individual committing the violation, and the amount of the settlement. Directs the committee to ensure that the identity of any individual who received a settlement, or who made an allegation of a violation, is not disclosed.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
