<bill session="114" type="s" number="2287" updated="2018-08-16T22:54:00Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accelerating Technology Transfer to Advance Innovation for the Nation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ATTAIN Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Department of Energy Organization Act to improve technology transfer at the Department of Energy by reducing bureaucratic barriers to industry, entrepreneurs, and small businesses, as well as ensure that public investments in research and development generate the greatest return on investment for taxpayers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">ATTAIN Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000039"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-17T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Accelerating Technology Transfer to Advance Innovation for the Nation Act of 2015 or the ATTAIN Act of 2015 

 This bill amends the Department of Energy Organization Act to establish the Office of Technology Transitions, directed by a Technology Transfer Coordinator, to improve Department of Energy (DOE) coordination and use of technology transfer resources, including increased coordination and use of small business innovation research.

DOE shall establish a Lab-Corps, modeled after the I-Corps of the National Science Foundation, to support investments in entrepreneurs, mentors, and principal investigators.

DOE may also establish and participate in technology commercialization challenges.

The Office shall: (1) work with each Office of Research and Technology Application at the National Laboratories, and (2) partner with foundations and nonprofit entities with similar technology transfer and entrepreneurship priorities and goals.

DOE and the Small Business Administration shall jointly establish a Technology Transfer Investment Initiative following prescribed guidelines.

The Office, in coordination with Lab-Corps, shall also establish and coordinate regional geographic areas to implement the Initiative.

DOE shall establish a pilot program, administered through the Office, to award grants to post-graduate researchers for the purpose of spinning off and licensing technology.

DOE may include, in a management and operating contract for a National Laboratory, partnership agreements with institutions of higher education.

The Government Accountability Office shall report to Congress on the results of the projects developed under this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
