<bill session="114" type="h" number="3934" updated="2018-11-09T00:09:05Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Corporate Fair Share Tax Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to limit the interest deduction for excessive interest of members of financial reporting groups.</title>
    <title type="display">Corporate Fair Share Tax Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000607"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2015-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2015-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2015-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2015-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2015-11-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Corporate Fair Share Tax Act

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to limit the tax deduction of the interest expense of a U.S. corporation that is a member of a financial reporting group (a group that prepares consolidated financial statements according to accepted accounting principles or international financial reporting standards) to: (1) the amount of interest on indebtedness of the corporation includible in the corporation's gross income for the taxable year plus its proportionate share of the group's net interest expense in the taxable year computed under U.S. income tax principles; or (2) not more than 10% of the corporation's adjusted taxable income, if the corporation fails to substantiate its proportionate share of interest expense.

The bill exempts from the limitation a corporation that is predominantly engaged in the active conduct of a banking, financing, or similar business or that has less than $5 million of net interest expense for the taxable year.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
