<bill session="115" type="s" number="1345" updated="2019-04-18T16:37:04Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance interstate commerce by creating a national hiring standard for motor carriers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transportation and Logistics Hiring Reform Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transportation and Logistics Hiring Reform Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Transportation and Logistics Hiring Reform Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000463"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2017-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2017-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1568"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Transportation and Logistics Hiring Reform Act of 2017

This bill establishes a national hiring standard for motor carriers.

The bill defines an"entity" as a person acting as:

 a shipper or a consignee; a broker, a freight forwarder, or a household goods freight forwarder; a non-vessel-operating common carrier, an ocean freight forwarder, or an ocean transportation intermediary; an indirect air carrier authorized to operate under a Standard Security Program approved by the Transportation Security Administration; a federally licensed customs broker; an interchange motor carrier; or a warehouse. Before tendering a shipment, but not more than 35 days before the pickup of a shipment by the hired motor carrier, an entity shall verify that the carrier:

 is registered with and authorized by the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA) to operate as a motor carrier or household goods motor carrier; has the minimum insurance coverage required by federal law; does not have an unsatisfactory safety rating issued by the FMCSA; and has not otherwise been ordered by FMCSA to discontinue operations. Only evidence of an entity's compliance with this bill may be admitted as evidence in a civil action for damages resulting from a case or legal proceeding alleging an entity's selection or retention of a motor carrier was negligent. No other motor carrier data created or maintained by the FMCSA, including safety measurement system data or analysis of such data, may be admitted in such case or proceeding.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
