<amendment session="113" chamber="h" number="569" updated="2016-10-25T12:38:37Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2804" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2014-02-27T14:11:31-05:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000725"/>
  <offered datetime="2014-02-27"/>
  <description>Amendment sought to insert an exception for any regulations, or modifications thereto, which have been recommended in writing by the Inspector General of a federal agency, including but not limited to those which would improve protections for taxpayers, students, public and workplace safety and health, or otherwise increase the effectiveness or efficiency of agency activities.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 11 printed in House Report 113-361 to exempt any regulations, or modifications thereto, which have been recommended in writing by the Inspector General of a federal agency, including but not limited to those which would improve protections for taxpayers, students, public and workplace safety and health, or otherwise increase the effectiveness or efficiency of agency activities.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2014-02-27T14:11:31-05:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="76">
      <text>On agreeing to the Miller, George amendment (A011) Failed by recorded vote: 181 - 232 (Roll no. 76).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27T13:11:12-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A011) offered by Mr. Miller, George.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2020-2021, H2024-2025" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2020" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27"/>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27T13:11:12-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A011) offered by Mr. Miller, George.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2020-2021, H2024-2025" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2020" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27T14:11:31-05:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Miller, George amendment (A011) Failed by recorded vote: 181 - 232 (Roll no. 76).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27T14:11:31-05:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27T14:11:31-05:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
