<bill session="113" type="h" number="2455" updated="2016-10-25T16:04:58Z">
  <state datetime="2014-12-01T16:49:42-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-12-01T16:49:42-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nevada Native Nations Lands Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Nevada Native Nations Lands Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Nevada Native Nations Land Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the sale or transfer of certain Federal lands in Nevada, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Nevada Native Nations Land Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000369"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2014-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2013-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-01">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-632.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-01" calendar="Union" number="472">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 472.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-01T16:44:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Hastings (WA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-01T16:44:11-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8188-8190" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-01T16:44:14-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2455.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2014-12-01T16:49:42-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8188-8189" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-12-01T16:49:44-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-02">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1167"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2480"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation facilities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-12-01T15:48:22Z" status="Passed House amended">Nevada Native Nations Land Act - Title I: Elko Motocross Land Conveyance - (Sec. 102) Directs the Department of the Interior to convey to Elko County, Nevada, without consideration, approximately 275 acres of land managed by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), Elko District, Nevada, for use as a motocross, bicycle, off-highway vehicle, or stock car racing area or for other public purpose consistent with the Recreation and Public Purposes Act.

Reverts the conveyed land to the United States if it ceases being used for a public purpose.

Title II: Conveyance of Land To Indian Tribes - (Sec. 201) Declares that the United States holds approximately 373 acres of BLM administered land in trust for the Te-moak Tribe of Western Shoshone Indians of Nevada. Makes such land part of the Tribe's reservation.

Declares further that the United States holds approximately 19,094 acres of BLM-administered land in trust for the Fort McDermitt Paiute and Shoshone Tribe. Makes such land part of that Tribe's reservation.

Declares that the United States also holds in trust the following lands:

 for the Shoshone Paiute Tribes, approximately 82 acres of land administered by the Forest Service depicted as the "Proposed Acquisition Site" on a Mountain City Administrative Site Proposed Acquisition map; for the Summit Lake Paiute Tribe, approximately 941 acres of BLM-administered land depicted as "Reservation Conveyance Lands" on a Summit Lake Indian Reservation Conveyance map; for the Reno-Sparks Indian Colony, approximately 13,434 acres of BLM-administered land depicted as "RSIC Amended Boundary" on a Reno-Sparks Indian Colony Expansion map; and for the Pyramid Lake Paiute Tribe, approximately 11,719 acres of BLM-administered land depicted as "Reservation Expansion Lands " on a Pyramid Lake Indian Reservation Expansion map. (Sec. 202) Prohibits certain gaming on the lands taken into trust under this Act.

Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to such lands, to carry out any fuel reduction and other landscape restoration activities on the land, including restoration of sage grouse habitat, beneficial to the Indian tribe and the BLM.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 113-632</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
