<bill session="115" type="s" number="1370" updated="2019-04-18T16:37:11Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to revise and extend projects relating to children and violence to provide access to school-based comprehensive mental health programs.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mental Health in Schools Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mental Health in Schools Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Mental Health in Schools Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000457"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2017-10-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="4142"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="2913"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Mental Health in Schools Act of 2017

This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to revise a community children and violence program to assist local communities and schools in applying a public health approach to mental health services, including by: (1) revising eligibility requirements for a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement; and (2) providing for comprehensive school mental health programs that are culturally and linguistically appropriate, trauma-informed, and age appropriate. A comprehensive school mental health program funded under this bill must assist children in dealing with trauma and violence. The bill makes only certain partnerships that include a state educational agency and one or more educational agencies, with a local agency serving as lead partner, eligible for funding. They include public or private entities that use evidence-based intervention.

The Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration shall develop a fiscally appropriate process for evaluating grant program activities, including the development of: (1) guidelines for the submission of program data by recipients; and (2) outcome measures to be applied by recipients in evaluating programs, including student and family measures and local educational measures.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
