<bill session="114" type="s" number="1504" updated="2018-06-02T06:54:57Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mobility and Opportunity for Vulnerable Employees Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MOVE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit employers from requiring low-wage employees to enter into covenants not to compete, to require employers to notify potential employees of any requirement to enter into a covenant not to compete, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">MOVE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001169"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2015-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2015-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2015-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2015-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2873"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4254"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-04T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Mobility and Opportunity for Vulnerable Employees Act or the MOVE Act

 This bill: (1) prohibits employers from entering into not to compete covenants with low-wage employees engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce, and (2) requires an employer of such employees to post notice of such prohibition in a conspicuous place on the employer's premises.

The bill defines "low-wage employee" as an employee who earns less than: (1) $15 per hour or the state or local minimum wage, or (2) $31,200 per year.

In order for an employer to require such an employee who is not a low-wage employee to enter into such a covenant, the employer must have disclosed the requirement for entering into such covenant before hiring such employee.

The Secretary of Labor shall: (1) enforce a complaint of a violation of this Act in the same manner as a complaint of a violation of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, and (2) impose a civil fine on any employer who violates this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
