<bill session="114" type="h" number="3484" updated="2018-06-02T04:41:55Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Los Angeles Homeless Veterans Leasing Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Los Angeles Homeless Veterans Leasing Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to enter into certain leases at the Department of Veterans Affairs West Los Angeles Campus in Los Angeles, California, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Los Angeles Homeless Veterans Leasing Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000582"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000287" joined="2015-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2015-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000623" joined="2016-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001063" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2015-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000387" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2015-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000486" joined="2015-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001156" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2015-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2016-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2016-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000474" joined="2015-10-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-25">
      <text>Subcommittee on Health Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-02-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-05-17">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 114-570.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-05-17" calendar="Union" number="442">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 442.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2013"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2921"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5286"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5936"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6062"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-17T14:08:36Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">Los Angeles Homeless Veterans Leasing Act of 2016

(Sec. 2) This bill authorizes the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to carry out the following leases at the VA's West Los Angeles Campus in Los Angeles, California:

 any enhanced-use lease of real property for supportive housing that principally benefits veterans and their families; any lease of real property for not to exceed 50 years to a third party for services that principally benefit veterans and their families and that are related to health and wellness, education, vocational training and employment, peer activities or recreation, legal and federal benefits assistance, volunteerism, family support services, and transportation; and a lease of real property for not to exceed 10 years to the Regents of the University of California, on behalf of the University of California, Los Angeles, if the lease is consistent with the VA master plan and the provision of veterans services is the predominant focus. The VA shall not enter into any land-sharing agreements unless the agreements provide additional health care resources and benefit veterans and their families in ways other than generating additional revenue.

Any funds received by the VA from a lease shall be credited to the applicable VA medical facilities account and shall be available, without fiscal year limitation and without further appropriation, exclusively for campus renovation and maintenance.

The VA may, notwithstanding any other provision of law other than federal laws relating to environmental and historic preservation, grant easements or rights-of-way on, above, or under campus lands to:

 any local or regional public transportation authority to construct, operate, or maintain public mass transit facilities; and California, the County of Los Angeles, the City of Los Angeles, any agency or political subdivision thereof, or any public utility company for the purpose of providing public utilities. The VA may not sell or convey to a third party fee simple title to any real property or related improvements made at the campus.

The VA shall ensure that each lease is consistent with the draft master plan approved by the VA on January 28, 2016, or successor master plans.

The VA shall establish a Community Veterans Engagement Board to coordinate locally with the VA to: (1) identify community goals; and (2) provide advice to improve services for veterans, members of the Armed Forces, and their families.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-570</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
