<bill session="113" type="h" number="5534" updated="2016-10-25T16:16:40Z">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Assistance, Quality, and Affordability Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to increase assistance for States, water systems, and disadvantaged communities; to encourage good financial and environmental management of water systems; to strengthen the Environmental Protection Agency's ability to enforce the requirements of the Act; and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Assistance, Quality, and Affordability Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000469"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000215" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Environment and the Economy" code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-09-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Assistance, Quality, and Affordability Act of 2014 - Amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to reauthorize, revise, and increase funding for the drinking water state revolving fund (SRF) for FY2015-FY2017. (The Drinking Water SRF program awards capitalization grants to states, which in turn provide financial assistance to public water systems for infrastructure improvements.) Expands the list of activities for which the SRF may be used and revises the process for prioritizing applications for SRF funds.

 Sets forth requirements concerning SRF funded projects using goods produced in the United States and giving prevailing wages to laborers and mechanics.

 Revises requirements for state Intended Use Plans for SRF funds, in part by requiring the plans to list systems that are not in compliance with national primary drinking water regulation and reserve a specified amount of funding for assistance for disadvantaged communities.

 Raises the cap on SRF funding that may be used for projects in American Samoa, Northern Mariana Islands, Guam, and the Virgin Islands.

 Repeals requirements for regulations on variance technologies. Repeals state authority to grant variances for compliance with a drinking water regulation requirement specifying a maximum contaminant level or treatment technique.

 Directs the EPA to:

 study the presence of pharmaceuticals and personal care products in drinking water sources, establish requirements for electronic submission of compliance monitoring data by public water systems, collect data on best practices for administration of SRF programs, and implement a voluntary certification program for effective water loss and leak control technology. Reauthorizes a program to provide technical assistance to enable small public water systems to achieve and maintain compliance with applicable national primary drinking water regulations for FY2015-FY2019.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
