<bill session="113" type="s" number="2607" updated="2016-10-25T16:31:29Z">
  <state datetime="2014-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Assisted Living Pilot Program for Veterans with Traumatic Brain Injury Extension Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend and modify the pilot program of the Department of Veterans Affairs on assisted living services for veterans with traumatic brain injury, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Assisted Living Pilot Program for Veterans with Traumatic Brain Injury Extension Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2014-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000291" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000550" joined="2014-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2014-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2014-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000590" joined="2014-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4504"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-07-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Assisted Living Pilot Program for Veterans with Traumatic Brain Injury Extension Act - Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008 to extend the pilot program to assess the effectiveness of providing assistance to eligible veterans with traumatic brain injury to enhance their rehabilitation, quality of life, and community integration.

Requires that at least one location of the program be in each health care region of the Veterans Health Administration that contains a polytrauma center of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA). (Under current law, selected locations also must include any location other than one described above in an area that contains a high concentration of veterans with traumatic brain injuries.)

Expands requirements for reports on the pilot program.

Replaces references to "assisted living" with the term "community-based brain injury residential rehabilitative care," including rehabilitation services within the meaning of such care.

Requires a veteran, in order to be eligible for such services, to have a traumatic brain injury that is classified as complex-mild to severe.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
