<bill session="115" type="s" number="3611" updated="2019-04-18T16:46:18Z">
  <state datetime="2018-12-20">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-12-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-11-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and the Higher Education Act of 1965 to facilitate the disclosure of tax return information to carry out the Higher Education Act of 1965, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Faster Access to Federal Student Aid Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Faster Access to Federal Student Aid Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Faster Access to Federal Student Aid Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Faster Access to Federal Student Aid Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Faster Access to Federal Student Aid Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000360"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2018-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2018-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2018-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2018-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2018-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2018-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2018-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2018-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2018-11-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-11-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-11-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-20">
      <text>Senate Committee on Finance discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2018-12-20" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-12-20T12:42:52-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-20">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-20T20:30:20-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="7386"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-11-13T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Faster Access to Federal Student Aid Act of 2018

This bill requires the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) to disclose certain tax return information to the Department of Education (ED) for the purpose of administering financial aid and loan programs under the Higher Education Act of 1965. (Under current law, students must obtain their own tax return information from the IRS and submit it to ED.)

Upon receiving a request from ED, the IRS must disclose specified tax return information to ED for the purposes of

 establishing, renewing, administering, and conducting analyses and forecasts for estimating costs related to income-contingent or income-based repayment programs; the discharge of loans based on a total and permanent disability; determining the eligibility for, and the amount of, federal student financial aid; and conducting analyses and forecasts for estimating costs related to federal student financial aid programs. ED may only use the disclosed information for the purposes above and for mitigating risks related to the programs. Mitigating risks includes activities related to analyzing or estimating costs, conducting oversight, developing statistics, and reducing improper payments. It does not include conducting criminal investigations or prosecutions.

With the consent of the taxpayer, ED may disclose the return information to certain institutions of higher education, state higher education agencies, and scholarship organizations solely for the use in financial aid programs.

The bill also specifies notification and reporting requirements related to the disclosures and the implementation of this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
