<bill session="115" type="hr" number="449" updated="2019-04-18T15:54:12Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-27">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Urging the Government of Kenya and Kenya's political parties to respect democratic principles and hold credible, peaceful, and transparent elections in August 2017.</title>
    <title type="display">Urging the Government of Kenya and Kenya's political parties to respect democratic principles and hold credible, peaceful, and transparent elections in August 2017.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000179"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001270" joined="2017-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001037" joined="2017-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000462" joined="2017-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2017-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2017-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2017-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000604" joined="2017-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000583" joined="2017-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000522" joined="2017-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000131" joined="2017-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-07-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="sr" session="115" relation="unknown" number="228"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Hate crimes"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Kenya"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Calls upon: (1) Kenya to hold free and fair presidential elections in August 2017 and to condemn the use of hate speech and the incitement of violence by political candidates, the media, or any Kenyan citizens; (2) Kenyan citizens to peacefully participate in the general elections and seek to resolve any disputes over results through the legal system; and (3) Kenyan political candidates to respect the Electoral Code of Conduct and the Political Party Code of Conduct.

Encourages: (1) Kenyan political parties, civil society, and the media to act responsibly with their parallel vote tabulations; (2) Kenyan civil society organizations to continue providing early warning and response measures to mitigate election-related violence and strengthen democratic processes; and (3) the Trump Administration to appoint an Assistant Secretary of State for African Affairs.

Commends the key role the faith-based community has played in ensuring a peaceful pre- and post-election environment through periodically convening the Multi-Sectoral Forum to deliberate on matters of governance, election management, and looming insecurity.

Supports efforts by the Department of State and the U.S. Agency for International Development to assist election-related preparations in Kenya.

Calls upon the United States and Kenya's other international partners to continue to support Kenya's efforts to address the remaining electoral preparation challenges and identify gaps in which additional resources or diplomatic engagement could make important contributions to the conduct of the elections.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
