<bill session="113" type="s" number="802" updated="2016-10-25T16:23:46Z">
  <state datetime="2013-04-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sensible Environmental Protection Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to clarify Congressional intent regarding the regulation of the use of pesticides in or near navigable waters, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Sensible Environmental Protection Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001049"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000174" joined="2013-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000286" joined="2013-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2013-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2013-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000607" joined="2013-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2013-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001069" joined="2013-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2013-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000550" joined="2013-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2013-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000590" joined="2013-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2013-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000127" joined="2013-04-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="935"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-04-24T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Sensible Environmental Protection Act of 2013 - Amends the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (FIFRA) and the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act [CWA]) to prohibit the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) or a state from requiring a permit under CWA for a discharge from a point source into navigable waters of: (1) a pesticide authorized for sale, distribution, or use under FIFRA; or (2) the residue of the pesticide, resulting from the application of the pesticide. Excepts: (1) a discharge resulting from the application of a pesticide in violation of a provision of FIFRA relevant to protecting water quality if the discharge would not have occurred without the violation or if the amount of pesticide or pesticide residue in the discharge is greater than would have occurred without the violation; (2) stormwater discharges regulated under the National Pollutant Discharge Elimination System (NPDES); and (3) discharges of manufacturing or industrial effluent, treatment works effluent, and discharges incidental to the normal operation of a vessel.

Directs the Administrator to report to specified congressional committees on: (1) the status of intra-agency coordination between the Office of Water and the Office of Pesticide Programs of EPA regarding streamlining information collection, standards of review, and data use relating to water quality impacts from the registration and use of pesticides; (2) an analysis of the effectiveness of current regulatory actions relating to pesticide registration and use aimed at protecting water quality; and (3) recommendations on how FIFRA can be modified to better protect water quality and human health.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
