<bill session="114" type="s" number="3006" updated="2018-08-16T22:54:09Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alaska Mental Health Trust Land Exchange Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the exchange of certain National Forest System land and non-Federal land in the State of Alaska, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Alaska Mental Health Trust Land Exchange Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2016-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3203"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Alaska Mental Health Trust Land Exchange Act of 2016

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA), if the Alaska Mental Health Trust Authority offers to convey to it certain nonfederal land, to convey certain federal land to the Trust Authority in exchange.

Before carrying out the land exchange, USDA shall complete any necessary land surveys and required pre-exchange clearances, mitigation activities, and approvals related to:

 threatened and endangered species, cultural and historic resources, wetland and floodplains, and hazardous materials. USDA and the Trust Authority shall select an appraiser to conduct appraisals of the federal and nonfederal lands in accordance with nationally recognized standards.

The Trust Authority shall agree to pay, without compensation, all costs associated with the exchange.

Upon acquisition by USDA, the nonfederal land shall become part of Tongass National Forest, and shall be withdrawn from:

 entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and disposition under the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
