<bill session="115" type="h" number="3017" updated="2019-06-13T17:59:49Z">
  <state datetime="2017-11-30T17:01:03-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-11-30T17:01:03-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Brownfields Enhancement, Economic Redevelopment, and Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Brownfields Enhancement, Economic Redevelopment, and Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Brownfields Enhancement, Economic Redevelopment, and Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Brownfields Enhancement, Economic Redevelopment, and Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Brownfields Enhancement, Economic Redevelopment, and Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Brownfields Enhancement, Economic Redevelopment, and Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 to reauthorize and improve the brownfields program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001180"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000293" joined="2017-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000386" joined="2017-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000034" joined="2017-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000364" joined="2017-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2017-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000791" joined="2017-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-06-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-09-11">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 115-303, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-11">
      <text>House Committee on Transportation Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Oct. 13, 2017.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-12">
      <text>House Committee on Transportation Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Nov. 9, 2017.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-09">
      <text>Committee on Transportation discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-11-09" calendar="Union" number="298">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 298.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-11-28T18:53:38-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 631 Reported to House. The rules provides 1 hour of general debate on both bills. For H.R. 3017, the bill is closed to amendments. For H.R. 3905, the rule provides for a specified amendment. The rule also provides for one motion to recommit with or without instructions on each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-30T14:18:05-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 631.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9538-9547" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-30T14:18:10-05:00">
      <text>The rules provides 1 hour of general debate on both bills. For H.R. 3017, the bill is closed to amendments. For H.R. 3905, the rule provides for a specified amendment. The rule also provides for one motion to recommit with or without instructions on each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-30T14:19:22-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 3017.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-30T14:56:01-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate on H.R. 3017.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-30T15:16:18-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-30T15:16:36-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.R. 3017, the Chair put the question on passage of the bill, and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Shimkus demanded the yeas and nays, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of passage until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-30T16:52:59-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9559" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="649" datetime="2017-11-30T17:01:03-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 409 - 8 (Roll no. 649).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9539-9540" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-11-30T17:01:05-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-01">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Environment and Climate Change" code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="unknown" number="631"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1758"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Small towns"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h488"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2017-11-30T13:40:40Z" status="Passed House amended">Brownfields Enhancement, Economic Redevelopment, and Reauthorization Act of 2017 (Sec. 2) This bill modifies the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (CERCLA) to specify if a state or local government takes title to a brownfield site as a result of law enforcement activity, that government is not an owner or operator for the purposes of CERCLA. (Brownfields are certain commercial properties that are hindered from reuse or redevelopment due to the presence of a hazardous substance, pollutant, or contaminant.) (Sec. 3) The bill modifies brownfield program eligibility with respect to petroleum sites where no viable responsible party exists. Specifically, it eliminates the requirement that sites be of relatively low risk. (Sec. 4) The bill revises leaseholder status regarding bona fide prospective purchasers. (Sec. 5) The bill expands CERCLA eligibility for nonprofit organizations and qualified community development entities. (Sec. 6) The brownfield site characterization and assessment grant program and the brownfield remediation grant and loan program are revised by authorizing eligible governmental entities to receive grants and loans for property that was acquired before January 11, 2002, even if the entities do not qualify as bona fide prospective purchasers. (Sec. 7) The bill increases the cap on the amount that may be given in grants and loans for each site to be remediated. (Sec. 8) The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) must establish a program to provide multipurpose grants to carry out inventory, characterization, assessment, planning, or remediation activities at brownfield sites. (Sec. 9) The bill allows grant recipients to use up to 5% of funds for administrative costs. (Sec. 10) The EPA must consider the production of renewable energy on brownfield sites as part of the grant application ranking process. (Sec. 11) The EPA is allowed to provide grants to assist small communities, Indian tribes, rural areas, or disadvantaged areas for the purpose of establishing a brownfields program. (Sec. 12) The bill reauthorizes brownfields revitalization funding through FY2022. (Sec. 13) The bill reauthorizes state response programs through FY2022.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-303</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
