<bill session="114" type="h" number="2172" updated="2018-06-02T03:38:33Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a pilot toll credit market place program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To establish a pilot toll credit market place program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000533" joined="2015-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000596" joined="2015-10-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Highways and Transit" code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Regional and metropolitan planning"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to establish a pilot toll credit marketplace program for states, metropolitan planning organizations (MPOs), or local governments to buy and sell toll credits and use the proceeds for highway, transit, and other related projects. States, MPOs, or local governments may not use federal funds to purchase toll credits on the marketplace or use them for more than 10% of its annual apportionment of federal-aid highway funds in a fiscal year.

The Federal Highway Administration shall determine how a toll credit marketplace will work.

The Railroad Revitalization and Regulatory Reform Act of 1976 is amended to revise railroad rehabilitation and improvement financing program requirements. Toll credits earned shall be eligible as collateral in determining credit risk premium amounts for direct loans or loan guarantees for railroad improvement projects.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
