<bill session="113" type="s" number="2481" updated="2016-10-25T16:30:56Z">
  <state datetime="2014-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Women's Small Business Procurement Parity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Small Business Act to provide authority for sole source contracts for certain small business concerns owned and controlled by women, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Women's Small Business Procurement Parity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2014-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2014-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001049" joined="2014-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2014-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2014-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2014-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="4435"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2693"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="5584"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-06-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Women's Small Business Procurement Parity Act - Amends the Small Business Act to revise procurement program requirements for women-owned small businesses.

Authorizes a contracting officer to award a sole source contract under this Act to small businesses owned and controlled by women if each of the businesses is at least 51% owned by one or more women who are economically disadvantaged (and such ownership is determined without regard to any community property law), and if:

 the small business is in an industry in which it is underrepresented, as determined by the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA); the contracting officer determines that it is a responsible contractor; the anticipated award price of the contract, including options, is not more than: (1) $6.5 million, in the case of a contract opportunity assigned a North American Industry Classification System code for manufacturing; or (2) $4 million, in the case of any other contract opportunity; and the contract award can be made at a fair and reasonable price. Authorizes a contracting officer to award a sole source contract to a small business owned and controlled by women meeting the same criteria in an industry in which such businesses are substantially underrepresented if the small business also meets specified certification requirements.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
