<bill session="114" type="s" number="1582" updated="2018-06-02T06:55:43Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preserving American Homeownership Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish pilot programs to encourage the use of shared equity mortgage modifications, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Preserving American Homeownership Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2015-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3519"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Preserving American Homeownership Act of 2015

 Requires the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency and the Federal Housing Commissioner each to establish a pilot program to encourage the use of shared equity mortgage modifications designed to return greater net present value to investors than other loss-mitigation activities, including foreclosure.

Requires a shared equity mortgage modification to:

 reduce by specified action the loan-to-value ratio of a covered mortgage to 100% or less within 3 years; reduce the interest rate if such a reduction of principal would not result in an affordable reduced monthly payment; reduce to a specified amount any periodic payment the homeowner is required to make; require the homeowner to pay the investor, upon refinancing or selling the real property securing a covered mortgage, up to 50% of the amount of the equity value of the real property, subject to certain conditions; be designed to deliver maximal net present value to the investor; be based on specified factors; and require disclosure to the homeowner, before entering into the shared equity mortgage modification, of the estimated net present value of the equity sharing interest to be determined under this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
