<bill session="115" type="h" number="5064" updated="2019-04-18T16:20:30Z">
  <state datetime="2018-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize aboriginal subsistence whaling pursuant to the regulations of the International Whaling Commission and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Whaling Convention Amendments Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Whaling Convention Amendments Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Whaling Convention Amendments Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-02-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2369"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-02-15T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Whaling Convention Amendments Act of 2018

This bill amends the Whaling Convention Act of 1949 to require the Department of Commerce to authorize aboriginal subsistence whaling if the whaling: (1) is for subsistence purposes, including the sale of authentic native articles of handicrafts and clothing; (2) does not include the striking, taking, or killing of calves or a whale accompanied by a calf; and (3) is not accomplished in a wasteful manner.

Commerce must establish catch limits for subsistence whaling by Alaska Natives if: (1) the International Whaling Commission (IWC) fails to establish the limits, and (2) Commerce determines that subsistence whaling is sustainable based on IWC's most recent review of the status of the affected whale.

The bill exempts actions taken under the Act with respect to a stock of a whale species from environmental review requirements under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 if Commerce determines that the action is sustainable based on the most recent review of the status of the stock by the IWC's Scientific Committee.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
