<bill session="115" type="s" number="1947" updated="2019-04-18T16:39:36Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-10-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve food safety, to encourage greater production of agricultural commodities for use in the locality of production, to reauthorize and expand Department of Agriculture support of those efforts, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Local FARMS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Local FARMS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Local Food and Regional Market Supply Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Local Food and Regional Market Supply Act</title>
    <title type="display">Local FARMS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2018-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2018-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-10-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3941"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="5316"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing and promotion"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-10-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Local Food And Regional Market Supply Act or the Local FARMS Act 

This bill consolidates, modifies, and authorizes several Department of Agriculture (USDA) programs to expand regional or local food markets and implement food safety practices.

The bill authorizes and provides mandatory funding for a new Agricultural Market Development Program that is administered by the Agricultural Marketing Service (AMS) and consolidates:

 the Farmers' Market and Local Food Promotion Program, Value-Added Producer Grants, regional food chain coordination, and public-private partnerships to plan and develop regional food systems. The bill modifies the Food Safety Outreach Program to move the program to the AMS, provide mandatory funding, and expand the project priorities.

The bill also:

 establishes a national food safety cost-share program; reauthorizes the National Organic Certification Cost-Share Program; authorizes rural development grants and loans to be used for meat, dairy, and poultry processing infrastructure; allows institutions participating in the school food programs to use locally grown, locally raised, or locally caught as a product specification; authorizes grants for produce prescription programs for low-income individuals and households; and reauthorizes the Senior Farmers Market Nutrition Program and expands eligibility to include low-income veterans. The bill modifies the Food and Agriculture Service Learning Program to: (1) require the majority of funds to be reserved for national or regional programs involving multiple states, and (2) expand the purposes of the program to include food waste reduction.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
