<bill session="114" type="s" number="718" updated="2018-08-16T22:54:08Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modify the boundary of Petersburg National Battlefield in the Commonwealth of Virginia, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to modify the boundary of Petersburg National Battlefield in the Commonwealth of Virginia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000805"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2015-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-17">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-08-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski under authority of the order of the Senate of 07/14/2016 with amendments. With written report No. 114-308.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-08-30" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="580">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 580.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks" code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1621"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4909"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-08-30T13:05:16Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">(Sec. 1) This bill modifies the boundary of Petersburg National Battlefield in Virginia to include the land and interests in land identified on the map titled "Petersburg National Battlefield Boundary Expansion," and dated March 2016.

The Department of the Interior may acquire lands and interests from willing sellers only, by donation, purchase, exchange, or transfer.

Interior shall administer any acquired lands or interests as a part of the Battlefield.

The bill transfers:

 from Interior to the Department of the Army administrative jurisdiction over approximately 1.170 acres of land for the Fort Lee Military Reservation, and from the Army to Interior administrative jurisdiction over approximately 1.171 acres of land for the Battlefield. The transferred lands shall not be subject to reimbursement or consideration.

The land transferred to the Army shall be excluded from the boundary of the Battlefield.

The land transferred to Interior shall be included within the boundary of the Battlefield and administered as part of it.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-308</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
