<bill session="115" type="h" number="2529" updated="2019-04-18T16:09:01Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to establish a national intersection and interchange safety construction program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Intersection and Interchange Safety Construction Program Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Intersection and Interchange Safety Construction Program Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">National Intersection and Interchange Safety Construction Program Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000294"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Highways and Transit" code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">National Intersection and Interchange Safety Construction Program Act of 2017

This bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to establish a national intersection and interchange safety construction grant program.

DOT may make competitive grants to a state or local government, U.S. territory, tribal government, or metropolitan planning organization for projects that:

 are eligible for federal-aid highway funding, and will improve the safety of intersections or interchanges on the National Highway System that are used by an average of 50,000 vehicles a day and that are in immediate need of safety improvement. The aggregate grant amount provided to an entity in a fiscal year shall not exceed 5% of the amount available for all grants under the program in that fiscal year.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
