<bill session="114" type="h" number="4895" updated="2018-11-21T20:31:14Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Detaining Terrorists to Protect Americans Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish various prohibitions regarding the transfer or release of individuals detained at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, and with respect to United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Detaining Terrorists to Protect Americans Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000290"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2016-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001067" joined="2016-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000813" joined="2016-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="2746"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Detaining Terrorists to Protect Americans Act of 2016

This bill prohibits the use of funds to transfer, release, or assist in the transfer or release to or within the United States, its territories, or possessions of Khalid Sheikh Mohammed or any other detainee who: (1) is not a U.S. citizen or a member of the Armed Forces; and (2) is or was held by the Department of Defense (DOD) on or after January 20, 2009, at Naval Station Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.

No funds may be used:

 to construct or modify any facility in the United States, its territories, or possessions to house any individual detained at Guantanamo under DOD custody or control unless expressly authorized by Congress; or through FY2017 to transfer, release, or assist in the transfer or release of an individual detained at Guantanamo to any foreign country or foreign entity unless expressly authorized by Congress. "Individual detained at Guantanamo" means any individual located at Guantanamo as of October 1, 2009, who: (1) is not a U.S. citizen or a member of the Armed Forces; and (2) is under DOD custody or control, or otherwise under detention at Guantanamo.

No funds may be used to: (1) close or abandon Guantanamo, (2) relinquish control of Guantanamo to Cuba, or (3) implement a material modification to the Treaty Between the United States of America and Cuba that constructively closes Guantanamo.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
