<bill session="114" type="s" number="1933" updated="2019-03-03T14:40:30Z">
  <state datetime="2015-08-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-08-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-08-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a comprehensive United States Government policy to encourage the efforts of countries in sub-Saharan Africa to develop an appropriate mix of power solutions, including renewable energy, for more broadly distributed electricity access in order to support poverty reduction, promote development outcomes, and drive economic growth, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Electrify Africa Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Electrify Africa Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000360" joined="2015-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2015-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2015-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2015-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2015-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2015-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2015-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2015-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2015-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2015-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2015-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2015-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2015-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2015-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2015-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2015-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2015-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2015-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2015-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2015-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2015-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2015-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-08-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-08-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2847"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2152"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International monetary system and foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Lighting, heating, cooling"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC)"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-08-04T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Electrify Africa Act of 2015 

This bill directs the President to establish a multiyear strategy to assist countries in sub-Saharan Africa implement national power strategies and develop an appropriate mix of power solutions, including renewable energy, to provide access to reliable, affordable, and sustainable power in order to reduce poverty and drive economic growth.

 The President may: (1) establish an interagency working group to coordinate the activities of U.S. government departments and agencies involved in carrying out the strategy, and (2) use U.S. influence to leverage international support to promote the strategy.

 The U.S. Agency for International Development, the Trade and Development Agency, the Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC), and the Millennium Challenge Corporation are urged to prioritize efforts and assistance for power projects and markets in sub-Saharan Africa.

The Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 is amended to extend OPIC's issuing authority through September 30, 2018.

OPIC should:

 simplify the application, approval, and post-approval processes for insurance, financing, investment, or reinsurance for power generation and distribution projects in sub-Saharan Africa for which total OPIC support is less than $20 million; prioritize its loan, guarantee, and insurance programs, and financial commitments in the areas of power generation, distribution, and off-grid power and lighting in sub-Saharan Africa, including through the use of an investment advisory council; and publish in an accessible digital format the amount, type, location, duration, and measurable results of its investments and financings. OPIC is temporarily authorized to: (1) issue local currency guarantees to African subsidiaries of foreign financial institutions to facilitate eligible investor lending for power projects in sub-Saharan Africa, and (2) make loans to eligible investors for power projects in sub-Saharan Africa for which total OPIC support does not exceed $50 million.

 Foreign corporations, partnerships, and other associations that are majority owned by one or more U.S. citizens or corporations, partnerships, or other associations shall be temporarily considered eligible investors for the sole purpose of receiving OPIC assistance for power projects in sub-Saharan Africa.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
