<bill session="114" type="h" number="5587" updated="2019-01-09T21:10:25Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-13T16:56:17-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-09-13T16:56:17-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Career and Technical Education for the 21st Century Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Strengthening Career and Technical Education for the 21st Century Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Strengthening Career and Technical Education for the 21st Century Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006.</title>
    <title type="display">Strengthening Career and Technical Education for the 21st Century Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000467"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000373" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001269" joined="2016-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001293" joined="2016-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2016-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001289" joined="2016-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001103" joined="2016-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001101" joined="2016-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001094" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001106" joined="2016-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001107" joined="2016-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000623" joined="2016-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000450" joined="2016-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001055" joined="2016-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2016-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000056" joined="2016-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000379" joined="2016-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000363" joined="2016-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000559" joined="2016-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2016-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001189" joined="2016-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000127" joined="2016-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2016-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000591" joined="2016-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000582" joined="2016-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001157" joined="2016-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000185" joined="2016-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2016-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2016-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2016-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-07" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 37 - 0.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-09-08">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Education and the Workforce. H. Rept. 114-728.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-09-08" calendar="Union" number="564">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 564.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-09-13T14:42:11-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thompson (PA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-13T14:42:34-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5365-5380" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-13T14:42:35-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5587.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-13T15:32:08-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-13T16:49:21-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5386" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="503" datetime="2016-09-13T16:56:17-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 405 - 5 (Roll no. 503).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5365-5375" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-09-13T16:56:18-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3344"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-13T13:34:22Z" status="Passed House amended">Strengthening Career and Technical Education for the 21st Century Act

This bill reauthorizes through FY2022 the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006, divides career and technical education (CTE) students into CTE concentrators and CTE participants, and revises requirements for within-state funding allocations.

The bill also revises requirements for core indicators of performance, including state adjusted levels of performance, to differentiate those for CTE concentrators who graduate from high school and for CTE concentrators at the postsecondary level.

The bill repeals the separate mandate for tech prep education.

 No state, beginning with FY2020, shall receive a fiscal year allotment that is less than 90% of the previous fiscal year's allotment.

 The bill increases funding reserved for career and technical education activities in rural areas and areas with high percentages or numbers of career and technical education students.

The Institute for Education Sciences shall act for the Department of Education (ED) to appoint the independent advisory panel on the evaluation of CTE programs. The bill revises requirements for the contents of an evaluation.

 ED shall (currently, may) carry out research, development, capacity building, and technical assistance with regard to career and technical education programs.

ED may award grants to eligible entities, including local educational agencies and area CTE schools, to:

 create, develop, implement, or take to scale evidence-based, field initiated innovations, including through a pay for success initiative to improve CTE student outcomes; and evaluate such innovations rigorously. Grant priority shall be given to eligible entities that predominantly serve low-income students.

 The bill revises specified funding-related provisions regarding Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and the Republic of Palau.

The bill reauthorizes through FY2022 grants for tribally controlled CTE institutions and repeals the authorization for assistance for certain occupational and information activities.

State plans shall be for four years instead of six years.

The bill revises requirements for:

 such plans, as well as state program improvement plans and state leadership activities; local applications for CTE programs, including a comprehensive CTE needs assessment, and local uses of funds; and state maintenance of efforts, including administrative penalties for failure to meet maintenance requirements. The bill permits a state, in order to receive its full fiscal year career and technical education funding allotment, to: (1) continue to use its existing fiscal effort per student or aggregate expenditure in determining qualifying expenditure levels, or (2) establish a new level of fiscal effort per student or aggregate expenditure.

The Government Accountability Office shall evaluate:

 the strategies, components, policies, and practices used successfully by eligible agencies or eligible recipients receiving funding to assist all students in pursuing and completing programs of study aligned to high-skill, high-wage occupations, as well as any specific underrepresented subgroup of students; and any challenges associated with replication of such strategies, components, policies, and practices. The Wagner-Peyser Act is amended to revise the duties of a state agency receiving federal assistance for participation in the nationwide employment statistics system of workforce and labor market information.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-728</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
