<bill session="114" type="s" number="2793" updated="2018-08-16T23:10:42Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SBIR and STTR Reauthorization and Improvement Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Small Business Act to reauthorize and improve the Small Business Innovation Research Program and the Small Business Technology Transfer Program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SBIR and STTR Reauthorization and Improvement Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2016-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000127" joined="2016-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="2812"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2136"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">SBIR and STTR Reauthorization and Improvement Act of 2016

This bill amends the Small Business Act to reauthorize and make permanent the Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) and Small Business Technology Transfer (STTR) programs.

The bill specifies budget amounts for the Department of Defense and other federal agencies to obligate for expenditure with small business concerns under the SBIR and STTR programs.

The Small Business Administration (SBA) shall modify certain policy directives to eliminate automatic annual inflation adjustments to awards under Phases I and II of the SBIR program.

The bill makes the Commercialization Development Awards pilot program permanent.

The national small business goal for federal agency research and development programs shall be at least 10% for FY2018 and ensuing fiscal years.

Annual reports to Congress on the SBIR and STTR programs shall include information regarding awards under the Rapid Innovation Program under the Ike Skelton National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2011.

An SBIR or STTR award may cover the indirect cost of seeking protection for intellectual property created through work performed under it.

The Government Accountability Office shall audit annually federal government compliance with SBIR and STTR goals and incentives.

Federal agencies and prime contractors shall issue Phase III awards relating to technology, including sole source awards, to the SBIR and STTR award recipients that developed the technology.

The SBA shall establish a Regional SBIR State Collaborative Initiative Pilot Program.

The bill reauthorizes the Federal and State Technology (FAST) Partnership Program through FY2021.

The bill establishes an SBIR and STTR Interagency Policy Committee to:

 determine how to collect data on achievements by small business concerns in each phase of the programs; and establish a uniform baseline for metrics that support improving the solicitation, contracting, funding, and execution of program management.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
