<bill session="114" type="s" number="745" updated="2018-06-02T06:41:03Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Debt and Taxation Transparency Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide debt and tax transparency to taxpayers.</title>
    <title type="display">National Debt and Taxation Transparency Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6050"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Debt and Taxation Transparency Act of 2015

This bill directs the Department of the Treasury, beginning not later than October 1, 2017, to provide each individual who has a valid social security number, who received a Form W-2 in the previous taxable year, and who has filed a tax return in any previous taxable year (eligible individual) with a taxpayer account statement. An initial statement must be provided to each eligible individual with a current mailing address not later than September 30, 2020.

The taxpayer account statement shall include: (1) a summary of the most recent Financial Report of the U.S. government, including the Statement of Long Term Fiscal Projections; (2) a calculation by Treasury of the eligible individual's share of the total obligations of the federal government; and (3) a 30-year calculation of the proportional increase in the federal income tax rates necessary to entirely finance the current fiscal path of the federal government, assuming there are no changes in current fiscal policy and no budget deficit.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
