<bill session="113" type="h" number="5877" updated="2016-10-25T16:17:53Z">
  <state datetime="2014-12-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Pension Investments Modernization Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and title 5, United States Code, to require plans to establish policies addressing firm-specific risks in asset management services, greater diversification in investment strategies, and the inclusion of diverse asset managers and minority brokerage firms, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">American Pension Investments Modernization Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001137"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000187" joined="2014-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-12-11T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">American Pension Investments Modernization Act of 2014 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to require the fiduciary of an employee benefit plan to establish policies for appointment of an investment manager or managers to manage any plan assets or business enterprise or enterprises for brokerage and investment banking services.

Requires the fiduciary, under these policies, to consider:

 the concentration level of the plan's exposure to firm-specific risks, including operational, compliance, and fraud risks; the inclusion, to the greatest extent feasible, of minority business enterprises for brokerage and investment banking services (including enterprises owned or controlled by specified percentages of African-Americans, Hispanic-Americans, Asian Pacific Americans, Subcontinent Asian Americans, Native Americans, women, or veterans); and the utilization of diverse asset managers, taking into consideration the investment opportunities they offer in sectors, strategies, geographies, and demographics not meaningfully available to the plans. Defines "diverse asset manager" as a minority business enterprise that manages an investment portfolio of between $100 million and $25 billion.

Directs the Secretary of Labor to issue related guidance and requires the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board (FRTIB) under the Federal Employees Retirement System (FERS) to take this guidance into account.

Directs the FRTIB to give current and former federal employees and Members of Congress in FERS the option to participate in actively managed funds within the employee's or Member's Thrift Savings Fund account (but no more than 20% of a current or former employee's or Member's funds).

Prohibits the FRTIB from subjecting more than 20% of the total assets under management of the Thrift Savings Fund to active management.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
