<bill session="114" type="s" number="1041" updated="2018-06-02T06:45:44Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">End Polluter Welfare Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to eliminate certain subsidies for fossil-fuel production.</title>
    <title type="display">End Polluter Welfare Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2015-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2015-12-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="1930"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">End Polluter Welfare Act of 2015

 Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act and the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to repeal the authority of the Department of the Interior to reduce or eliminate royalty payments for oil and natural gas leases in the Outer Continental Shelf.

 Amends the Mineral Leasing Act to increase minimum royalty payments for coal, oil, and natural gas leases.

Amends the Federal Oil and Gas Royalty Management Act of 1982 to prohibit payment of interest upon any overpayment of royalties.

Amends the Oil Pollution Act to eliminate the limitation on liability for offshore facilities and pipeline operators for oil spills.

Rescinds all unobligated balances made available to the World Bank, the Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC), the Export-Import Bank, the Advanced Research Projects Agency in the Department of Energy (DOE), and other international financing entities to carry out any project that supports power plants that operate on fossil fuel (i.e., coal, petroleum, natural gas, or any derivatives used for fuel). Exempts from such rescission any fossil-fueled power plant project located in a Least Developed Country if no other economically feasible alternative exists, and the project uses the most efficient technology available.

Terminates the Office of Fossil Energy Research and Development in DOE and related implementation authority.

Prohibits the Department of Agriculture from making loans under the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 to carry out projects that will use fossil fuel.

Prohibits the use of Department of Transportation funds to award any grant or other direct assistance to any rail or port project that transports fossil fuel.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) limit or repeal provisions allowing tax incentives for investment in fossil fuels, (2) increase the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund financing rate, and (3) impose a 13% tax on the removal price of any taxable crude oil or natural gas from the Outer Continental Shelf in the Gulf of Mexico.

Repeals the corporate income tax exemption for publicly traded partnerships with qualifying income and gains from activities relating to fossil fuels.

Designates the Powder River Basin in southeast Montana and northeast Wyoming as a coal producing region.

Eliminates accelerated depreciation for property that is receiving a subsidy for fossil fuel production.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
