<bill session="113" type="s" number="410" updated="2016-10-25T16:21:15Z">
  <state datetime="2013-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wall Street Trading and Speculators Tax Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to impose a tax on certain trading transactions.</title>
    <title type="display">Wall Street Trading and Speculators Tax Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000206"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2013-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1579"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="identical" number="880"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="277"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Commodities markets"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-02-28T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Wall Street Trading and Speculators Tax Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose a .03% excise tax on the purchase of a security if: (1) such purchase occurs or is cleared on a trading facility located in the United States, or (2) the purchaser or seller is a U.S. person.

Defines "security" to include: (1) stocks, partnership interests, notes, bonds, debentures, or other evidences of indebtedness; (2) interests in a derivative financial instrument (i.e., any option, forward contract, futures contract, or any similar financial instrument) and (3) any notional principal contract.

Exempts from such tax: (1) initial issues of securities; (2) any note, bond, debenture, or other evidence of indebtedness which is traded on a trading facility located in the United States and has a fixed maturity of not more than 100 days; and (3) securities traded pursuant to certain lending arrangements. Makes such tax applicable to transactions by controlled foreign corporations and payable by its U.S. shareholders.

Allows an offset against such tax for contributions to certain tax-favored accounts, including tax-exempt retirement plans, Archer medical savings accounts, health savings accounts, and qualified tuition plans and Coverdell education savings accounts.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
