<bill session="114" type="s" number="2304" updated="2019-06-21T11:07:12Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-27">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for tribal demonstration projects for the integration of early childhood development, education, including Native language and culture, and related services, for evaluation of those demonstration projects, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tribal Early Childhood, Education, and Related Services Integration Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Tribal Early Childhood, Education, and Related Services Integration Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2016-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2015-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-06">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 114-287.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5072"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-18T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Tribal Early Childhood, Education, and Related Services Integration Act of 2015

This bill amends the Native American Programs Act of 1974 to require the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a demonstration program to support tribal early childhood education demonstration projects. Funding for projects is through existing programs that have a purpose consistent with the purpose of the demonstration program. HHS may waive certain provisions of law, policy, or procedure related to the programs providing funding for projects.

Demonstration projects must be: (1) carried out by an Indian tribe, a tribal organization, or a consortium with a tribe or tribal organization as its primary member; (2) designed around new approaches that address tribal community needs and improve early childhood education and services; and (3) focused on Native culture, culturally based early childhood education, and related services.

HHS must make grants to demonstration projects to: (1) build or upgrade facilities for early childhood care and development, and (2) reimburse early childhood educators who fulfill a period of obligated service for costs associated with obtaining early childhood certification or credentials.

This bill amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to revise federal student loan forgiveness and loan cancellation for teachers to increase the maximum amounts of loan forgiveness and cancellation that may be provided to early childhood teachers in programs operated by Indian tribes or serving a large percentage of Indian children. Cancellation of student loans for public service is expanded to include service in Indian prekindergarten, child care programs, or early childhood learning and development centers.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
