<bill session="113" type="h" number="4349" updated="2016-10-25T16:12:04Z">
  <state datetime="2014-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Crude Oil Export Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To repeal the crude oil export ban under the Energy Policy and Conservation Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Crude Oil Export Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001157"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001283" joined="2014-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2014-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001048" joined="2014-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2014-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000460" joined="2014-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000592" joined="2014-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001192" joined="2014-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000796" joined="2014-04-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, Energy and Commerce, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-01">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-01">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-01">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Terrorism, Nonproliferation, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Terrorism,  Nonproliferation, and Trade" code="HSFA18" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Power" code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="4286"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2170"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-04-01T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Crude Oil Export Act - Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to repeal the authority of the President to restrict exports of: (1) coal, petroleum products, natural gas, or petrochemical feedstocks, and (2) materials or equipment which he determines necessary for either exploration, production, refining, or transportation of energy supplies, or for construction or maintenance of energy facilities within the United States.

Amends the Mineral Leasing Act to repeal limitations on exports of oil.

Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to repeal limitations on export of Outer Continental Shelf oil or gas on the lands within its purview.

Declares without force or effect: (1) the limitation placed upon crude oil exports by the Export Administration Act of 1979, and (2) a specified regulation relating to crude oil.

Directs the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce to grant licenses to export crude oil to a country unless: (1) the country is subject to sanctions or trade restrictions imposed by the United States, or (2) either the President or Congress has designated the country as subject to exclusion for reasons of national security.

Authorizes the President, subject to a congressional resolution of disapproval, to ban the export of crude oil from the United States for a maximum period of 90 days during a national emergency. Permits renewal of such ban during periods of national emergency.

Subjects any act of imposing or renewing a ban to a resolution of disapproval under the Congressional Review Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
