<bill session="114" type="h" number="6056" updated="2018-11-09T00:09:34Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NAFTA Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To assess the impact of the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA), to require further negotiation of certain provisions of NAFTA, and to provide for the withdrawal from NAFTA unless certain conditions are met.</title>
    <title type="display">NAFTA Accountability Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000009"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Trade" code="HSWM04" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">NAFTA Accountability Act

This bill provides that unless the specified conditions set forth in this bill are met:

 Congress withdraws its approval of the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) effective one year after enactment of this bill; and the President, not later than six months after this bill's enactment, shall provide written notice of withdrawal to the governments of Canada and Mexico. The bill requires the President to confer with the governments of Canada and Mexico and renegotiate NAFTA to correct:

 trade deficits, currency distortions, and the impact of agricultural imports on U.S. agricultural production. The bill also prescribes requirements for:

 gains in U.S. jobs and living standards, increased domestic manufacturing, health and environmental standards, a non-increase in crime with illegal drugs, and democracy and human freedoms in Mexico. The bill expresses the sense of Congress that, until the conditions set forth in this bill are met, the President should not engage in negotiations to expand NAFTA to include other countries, and trade promotion authority should not be renewed with respect to the approval of any such NAFTA expansion.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
