<bill session="115" type="h" number="1912" updated="2019-04-18T16:06:23Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that claims for benefits under the Black Lung Benefits Act are processed in a fair and timely manner, to better protect miners from pneumoconiosis (commonly known as "black lung disease"), and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Black Lung Benefits Improvement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Black Lung Benefits Improvement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Black Lung Benefits Improvement Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2017-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000188" joined="2017-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000185" joined="2017-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000808" joined="2017-04-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="855"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Black Lung Benefits Improvement Act of 2017

This bill amends the Black Lung Benefits Act to revise requirements for miners' claims for pneumoconiosis (black lung) benefits.

The Department of Labor must pay the attorneys' fees of prevailing parties on a qualifying benefit claim.

This bill revises: (1) the standards of medical evidence that establish a presumption that a miner is totally disabled by black lung, and (2) payments to such miners (including their dependents).

Black lung clinics may use federal funds to help individuals file claims.

A person may not knowingly and willfully: (1) make a false statement or misrepresentation in increasing or reducing black lung benefits, or (2) threaten or mislead a participant in a proceeding regarding the benefits.

Labor, upon request, must give a claimant the opportunity to substantiate a claim for benefits through a pulmonary evaluation of the miner. Labor must also authorize a computerized tomography scan in diagnosing complicated pneumoconiosis.

The National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health must establish a pilot program to ensure accurate classifications of chest radiographs in black lung cases where the diagnosis is at issue.

Labor must educate certain individuals who work on black lung benefits about medical evidence relevant to claims.

A previously denied claimant may file a new claim for black lung benefits within one year.

This bill amends the Federal Mine Safety and Health Act of 1977 to direct Labor to use data from continuous personal dust monitors to determine whether to make changes to respirable dust concentration standards, controls, and measurements.

This bill provides statutory authority for the Office of Workers' Compensation Programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
