<bill session="114" type="s" number="673" updated="2018-06-02T06:40:41Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Winding Down ObamaCare Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide a transition plan for those individuals who may be affected by ObamaCare's unlawful implementation.</title>
    <title type="display">Winding Down ObamaCare Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001197"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-04T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Winding Down ObamaCare Act

This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to require health insurers to offer at least 18 months of continuation coverage to enrollees who lose their health insurance coverage or federal premium assistance as a result of the Supreme Court's decision in King v. Burwell. Continuation coverage must be the same as an enrollee's coverage at the time of the decision, unless the health insurer modifies coverage for all similar enrollees. Individuals must elect continuation coverage within 60 days of the decision.

Health insurers cannot raise premiums during the period of continuation coverage.

The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) cannot enter into a new contract with a state to provide the state with technology from the federal health insurance exchange.

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish a new tax credit for individuals with continuation coverage that is equal to 65% of the amount paid for continuation coverage, with the percentage decreasing by 5% each month after six months. The Department of the Treasury must pay advance payments on the tax credit.

This bill amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to prohibit HHS from waiving state Medicaid plan requirements in order to allow a state to undertake a demonstration project unless HHS establishes project spending limits that are reviewed by actuaries.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
