<bill session="114" type="h" number="3147" updated="2018-06-02T04:38:20Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Constituent Services Disclosure Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the House of Representatives Administrative Reform Technical Corrections Act to require that certain types of services be provided at no cost to constituents, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Constituent Services Disclosure Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000608"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Constituent Services Disclosure Act of 2015

This bill amends the House of Representatives Administrative Reform Technical Corrections Act to prohibit the availability of 20% of the Members' Representational Allowance to a Member's office unless it provides certain free assistance with respect to:

 passports; individual federal income tax returns; 501(c)(3) tax-exempt status applications; benefits under titles XVIII (Medicare), II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance), and XVI (Supplemental Security Income) of the Social Security Act; student loans; and veterans' benefits or other laws administered by the Department of Veterans Affairs. Each Member's office must make publicly available in print or on its congressional website all the constituent services it provides.

It is the sense of Congress that private companies that provide the same or similar assistance to individuals as described in the House of Representatives Administrative Reform Technical Corrections Act (as amended by this Act) should disclose that such assistance could be provided free by the office of a Member of the House of Representatives.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
