<bill session="115" type="h" number="1420" updated="2019-04-18T16:03:59Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to require an air carrier to provide information to the public regarding its policies for imposing baggage fees and assisting passengers during a widespread disruption of service, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Know Before You Fly Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Know Before You Fly Act</title>
    <title type="display">Know Before You Fly Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000560" joined="2017-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Aviation" code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-08T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Know Before You Fly Act

This bill makes it an unfair or deceptive practice for an air carrier, foreign air carrier, or ticket agent to fail to disclose in its Internet fare quotation a clear and prominent statement of checked baggage and carry-on baggage fees, along with a prominent website link to a list of all such fees.

 A covered air carrier shall publish on its website a clear statement indicating whether it will provide passengers whose travel is interrupted due to a widespread disruption:

 hotel accommodations; ground transportation; meal vouchers; transportation on another air carrier to the passenger's destination; and sleeping facilities, food, and water inside the airport terminal. A "covered air carrier" is defined as an air carrier that provides scheduled or public charter air transportation in an aircraft designed for a passenger capacity of 30 or more.

The Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) shall designate a FAA office to receive and analyze reports involving fumes in the air conditioning and pressurization systems of commercial aircraft.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
