<bill session="114" type="s" number="1738" updated="2018-06-02T06:57:30Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safer Communities Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect individuals by strengthening the Nation's mental health infrastructure, improving the understanding of violence, strengthening firearm prohibitions and protections for at-risk individuals, and improving and expanding the reporting of mental health records to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System.</title>
    <title type="display">Safer Communities Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2994"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="731"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1211"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1588"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2192"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3926"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1217"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-09T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Safer Communities Act of 2015

This bill provides grants to expand mental health crisis assistance programs, to support comprehensive school mental health programs, and to enhance mental health and substance abuse needs of prison inmates.

The bill directs the Department of Health and Human Services to expand research on violence associated with mental illness and substance abuse disorders.

It requires the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to expand the National Violent Death Reporting System to all 50 states and to research the causes, mechanisms, prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of injuries from gun violence.

The bill states that no provision of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act prohibits physicians from asking patients about guns in their homes, speaking to a patient about gun safety, or reporting a patient's threat of violence.

It amends the Gun Control Act of 1968 to specify that the term "committed to a mental institution" applies to involuntary inpatient or outpatient treatment.

The bill amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to permit the Department of Justice (DOJ) to award grants to states to remove firearms from individuals who pose a threat to themselves or others.

DOJ must promptly notify law enforcement agencies when a prohibited person attempts to purchase a firearm.

The bill replaces statutory references to persons "adjudicated as a mental defective" with persons "adjudicated as ineligible due to disqualifying mental status."

It amends the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007 to:

 establish procedures to restore firearm ownership rights after a mental health adjudication or commitment, require an annual report on record submissions due to domestic violence misdemeanor convictions, authorize state grants to improve the automation and transmittal of mental health and criminal history records, and require quarterly updates to federal agency record submissions. The bill reauthorizes the National Criminal History Records Improvement Program for FY2016-FY2019.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
