<bill session="114" type="s" number="1109" updated="2019-03-03T14:40:26Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-21">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require adequate information regarding the tax treatment of payments under settlement agreements entered into by Federal agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Truth in Settlements Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Truth in Settlements Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Truth in Settlements Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Truth in Settlements Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Truth in Settlements Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2015-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2015-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure:CR S2476-2477"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-05-06" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-07-07">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson without amendment. With written report No. 114-76.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-07-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="140">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 140.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-09-21">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6851-6852" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2015-09-21" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6852" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-09-22">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-22T16:05:34-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-01">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-03-01">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-06-09">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 114-613.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-06-09" calendar="Union" number="476">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 476.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="2648"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2668"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2016-06-09T11:08:30Z" status="Reported to House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on September 21, 2015. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Truth in Settlements Act of 2015

Sets forth new requirements for the public disclosure of any covered settlement agreement entered into by a federal executive agency.&#160;

(Sec. 2) Defines "covered settlement agreement" as a settlement agreement (including a consent decree) that: (1) is entered into by an executive agency, relates to an alleged violation of federal civil or criminal law, and requires the payment of not less than $1 million by one or more non-federal persons (entities not within the federal government); or (2) relates to the rulemaking process or an alleged failure of an executive agency to engage in such process and requires the payment of not less&#160;than $200,000 in attorney fees, costs, or expenses by an executive agency to a non-federal person.

Requires agency heads to make publicly available on the agency website&#160;a copy of each covered settlement agreement entered into by the agency and a list for each agreement, which shall include:

 the names of the parties to the settlement&#160;agreement and the date of such agreement; a description of the claims that were settled under the agreement; the amount each party to the agreement is obligated to pay under the terms of the agreement and the total amounts required to be paid; for each settling party, the amount the settling party is obligated to pay that has been expressly specified as a civil or criminal penalty or fine and any amount expressly specified as not deductible for tax purposes; and a description of where amounts collected under the agreement will be deposited. Requires each agency to ensure that: (1) such information remains publicly available for not less than 5 years beginning on the date of the agreement, and (2) a copy of a covered settlement agreement remains publicly available for not less than 1 year beginning on such date or for not less than 5 years in the case of an agreement under which a non-federal person is required to pay at least $50 million.

Exempts the provisions of a covered settlement agreement that are subject to a confidentiality agreement from disclosure. Directs an agency to issue a public statement explaining any determination that confidentiality of an agreement is required to protect U.S. interests.

Requires agencies to submit an annual report indicating:

 how many covered settlement agreements the agency entered into during the previous fiscal year; how many of such agreements had terms or conditions that were required to be kept confidential; the total amount of attorney fees, costs, and expenses paid to non-federal persons under such agreements; and the number of such agreements between the agency and non-federal persons that involved regulatory action or regulatory changes during that fiscal year. Directs the Comptroller General to report to Congress on how agencies determine whether the terms or existence of a settlement agreement will be treated as confidential.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-613</report>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-76</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
