<bill session="114" type="s" number="2887" updated="2018-06-02T07:18:27Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Missile Defense Defend and Deter Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Missile Defense Agency to conduct annual tests of the ground-based midcourse defense element of the ballistic missile defense system, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Missile Defense Defend and Deter Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001198"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Missile Defense Defend and Deter Act of 2016

This bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD) Missile Defense Agency to administer an intercept flight test of the ground-based midcourse defense element of the ballistic missile defense system at least once each fiscal year.

Each test shall provide for:

 validation of the defense element's operational effectiveness; use of assets in their operational configuration against an inventory of targets to assess performance in a variety of flight test regimes; use of operational doctrine and real-world constraints; evaluation of new concepts of operations, tactics, and techniques; and mechanisms to assure the confidence of members of the Armed Forces in the basic design of the ground-based midcourse defense element, its hit-to-kill effectiveness, and its operational capability. The Agency may forgo a test if:

 it would jeopardize national security, not be successful due to specific ground-based midcourse defense components needing a non-intercept test, and likely fail due to impractical time considerations; or funding is insufficient. The Agency also may forgo a test if DOD determines that the testing is detrimental to U.S. national security interests and provides notice to Congress.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
