<bill session="114" type="s" number="3056" updated="2018-06-02T07:46:25Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CREATES Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Creating and Restoring Equal Access to Equivalent Samples Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for certain causes of action relating to delays of generic drugs and biosimilar biological products.</title>
    <title type="display">CREATES Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2016-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2016-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2016-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2016-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2016-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2016-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2016-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000127" joined="2016-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2016-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3862-3863" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-21">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary Subcommittee on Antitrust, Competition Policy and Consumer Rights. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Antitrust, Competition Policy and Consumer Rights" code="SSJU01" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Product development and innovation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Creating and Restoring Equal Access to Equivalent Samples Act of 2016 or the CREATES Act of 2016

This bill permits the developer of a drug or biological product to bring a civil action against the license holder of an approved medication alleging that the license holder: (1) declined to make available sufficient quantities of the approved medication for the developer's testing; or (2) failed to agree on, or refused to allow the developer to join, a single, shared system of elements to assure safe use (ETASU) of the medication. (Under current law, a generic version of a medication with ETASU must join the brand name medication's system of ETASU unless the developer of the generic has a waiver from the Food and Drug Administration.) The bill does not apply to medications for which there is a shortage, unless the shortage will not be promptly resolved.

In a civil action regarding the availability of sufficient quantities of a medication, it is an affirmative defense that the license holder: (1) is not manufacturing or marketing the medication and does not have access to a supply of the medication to make available, or (2) sells the medication without restrictions through other entities and the developer can purchase sufficient quantities of the medication from those entities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
