<bill session="115" type="s" number="3025" updated="2019-04-18T16:43:50Z">
  <state datetime="2018-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to prevent the illegal trafficking of supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits by requiring all program beneficiaries to show valid photo identification when purchasing items with program benefits.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fraud Reduction Through Photographic Identification Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fraud Reduction Through Photographic Identification Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Fraud Reduction Through Photographic Identification Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000393"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Photography and imaging"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-06-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fraud Reduction Through Photographic Identification Act of 2018 

This bill amends the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to require Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP, formerly known as the food stamp program) beneficiaries to show photographic identification when making purchases using SNAP benefits.

State agencies must require the electronic benefits transfer card used for SNAP benefits to list the names of:

 the head of the household, each adult member of the household, and each adult that is not a member of the household that is authorized to use that card. Each individual listed on the card must show photographic identification at the point of sale when using the card. A head of a household is not required to show photographic identification if the card includes a photograph of that individual.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
