<bill session="114" type="hj" number="90" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:32Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide limitations on the transfer of certain United States munitions from the United States to Saudi Arabia.</title>
    <title type="display">To provide limitations on the transfer of certain United States munitions from the United States to Saudi Arabia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000582"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2016-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2016-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2016-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2016-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2016-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2016-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000065" joined="2016-04-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="sj" session="114" relation="identical" number="32"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Saudi Arabia"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Yemen"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This joint resolution expresses the sense of Congress that no transfer to Saudi Arabia of U.S. air-to-ground munitions should occur until the President certifies that Saudi Arabia: (1) demonstrates an ongoing effort to combat the mutual threat our nations face from foreign terrorist organizations, and (2) takes all feasible precautions to reduce the risk of civilian harm in the course of military actions.

No transfer of U.S. air-to-ground munitions may occur until the President certifies to Congress that Saudi Arabia:

 is not providing funding, material support, or lethal aid to foreign terrorist organizations; is, with its coalition partners, taking all feasible precautions to reduce the risk of civilian harm and exercising proportional use of force in the course of military actions; is, with its coalition partners, making demonstrable efforts to facilitate the flow of critical humanitarian aid and commercial goods; and is taking necessary measures to target designated foreign terrorist organizations, including al Qaeda in the Arabian Peninsula and affiliates of the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant, as part of its military operations in Yemen.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
