<bill session="114" type="h" number="3224" updated="2019-01-29T22:16:12Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gun Look-Alike Case Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To regulate the sale of cases and covers that resemble firearms, to amend the Consumer Product Safety Improvement Act of 2008 with respect to the regulation of toy, look-alike, and imitation firearms, and to provide penalties for a violation of such regulations.</title>
    <title type="display">Gun Look-Alike Case Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000179"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2015-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2016-02-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Consumer Protection and Commerce" code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Gun Look-Alike Case Act

Transfers the Department of Commerce's authority to regulate the markings on toy, look-alike, or imitation firearms under the Federal Energy Management Improvement Act of 1988 to the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) under the Consumer Product Safety Improvement Act of 2008 (CPSIA).

Amends the CPSIA to prohibit a toy, look-alike, or imitation firearm from being manufactured, entered into commerce, shipped, transported, or received unless it contains, or has affixed to it, a marking approved by the CPSC.

Maintains existing standards that require such firearms, subject to regulatory exceptions, to have a blaze orange plug inserted in their barrels. Sets forth exceptions that: (1) authorize the CPSC to provide for alternative markings or devices, or (2) require former Commerce regulations concerning approved markings to be considered approved by the CPSC in the absence of any CPSC regulations.

Expands the categories of look-alike firearms subject to such marking requirements and regulations to include product cases or covers that have the appearance, shape, or configuration of a firearm.

Repeals Commerce's authorities for approving alternative markings and penalizing violations. Requires violations to instead be treated under the CPSIA.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
