<bill session="115" type="hr" number="748" updated="2019-04-18T15:55:01Z">
  <state datetime="2018-02-27T13:53:20-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-02-27T13:53:20-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1865) to amend the Communications Act of 1934 to clarify that section 230 of such Act does not prohibit the enforcement against providers and users of interactive computer services of Federal and State criminal and civil law relating to sexual exploitation of children or sex trafficking, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1865) to amend the Communications Act of 1934 to clarify that section 230 of such Act does not prohibit the enforcement against providers and users of interactive computer services of Federal and State criminal and civil law relating to sexual exploitation of children or sex trafficking, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001093"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-02-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-26">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 115-583, by Mr. Collins (GA).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-26T19:26:36-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1865 under a structured rule with one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the Chair and Ranking Member of the Committee on the Judiciary. The rule makes in order an amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary printed in the bill. The rule also provides one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-02-26" state="REPORTED" calendar="House" number="129">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 129.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-02-27T11:18:47-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1277-1280" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-27T11:20:06-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 748.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-27T11:47:20-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 748, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Slaughter demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on ordering the previous question until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-27T13:39:05-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1287-1289" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-27T13:46:26-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 228 - 184 (Roll no. 84).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="85" datetime="2018-02-27T13:53:20-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 235 - 175 (Roll no. 85).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1277" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-02-27T13:53:22-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="procedurally-related" number="1865"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-02-26T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1865) to amend the Communications Act of 1934 to clarify that section 230 of such Act does not prohibit the enforcement against providers and users of interactive computer services of Federal and State criminal and civil law relating to sexual exploitation of children or sex trafficking.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-583</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
