<bill session="114" type="s" number="2502" updated="2018-06-02T07:14:35Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Affordable Retirement Advice Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to ensure that retirement investors receive advice in their best interests, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Affordable Retirement Advice Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000360" joined="2016-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2016-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2016-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2016-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2016-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2016-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2016-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2016-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2016-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2016-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2016-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2016-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2016-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2016-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2016-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2016-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4293"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4294"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2505"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-04T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Affordable Retirement Advice Protection Act

This bill amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to define "investment advice," as it relates to fiduciary duties under such Act, as a recommendation that relates to: (1) the advisability of acquiring, holding, disposing, or exchanging any moneys or other property of a pension plan (or Individual Retirement Account) by the plan, plan participants, or plan beneficiaries, including any recommendation regarding whether to take a distribution of benefits from the plan or any recommendation relating to a rollover or distribution from such plan; (2) the management of moneys or other property of the plan, including recommendations relating to the management of plan assets to be rolled over or otherwise distributed from the plan; or (3) the advisability of retaining or ceasing to retain a person who would receive a fee or other compensation for providing investment advice. Investment advice must be rendered pursuant to either: (1) a written acknowledgment of the obligation of the investment advisor to act in accordance with fiduciary standards under ERISA; or (2) a mutual agreement, arrangement, or understanding that may include limitations on scope, timing, and responsibility to provide ongoing monitoring or advice services.

The bill allows an exemption from ERISA prohibited transactions rules for investment advice: (1) for which no more than reasonable compensation is paid; or (2) that is based on a limited range of investment options or may result in variable income to the investment advisor if a clearly-stated notice is provided to the advice recipient that the same or similar investments may be available at a greater or lesser cost from other sources.

The bill prohibits the Department of Labor from amending any rules or administrative positions regarding investment advice promulgated under ERISA and no such rules or administrative positions promulgated prior to the enactment date of this Act, but not effective on January 1, 2015, may become effective unless a bill or joint resolution specifically approving such rules or positions is enacted not later than 60 days after the enactment of this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
