<bill session="113" type="h" number="3038" updated="2016-10-25T16:07:00Z">
  <state datetime="2013-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SOARS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Suborbital and Orbital Advancement and Regulatory Streamlining Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To streamline the process of commercial space launch licensing and to establish demonstration projects involving the use of experimental aircraft in direct and indirect support of commercial space launch activities.</title>
    <title type="display">SOARS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001165"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001256" joined="2013-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001045" joined="2013-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2013-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2013-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Space.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Space" code="HSSY16" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2140"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Space flight and exploration"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-08-02T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Suborbital and Orbital Advancement and Regulatory Streamlining Act or SOARS Act - Amends commercial space launch licensing requirements.

Revises the definition of "launch services" to include activities involved in the preparation of a launch vehicle (as under current law) or element thereof, including space flight participant training for a launch.

Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to issue a single license or permit for flight of a launch or reentry vehicle, or element thereof, in support of a launch or reentry, even when the vehicle or element is not being launched or reentered. Requires the Secretary to ensure that all DOT regulations for a licensed or permitted launch or reentry are satisfied under a single license or permit.

Authorizes the issuance of an experimental permit for a particular reusable suborbital rocket (as under current law) or rocket design after a license has been issued for the launch or reentry of a rocket of that design. Declares that any permits already issued shall remain valid for research and development (R&amp;D) and other specified purposes.

Directs the Secretary to establish, under the Office of Commercial Space Transportation of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), a demonstration project to evaluate the benefits of using experimental aircraft for both the direct and indirect support of commercial space launch and reentry activities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
