<bill session="114" type="h" number="6528" updated="2019-02-13T17:31:18Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Litigation Relief for Forest Management Projects Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 and the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to discourage litigation against the Forest Service and the Bureau of Land Management relating to land management projects.</title>
    <title type="display">Litigation Relief for Forest Management Projects Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Z000018"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-12-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="3533"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-12T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Litigation Relief for Forest Management Projects Act

This bill amends the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 to prohibit any additional consultation from being required with respect to: (1) the listing of a species as threatened or endangered, or a designation of a critical habitat, if a land management plan has been adopted by the Department of Agriculture as of the designation date; or (2) any provision of such an adopted plan.

The bill amends the Federal land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to prohibit any additional consultation from being required with respect to: (1) the listing of a species as threatened or endangered, or a designation of critical habitat, if a land use plan has been adopted by the Department of the Interior as of the designation date; or (2) any provision of such an adopted plan.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
