<bill session="114" type="s" number="741" updated="2018-06-02T06:41:02Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Water Infrastructure Resiliency and Sustainability Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to establish a program of awarding grants to owners or operators of water systems to increase the resiliency or adaptability of the systems to any ongoing or forecasted changes to the hydrologic conditions of a region of the United States.</title>
    <title type="display">Water Infrastructure Resiliency and Sustainability Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2015-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000146" joined="2015-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2015-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1530" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1530-1531" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1278"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Hydrology and hydrography"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Water Infrastructure Resiliency and Sustainability Act of 2015

This bill requires the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish the Water Infrastructure Resiliency and Sustainability Program to provide grants in each of FY2015-FY2019 for programs or projects to increase the resiliency or adaptability of water systems to any ongoing or forecasted changes to the hydrologic conditions of a U.S. region. A water system is a community water system, a treatment works, a decentralized wastewater treatment system for domestic sewage, a groundwater storage and replenishment system, a system for transport and delivery of water for irrigation or conservation, or a natural or engineered system that manages floodwater.

The EPA must give priority to owners or operators of water systems that are at the greatest and most immediate risk of facing significant negative impacts due to changing hydrologic conditions.

The EPA must ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that the list of grant applications funded includes a substantial number that propose to use innovative approaches that meet at least one of these goals:

 promote more efficient water use, conservation, reuse, or recycling; use decentralized, low-impact development technologies and nonstructural approaches; reduce stormwater runoff or flooding by protecting or enhancing natural ecosystem functions; modify, upgrade, enhance, or replace existing water system infrastructure in response to changing hydrologic conditions; improve water quality or quantity for agricultural and municipal uses; and provide multiple benefits, including water supply enhancement or demand reduction, water quality protection or improvement, increased flood protection, and ecosystem protection or improvement.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
