<bill session="114" type="h" number="1815" updated="2019-02-13T17:31:18Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-07T19:14:21-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-06-07T19:14:21-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Eastern Nevada Land Implementation Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Eastern Nevada Land Implementation Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Eastern Nevada Land Implementation Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To facilitate certain pinyon-juniper related projects in Lincoln County, Nevada, to modify the boundaries of certain wilderness areas in the State of Nevada, and to provide for the implementation of a conservation plan for the Virgin River, Nevada.</title>
    <title type="display">Eastern Nevada Land Implementation Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000369" joined="2015-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001055" joined="2015-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2015-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-04">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02">
      <text>Subcommittee on Federal Lands Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-02-03" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-04-11">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 114-479.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-11" calendar="Union" number="365">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 365.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-06-07T17:19:40-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hardy moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-07T17:19:54-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3482-3484" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-07T17:19:56-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1815.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-07T17:25:59-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-07T19:08:32-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3492-3493" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="272" datetime="2016-06-07T19:14:21-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 360 - 7 (Roll no. 272).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3482-3483" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-06-07T19:14:22-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-08">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="953"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-07T10:58:13Z" status="Passed House amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on April 25, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Eastern Nevada Land Implementation Improvement Act

 (Sec. 2) This bill amends the Lincoln County Land Act of 2000 (LCLA) to require implementation of a multispecies habitat conservation plan in Lincoln County, Nevada.

Both the LCLA and the Lincoln County Conservation, Recreation, and Development Act of 2004 (LCCRDA) are amended to make certain amounts available for comprehensive, cost-effective, and multijurisdictional hazardous fuels reduction projects and wildfire prevention planning activities (particularly for pinyon-juniper dominated landscapes) and other rangeland and woodland restoration projects within the county, consistent with the Ely Resource Management Plan or a subsequent amendment to it.

 The bill requires cooperative agreements between the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) and Lincoln County for certain county-provided law enforcement and planning related activities approved by the Department of the Interior.

 Certain portions of land sale proceeds returned to the County under the LCLA and the LCCRDA shall be used in part for the Lincoln County Regional Development Authority.

Under the LCCRDA Interior shall realign a specified portion of a 2,640-foot wide utility corridor.

The bill:

 affirms and validates patent number 27-2005-0081 issued by the BLM on February 18, 2005, as having been issued pursuant to and in compliance with specified law for the benefit of the desert tortoise, other species, and their habitat to increase the likelihood of their recovery; and ratifies the processes used by the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service and the BLM in reconfiguring the land covered by the patent. Interior may issue a corrective patent for 7,548 specified acres of land in Lincoln County.

(Sec. 3) The bill amends the Pam White Wilderness Act to adjust the boundary of the Mt. Moriah Wilderness to include specified lands, and the boundary of the High Schells Wilderness to include and exclude specified lands.

The bill amends the Nevada Wilderness Protection Act of 1989 to adjust the boundary of the Arc Dome Wilderness to exclude specified land.

(Sec. 4) The bill amends the Mesquite Lands Act of 1988 to require the proceeds of the sales of certain parcels of land by Interior to the city of Mesquite, Nevada, to be made available for use for the development and implementation of a conservation plan to benefit fish and wildlife species of the Virgin River in Clark County (rather than, as currently, for development of a multispecies habitat conservation plan).</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-479</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
