<bill session="115" type="s" number="1327" updated="2019-04-18T16:36:59Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Controlled Substances Act to clarify how controlled substance analogues are to be regulated, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SITSA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop the Importation and Trafficking of Synthetic Analogues Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop the Importation and Trafficking of Synthetic Analogues Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">SITSA Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2017-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2017-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2017-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2851"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="5531"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="6"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-08T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stop the Importation and Trafficking of Synthetic Analogues Act of 2017 or the SITSA Act

This bill amends the Controlled Substances Act to establish a new, sixth schedule of controlled substances&#8212;schedule A. A drug or substance in schedule A has a chemical structure that is similar to, and an effect on the body that is similar to or greater than, a controlled substance in schedule I, II, III, IV, or V.

The bill adds 13 synthetic fentanyl-related substances to schedule A. It also authorizes, and establishes procedures for, the Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA) to temporarily and permanently place a drug or substance in schedule A.

The bill establishes criminal penalties for an individual who imports, exports, manufactures, distributes, or possesses with intent to distribute a schedule A substance. However, it explicitly prohibits criminal and civil penalties solely for possession of a schedule A controlled substance.

The bill makes it unlawful to import, export, manufacture, distribute, dispense, or possess with intent to manufacture, distribute, or dispense, a schedule A substance that is not clearly labeled.

Finally, it establishes new, separate DEA registration requirements for manufacturers, distributors, and importers and exporters of schedule A substances.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
