<bill session="115" type="s" number="1552" updated="2019-05-17T18:16:46Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow individuals to designate that up to 10 percent of their income tax liability be used to reduce the national debt, and to require spending reductions equal to the amounts so designated.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Debt Buy-Down Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Debt Buy-Down Act</title>
    <title type="display">Debt Buy-Down Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000444"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2017-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3999" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Debt Buy-Down Act

 This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow individual taxpayers to designate up to 10% of their adjusted income tax liability for the reduction of the public debt.

The bill also establishes in the Treasury a Public Debt Reduction Trust Fund to hold tax revenues generated by this bill for the reduction of the public debt.

The bill amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to: (1) require spending to be reduced annually by an amount equivalent to the revenue generated by this bill, and (2) enforce the requirement for spending reductions using a sequestration, with exemptions for Social Security retirement benefits, veterans benefits, and net interest payments on the debt.

(Sequestration is a process of automatic, usually across-the-board spending reductions under which budgetary resources are permanently cancelled to enforce specific budget policy goals.)</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
