<bill session="114" type="sr" number="485" updated="2018-06-02T06:20:50Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-13">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution to encourage the Government of the Democratic Republic of the Congo to abide by constitutional provisions regarding the holding of presidential elections in 2016, with the aim of ensuring a peaceful and orderly democratic transition of power.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by senate">A resolution urging the Government of the Democratic Republic of the Congo to comply with constitutional limits on presidential terms and fulfill its constitutional mandate for a democratic transition of power in 2016.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution urging the Government of the Democratic Republic of the Congo to comply with constitutional limits on presidential terms and fulfill its constitutional mandate for a democratic transition of power in 2016.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000444"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2016-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2016-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2016-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2016-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2016-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Corker with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title and with an amended preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="574">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 574.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2016-09-13" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title and an amended preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5677-5678" label="considered"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5677-5678" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Democratic Republic of the Congo"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-13T13:47:23Z" status="Passed Senate amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the Senate on July 14, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Expresses concern with respect to the failure of the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) to take actions required to hold elections in November 2016 as required by its Constitution.

Recognizes that impunity and lack of effective rule of law undermine democracy and that the arrest and detention of civil society activists and the harassment of political opponents close political space and repress peaceful dissent.

Reaffirms support for democracy and good governance in sub-Saharan Africa.

Calls on the DRC government and all other parties to respect the Constitution of the DRC and ensure a free, open, peaceful, and democratic transition of power. Urges such government to demonstrate leadership and commitment to elections by accelerating concrete steps towards holding elections, including registering voters and protecting partisan political speech and activities.

Encourages such government and all other relevant parties to engage in a focused discussion to advance the electoral process and reach consensus on the way forward by establishing a detailed electoral calendar for all elections and enabling the candidate selection and campaign process.

Urges the President of the United States, in close coordination with regional and international partners, to:

 continuously verify that such necessary technical dialogue occurs and proceeds in a time and manner required to ensure the conduct of timely elections; use appropriate means to ensure the objectives of this resolution, which may include imposition of additional targeted sanctions on individuals or entities responsible for violence and human rights violations and undermining democratic processes in the DRC; and continue U.S. policy with respect to providing support for the organizing of free, fair, and peaceful national elections.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
