<bill session="113" type="s" number="2966" updated="2016-10-25T16:32:49Z">
  <state datetime="2014-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Critical Care Assessment and Improvement Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the understanding and coordination of critical care health services.</title>
    <title type="display">Critical Care Assessment and Improvement Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2014-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2014-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2651"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-11-20T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Critical Care Assessment and Improvement Act of 2014 - Requires studies on critical care health services by the Institute of Medicine and the Health Resources and Services Administration of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS).&#160;

Directs HHS to establish the Critical Care Coordinating Working Group within the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to: (1) advance research and research training in the critical care setting across NIH and HHS; (2) coordinate funding opportunities that involve multiple components of HHS; (3) catalyze the development of new funding opportunities; (4) inform investigators about funding opportunities; (5) represent NIH in government-wide efforts to improve the critical care system; (6) coordinate the collection and analysis of information on NIH research relating to critical care and identify gaps in this research; (7) report annually to the Director of NIH on NIH research efforts relating to critical care; and (8) make recommendations on how to strengthen partnerships within NIH and HHS and public and private entities to expand collaborative, cross-cutting research.

Requires HHS to carry out a demonstration project to improve the quality and efficiency of critical care in acute care hospitals.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
