<bill session="113" type="h" number="5039" updated="2016-10-25T16:14:52Z">
  <state datetime="2014-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To make technical amendments to Public Law 93-531, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To make technical amendments to Public Law 93-531, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000368"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-07-09T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Requires a border of any parcel of land that is transferred to or acquired by the Navajo Reservation to be within 18 miles of the trust lands of the Navajo Tribe, including the bands of the Tribe, as of January 2014.

Allows the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) lands anywhere within Arizona and New Mexico to be exchanged for lands within 18 miles of those trust lands.

Gives the Navajo Tribe the right to deselect not more than 757 acres of the land selected as of January 2014, whether or not such land has already been taken into trust by the Secretary of the Interior. Gives the Tribe the right to reselect land up to the amount it deselected.

Directs the Secretary to report on annual rents owed by the Navajo Tribe to the Hopi Tribe for each of the years 2001-2013.

Authorizes the Navajo Tribe to designate up to 150,000 acres within specified lands to be designated as Navajo Sovereignty Empowerment Zones. Makes inapplicable specified laws within such Zones.

Amends the Navajo-Hopi Land Dispute Settlement Act of 1996 to set forth the rights of Navajo heads of household or their successors to relinquish an Accommodation Agreement they have entered into with the Hopi Tribe regarding their residence on Hopi lands.

Reauthorizes and revises the Navajo Rehabilitation Trust Fund. Allows for its use for the development of Navajo Sovereignty Empowerment Zones.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
