<bill session="114" type="h" number="3921" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:26Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hedge Fund Sunshine Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to require certain reporting by hedge funds that are the beneficial owner of more than 1 percent of a class of security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Hedge Fund Sunshine Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2015-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-04T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Hedge Fund Sunshine Act of 2015

This bill amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to require that hedge funds send specified information to both the issuer of a security and each exchange where the security is rated within five (instead of 10) days of acquiring 1% (instead of 5%) of the beneficial ownership of an equity security, and also to file specified information required by the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC).

 For purposes of determining such beneficial ownership, a hedge fund shall include any equity security with respect to which it owns a derivative instrument that includes the opportunity to profit or share in any profit derived from an increase in the value of such equity security.

In addition, a hedge fund must file a quarterly report with the SEC if it: (1) has $100 million or more in assets under management, and (2) is the beneficial owner of more than 1% of a class of any security.

The SEC shall make all reports received under this Act publicly available on its website.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
