<bill session="114" type="s" number="3478" updated="2018-06-02T07:48:48Z">
  <state datetime="2016-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Combating European Anti-Semitism Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require continued and enhanced annual reporting to Congress in the Annual Report on International Religious Freedom on anti-Semitic incidents in Europe, the safety and security of European Jewish communities, and the efforts of the United States to partner with European governments, the European Union, and civil society groups, to combat anti-Semitism, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Combating European Anti-Semitism Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2016-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2016-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2016-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2016-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2016-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2016-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2016-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2016-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2016-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-11-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="6208"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-11-17T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Combating European Anti-Semitism Act of 2016

This bill expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) it is in the U.S. national interest to combat anti-Semitism at home and abroad; (2) there is a need to ensure the security of European Jewish communities, including synagogues, schools, and cemeteries; and (3) the United States should continue to emphasize the importance of combating anti-Semitism in multilateral bodies.

The International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 is amended to require the Department of State's Annual Report on International Religious Freedom to include, for each European country in which threats or attacks against Jewish persons, schools, and religious institutions are particularly significant, a description of:

 the security challenges and needs of European Jewish communities and European law enforcement agencies; U.S. efforts to partner with European law enforcement agencies and civil society groups to combat anti-Semitic incidents; educational programming and public awareness initiatives that impart values of pluralism and tolerance, showcase the positive contributions of Jews, and pay special attention to population segments that exhibit a high degree of anti-Semitic animus; and efforts by European governments to adopt and apply a working definition of anti-Semitism.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
