<bill session="114" type="h" number="4254" updated="2019-01-09T21:10:14Z">
  <state datetime="2015-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Freedom for Workers to Seek Opportunity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit employers from requiring grocery store employees to enter into covenants not to compete, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Freedom for Workers to Seek Opportunity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000381"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Workforce Protections" code="HSED10" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2873"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1504"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-12-15T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Freedom for Workers to Seek Opportunity Act

This bill: (1) prohibits employers from entering into not-to-compete covenants with any grocery store employees engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce, and (2) requires an employer of such employees to post a notice of this prohibition in a conspicuous place on the employer's premises.

No employers who own or operate at least one grocery store may, in conjunction with the purchase of one or more grocery stores owned or operated by another employer, include in any agreement between such employers any provision that restricts either employer from hiring a grocery store employee of the other employer.

An employer who acquires the operation of another employer and retains in employment a grocery store employee of the former employee at the same grocery store of the former employer shall continue to recognize, for all employment purposes, the seniority of that grocery store employee, and, to the extent practicable, make available to such employees any benefits made available by the former employer.

The Secretary of Labor shall: (1) enforce a complaint of a violation of this Act in the same manner as a complaint of a violation of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, and (2) impose a specified civil fine on any employer who violates this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
