<bill session="115" type="s" number="1012" updated="2019-04-18T16:35:37Z">
  <state datetime="2018-10-02">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-10-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">New Mexico Drought Preparedness Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">New Mexico Drought Preparedness Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">New Mexico Drought Preparedness Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">New Mexico Drought Preparedness Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">New Mexico Drought Preparedness Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">New Mexico Drought Preparedness Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for drought preparedness measures in the State of New Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000039"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2017-05-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-14">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 115-38.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-10-02" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-11-14">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 115-358.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-11-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="645">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 645.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water and Power" code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hydrology and hydrography"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-11-14T16:07:05Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">New Mexico Drought Preparedness Act of 2018

 This bill directs the Bureau of Reclamation to carry out a water acquisition program in specified basins in New Mexico, under which Reclamation shall: (1) make acquisitions of water by lease or purchase of water rights or contractual entitlements from willing lessors or sellers, consistent with the Rio Grande Compact and applicable state water rights law; and (2) take other actions to enhance stream flow to benefit fish and wildlife (including endangered species), water quality, and river ecosystem restoration and to enhance stewardship and conservation of working land, water, and watersheds.

Reclamation, in cooperation with the Middle Rio Grande Conservancy District, may provide funding and technical assistance for the installation of metering and measurement devices and the construction of check structures to: (1) ensure the conservation and efficient use of water by reducing actual consumptive use or by not increasing the use of water, and (2) improve the measurement and allocation of water.

The National Academy of Sciences shall carry out a study on water and reservoir management and operation issues in specified basins.

The bill authorizes financial assistance to be made available for eligible water projects to help western states and tribal governments address drought-related impacts to water supplies or any other immediate water-related crisis or conflict.

The Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 is amended to: (1) authorize the use of water management improvement grants to assist applicants in planning for or addressing the impacts of drought, (2) change to December 31, 2019, the reporting date on the implementation of recommended Rio Grande Pueblo irrigation infrastructure projects, and (3) reauthorize for FY2018-FY2026 the Rio Grande Pueblo irrigation infrastructure grant program.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-358</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
