<bill session="115" type="h" number="3042" updated="2019-04-18T16:11:51Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide greater whistleblower protections for Federal employees, increased awareness of Federal whistleblower protections, and increased accountability and required discipline for Federal supervisors who retaliate against whistleblowers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Dr. Chris Kirkpatrick Whistleblower Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Dr. Chris Kirkpatrick Whistleblower Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Dr. Chris Kirkpatrick Whistleblower Protection Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000614"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001301" joined="2017-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001077" joined="2017-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000579" joined="2017-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000576" joined="2017-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000292" joined="2017-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2017-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001193" joined="2017-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000244" joined="2017-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2017-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001199" joined="2017-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000066" joined="2017-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="585"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Employee performance"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Merit Systems Protection Board"/>
    <term name="Office of Special Counsel"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Dr. Chris Kirkpatrick Whistleblower Protection Act of 2017

This bill directs federal agencies (excluding any entity that is an element of the intelligence community) to give priority to an employee transfer request if the Merit Systems Protection Board (MSPB) grants a stay of a personnel action at the request of: (1) the Office of Special Counsel (OSC) if the OSC determines the personnel action was taken, or is to be taken, as a result of a prohibited personnel practice; or (2) the employee if such employee is in probationary status and seeks corrective action.

The bill: (1) prohibits any employee who has the authority to take, direct others to take, recommend, or approve&#160;of any&#160;personnel action to access the medical records of another employee or applicant for employment; and (2) authorizes disciplinary action against supervisors for retaliation against whistle-blowers.

Agencies must: (1) refer information about employee suicides to the OSC, (2) train supervisors on responding to complaints alleging whistle-blower protections violations, (3) provide information regarding whistle-blower protections to new employees during probationary periods, (4) inform employees of the role of the OSC and the MSPB with regard to whistle-blower protection, and (5) make information about such protections available on agency websites.

The Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) must: (1) submit a plan to Congress on efforts to prevent any unauthorized access to the medical records of VA employees; (2) conduct an outreach program to inform its employees of any mental health services, including telemedicine options; and (3) ensure protocols are in effect to address threats against VA employees providing health care.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
