<amendment session="114" chamber="s" number="755" updated="2018-06-04T02:15:42Z">
  <amends type="sc" number="11" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2015-03-25">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000770"/>
  <offered datetime="2015-03-25"/>
  <description>To establish a deficit-neutral reserve fund relating to keeping the Federal Water Pollution Control Act focused on protection of water quality, to establish bright lines for Federal jurisdiction, and to create clear and unambiguous exemptions for features that the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency or the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, claim they are not seeking to regulate.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2015-03-25" how="roll" result="pass" roll="87">
      <text>Amendment SA 755 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 99 - 0. Record Vote Number: 87.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Amendment SA 755 proposed by Senator Stabenow. (consideration: CR S1845-1846, S1868-1869; text: CR S1845) To establish a deficit-neutral reserve fund relating to keeping the Federal Water Pollution Control Act focused on protection of water quality, to establish bright lines for Federal jurisdiction, and to create clear and unambiguous exemptions for features that the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency or the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, claim they are not seeking to regulate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25"/>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 755 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 99 - 0. Record Vote Number: 87.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 755 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 99 - 0. Record Vote Number: 87.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 755 proposed by Senator Stabenow.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1845-1846, S1868-1869" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1845" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
