<amendment session="114" chamber="s" number="2907" updated="2018-06-04T17:54:24Z">
  <amends type="h" number="3762" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2015-12-03">offered</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001267"/>
  <offered datetime="2015-12-03"/>
  <description>To provide additional amounts to the Department of Veterans Affairs to increase the access of veterans to care and improve the physical infrastructure of the Department of Veterans Affairs and to impose a fair share tax on high-income taxpayers.</description>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-03">
      <text>Amendment SA 2907 ruled out of order by the chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-03">
      <text>Motion to waive all applicable budgetary discipline with respect to amendment SA 2907 rejected in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 47 - 52. Record Vote Number: 322.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8349-8350" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-03">
      <text>Point of order that the amendment violates section 302(f) of the CBA raised in Senate with respect to amendment SA 2907.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-03">
      <text>Amendment SA 2907 proposed by Senator Bennet to Amendment SA 2874. (consideration: CR S8348-8350; text: CR S8348-8349) To provide additional amounts to the Department of Veterans Affairs to increase the access of veterans to care and improve the physical infrastructure of the Department of Veterans Affairs and to impose a fair share tax on high-income taxpayers.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-03"/>
    <action datetime="2015-12-03">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 2907 proposed by Senator Bennet to Amendment SA 2874.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8348-8350" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S8348-8349" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-03">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Motion to waive all applicable budgetary discipline with respect to amendment SA 2907 rejected in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 47 - 52. Record Vote Number: 322.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8349-8350" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-03">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
