<bill session="114" type="h" number="2098" updated="2018-11-21T20:16:58Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Common Sense in Species Protection Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to require the Secretary of the Interior to publish and make available for public comment a draft economic analysis at the time a proposed rule to designate critical habitat is published.</title>
    <title type="display">Common Sense in Species Protection Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001072" joined="2015-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2015-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000821" joined="2015-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000809" joined="2015-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="112"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Common Sense in Species Protection Act of 2015

This bill amends the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to require the Department of the Interior or the Department of Commerce to exclude an area from designation as a critical habitat to conserve an endangered or threatened species if the benefits of exclusion outweigh the benefits of including the area, unless the failure to designate the area as critical habitat will result in the extinction of the species.

At the time a proposed rule to designate a critical habitat is published, the appropriate department must make available for public comment a draft analysis that: (1) examines the incremental and cumulative economic effects of all actions to protect the species and its habitat upon each state and locality that is affected by the proposed designation; (2) includes consideration of economic effects on possible uses of land and property values, employment, revenues available for state and local governments, and the provision of water, power, or other public services; and (3) assesses those effects on a quantitative and qualitative basis.

The bill applies to any designation of critical habitat on or after August 28, 2013.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
