<amendment session="115" chamber="h" number="611" updated="2019-06-30T15:28:07Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2018-05-17T18:03:55-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001177"/>
  <offered datetime="2018-05-17"/>
  <description>Amendment sought to amend SNAP work requirements to repeal geographic area waivers to allow States to exempt only 5% of SNAP recipients, set the same hour per week work requirement for married parents as for single parents, exempt parents of children under 3 instead of children under 6, require participants in training programs to go through E Verify.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 8 printed in House Report 115-679 to amend SNAP work requirements to repeal geographic area waivers to allow states to exempt only 5% of SNAP recipients, set the same hour per week work requirement for married parents as for single parents, exempt parents of children under 3 instead of children under 6, require participants in training programs to go through E Verify.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2018-05-17T18:03:55-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="195">
      <text>On agreeing to the McClintock amendment (A026) Failed by recorded vote: 83 - 330 (Roll no. 195).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-05-17T16:19:14-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A026) offered by Mr. McClintock.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4186-4188, H4197-4198" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4186" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-17"/>
    <action datetime="2018-05-17T16:19:14-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A026) offered by Mr. McClintock.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4186-4188, H4197-4198" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4186" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-17T18:03:55-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-17T18:03:55-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-17T18:03:55-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the McClintock amendment (A026) Failed by recorded vote: 83 - 330 (Roll no. 195).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-17">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
