<bill session="115" type="s" number="2655" updated="2019-04-18T16:42:35Z">
  <state datetime="2018-04-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-04-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-04-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Power Act to promote hydropower development at existing nonpowered dams, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Hydropower Development and Jobs Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Hydropower Development and Jobs Act</title>
    <title type="display">Promoting Hydropower Development and Jobs Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000449"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2018-04-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-04-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2872"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="4696"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-04-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Promoting Hydropower Development and Jobs Act

This bill amends the Federal Power Act to authorize the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)to establish an expedited process for issuing and amending licenses and preliminary permits for qualifying hydropower facilities that will be associated with existing nonpowered dams.

In establishing the expedited process, FERC shall convene an interagency task force with federal and state agencies and Indian tribes to coordinate the regulatory process associated with the authorizations required to construct and operate a qualifying facility.

FERC must assess the safety of existing nonfederal dams and other nonfederal structures related to a qualifying facility before licensing the facility.

FERC must coordinate with the Department of the Army, the Department of the Interior, and the Department of Agriculture to jointly develop a list of existing nonpowered federal dams that have the greatest potential for nonfederal hydropower development.

Licensees of a qualifying facility are not required to pay an annual charge for administrative expenses until construction commences.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
