<bill session="114" type="s" number="1622" updated="2018-06-02T06:56:19Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FDA Device Accountability Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">FDA Device Accountability Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to devices.</title>
    <title type="display">FDA Device Accountability Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001135"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000360" joined="2016-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2016-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2015-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2015-10-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-02-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-04-18">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Alexander with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="426">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 426.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-18T18:20:44Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">FDA Device Accountability Act of 2016

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to eliminate the requirement for the Institutional Review Board supervising the clinical testing of an investigational or humanitarian medical device to be local.

(Sec. 3) The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) must revise the guidance entitled &#8220;Recommendations for Clinical Laboratory Improvement Amendments of 1988 (CLIA) Waiver Applications for Manufacturers of In Vitro Diagnostic Devices.&#8221;

(Sec. 4) The FDA must ensure that employees who review premarket submissions of medical devices receive training on least burdensome means requirements. (Currently, the FDA is required to consider the least burdensome appropriate means for a sponsor to demonstrate the effectiveness of a medical device or demonstrate a device&#8217;s substantial equivalence to an approved medical device.) The FDA must periodically assess the implementation of those requirements. The ombudsman for any applicable unit of the FDA must audit and report on the training.

The FDA must consider the least burdensome appropriate means necessary to demonstrate medical device safety and effectiveness when requesting additional information from a device sponsor to support a premarket approval application, including the role of postmarket information in such a demonstration.

The FDA&#8217;s documented rationale for a significant decision regarding a medical device must include a statement regarding how the least burdensome requirements were considered and applied.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
