<bill session="114" type="s" number="1345" updated="2018-06-02T06:53:37Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Access to Quality Diabetes Education Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to improve access to diabetes self-management training by authorizing certified diabetes educators to provide diabetes self-management training services, including as part of telehealth services, under part B of the Medicare program.</title>
    <title type="display">Access to Quality Diabetes Education Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2015-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000174" joined="2016-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000607" joined="2015-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2015-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2015-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2015-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2015-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="1726"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Access to Quality Diabetes Education Act of 2015 

Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to recognize state-licensed or -registered certified diabetes educators or state-licensed or -registered health care professionals who specialize in teaching individuals with diabetes to develop the necessary skills and knowledge to manage the individual's diabetic condition and are certified as a diabetes educator by a recognized certifying body.

Directs the Government Accountability Office to study the barriers that exist for Medicare beneficiaries with diabetes in accessing diabetes self-management training services under the Medicare program.

Requires the Director of the Agency for Health Care Research and Quality of the Department of Health and Human Services to develop a series of recommendations on effective outreach methods to educate primary care physicians and other health care providers as well as the public about the benefits of diabetes self-management training.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
