<bill session="113" type="s" number="1925" updated="2016-10-25T16:28:27Z">
  <state datetime="2014-04-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Driver Privacy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Driver Privacy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to limit the retrieval of data from vehicle event data recorders.</title>
    <title type="display">Driver Privacy Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2014-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001265" joined="2014-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2014-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2014-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2014-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000286" joined="2014-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2014-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2014-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2014-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2014-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2014-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2014-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000291" joined="2014-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2014-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2014-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2014-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2014-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2014-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2014-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000590" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2014-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2014-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2014-01-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S327-328, S329"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-04-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-09-15">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 113-255.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-09-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="563">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 563.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-09-15T15:20:39Z" status="Reported to Senate amended">Driver Privacy Act - Declares that any data retained by a motor vehicle's event data recorder (as defined in Department of Transportation [DOT] regulations) is the property of the owner or lessee of the motor vehicle in which the recorder is installed, regardless of when the vehicle was manufactured.

Prohibits a person, other than the owner or lessee of the motor vehicle, from accessing data recorded or transmitted by such a recorder unless: (1) a court or other judicial or administrative authority authorizes the retrieval of such data subject to admissibility of evidence standards; (2) an owner or lessee provides written or electronic consent to such retrieval for any purpose, including vehicle diagnosis, service, or repair; (3) the data is retrieved pursuant to certain authorized investigations or inspections of the National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) or DOT; (4) the data is retrieved to determine the appropriate emergency medical response to a motor vehicle crash; or (5) the data is retrieved for traffic safety research.

Prohibits, when data is retrieved in connection with traffic safety research or an NTSB or DOT investigation or inspection, the disclosure of: (1) personally identifiable information of the vehicle owner or lessee, and (2) the vehicle identification number (VIN). Provides an exemption from such prohibition to allow disclosure of VINs to certifying manufacturers.

Directs the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA), after completing a study and submitting a report to Congress, to promulgate regulations concerning the amount of time event data recorders installed in passenger motor vehicles should capture and record vehicle-related data in conjunction with an event in order to provide sufficient information to investigate the cause of crashes.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 113-255</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
