<bill session="114" type="s" number="921" updated="2018-06-02T06:44:57Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-18">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Delaware River Basin Conservation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Delaware River Basin Conservation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish a nonregulatory program to build on and help coordinate funding for restoration and protection efforts of the 4-State Delaware River Basin region, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Delaware River Basin Conservation Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2015-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-05-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Inhofe without amendment. With written report No. 114-294.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="548">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 548.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="1772"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2848"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="612"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Delaware"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-07T13:26:13Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Delaware River Basin Conservation Act of 2015

(Sec. 4) This bill requires the United States Fish and Wildlife Service (USFWS) to establish a nonregulatory Delaware River Basin restoration program, under which it shall: (1) draw on management plans for the basin or portions of the basin and work in consultation with applicable management entities, including representatives of the Partnership for the Delaware Estuary, the Delaware River Basin Commission, the federal government, other state and local governments, and regional and nonprofit organizations, to identify, prioritize, and implement restoration and protection activities within the basin; (2) adopt a basin-wide strategy that supports the implementation of a shared set of science-based restoration and protection activities, targets cost-effective projects with measurable results, and maximizes conservation outcomes with no net gain of federal full-time equivalent employees; and (3) establish the voluntary grant and technical assistance programs in accordance with this bill.

"Basin" is defined as the four-state Delaware Basin region, including all of Delaware Bay and portions of Delaware, New Jersey, New York, and Pennsylvania located in the Delaware River watershed.

(Sec. 5) The&#160;USFWS shall: (1) establish the Delaware River Basin restoration grant program to provide competitive matching grants to carry out restoration and protection activities within the basin, and (2) develop criteria to ensure that funded activities accomplish specified purposes and advance the implementation of priority actions or needs identified in the strategy adopted under this bill.

The&#160;USFWS may contract with the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation or another organization that offers grant management services.

(Sec. 6) The USFWS shall submit to Congress annually a report on the implementation of this bill, including a description of each project that has received funding.

(Sec. 7) Appropriations are authorized to carry out this bill for FY2016-FY2021. The USFWS shall use at least 75% of any amount made available for each fiscal year to carry out the grant program and to provide or provide for technical assistance under such program.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-294</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
