<bill session="115" type="s" number="2832" updated="2019-04-18T16:43:05Z">
  <state datetime="2018-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the collection of data by officers enforcing United States laws and regulations, including at border security stops within United States borders, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DATA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DATA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Homeland Security Accountability and Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Homeland Security Accountability and Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="display">DATA Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000555"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2018-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2018-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2018-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-05-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="5991"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-05-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Department of Homeland Security Accountability and Transparency Act or the DATA Act

This bill requires law enforcement officials (i.e., officers or agents of U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE), or certain state or local officials carrying out the functions of an immigration officer) who initiate a patrol stop or who detain any individual beyond a brief and limited inquiry, such as a primary inspection at a checkpoint, to record certain data, including (1) the date, time, location, and duration of the contact; (2) the basis for the contact and if it was race-related; (3) a description of any items seized during any search; (4) whether a body-worn camera recorded the stop or detention; and (5) whether force was used by the law enforcement official.

The bill also requires the CBP to collect data on the number of permanent and temporary checkpoints used by its officers, the location and a description of each checkpoint, and the dates on which a temporary checkpoint was used. The Department of Homeland Security must compile the data collected by ICE and the CBP and consider it in making policy and program decisions.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
