<bill session="114" type="h" number="1633" updated="2019-04-11T15:39:45Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-23T16:34:59-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-06-23T16:34:59-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DHS Paid Administrative Leave Accountability Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">DHS Paid Administrative Leave Accountability Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">DHS Paid Administrative Leave Accountability Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for certain improvements relating to the tracking and reporting of employees of the Department of Homeland Security placed on administrative leave, or any other type of paid non-duty status without charge to leave, for personnel matters, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">DHS Paid Administrative Leave Accountability Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000583"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001103" joined="2015-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001036" joined="2015-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001073" joined="2015-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000386" joined="2015-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2015-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001197" joined="2015-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001150" joined="2015-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000605" joined="2015-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000601" joined="2015-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001189" joined="2015-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000819" joined="2015-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight and Management Efficiency.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-13">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-13">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-05-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-06-17">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 114-163.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-06-17" calendar="Union" number="119">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 119.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-06-23T16:22:13-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Loudermilk moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-23T16:22:27-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4566-4569" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-23T16:22:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1633.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2015-06-23T16:34:59-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4566-4567" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-06-23T16:35:04-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Oversight, Management, and Accountability" code="HSHM09" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-23T14:04:45Z" status="Passed House amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on June 17, 2015. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

DHS Paid Administrative Leave Accountability Act of 2015

(Sec. 2) Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the head of each component of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), on a quarterly basis, to submit to the Chief Human Capital Officer of DHS (the Chief): (1) the number of employees who had been on administrative leave, or any other type of paid non-duty status without charge to leave, for personnel matters for six consecutive months or longer; (2) the total cost to the component associated with such leave and paid non-duty status for the quarter; and (3) the average duration that employees are placed on administrative leave, or any other type of paid non-duty status without charge to leave, for personnel matters for a period of six consecutive months or longer.

Requires the Chief to: (1) maintain records of the number of such employees and the associated costs; and (2) determine appropriate actions to be taken by DHS to resolve any personnel matter objectively, appropriately, and expeditiously or to reduce the use of such leave and paid non-duty status in addressing any personnel matter.

Encourages DHS to leverage systems and operations in use on the date of this Act's enactment to implement this Act's requirements.

(Sec. 3) Directs the Chief to develop and implement a department-wide policy in accordance with existing federal guidance specifically related to the use of such leave or paid non-duty status for personnel matters.

Requires such policy to: (1) include the responsibilities of the DHS components for reporting information relating to such administrative leave and such paid non-duty status to the Chief, and (2) provide guidance on expediting the resolution of a personnel matter for which an employee has been on administrative leave or any other type of paid non-duty status without charge to leave for a period of six consecutive months or longer in an objective and appropriate manner.

(Sec. 4) Directs the Chief to submit a report after each calendar quarter of 2016-2018 on the number of DHS employees on such leave or paid non-duty status for personnel matters for six consecutive months or longer.

Requires each such report to include: (1) the costs to DHS associated with the placement of such employees on administrative leave or such paid non-duty status (including salary and benefits) for the period covered by the report; and (2) a description of any actions taken by DHS to resolve any personnel matter for which an employee has been placed on administrative leave or paid non-duty status without charge to leave.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-163</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
