<bill session="114" type="s" number="540" updated="2018-08-16T23:01:09Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">School Food Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to require the Secretary of Agriculture to make loan guarantees and grants to finance certain improvements to school lunch facilities, to train school food service personnel, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">School Food Modernization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2016-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2015-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2015-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001069" joined="2015-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2015-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2015-10-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1077" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3316"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-24T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">School Food Modernization Act

Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to direct the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to issue loan guarantees to local educational agencies (LEAs) or school food authorities administering or operating a school lunch program, tribal organizations, or consortia of such entities to finance the construction, remodeling, or expansion of infrastructure or the purchase of durable equipment that will facilitate their provision of healthy meals through the school lunch program.

 Requires USDA to give a preference to applicants that demonstrate a substantial or disproportionate need for food service infrastructure or durable equipment. Prohibits a loan guarantee from covering more than 80% of a loan's principal.

Requires USDA to establish fees for the loan guarantee program that: (1) are sufficient to cover the federal government's administrative costs in operating the program, and (2) may be based on the risk premium associated with the particular loan or loan guarantee.

Directs USDA to award competitive matching grants to assist LEAs or school food authorities administering or operating a school lunch program, tribal organizations, or consortia of such entities in purchasing the durable equipment and infrastructure they need to serve healthier meals and improve food safety.

Requires USDA to give grant priority to applicants that: (1) have identified and are reasonably expected to meet an unmet local or community need, and (2) are located in states that have enacted funding measures to assist them with such purchases.

Prohibits such a grant from covering more than 80% of the total cost of the durable equipment and infrastructure.

Directs USDA to award competitive matching grants to experienced third-party training institutions to provide school food service personnel with the training and technical assistance they need to: (1) meet school lunch program nutrition standards, and (2) improve the efficacy and efficiency of the school lunch and breakfast programs.

Prohibits such a grant from covering more than 80% of the total cost of the training and technical assistance.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
