<bill session="115" type="h" number="4818" updated="2019-04-18T16:19:41Z">
  <state datetime="2018-01-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-01-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-01-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the use of Federal funds made available in the form of an earmark, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pulled Pork Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pulled Pork Act</title>
    <title type="display">Pulled Pork Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2018-01-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-01-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-01-17T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Pulled Pork Act 

This bill prohibits federal agencies from using funds made available through an earmark after the enactment of this bill. It also rescinds the earmarked funds effective on the date the funds are made available.

An "earmark" is a provision or report language included primarily at the request of a Member of Congress providing, authorizing, or recommending a specific amount of discretionary budget authority, credit authority, or other spending authority for a contract, loan, loan guarantee, grant, loan authority, or other expenditure with or to an entity, or targeted to a specific state, locality or congressional district, other than through a statutory or administrative formula-driven or competitive award process.

Each agency must submit to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) an annual report identifying each earmark that is ineligible for funding under this bill. OMB must then submit to Congress and publish on its website an annual report detailing the identified earmarks and the annual savings resulting from this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
