<bill session="115" type="s" number="2787" updated="2019-04-18T16:42:57Z">
  <state datetime="2018-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to clarify and expand food donation under the Bill Emerson Good Samaritan Food Donation Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Food Donation Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Food Donation Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Food Donation Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2018-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="952"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-04-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Food Donation Act of 2018

This bill amends the Bill Emerson Good Samaritan Food Donation Act to expand the liability protections for the donation of food.

The bill expands the liability protections to include donations of an apparently fit grocery product or apparently wholesome food:

 that is mislabeled in a manner that is not related to safety and safety-related labeling standards and regulations; meets safety and safety-related labeling standards and regulations but is past the date label; for which the recipient is charged a "good Samaritan reduced" price that is no greater than the cost of handling, administering, and distributing the product; or that is donated directly to a needy individual by a retail grocer, wholesaler, agricultural producer, restaurant, caterer, school food authority, or institution of higher education. The Department of Agriculture must: (1) issue regulations with respect to the safety and safety-related labeling standards of apparently wholesome food and an apparently fit grocery product under the Bill Emerson Good Samaritan Food Donation Act, (2) promote awareness of food donation under the Act, and (3) issue guidance with respect to the amendments made by this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
