<bill session="114" type="s" number="1162" updated="2018-06-02T06:46:31Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Law Enforcement Self-Defense and Protection Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure Federal law enforcement officers remain able to ensure their own safety, and the safety of their families, during a covered furlough.</title>
    <title type="display">Federal Law Enforcement Self-Defense and Protection Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000461"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2015-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2137"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Federal Law Enforcement Self-Defense and Protection Act of 2015

Grants covered federal law enforcement officers the same rights to carry a government-issued firearm during a covered furlough as they had before such furlough was in effect.

Defines: (1) "covered federal law enforcement officer" to mean any agency employee who has the authority to make arrests or apprehensions for or prosecute violations of federal law and who, on the day before the applicable covered furlough begins, is authorized by the agency to carry a firearm in the course of official duties; and (2) "covered furlough" to mean a planned event by an agency during which employees are involuntarily furloughed due to downsizing, reduced funding, lack of work, or any budget situation other than a lapse in appropriations, and an event during which agency employees are involuntarily furloughed due to a lapse in appropriations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
