<bill session="114" type="h" number="4963" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:48Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Elder Abuse Victims Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To better protect, serve, and advance the rights of victims of elder abuse and exploitation by establishing a program to encourage States and other qualified entities to create jobs designed to hold offenders accountable, enhance the capacity of the justice system to investigate, pursue, and prosecute elder abuse cases, identify existing resources to leverage to the extent possible, and assure data collection, research, and evaluation to promote the efficacy and efficiency of the activities described in this Act.</title>
    <title type="display">Elder Abuse Victims Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000210"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2016-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000623" joined="2016-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2016-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2016-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2016-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2016-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1663"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Elder Abuse Victims Act of 2016

This bill establishes within the Department of Justice (DOJ) an Office of Elder Justice to provide information, training, and technical assistance for state and local governments to investigate, prosecute, prevent, and mitigate the impact of elder abuse, exploitation, and neglect. The office must be headed by a director who is appointed by the President and confirmed by the Senate.

It authorizes the Office of Elder Justice to award grants to states to develop, establish, and operate programs to improve the response to, investigation of, and prosecution of elder abuse cases. An eligible state must have a compensation program for crime victims and a multidisciplinary task force on elder justice.

DOJ must identify, collect, and publish data related to the incidence of elder abuse. It must also develop recommendations for collecting additional data related to elder abuse.

Finally, the bill amends the Social Security Act to include the director of the Office of Elder Justice as the alternate for the Attorney General on the Elder Justice Coordinating Council.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
