<amendment session="115" chamber="s" number="1955" updated="2019-06-13T18:45:45Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2579" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2018-02-13">offered</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001088"/>
  <offered datetime="2018-02-13"/>
  <description>To provide relief from removal and adjustment of status of certain individuals who are long-term United States residents and who entered the United States before reaching the age of 18, improve border security, foster United States engagement in Central America, and for other purposes.</description>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-02-15">
      <text>Cloture on amendment SA 1955 not invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 52 - 47. Record Vote Number: 33.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1146"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-15">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1131, S1146"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-14">
      <text>Cloture motion on amendment SA 1955 presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S965"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-14">
      <text>Amendment SA 1955 proposed by Senator Durbin for Senator Coons to Amendment SA 1958. (consideration: CR S931-932, S965) To provide relief from removal and adjustment of status of certain individuals who are long-term United States residents and who entered the United States before reaching the age of 18, improve border security, foster United States engagement in Central America, and for other purposes.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-13"/>
    <action datetime="2018-02-15">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Cloture on amendment SA 1955 not invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 52 - 47. Record Vote Number: 33.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1146"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-14">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 1955 proposed by Senator Durbin for Senator Coons to Amendment SA 1958.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S931-932, S965" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-13">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
