<bill session="115" type="s" number="2318" updated="2019-04-18T16:41:06Z">
  <state datetime="2018-01-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-01-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-01-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the payment of user fees by qualified professional asset managers seeking an individual exemption from certain requirements.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pension Stability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pension Stability Act</title>
    <title type="display">Pension Stability Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2018-01-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-01-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-01-17T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Pension Stability Act 

This bill requires the Department of Labor to establish user fees for qualified professional asset managers (QPAMs) who have been convicted of a crime and apply for an individual exemption (known as a QPAM waiver) to the prohibited transaction rules under the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA). The fees:

 apply to large regulated banks, savings and loan associations, insurance companies, and federally registered investment advisors who are QPAMs; must be at least $1 million per application for an individual exemption; and increase based on the severity of the crime and the number of prior applications for individual exemptions. Labor must transfer the amounts collected from the user fees to the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation to assist in guaranteeing benefits under pension plans.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
