<amendment session="114" chamber="h" number="58" updated="2019-01-09T21:07:54Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2015-07-08T17:55:25-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001072"/>
  <offered datetime="2015-02-26"/>
  <description>Amendment sought to advance assessments of student achievement and instructional practices, effective teacher preparation and continuing professional development, education administration, and international comparisons. Amendment also sought to support development of a national research strategy to ensure that students, particularly at risk students, have effective teachers and are being prepared for the future.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment No. 35 printed in part B of House Report 114-29 to advance assessments of student achievement and instructional practices, effective teacher preparation and continuing professional development, education administration, and international comparisons. The amendment supports development of a national research strategy to ensure that students, particularly at risk students, have effective teachers and are being prepared for the future.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2015-07-08T17:55:25-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="414">
      <text>On agreeing to the Carson (IN) amendment (A035) Failed by recorded vote: 186 - 245 (Roll no. 414).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4927-4928" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-02-26T21:43:44-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A035) offered by Mr. Carson (IN).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1290-1291" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1290" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-26"/>
    <action datetime="2015-07-08T17:55:25-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-08T17:55:25-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-08T17:55:25-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Carson (IN) amendment (A035) Failed by recorded vote: 186 - 245 (Roll no. 414).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4927-4928" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-26T21:43:44-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A035) offered by Mr. Carson (IN).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1290-1291" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1290" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-26">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
