<bill session="114" type="h" number="617" updated="2018-11-21T21:22:58Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clinical Trial Cancer Mission 2020 Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to enhance the clinical trial registry data bank reporting requirements and enforcement measures.</title>
    <title type="display">Clinical Trial Cancer Mission 2020 Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000585"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000911" joined="2015-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000480" joined="2015-01-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-28T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Clinical Trial Cancer Mission 2020 Act

Amends the Public Health Service Act to revise clinical trial registry data bank provisions to specify that a device or drug clinical trial must be included in the clinical trial registry data bank regardless of whether it results in a positive or negative outcome.

Requires the responsible party of any clinical trials funded in whole or in part by the Department of Defense (DOD) to certify in all required grant or progress forms that the required submissions to the clinical trial registry data bank have been made. Requires DOD to verify that the clinical trial information has been submitted before releasing any remaining grant funds or funding future grants.

Makes a clinical trial grantee of the Department of Health and Human Services or DOD who fails to submit the required information to the data bank ineligible for the remaining grant funds or future funds. Makes the grantee liable for repayment of grant amounts already provided.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
