<bill session="114" type="s" number="469" updated="2018-06-02T06:33:27Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Women Veterans and Families Health Services Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the reproductive assistance provided by the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs to severely wounded, ill, or injured members of the Armed Forces, veterans, and their spouses or partners, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Women Veterans and Families Health Services Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001111"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2015-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2015-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2015-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2016-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2015-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2015-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2015-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2016-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2015-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2015-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2015-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S944-945" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-24">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1496"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1948"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="3365"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-11T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Women Veterans and Families Health Services Act of 2015

 Directs the Department of Defense (DOD) to furnish fertility treatment and counseling, including through the use of assisted reproductive technology, to a spouse, partner, or gestational surrogate of a severely wounded, ill, or injured member of the Armed Forces who has an infertility condition incurred or aggravated while serving on active duty in the Armed Forces.

 Requires provision of fertility treatment and counseling to a spouse, partner, or gestational surrogate of a member of the Armed Forces without regard to the member's sex or marital status.

 States that, if a member of the Armed Forces is unable to provide gametes for fertility treatment purposes, the Secretary shall, at the member's election, allow the member to be treated with donated gametes and pay or reimburse the reasonable costs of procuring donor gametes.

 Directs DOD to:

 establish procedures for gamete retrieval from a member of the Armed Forces in cases in which the fertility of such member is potentially jeopardized as a result of an injury or illness incurred or aggravated while serving on active duty in the Armed Forces; and give members of the Armed Forces on active duty the opportunity to cryopreserve and store their gametes prior to deployment to a combat zone at no cost to the member. Directs DOD and the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to share best practices and facilitate fertility treatment and counseling referrals to eligible individuals.

Includes fertility counseling and treatment within authorized VA medical services.

Authorizes the VA to pay the adoption expenses (for up to three adoptions) for a severely wounded, ill, or injured veteran who has an infertility condition incurred or aggravated in the line of duty and who is enrolled in the VA health care system.

Directs the VA to report annually to Congress on the counseling and treatment provided under this Act; and (2) prescribe regulations on the furnishing of such counseling, treatment, and adoption assistance.

Directs the VA to facilitate research conducted collaboratively by DOD and the Department of Health and Human Services in order to improve the VA's ability to meet the long-term reproductive health care needs of veterans who have a service-connected genitourinary disability or a condition that was incurred or aggravated in the line of duty that affects the veterans' reproductive ability.

Requires the VA to enhance the capabilities of the VA women veterans contact center to: (1) respond to requests for assistance with accessing VA health care and benefits, and (2) refer such veterans to federal or community resources to obtain assistance not furnished by the VA.

Amends the Caregivers and Veterans Omnibus Health Services Act of 2010 regarding a pilot program of group retreat reintegration and readjustment counseling for women veterans recently separated from service to: (1) increase the number of counseling locations, and (2) extend the program.

 Establishes VA programs to provide assistance to qualified veterans to obtain child care so that such veterans can receive: (1) regular mental health care services, intensive mental health care services, or other intensive health care services; and (2) readjustment counseling and related mental health services.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
