<bill session="115" type="h" number="5479" updated="2019-04-18T16:21:48Z">
  <state datetime="2018-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Commissioner of the Internal Revenue Service to establish a special unit within the office of Stakeholder Partnership, Education and Communication to provide members of the uniformed services with tax assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Taxpayer Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Taxpayer Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="display">Military Taxpayer Assistance Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000799"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000188" joined="2018-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-04-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-04-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Military Taxpayer Assistance Act 

This bill requires the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) to establish a special unit within the IRS office of Stakeholder Partnership, Education and Communication to be responsible for outreach, education, and assistance concerning the tax issues applicable to members of the uniformed services and organizations that provide tax assistance to them.

 The IRS must: (1) staff the new unit with veterans, to the extent possible; and (2) ensure that ample funding is allocated to the unit to provide face-to-face training for the military volunteers providing income tax assistance in overseas locations.

The IRS must also: (1) establish and maintain a toll-free telephone number to answer tax questions and resolve tax account and compliance issues for members of the uniformed services and their families, and (2) ensure that information relating to military taxpayers is current on the IRS website.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
