<bill session="114" type="s" number="3442" updated="2018-06-02T07:48:39Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Terrorism Victims Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Terrorism Risk Insurance Act of 2002 to provide for the release of certain blocked assets, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Terrorism Victims Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Terrorism Victims Protection Act 

This bill amends the Terrorism Risk Insurance Act of 2002 to allow a person's judgment against a terrorist party or a state sponsor of terrorism to be satisfied with: (1) assets blocked by the U.S. government that pass through the U.S. financial system as a transfer of funds between non-state owned, non-U.S. financial institutions located outside the United States or as a mid-stream electronic fund transfer in possession of an intermediary bank; (2) assets located outside the United States that, if located in the United States, would be subject to seizure or freezing under the Trading with the Enemy Act or the International Emergency Economic Powers Act, if a U.S. court has jurisdiction over the person in possession; or (3) attempted transfers for the benefit of a terrorist party to accounts located outside the United States.

 The bill protects the interests of non-terrorist third parties in the blocked assets, but these third-party protections do not apply to custodial interests of a foreign securities intermediary holding blocked assets outside the United States for the government of Iran.

The bill nullifies attempted transfers outside the United States of assets of a state sponsor of terrorism liable for personal injury or death, unless the person who held the asset establishes that the transfer was not a willful violation of a court order or an enforcement process.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
