<bill session="114" type="h" number="3045" updated="2019-02-08T20:13:09Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">California Water Recycling and Drought Relief Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize certain recycled water projects, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">California Water Recycling and Drought Relief Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001166"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000623" joined="2015-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000030" joined="2015-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2015-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2015-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2015-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2015-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001175" joined="2015-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001193" joined="2015-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2015-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-08-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water, Oceans, and Wildlife" code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5159"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">California Water Recycling and Drought Relief Act

This bill amends the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Department of the Interior to participate in the design, planning, and construction of recycled water system facilities in California in cooperation with:

 the cities of Benicia, Brentwood, Ceres, Fresno, Hayward, Modesto, Mountain View, Palo Alto, Pleasanton, Redwood City, Sunnyvale, and Turlock; the Dublin San Ramon Services District; the Central Contra Costa Sanitary District; the Delta Diablo; the Ironhouse Sanitary District; the Monterey Regional Water Pollution Control Agency; the Del Puerto Water District; Stanislaus County; the Santa Clara Valley Water District; the San Jose Water Company; the West Bay Sanitary District; and the town of Yountville. The federal share of each project is limited to 25%. Interior must enter into individual agreements to fund such projects and include in such agreements a provision for the reimbursement of design, planning, and construction costs, but may not provide funds for project operation and maintenance.

The bill increases the authorization of appropriations for the Antioch, California, recycled water system facilities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
