<bill session="114" type="s" number="3313" updated="2018-06-02T07:48:01Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Burma Strategy Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize assistance to Burma and to support a principled engagement strategy for a peaceful, prosperous, and democratic Burma that respects the human rights of all its people, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Burma Strategy Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2016-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2016-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2016-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Burma Strategy Act of 2016

This bill authorizes FY2017 appropriations for assistance to Burma to: (1) support civil society organizations and strengthen anti-corruption efforts, (2) implement a specified democracy and human rights strategy, (3) support refugee-assistance organizations operating in Thailand, (4) promote ethnic reconciliation, and (5) reduce the military's position in the economy.

Funds may not be provided to: (1) the military of Burma or any individual or organization credibly alleged to have committed gross violations of human rights, or (2) any individual or organization that advocates violence against ethnic or religious groups and individuals in Burma. The bill provides for a U.S. national security waiver.

The Department of the Treasury shall instruct the U.S. executive director of each international financial institution to use U.S. influence to support only those projects in Burma that meet specified accountability, social and cultural, environmental and natural resource, and indigenous peoples protections. 

Foreign military sales funds are made available for English language training for Burma's military under the Defense Language Institute English Language Center.

The Department of State may establish an exchange program between military and civilian personnel of Burma and their counterparts in: (1) countries that are strengthening a democratic form of government and demonstrating civilian oversight of the military, or (2) North Atlantic Treaty Organization countries.

The President may designate a private, nonprofit organization as the Win Tin Burma-American Enterprise Fund to receive financial assistance and support under this bill. No military-owned enterprises are eligible for fund participation.

The U.S. Trade Representative is urged to: (1) help Burma achieve eligibility for the generalized system of preferences, and (2) urge other countries to support such eligibility.

The State Department shall submit a strategy to promote transparency and good governance in Burma's jadeite, ruby, and gemstones sector.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
