<bill session="114" type="h" number="5978" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:38Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-26T19:23:51-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-09-26T19:23:51-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 14, United States Code, to clarify the functions of the Chief Acquisition Officer of the Coast Guard, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation Amendments Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">National Positioning, Navigation, and Timing Resilience and Security Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation Amendments Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">National Positioning, Navigation, and Timing Resilience and Security Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="display">Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation Amendments Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001048"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000460" joined="2016-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2016-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000603" joined="2016-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2016-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000017" joined="2016-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-14">
      <text>Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-09-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-09-26T19:03:14-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hunter moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-26T19:03:20-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5894-5905" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-26T19:03:22-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5978.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2016-09-26T19:23:51-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5894-5897" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-09-26T19:23:54-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-27">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" code="HSPW07" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4909"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5531"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5536"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-26T14:35:34Z" status="Passed House amended">Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation Amendments Act of 2016

TITLE I--COAST GUARD, NAVIGATION, AND SHIPPING

(Sec.101)This bill makes several changes to the U.S. Coast Guard major acquisition system.The changes are designed to establish a customer-oriented acquisition system.

The bill expands the acquisition responsibilities of the Coast Guard's Chief Acquisition Officer and Vice Commandant. Additionally, the bill limits the Coast Guard's authority to procure unmanned aerial systems (drones).

The Coast Guard may extend an acquisition contract without competition if the Department of Homeland Security (DHS)approves.DHS must study the effects that multi-year contracting has on Coast Guard acquisition programs.

(Sec.102)The bill requires the Coast Guard to make payment based on a predetermined fixed amount to the Department of Defense (DOD)for medical treatment of current or former members of the Coast Guard and their dependents at DOD facilities.

(Sec. 103) The bill amends the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 to repeal certain audit requirements for the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund and to revise reporting requirements for the fund.

(Sec.104)The bill revises the deadline for compliance by certain fishing vessels with the alternative safety compliance program.

(Sec. 105) The Coast Guard must report on plans for berthing the USCGC Diligence in Wilmington, North Carolina while the Coast Guard pier is being repaired.

(Sec. 106) National Positioning, Navigation, and Timing Resilience and Security Act of 2016

The Coast Guard must develop a land-based system to backup its Global Positioning System.

(Sec.107) The Coast Guard may approve alternative planning criteria for the Arctic area.

TITLE II--OTHER MATTERS

(Sec.201)The Coast Guard must issue a certificate of documentation with a coastwise endorsement for the vessel Apollonia.

(Sec. 202) The Coast Guard may reimburse private entities for project costs incurred to construct and establish an aid to navigation.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
