<bill session="114" type="s" number="1040" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:39Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Consumer Product Safety Commission and the National Academy of Sciences to study the vehicle handling requirements proposed by the Commission for recreational off-highway vehicles and to prohibit the adoption of any such requirements until the completion of the study, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">ROV In-Depth Examination Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ROV In-Depth Examination Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">ROV In-Depth Examination Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2015-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2015-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2015-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2015-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2015-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2015-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2015-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2015-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-05-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Thune with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 114-357.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-09-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="642">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 642.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="999"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-22T13:06:06Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">ROV In-Depth Examination Act of 2015

(Sec. 2) This bill denies the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) authority to establish recreational off-highway vehicle (ROV) performance or configuration standards, or to require ROV manufacturers to provide performance and technical data to prospective purchasers and to the first purchaser of an ROV for purposes other than resale, until the study required by this bill is completed.

The CPSC shall contract with the National Academy of Sciences (NAS) to complete within two years after enactment of this bill a study of the lateral stability and vehicle handling requirements proposed by the CPSC in a notice of proposed rulemaking published on November 19, 2014. Such study shall determine:

 the technical validity of such proposed requirements for reducing the risk of ROV off-road rollovers, and whether there is a technical basis for the proposal to provide information on a point-of-sale hangtag about a vehicle's rollover resistance on a progressive scale. The CPSC must consider the results of the study in any subsequent rulemaking regarding the performance or configuration of ROVs or the provision of point-of-sale information regarding ROV performance.

If the CPSC is unable to enter into an acceptable agreement for the study with NAS within a specified time frame, it shall seek to enter into such agreement with another appropriate organization that is not part of the government, that operates as a not-for-profit entity, and that has expertise and objectivity comparable to NAS.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-357</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
