<bill session="115" type="s" number="2748" updated="2019-07-18T05:27:22Z">
  <state datetime="2018-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to require members of the Armed Forces to receive additional training under the Transition Assistance Program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BATTLE for Servicemembers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BATTLE for Ser&#173;vice&#173;mem&#173;bers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Better Access to Technical Training, Learning, and Entrepreneurship for Servicemembers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Better Access to Technical Training, Learning, and Entrepreneurship for Ser&#173;vice&#173;mem&#173;bers Act</title>
    <title type="display">BATTLE for Servicemembers Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2018-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2018-04-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-04-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-08-01">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 115-616.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="4954"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-04-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Better Access to Technical Training, Learning, and Entrepreneurship for Servicemembers Act or the BATTLE for Servicemembers Act

This bill directs the Department of Defense and the Department of Homeland Security to waive additional training under the Transition Assistance Program (TAP) under certain circumstances. The TAP provides information and training to service members and their spouses to assist them in the transition to civilian life by pursuing additional education, finding a job in the public or private sector, or starting their own business. Under the bill, service members must participate in TAP training programs unless they choose to opt out of such programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
