<bill session="114" type="h" number="5117" updated="2019-01-29T22:16:15Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Developing Innovation and Growing the Internet of Things Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DIGIT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure appropriate policies, planning, interagency coordination, and spectrum availability to support the Internet of Things.</title>
    <title type="display">DIGIT Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000594"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2016-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Consumer Protection and Commerce" code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2607"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Developing Innovation and Growing the Internet of Things Act or the DIGIT Act

This bill requires the Department of Commerce to convene a working group of federal stakeholders to provide recommendations and a report to Congress regarding the Internet of Things (IoT) for the growing number of connected and interconnected devices. The bill establishes a steering committee to be composed of stakeholders outside the federal government to advise the working group.

 The bill expresses the sense of Congress that IoT policies should maximize the potential and development of the IoT to benefit all stakeholders, including businesses, governments, and consumers.

The working group must: (1) identify federal laws and regulations, grant practices, budgetary or jurisdictional challenges, and other sector-specific policies that inhibit IoT development; (2) consider policies or programs that encourage and improve coordination among federal agencies with IoT jurisdiction; (3) implement recommendations from the steering committee; and (4) examine how federal agencies can benefit from, use, and prepare for the IoT.

The working group must consult with nongovernmental stakeholders. The steering committee must advise the working group about spectrum needs, individual privacy, security, and any international proceedings or negotiations affecting the IoT.

Within 18 months after enactment of this bill, the working group must report its findings and recommendations, its reasons for inaction on steering committee recommendations, and an accounting of any progress by federal agencies to implement recommendations.

The Federal Communications Commission must seek public comment on the IoT's spectrum needs and submit a summary of those comments to Congress.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
