<bill session="114" type="s" number="1683" updated="2018-06-02T06:56:51Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SCRUB Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Searching for and Cutting Regulations that are Unnecessarily Burdensome Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the establishment of a process for the review of rules and sets of rules, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SCRUB Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2016-01-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1155"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Searching for and Cutting Regulations that are Unnecessarily Burdensome Act of 2015 or the SCRUB Act of 2015

Establishes the Retrospective Regulatory Review Commission to review the Code of Federal Regulations to identify, using specified criteria, rules and sets of rules that collectively implement a regulatory program&#160;that should be repealed to lower the cost of regulation to the economy, giving priority to major rules that: (1) have been in effect more than 15 years, (2) impose paperwork burdens that could be reduced substantially without significantly diminishing regulatory effectiveness,&#160;(3) impose disproportionately high costs on small business entities, and (4) could be strengthened in their effectiveness while reducing regulatory costs.&#160;

Sets forth congressional procedures for consideration of recommendations for the repeal of rules in the Commission's reports. Requires agencies to repeal a rule or set of rules as recommended by the Commission within 60 days after the enactment of a joint resolution approving the recommendations in the Commission's reports. Prohibits the reissuance of a rule similar to any rule that has been repealed or that results in the same adverse effects of a repealed rule.

Requires the Commission to: (1) establish a public website to make regulatory information accessible to the public at no cost, and (2) make any of its meetings of hearings open to the public.

Requires a federal agency that makes a new rule to: (1)&#160;repeal rules identified by the Commission to offset the cost to the economy of&#160;such new rule (cut-go procedures), and (2) include in the final issuance of such rule a plan for reviewing the rule not later than 10 years after it is promulgated. Requires the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs of the Office of Management and Budget to review and certify the accuracy of agency determinations of the cost of new rules.

Makes agency compliance with the requirements of this Act subject to judicial review.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
