<bill session="113" type="h" number="4694" updated="2016-10-25T16:13:25Z">
  <state datetime="2014-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Claims Resolution Act of 2010 to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to contract with eligible Indian tribes to manage land buy-back programs, to require that certain amounts be deposited into interest bearing accounts, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Claims Resolution Act of 2010 to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to contract with eligible Indian tribes to manage land buy-back programs, to require that certain amounts be deposited into interest bearing accounts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001050" joined="2014-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="identical" number="2387"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-05-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends the Claims Resolution Act of 2010 to authorize the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary) to enter into contracts under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act with eligible Indian tribes to carry out activities under the Land Consolidation Program.

Requires the Secretary to invest the amounts remaining in the Trust Land Consolidation Fund into public debt securities with maturities suitable to the needs of the Fund.

Deems invested funds to have been used to conduct the Land Consolidation Program and for other costs associated with the Class Action Settlement Agreement.

Makes the Secretary responsible for ensuring that all payments are made to beneficiaries within one year.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
