<bill session="114" type="h" number="4697" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:51Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prevent Drug Addiction Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for increased Federal oversight of prescription opioid treatment and assistance to States in reducing opioid addiction, diversion, and deaths.</title>
    <title type="display">Prevent Drug Addiction Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000293"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001106" joined="2016-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001069" joined="2016-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000387" joined="2016-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1431"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1913"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Prevent Drug Addiction Act of 2016

This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA) to award grants for consumer education about opioid addiction. (Opioids are drugs with effects similar to opium, such as heroin or certain prescription painkillers.)

This bill amends the Controlled Substances Act to require medical practitioners to be trained in the treatment of opioid-dependent patients, pain management, and early detection of opioid addiction before they can be registered by the Drug Enforcement Administration to dispense opioids.

Opioid treatment programs that close on any day must make arrangements for each patient to receive treatment during the closure, as necessary.

A report must be submitted to SAMHSA for each individual who dies while receiving treatment in an opioid treatment program. In states receiving funding for controlled substance monitoring programs, deaths where an opioid drug is detected in the body must be reported to SAMHSA.

The National Center for Health Statistics of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention must establish a National Opioid Death Registry to track opioid-related deaths.

The Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality must develop and apply prescription drug addiction prevention and treatment quality measures.

This bill amends part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to allow prescription drug plan (PDP) sponsors to limit the access of certain beneficiaries to addictive drugs. PDP sponsors must have a utilization management tool to prevent drug addiction.

Medicare Drug Integrity Contractors may accept prescription and medical records to determine whether a beneficiary is at risk for prescription drug addiction.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
