<bill session="114" type="sc" number="41" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:37Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A concurrent resolution expressing the sense of Congress on the Peshmerga of the Kurdistan Region of Iraq.</title>
    <title type="display">A concurrent resolution expressing the sense of Congress on the Peshmerga of the Kurdistan Region of Iraq.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2016-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2016-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4306" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Corker with amendments. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="566">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 566.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2016-07-14" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate with amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5186-5187" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5186-5187" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-07-15">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-18T14:35:25-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T18:18:50Z" status="Passed Senate amended">Expresses the sense of Congress that:

 the Peshmerga of the Kurdistan Region of Iraq have been one of the most effective fighting forces in the military campaign against the Islamic State of Iraq and al-Sham (ISIS); ISIS poses an acute threat to the Iraqi people and territorial integrity of Iraq, including the Kurdistan Region, and the security and stability of the Middle East; the severe budget shortfalls faced by the government of Iraq and the Kurdistan regional government are hindering the stability of Iraq and have the potential to undermine long-term efforts to bring about the sustainable defeat of ISIS; specified funds pledged by the U.S. government to the Kurdish Peshmerga in April 2016 should remain a priority for the United States as part of continued support for Iraqi Security Forces; the Peshmerga should receive all weapons and equipment that the United States agrees to provide in an expeditious and timely manner; it should be the policy of the United States to support, within the framework of the Iraq Constitution, Iraqi Security Forces, the Kurdish Peshmerga in Iraq, Sunni tribal forces, and other local security forces in the campaign against ISIS; ensuring the safe resettlement and reintegration of ethnic and religious minorities into their homelands in Iraq is a critical component toward achieving a safe, secure, and sovereign Iraq; the Peshmerga require equipment that will allow them to defend themselves and their coalition advisers against the increased use of vehicle-borne improvised explosive devices; the Peshmerga are vital partners in the fight against ISIS; and the United States, in coordination with the Iraqi government, will endeavor to increase assistance to Iraqi Kurdish Forces to enhance their combat medicine and logistical capabilities, defend internally displaced persons and refugees, and defend the Peshmerga and their coalition advisers.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
