<amendment session="113" chamber="h" number="527" updated="2016-10-25T12:38:31Z">
  <amends type="h" number="3309" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2013-12-05T13:02:25-05:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000714"/>
  <offered datetime="2013-12-05"/>
  <description>Amendment in the nature of a substitute sought to insert a complete new text entitled "Deceptive Patent Practices Reduction Act" which promoted transparency in patent ownership; protected customers who are targeted in infringement suits; directed the PTO to develop educational resources for small businesses; and instructed the PTO and others to prepare reports on several issues including the use of deceptive demand letters.</description>
  <purpose>Numbered 8 printed in Part A of House Report 113-283 to promote transparency in patent ownership; prote cts customers who are targeted in infringement suits; directs the PTO to develop educational resources for small businesses; instructs the PTO and others to prepare reports on several issues including the use of deceptive demand letters.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2013-12-05T13:02:25-05:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="628">
      <text>On agreeing to the Conyers amendment (A008) Failed by recorded vote: 157 - 258 (Roll no. 628).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-12-05T11:53:11-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A008) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mr. Conyers.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7546-7551, H7555" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7546-7549" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-05"/>
    <action datetime="2013-12-05T13:02:25-05:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-05T13:02:25-05:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-05T13:02:25-05:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Conyers amendment (A008) Failed by recorded vote: 157 - 258 (Roll no. 628).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-05T11:53:11-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A008) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mr. Conyers.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7546-7551, H7555" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7546-7549" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-05">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
