<bill session="114" type="h" number="5055" updated="2019-02-17T14:41:22Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-26T11:13:03-04:00">FAIL:ORIGINATING:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-05-26T11:13:03-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for energy and water development and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2017, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001148"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-26">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 114-532, by Mr. Simpson.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-26" state="REPORTED" calendar="Union" number="411">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 411.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-05-23T20:06:01-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 743 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5055. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T14:24:46-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 743 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T17:19:45-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 743.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3047-3057, H3057-3092" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3056, H3058, H3059, H3060-3061, H3061-3062, H3063" label="text of Title I as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3064-3065, H3067-3069" label="text of Title II as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3069, H3075, H3077, H3077-3078, H3078, H3080, H3081, H3084, H3085-3086" label="text of Title III as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3086-3087, H3087-3088" label="text of Title IV as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3088, H3089" label="text of Title V as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T17:19:50-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5055. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T17:19:58-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 743 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T17:19:59-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Ileana Ros-Lehtinen to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T17:21:01-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 5055.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T17:58:55-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gosar amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T18:01:39-04:00">
      <text>RISING INFORMALLY - The Committee of the Whole rose informally to receive a message from the Secretary of the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T18:02:15-04:00">
      <text>The Committee of the Whole resumed its sitting.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T18:03:37-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rodney Davis amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T18:09:58-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Clawson amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T18:19:30-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Clawson amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Clawson demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T18:20:04-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rice (SC) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T18:23:41-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Graham amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T18:30:18-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the first Beyer amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T18:36:05-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Beyer amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Simpson demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T18:37:15-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Beyer amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T18:47:54-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the DeSaulnier amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T18:54:04-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McNerney amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T19:16:47-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Beyer amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. McNerney demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T19:18:59-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Griffith amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T19:29:16-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Beyer amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Kaptur demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T19:30:14-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McNerney amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T19:32:35-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Buck amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T19:40:09-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate on the Buck amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Buck demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T19:41:20-04:00">
      <text>VACATING DEMAND FOR RECORDED VOTE - Mr. Simpson asked unanimous consent to withdraw his request for a recorded vote on the amendment offered by Mr. Beyer, to the end that the Chair put the question de novo. Agreed to without objection. The Chair subsequently put the question on the amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T19:42:09-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lujan Grisham amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T19:46:27-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T19:50:02-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bonamici amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T19:54:14-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Polis amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T20:02:04-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Polis amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Polis demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T20:02:22-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Polis amendment, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T20:09:54-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Polis amendment, pending reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the reservation was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T20:21:07-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Polis amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Polis demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T20:21:51-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Katko amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T20:25:33-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Schiff amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T20:29:33-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Weber amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T20:36:10-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Weber amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Weber demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T20:36:37-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Welch amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T20:40:57-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Welch amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Welch demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T20:41:42-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ellison amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T20:49:42-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ellison amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Ellison demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T20:51:24-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Langevin amendment, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T20:55:04-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Langevin amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T20:58:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Garamendi amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T21:18:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Polis amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T21:25:50-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Keating amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T21:33:04-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Farr amendment no. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T21:42:29-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Farr amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Farr demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T21:43:37-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brownley (CA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T21:46:46-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Burgess amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T21:55:40-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Garamendi amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T22:02:32-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Garamendi amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Garamendi demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T22:02:58-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Simpson moved that the Committee now rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T22:03:17-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee now rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24T22:03:28-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 5055 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T13:43:32-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3113-3117" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T13:43:49-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T14:11:23-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Simpson moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T14:11:36-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T14:12:17-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 5055 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T17:48:33-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3220-3260" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T17:49:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T17:49:43-04:00">
      <text>VACATING DEMAND FOR RECORDED VOTE - Ms. Kaptur asked unanimous consent to withdraw the request for a recorded vote on the amendment offered by Mr. Welch, to the end that the Chair put the question de novo. Agreed to without objection. The Chair subsequently put the question on the amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T17:50:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pittenger amendment No. 34.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T18:02:43-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Pittenger amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Kaptur demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T18:03:43-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Garamendi amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T18:15:05-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gosar amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T18:26:18-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gosar amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Kaptur demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T18:27:15-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Garamendi amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T18:35:54-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gosar amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T18:46:48-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Al Green of Texas amendment, pending a reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T18:56:34-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Yoho amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T19:06:40-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Foster amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T19:16:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Foster amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Foster demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T19:16:23-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Black amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T19:24:40-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McNerney amendment, pending a reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T19:29:10-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Byrne amendment, pending a reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T19:34:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McNerney amendment, pending a reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T19:38:13-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Byrne amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T19:46:51-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Sean Maloney amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T19:54:14-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes on the Pitts of Pennsylvania amendment to the amendment offered by Mr. Maloney of New York, pending a reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the reservation of a point of order was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T20:07:04-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Sean Patrick Maloney amendment as amended by the Pitts amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the Maloney amendment as amended, and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment as amended until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T20:07:39-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Byrne amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T20:13:51-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Byrne amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Kaptur demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T20:14:17-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Higgins amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T20:18:35-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Grayson amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T20:19:58-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Babin amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T20:25:56-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lowenthal amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T20:32:24-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Meadows amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T20:35:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson Lee amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T20:38:51-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Stivers amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T20:41:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson Lee amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T20:47:27-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Mullin amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T20:56:19-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson Lee amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T21:02:54-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gosar amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T21:08:55-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Engel amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T21:12:10-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gosar amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T21:20:40-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Sanford amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T21:31:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Buck amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T21:35:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Blackburn amendment No 14.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T21:41:45-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Blackburn amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mrs. Blackburn demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T21:42:25-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Smith (MO) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T21:48:48-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Smith (MO) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Smith (MO) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T21:49:13-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Walker amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T21:59:44-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Walker amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Walker demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T22:00:22-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 743, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the DeSantis amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T22:04:23-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the DeSantis amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Gosar demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T22:06:02-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question on adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T23:11:05-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Simpson moved that the Committee now rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T23:11:08-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee now rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25T23:11:49-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 5055 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26T10:30:32-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3280-3283" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26T10:30:44-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26T10:31:49-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Simpson moved for the Committee of the Whole to rise and report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26T10:31:54-04:00">
      <text>On motion to rise and report Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26T10:31:57-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 5055.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26T10:33:15-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26T10:33:52-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Langevin moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3281" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3281" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26T10:34:03-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to increase funds in the Defense Nuclear Nonproliferation account by $20,000,000 and reduce funds in the Federal Salaries and Espenses account, relating to the National Nuclear Security Administration by $20,000,000.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26T10:43:38-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3282" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26T11:04:42-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 178 - 236 (Roll no. 265).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3282" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="266" datetime="2016-05-26T11:13:03-04:00" where="h" result="fail" state="FAIL:ORIGINATING:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 112 - 305 (Roll no. 266).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3283" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26T11:13:06-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2804"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="114" relation="procedurally-related" number="743"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Appalachian Regional Commission"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Army Corps of Engineers"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board"/>
    <term name="Delta Regional Authority"/>
    <term name="Denali Commission"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Hybrid, electric, and advanced technology vehicles"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Lighting, heating, cooling"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Mississippi River"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC)"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1149"/>
    <amendment number="h1148"/>
    <amendment number="h1147"/>
    <amendment number="h1146"/>
    <amendment number="h1145"/>
    <amendment number="h1144"/>
    <amendment number="h1143"/>
    <amendment number="h1142"/>
    <amendment number="h1141"/>
    <amendment number="h1140"/>
    <amendment number="h1139"/>
    <amendment number="h1138"/>
    <amendment number="h1137"/>
    <amendment number="h1136"/>
    <amendment number="h1135"/>
    <amendment number="h1134"/>
    <amendment number="h1133"/>
    <amendment number="h1132"/>
    <amendment number="h1131"/>
    <amendment number="h1130"/>
    <amendment number="h1129"/>
    <amendment number="h1128"/>
    <amendment number="h1127"/>
    <amendment number="h1126"/>
    <amendment number="h1125"/>
    <amendment number="h1124"/>
    <amendment number="h1123"/>
    <amendment number="h1122"/>
    <amendment number="h1121"/>
    <amendment number="h1120"/>
    <amendment number="h1119"/>
    <amendment number="h1118"/>
    <amendment number="h1117"/>
    <amendment number="h1116"/>
    <amendment number="h1115"/>
    <amendment number="h1113"/>
    <amendment number="h1112"/>
    <amendment number="h1111"/>
    <amendment number="h1110"/>
    <amendment number="h1109"/>
    <amendment number="h1108"/>
    <amendment number="h1107"/>
    <amendment number="h1106"/>
    <amendment number="h1105"/>
    <amendment number="h1104"/>
    <amendment number="h1103"/>
    <amendment number="h1102"/>
    <amendment number="h1101"/>
    <amendment number="h1100"/>
    <amendment number="h1099"/>
    <amendment number="h1098"/>
    <amendment number="h1097"/>
    <amendment number="h1096"/>
    <amendment number="h1095"/>
    <amendment number="h1094"/>
    <amendment number="h1093"/>
    <amendment number="h1092"/>
    <amendment number="h1091"/>
    <amendment number="h1090"/>
    <amendment number="h1089"/>
    <amendment number="h1088"/>
    <amendment number="h1087"/>
    <amendment number="h1086"/>
    <amendment number="h1085"/>
    <amendment number="h1084"/>
    <amendment number="h1083"/>
    <amendment number="h1082"/>
    <amendment number="h1081"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2016-04-26T17:25:48Z" status="Reported to House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

 Highlights: 

This bill provides FY2017 appropriations for:

 the civil works projects of the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers; the Department of the Interior's Bureau of Reclamation and Central Utah Project; the Department of Energy (DOE); and several independent agencies, including the Nuclear Regulatory Commission. The bill increases overall FY2017 Energy and Water Development funding above FY2016 levels and includes increases for both DOE and the Army Corps of Engineers. The bill decreases funding for the Bureau of Reclamation below the FY2016 level.

Within the DOE budget, the bill increases funding above FY2016 levels for:

 Science, the National Nuclear Security Administration, Nuclear Energy, Fossil Energy Research and Development, Electricity Delivery and Energy Reliability, the Power Marketing Administrations, and Nuclear Waste Disposal. The bill decreases DOE funding below FY2016 levels for:

 Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, Non-Defense Environmental Cleanup, and Defense Environmental Cleanup. The bill also includes provisions that affect policies in areas such as:

 federal jurisdiction under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act), the definition of "fill material" or "discharge of fill material" under the Clean Water Act, the possession of firearms on Corps of Engineers lands, nuclear nonproliferation projects in Russia, and the drought and water policy in California. Full Summary: 

Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2017 

TITLE I--CORPS OF ENGINEERS--CIVIL

Provides appropriations to the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers for authorized civil functions pertaining to rivers and harbors, flood and storm damage reduction, shore protection, aquatic ecosystem restoration, and related efforts.

Provides appropriations to the Corps of Engineers for:

 Investigations; Construction; Mississippi River and Tributaries, including flood damage reduction projects in the Mississippi River alluvial valley below Cape Girardeau, Missouri; Operation and Maintenance; the Regulatory Program pertaining to navigable waters and wetlands; the Formerly Utilized Sites Remedial Action Program for clean-up of early atomic energy program contamination; Flood Control and Coastal Emergencies, including hurricanes, floods, and other natural disasters; Expenses, necessary for the supervision and general administration of the civil works program; and the Office of the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works. (Sec. 101) Prohibits the reprogramming of funds provided by this title except in specified circumstances.

(Sec. 102) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used for a contract that commits funds beyond the amounts appropriated for that program, project, or activity that remain unobligated. Includes exception for funds made available through reprogramming.

(Sec. 103) Permits the Corps of Engineers to transfer to the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service up to $5.4 million in Operation and Maintenance funds to mitigate for fisheries lost due to Corps of Engineers civil works projects.

(Sec. 104) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for an open lake placement of dredged material originating from Lake Erie or its tributaries, unless it is approved under a state water quality certification. Requires the Corps to continue upland placement of the dredged material until an open lake placement for dredged materials is approved under a state water quality certification.

(Sec. 105) Requires acquisitions funded by this title to comply with regulations that prohibit the Department of Defense from purchasing a certain anchor and mooring chain unless it is procured from a U.S. manufacturer.

(Sec. 106) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for a water supply reallocation study under the Wolf Creek Dam, Lake Cumberland, Kentucky, project authorized under the Act of July 24, 1946.

(Sec. 107) Permits the Corps of Engineers to accept specified payments from the Trinity River Authority of Texas as payment in full for amounts owed to the United States for water supply storage space in Joe Pool Lake, Texas (previously known as Lakeview Lake) under a specified contract.

(Sec. 108) Prohibits the Corps of Engineers from using funds to develop, adopt, implement, administer, or enforce any change to regulations in effect on October 1, 2012, pertaining to the definitions of "fill material" or "discharge of fill material" for the purposes of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act).

(Sec. 109) Prohibits funds made available by this bill from being used to require a permit for the discharge of dredged or fill material under the Clean Water Act for specified agricultural activities.

(Sec. 110) Prohibits funds from being used to develop, adopt, implement, administer, or enforce any change to the regulations and guidance in effect on October 1, 2012, pertaining to the definition of waters under the jurisdiction of the Clean Water Act, including provisions of specified rules pertaining to the jurisdiction.

(Sec. 111) Permits individuals to possess firearms at Corps of Engineers water resources development projects if: (1) the individual is not otherwise prohibited by law from possessing the firearm; and (2) the possession of the firearm complies with the law of the state in which the project is located. (The Corps of Engineers currently prohibits private individuals from possessing firearms and other weapons at the projects unless the weapons are being used for hunting, at authorized shooting ranges, or with written permission of the Corps District Commander.)

TITLE II--DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR

Provides appropriations to the Department of the Interior for the Central Utah Project.

Provides appropriations to the Bureau of Reclamation for:

 Water and Related Resources, the Central Valley Project Restoration Fund, California Bay-Delta Restoration, and Policy and Administration. Permits appropriations to the Bureau of Reclamation to be used for purchasing replacements for up to five passenger motor vehicles.

(Sec. 201) Specifies the circumstances in which Reclamation may reprogram or transfer funds provided by this title.

(Sec. 202) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to determine the final point of discharge for the interceptor drain for the San Luis Unit until Interior and California develop a plan to minimize any detrimental effect of the San Luis drainage waters. Requires the plan to conform to California water quality standards as approved by the Environmental Protection Agency.

Directs Interior to classify the costs of the Kesterson Reservoir Cleanup Program and the San Joaquin Valley Drainage Program as either reimbursable or nonreimbursable and collected until fully repaid pursuant to specified alternative repayment plans.

Requires future federal obligations of funds regarding drainage service or drainage studies for the San Luis Unit to be fully reimbursable by San Luis Unit beneficiaries of the service or studies.

(Sec. 203) Extends the deadline for Reclamation to complete and submit to Congress feasibility studies for specified water storage projects in California.

(In response to the drought in California, Sec. 204 and Sec. 205 require Reclamation to alter pumping restrictions related to certain endangered species. The restrictions govern how much water the federal Central Valley Project [CVP] and the California State Water Project [SWP] can send south of the Sacramento/San Joaquin Delta.)

(Sec. 204) Sets the reverse flow rate of the Old and Middle Rivers (OMR) at -5,000 cubic feet per second unless Reclamation concludes, using the best scientific and commercial data available, that a lower flow rate (less pumping) is necessary to avoid a significant negative impact on the long-term survival of certain species of smelt and salmon.

(Sec. 205) Requires Reclamation and the Department of Commerce to authorize the CVP and the SWP, combined, to operate at levels that result in negative OMR flows at -7,500 cubic feet per second to capture peak flows during storm events unless the action would jeopardize the long-term survival of certain species of smelt and salmon.

(Sec. 206) Sets forth requirements for protecting certain water rights and allocating water if California revokes its consistency determination under California environmental laws between the SWP and the CVP as a result of the provisions of this bill. (A consistency determination applies to threatened and endangered species protected under both federal and California law and determines whether federal actions are consistent with state laws.)

(Sec. 207) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to implement the San Joaquin River Restoration Settlement Agreement.

(Sec. 208) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to purchase water in California to supplement instream flow within a river basin that has suffered a drought within the last two years.

(Sec. 209) Requires Reclamation to work with local water and irrigation districts in the Stanislaus River Basin to ascertain the water storage made available by the Draft Plan of Operations in New Melones Reservoir to maximize water storage and ensure the beneficial use of the water resources in the Stanislaus River Basin.

TITLE III--DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY

Provides appropriations to the Department of Energy (DOE) for Energy Programs, including:

 Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, Electricity Delivery and Energy Reliability, Nuclear Energy, Fossil Energy Research and Development, the Office of Technology Transitions, Naval Petroleum and Oil Shale Reserves, the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, the Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve, the Energy Information Administration, Non-Defense Environmental Cleanup, the Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning Fund, Science, Nuclear Waste Disposal, the Advanced Research Projects Agency--Energy, the Title 17 Innovative Technology Loan Guarantee Loan Program, the Advanced Technology Vehicles Manufacturing Loan Program, Departmental Administration, and the Office of the Inspector General. Provides appropriations for the Atomic Energy Defense Activities of the National Nuclear Security Administration (NNSA), including:

 Weapons Activities, Defense Nuclear Nonproliferation, Naval Reactors, and Federal Salaries and Expenses. Provides appropriations for Environmental and Other Defense Activities, including:

 Defense Environmental Cleanup, and Other Defense Activities. Provides appropriations for the Power Marketing Administrations, including:

 the Bonneville Power Administration Fund; Southeastern Power Administration Operation and Maintenance; Southwestern Power Administration Operation and Maintenance; Western Area Power Administration Operation and Maintenance, Construction, and Rehabilitation; and the Falcon and Amistad Operating and Maintenance Fund. Provides appropriations for the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.

(Sec. 301) Prohibits the use of funds provided in this title for programs, projects, or activities that have not been funded by Congress.

Prohibits specified grants, contracts, allocations, and agreements unless Congress is notified in advance.

Prohibits funds from being used for certain multiyear Department of Energy--Energy Programs activities unless specified conditions are met and Congress is notified.

Establishes requirements and restrictions for the reprogramming of funds provided in this title.

(Sec. 302) Permits unexpended balances of prior appropriations provided for activities in this bill to be transferred and merged with appropriations accounts established in this bill.

(Sec. 303) Deems funds appropriated by this bill for intelligence activities to be specifically authorized by Congress during FY2017 until the enactment of the Intelligence Authorization Act for FY2017.

(Sec. 304) Prohibits funds provided by this tile from being used to construct specified high-hazard nuclear facilities unless independent oversight is conducted by the Office of Independent Enterprise Assessments to ensure compliance with nuclear safety requirements.

(Sec. 305) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used to approve certain critical decisions for construction projects exceeding $100 million until a separate independent cost estimate has been developed.

(Sec. 306) Prohibits Defense Nuclear Nonproliferation funds from being used for contracts with or agreements for federal assistance to the Russian Federation. Permits DOE to waive the prohibition if the activity is in the national security interests of the United States and a report justifying the waiver is submitted to Congress.

(Sec. 307) Prohibits DOE from establishing any new regional petroleum product reserve unless funding is explicitly requested in advance and approved by Congress in an appropriations Act.

(Sec. 308) Rescinds specified unobligated balances of funds provided to the NNSA.

(Sec. 309) Permits up to $2 million of the funds provided by this title to be used for project engineering and design of the Consolidated Emergency Operations Center.

TITLE IV--INDEPENDENT AGENCIES

Provides appropriations for independent agencies, including:

 the Appalachian Regional Commission, the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board, the Delta Regional Authority, the Denali Commission, the Northern Border Regional Commission, the Southeast Crescent Regional Commission, the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC), and the Nuclear Waste Technical Review Board. (Sec. 401) Requires the NRC to comply with specified internal procedures when responding to congressional requests for information.

(Sec. 402) Specifies the circumstances in which funds provided by this title may be reprogrammed.

TITLE V--GENERAL PROVISIONS

(Sec. 501) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to influence congressional action on any legislation or appropriation matters pending before Congress.

(Sec. 502) Prohibits transfers of funds made available in title III (Department of Energy) of this bill except pursuant to specified authorities for transferring funds or providing goods and services to another entity of the U.S. government. Requires agencies that utilize transfer authority to provide a semiannual report to Congress detailing the transfer authority used, including the amounts transferred and the purposes for which they were transferred.

(Sec. 503) Prohibits the use of funds to contravene Executive Order No. 12898 of February 11, 1994 (Federal Actions to Address Environmental Justice in Minority Populations and Low-Income Populations).

(Sec. 504) Prohibits the use of funds made available in this bill for a computer network that does not block pornography, except for law enforcement purposes

(Sec. 505) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill: (1) to conduct closure of adjudicatory functions, technical review, or support activities associated with the Yucca Mountain geologic repository license application; or (2) for actions that irrevocably remove the possibility that Yucca Mountain may be a repository option in the future.

(Sec. 506) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for further implementation of the coastal and marine spatial planning and ecosystem-based management components of the National Ocean Policy developed under Executive Order 13547 (Stewardship of the Ocean, Our Coasts, and the Great Lakes).

(Sec. 507) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for the removal of any federally owned or operated dam.

(Sec. 508) Establishes a spending reduction account for the amount by which spending proposed in this bill exceeds the subcommittee's allocation under the Congressional Budget Act of 1974. Specifies that the amount is $0. (Under the Rules of the House of Representatives, any savings included in the spending reduction account are not available for further appropriation during consideration of the bill.)</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-532</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
