<bill session="114" type="h" number="6177" updated="2019-02-14T23:05:47Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accountability in Rulemaking Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs and the head of each Federal agency to increase transparency in the regulatory review process, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Accountability in Rulemaking Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000191"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-10-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Antitrust, Commercial, and Administrative Law" code="HSJU05" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Accountability in Rulemaking Act

This bill requires each federal agency to submit to the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs (OIRA), by December 31, March 31, June 30, and September 30 of each year, a unified regulatory agenda listing each regulation under development or review by such agency. The agenda shall include a brief summary of, and the legal authority for, such regulation and a statement of whether the OIRA has declared the regulation to be a significant regulatory action.

A "significant regulatory action" is defined as any regulatory action that is likely to result in a regulation that may:

 have an annual effect on the economy of $167 million or more; adversely affect in a material way the economy, a sector of the economy, productivity, competition, jobs, the environment, public health or safety, or state, local, or tribal governments or communities; create a serious inconsistency or otherwise interfere with an action of another agency; materially alter the budgetary impact of entitlements, grants, user fees, or loan programs or the rights and obligations of recipients; or raise novel legal or policy issues arising out of legal mandates. The OIRA shall: (1) make each such agenda available on a public website, and (2) review each significant regulatory action listed within 90 days of its submission to ensure such action is consistent with applicable law. The bill sets forth limitations on third-party communication during the review process.

The OIRA shall: (1) document any change made by it to a significant regulatory action during the review process and make such change available on a public website; and (2) for each such action the OIRA returns to an agency for further consideration, it shall provide a written explanation of why further consideration is necessary.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
