<bill session="114" type="h" number="2398" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:42Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Social Security Identity Defense Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to permit the Secretary of the Treasury and the Commissioner of the Social Security Administration to disclose certain return information related to identity theft, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Social Security Identity Defense Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000576"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001284" joined="2015-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000168" joined="2015-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001183" joined="2015-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000244" joined="2015-07-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="1323"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Social Security Identity Defense Act of 2015

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the disclosure of tax return information in cases of identity theft, to require the Department of the Treasury to: (1) disclose to the holder of a valid social security account number that there is reason to believe that there has been a&#160;fraudulent use of such account number; and&#160;(2) disclose to the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)&#160;and the Department of Justice (DOJ)&#160;such social security account number, that there is reason to believe that such account number has been fraudulently used in the employment context, and the taxpayer identity information of the individual who was assigned such account number.

The bill authorizes the FBI and DOJ to disclose taxpayer information to appropriate federal, state, and local law enforcement officials solely for purposes of carrying out criminal investigations or prosecutions.

The bill also imposes new criminal and civil penalties for tax-related identity theft and misappropriation of tax identification numbers.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
