<bill session="114" type="s" number="2934" updated="2018-06-02T07:18:46Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fix Gun Checks Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that all individuals who should be prohibited from buying a firearm are listed in the national instant criminal background check system and require a background check for every firearm sale.</title>
    <title type="display">Fix Gun Checks Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000148"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2016-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2016-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2016-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2016-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2016-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2016-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2016-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2016-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2016-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2016-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000146" joined="2016-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2016-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2016-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2016-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5671"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3411"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fix Gun Checks Act of 2016

This bill amends the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007 to revise an eligibility condition for a state to receive a grant under the NICS Act Record Improvement Program and a waiver of the grant match requirement under the National Criminal History Improvement Program.

Specifically, it directs the Department of Justice (DOJ) to establish a four-year state implementation plan, including benchmarks, to maximize the automation and submission of mental health and criminal history records to the National Instant Criminal Back Check System (NICS). DOJ must reduce the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Program funding for a state that fails to comply with benchmarks.

The bill amends the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act to require each federal agency and department, including a federal court, to certify whether it has provided to the Federal Bureau of Investigation disqualifying records of persons prohibited from receiving or possessing a firearm.

It amends the federal criminal code and the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007 to define the terms "adjudicated as a mental defective" and "committed to a mental institution."

The bill extends the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act background check requirements to a transfer of a firearm between private parties by prohibiting such a transfer unless a licensed importer, manufacturer, or dealer has first taken possession of the firearm for the purpose of submitting a background check.

A gun owner must report a lost or stolen firearm to DOJ and local law enforcement authorities within 48 hours of discovery.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
