<bill session="114" type="s" number="2884" updated="2018-06-02T07:18:27Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">EPA Accountability in Flint Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to address the liability of the Environmental Protection Agency relating to the lead contamination of the water supply of the City of Flint, Michigan.</title>
    <title type="display">EPA Accountability in Flint Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001095"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">EPA Accountability in Flint Act

This bill makes the Federal Tort Claims Act exemption inapplicable to any claim brought against the federal government relating to an act or omission of, exercise or performance of, or failure to exercise or perform a discretionary function or duty by, the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) relating to the lead contamination of the drinking water of the city of Flint, Michigan, between April 1, 2014, and the date on which the EPA determines that the drinking water of the city complies with federal standards.

A civil action relating to the EPA's conduct in relation to such contamination must be commenced within 10 years after the cause of action accrues.

 Any award against, or compromise settlement by, the government relating to the EPA's conduct in relation to such contamination shall be paid out of unobligated balances in the Environmental Programs And Management account.

The EPA shall work with any affected state or local government to implement a program for the long-term monitoring of the quality of Flint's drinking water in response to such contamination.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
