<bill session="114" type="h" number="3380" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:50Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-04-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transnational Drug Trafficking Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Transnational Drug Trafficking Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide the Department of Justice with additional tools to target extraterritorial drug trafficking activity, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Transnational Drug Trafficking Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001179"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001260" joined="2016-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000596" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000606" joined="2016-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000017" joined="2016-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-17">
      <text>Committee on United States Senate Caucus on International Narcotics Control. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-15">
      <text>Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-06-03">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 114-603, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-03">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Commerce discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-06-03" calendar="Union" number="469">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 469.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SCNC" name="Senate Senate Narcotics Caucus" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="32"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="524"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-03T13:09:23Z" status="Reported to House without amendment, Part I">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Transnational Drug Trafficking Act of 2015

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act to broaden the scope of persons subject to criminal prosecution for manufacturing or distributing a controlled substance in schedule I or II, a precursor chemical, or flunitrazepam for unlawful import into the United States. The Controlled Substances Act classifies drugs, substances, and chemicals used to make drugs into one of five schedules based on the drug's medical use, potential for abuse, and risk of dependence.

Current law prohibits such manufacture or distribution by a person who knows or intends that the substance or chemical will be unlawfully imported. This bill broadens the scope to also prohibit such manufacture or distribution by a person who reasonably believes that the substance or chemical will be unlawfully imported.

In addition, this bill prohibits the manufacture or distribution of a precursor chemical by a person who: (1) knows or intends that the chemical will be used to manufacture a controlled substance; and (2) knows, intends, or reasonably believes that the controlled substance will be unlawfully imported into the United States.

(Sec. 3) The legislation amends the federal criminal code to replace statutory references to prohibited trafficking in a "counterfeit drug" with references to prohibited trafficking in a "drug that uses a counterfeit mark on or in connection with the drug."</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-603</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
