<bill session="115" type="s" number="1168" updated="2019-04-18T16:36:20Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to facilitate efficient investments and financing of infrastructure projects and new, long-term job creation through the establishment of an Infrastructure Financing Authority, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BRIDGE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BRIDGE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Building and Renewing Infrastructure for Development and Growth in Employment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Building and Renewing Infrastructure for Development and Growth in Employment Act</title>
    <title type="display">BRIDGE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000805"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2017-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2017-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2017-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2018-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2017-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2017-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2017-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2017-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2017-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Building and Renewing Infrastructure for Development and Growth in Employment Act or the BRIDGE Act

 This bill establishes the Infrastructure Financing Authority (IFA) as a wholly-owned government corporation to provide direct loans and loan guarantees to eligible entities to facilitate the construction, consolidation, alteration, or repair of transportation, water, and energy infrastructure projects. Such projects shall have costs reasonably anticipated to equal or exceed $50 million ($10 million for rural infrastructure projects).

The bill establishes an Office of Technical and Rural Assistance and an Office of Special Inspector General for the IFA.

The bill prohibits IFA financing of a project if:

 it is private or does not create a public benefit, or the loan applicant is unable to demonstrate a sufficient revenue stream. The bill establishes within the IFA the Project Delivery Task Force to establish and coordinate a permitting timetable for the environmental review of a project.

The Chief Executive Officer of the IFA shall:

 establish fees with respect to loans and loan guarantees that are sufficient to cover the IFA's administrative costs; and take actions to make the IFA a self-sustaining entity, with administrative and federal credit subsidy costs fully funded by fees and risk premiums on loans and loan guarantees. The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase from $15 billion to $16 billion the aggregate amount of proceeds from tax-exempt facility bonds that the Department of Transportation shall allocate among qualified highway or surface freight transfer facilities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
