<bill session="114" type="h" number="5424" updated="2018-09-07T15:16:01Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-09T12:10:48-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-09-09T12:10:48-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Investment Advisers Modernization Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Investment Advisers Modernization Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Investment Advisers Modernization Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 and to direct the Securities and Exchange Commission to amend its rules to modernize certain requirements relating to investment advisers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Investment Advisers Modernization Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000454" joined="2016-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001059" joined="2016-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2016-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001187" joined="2016-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000130" joined="2016-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-17">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises Prior to Introduction and Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-06-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 47 - 12.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-07-21">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 114-698.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-21" calendar="Union" number="540">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 540.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-09-06T19:21:29-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 844 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2357 and H.R. 5424.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-08T14:13:15-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 844 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-09T09:17:48-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Hurt asked unanimous consent that the question of adopting a motion to recommit on H.R. 5424 may be subject to postponement as though under clause 8 of rule 20.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-09T09:17:50-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 844.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5230-5239" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5230-5231" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-09T09:17:55-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2357 and H.R. 5424.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-09T09:20:14-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 5424.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-09T10:19:35-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 844, the House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Foster amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-09T10:29:48-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Torres moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Financial Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5238-5239, H5244-5245" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5238-5239" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-09T10:30:46-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Torres motion to recommit with instructions pending a reservation of a point of order. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to add at the end of the bill a section pertaining to Report on Emergency Vehicle Response Times of Companies Owned by Private Funds. Subsequently, the reservation was removed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-09T10:36:28-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5244" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-09T10:36:38-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Torres motion to recommit, the Chair put the question on adoption of the motion and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mrs. Torres demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the motion to recommit until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-09T11:41:55-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5244-5246" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-09T12:04:09-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 176 - 232 (Roll no. 494).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="495" datetime="2016-09-09T12:10:48-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 261 - 145 (Roll no. 495).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-09-09T12:10:51-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises" code="HSBA16" name="House Financial Services" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="114" relation="procedurally-related" number="844"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1391"/>
    <amendment number="h1390"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2016-09-09T14:27:42Z" status="Passed House amended">Investment Advisers Modernization Act of 2016

This bill directs the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to amend specified regulations for investment advisers as they apply to private equity firms and private investment funds.

(Sec. 2) The bill revises the disclaimer that, in the case of an investment adviser that is a partnership, an assignment shall not be deemed to result from the death, withdrawal, sale or transfer of minority interests to apply the disclaimer also to minority members, shareholders, for other equity owners of the investment adviser. Qualified clients of an investment adviser may consent to an assignment of the investment adviser contract at the time they enter into an advisory contract.

The Investment Advisers Act of 1940 is amended to repeal the requirement that advisers organized as partnerships notify the other party to an investment adviser contract every time there is a change in the composition of the partnership.

The SEC shall waive the application of specified antifraud prohibitions to advisers who advertise exclusively to:

 qualified clients, determined as of the time of the publication, circulation, or distribution of the advertisement rather than immediately before or after entering into the investment advisory contract; knowledgeable employees of any private fund to which the investment adviser acts as an investment adviser; qualified purchasers; or accredited investors (determined as if the investment adviser were the securities issuer and the time of the publication, circulation, or distribution of the advertisement were the sale of such securities). (Sec. 3) The SEC must amend a certain regulation regarding Form PF which registered investment advisers with at least $150 million in private funds assets under management must file with the SEC to report information about the private funds that they manage. This amendment shall state that an investment adviser to a private fund is not required to report any information beyond that which is required by sections 1a and 1b of Form PF unless it is a large hedge fund adviser or a large liquidity fund adviser.

The SEC shall also amend the regulation requiring that client funds and securities of which an investment adviser has custody are verified by actual examination periodically by an independent public accountant.

The SEC shall amend the proxy voting regulation to waive its application to any voting authority exercised by an investment adviser regarding client securities that are not public securities.

(Sec. 4) On the other hand, the SEC may not:

 amend a specified regulation to extend its requirements and prohibitions concerning investment company sales literature to offerings of securities issued by private funds, or adopt substantially similar rules applicable to such offerings. (Sec. 5) This bill shall not apply to advisory services supplied to an investment company registered under the Investment Company Act of 1940.

(Sec. 6) Any regulation referred to in this bill includes any successor regulation.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-698</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
