<bill session="113" type="s" number="3017" updated="2016-10-25T16:33:01Z">
  <state datetime="2014-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sage-Grouse Habitat Conservation and Restoration Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide a categorical exclusion under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 to allow the Director of the Bureau of Land Management and the Chief of the Forest Service to remove Pinyon-Juniper trees to conserve and restore the habitat of the greater sage-grouse.</title>
    <title type="display">Sage-Grouse Habitat Conservation and Restoration Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-12-12T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Sage-Grouse Habitat Conservation and Restoration Act of 2014 - Provides a categorical exclusion under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA) for a vegetation management project by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) or the Forest Service involving removal or treatment of any Pinyon or Juniper tree to conserve or restore the habitat of the greater sage-grouse.

(Under NEPA a categorical exclusion is a category of actions which do not individually or cumulatively have a significant effect on the human environment and which have been found to have no such effect in procedures adopted by a federal agency in implementing environmental regulations and for which, therefore, neither an Environmental Assessment nor an Environmental Impact Statement is required.)</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
