<bill session="114" type="h" number="3442" updated="2018-11-09T00:09:04Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-11T16:43:30-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-02-11T16:43:30-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Debt Management and Fiscal Responsibility Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Debt Management and Fiscal Responsibility Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Debt Management and Fiscal Responsibility Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide further means of accountability of the United States debt and promote fiscal responsibility.</title>
    <title type="display">Debt Management and Fiscal Responsibility Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001158"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001273" joined="2015-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001255" joined="2015-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000755" joined="2015-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001260" joined="2015-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001051" joined="2015-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001062" joined="2015-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000460" joined="2015-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000461" joined="2015-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000445" joined="2015-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000450" joined="2015-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001036" joined="2015-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001065" joined="2015-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000290" joined="2015-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000174" joined="2015-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000376" joined="2015-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2015-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001181" joined="2015-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000184" joined="2015-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000181" joined="2015-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000168" joined="2015-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000594" joined="2015-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000591" joined="2015-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000585" joined="2015-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000578" joined="2015-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000586" joined="2015-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000580" joined="2015-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2015-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001172" joined="2015-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000583" joined="2015-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000238" joined="2015-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000462" joined="2015-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000796" joined="2015-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000816" joined="2015-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000810" joined="2015-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2015-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-09-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 22 - 14.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-10-07">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 114-291.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-10-07" calendar="Union" number="220">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 220.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-02-09T19:55:53-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 609 Reported to House. Resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 3442 and H.R. 3293.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11T13:26:03-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 609.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H728-749" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H735-736" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11T13:26:08-05:00">
      <text>Resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 3442 and H.R. 3293.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11T13:26:53-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 609 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11T13:26:53-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Bradley Byrne to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11T13:27:02-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 3442.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11T14:38:27-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 609, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Grijalva amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11T14:43:59-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 609, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Huelskamp amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11T14:55:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 609, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Newhouse amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11T15:05:12-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 609, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kelly (IL) amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11T15:09:23-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Kelly (IL) amendment No. 4, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Kelly (IL) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11T15:10:08-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 609, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Duffy amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11T15:21:59-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Duffy amendment No. 5, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Duffy demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11T15:23:10-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 609, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Messer amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11T15:34:45-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 609, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Grijalva amendment No. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11T15:39:37-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Grijalva amendment No. 7, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Grijavla demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11T15:40:19-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 609, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Takano amendment No. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11T15:44:19-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Takano amendment No. 8, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Takano demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11T16:20:19-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 3442.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11T16:20:28-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H746" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11T16:20:46-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11T16:21:34-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Doggett moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H747-748" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H747" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11T16:22:13-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Doggett motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with amendments to require an analysis of the long-term revenue lost from tax avoidance and evasion resulting from inversions and the exploitation of tax loopholes by businesses and wealthy individuals and the long-term revenue effect of a shrinking middle class.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11T16:30:56-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H748" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11T16:37:31-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 179 - 238 (Roll no. 75).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H748" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="76" datetime="2016-02-11T16:43:30-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 267 - 151 (Roll no. 76).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11T16:43:32-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11T16:56:28-05:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 3442.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3182"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="114" relation="unknown" number="609"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="International monetary system and foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h941"/>
    <amendment number="h940"/>
    <amendment number="h939"/>
    <amendment number="h938"/>
    <amendment number="h937"/>
    <amendment number="h936"/>
    <amendment number="h935"/>
    <amendment number="h934"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2016-02-11T13:08:16Z" status="Passed House amended">Debt Management and Fiscal Responsibility Act of 2015 

(Sec. 2) This bill requires the Secretary of the Treasury to provide a report to Congress prior to any date on which the Secretary anticipates the public debt will reach the statutory limit.

The Secretary must appear before the House Ways and Means Committee and the Senate Finance Committee to submit a report including:

 historic, current, and projected levels of debt; historic levels of revenue; the drivers and composition of future debt; how the United States will meet debt obligations if the debt limit is raised; reduction measures Treasury intends to take to fund obligations if the debt limit is not raised; and the President's recommendation regarding a balanced budget amendment to the U.S. Constitution. The Secretary must also provide a detailed explanation of:

 proposals to reduce the debt and a progress report on implementing them; the impact an increased debt limit will have on future spending, debt service, and the position of the U.S. dollar as the international reserve currency; projections of the fiscal health and sustainability of major entitlement programs (including Social Security, Medicare, and Medicaid); measures Treasury is taking or intends to take to avoid default, including a plan to publicly disclose the details; and Treasury's capability to pay only principal and interest on the debt if the limit is reached. Treasury must make the information required by this bill available to the public on its website.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-291</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
