<bill session="115" type="hr" number="441" updated="2019-04-18T15:54:10Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to prohibit the consideration of any bill or joint resolution until a cost estimate prepared by the Congressional Budget Office has been available to the public, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Require a Score Before the Floor Resolution</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Require a Score Before the Floor Resolution</title>
    <title type="display">Require a Score Before the Floor Resolution</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000298" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2017-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2017-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5771"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional Budget Office (CBO)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Require a Score Before the Floor Resolution

Amends Rule XXI (Restrictions on Certain Bills) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to make it out of order in the House to consider a bill (including any reconciliation bill reported by the Committee on the Budget) or joint resolution, an amendment thereto (including an amendment offered in the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union or an amendment adopted pursuant to adoption of a rule providing for consideration of the legislation), or a conference report thereon until an estimate of the costs of carrying out such measure prepared by the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) has been made available to the public on the CBO's website.

Amends Rule XI (Procedures of Committees and Unfinished Business) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to make it out of order for the Committee on the Budget to report or discharge from consideration any reconciliation bill or joint resolution unless and until an estimate of the cost of carrying out such measure prepared by the CBO has been made available to the public on the CBO's website.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
