<bill session="114" type="h" number="4881" updated="2019-02-09T00:55:40Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Healthy Food Choices Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to require that supplemental nutrition assistance benefits be used to purchase supplemental foods that are eligible for purchase under section 17 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (commonly known as the WIC program) and certain additional foods.</title>
    <title type="display">Healthy Food Choices Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000582"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Nutrition, Oversight, and Department Operations" code="HSAG03" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Fruit and vegetables"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Seafood"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Healthy Food Choices Act of 2016

This bill amends the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to apply nutritional standards for the Department of Agriculture's (USDA's) Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC) to foods purchased for USDA's Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP, formerly known as the food stamp program), with the addition of:

 meat, fish, and poultry; beans, soups, and immature varieties of legumes (such as those used in canned green peas, green beans, snap beans, yellow beans, and wax beans); and baked beans with meat. (Foods purchased for WIC must: (1) contain nutrients determined by nutritional research to be lacking in the diets of pregnant, breastfeeding, and postpartum women, infants, or children; or (2) promote the health of the population served by the program.)</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
