<bill session="114" type="h" number="6343" updated="2018-11-09T00:09:32Z">
  <state datetime="2016-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Farmers Markets for Food Deserts Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to encourage the sale of locally and regionally produced agricultural products in underserved communities.</title>
    <title type="display">Farmers Markets for Food Deserts Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000131"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001097" joined="2016-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2016-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-11-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Biotechnology, Horticulture, and Research.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Biotechnology, Horticulture, and Research" code="HSAG14" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-11-17T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Farmers Markets for Food Deserts Act of 2016 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to exclude from gross income amounts received by the taxpayer from the sale of locally and regionally produced agricultural products to members of the general public at a fixed location (other than a retail store) in an underserved community. (Underserved communities are located in areas of concentrated poverty with limited access to fresh locally or regionally grown foods.)

The bill also amends the Farmer-to-Consumer Direct Marketing Act of 1976 to specify that grants or other assistance provided under the Farmers' Market and Local Food Promotion Program may be used to pay any fees associated with obtaining a permit to sell locally and regionally produced agricultural products at a farmers' market located in an underserved community.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
