<bill session="114" type="s" number="1544" updated="2018-06-02T06:55:11Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jurassic Pork Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to rescind unused earmarks provided for the Department of Transportation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Jurassic Pork Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000444"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2015-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2015-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Jurassic Pork Act 

This bill rescinds unused earmarks previously appropriated to the Department of Transportation (DOT) and transfers the balances to the Highway Trust Fund.

Under the House and Senate rules, an earmark is a provision or report language included primarily at the request of a Member of Congress providing, authorizing, or recommending a specific amount of discretionary budget authority, credit authority, or other spending authority for a contract, loan, loan guarantee, grant, loan authority, or other expenditure with or to an entity, or targeted to a specific state, locality or congressional district, other than through a statutory or administrative formula-driven or competitive award process.

Under this bill, earmarks provided to DOT are unused and rescinded if more than 90% of the funding remains available for obligation at the end of the 9th fiscal year following the year the earmark was made available. DOT may delay the rescission if it determines that an additional obligation is likely to occur during the 10th year after funds were made available.

The bill requires each federal agency to submit an annual report to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) identifying: (1) each earmark for a project that is ineligible for funding, (2) projects for which funding has been made available under an earmark, and (3) projects with unobligated balances.

OMB must submit to Congress and post on its website an annual report including an accounting of unobligated earmarks, rescissions resulting from this bill, and DOT earmarks scheduled to be rescinded.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
