<bill session="115" type="s" number="2602" updated="2019-04-18T16:42:24Z">
  <state datetime="2018-05-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to support carbon dioxide utilization and direct air capture research, to facilitate the permitting and development of carbon capture, utilization, and sequestration projects and carbon dioxide pipelines, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">USE IT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">USE IT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Utilizing Significant Emissions with Innovative Technologies</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Utilizing Significant Emissions with Innovative Technologies Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">USE IT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">USE IT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Utilizing Significant Emissions with Innovative Technologies Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Utilizing Significant Emissions with Innovative Technologies Act</title>
    <title type="display">USE IT Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2018-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2018-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2018-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001069" joined="2018-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2018-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2018-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-03-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-11">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 115-456.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-05-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-05-24">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Barrasso with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-05-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="435">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 435.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-09-04">
      <text>By Senator Barrasso from Committee on Environment and Public Works filed written report. Report No. 115-328.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="7347"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-05-24T10:50:23Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Utilizing Significant Emissions with Innovative Technologies Act or the USE IT Act

This bill amends the Clean Air Act to require the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish: (1) a competitive prize program for certain technology projects that capture carbon dioxide directly from the air, and (2) a Direct Air Capture Technology Advisory Board to advise the EPA on carrying out the program.

The EPA must: (1) carry out a research and development program for carbon dioxide utilization to promote technologies that transform carbon dioxide generated by industrial processes into a product of commercial value, and (2) support activities relating to carbon dioxide utilization by providing technical and financial assistance.

The bill amends the Fixing America's Surface Transportation Act to apply the Act's accelerated environmental review and permitting procedures to the construction of infrastructure that captures, utilizes, or sequesters carbon dioxide and the construction of carbon dioxide pipelines.

The Council on Environmental Quality (CEQ) must submit guidance to relevant federal agencies. The guidance must: (1) facilitate reviews associated with the deployment of carbon capture, utilization, and sequestration projects and carbon dioxide pipelines; and (2) support the efficient, orderly, and responsible development of the projects and pipelines.

The CEQ must also establish at least two regional task forces to: (1) identify permitting challenges that permitting authorities and project developers and operators face, and (2) improve the performance of the permitting process and regional coordination.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-328</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
