<bill session="115" type="s" number="2189" updated="2019-04-18T16:40:36Z">
  <state datetime="2017-12-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-12-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-12-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Treasury to mint coins in commemoration of the 400th anniversary of the landing of the Mayflower and settlement of Plymouth Colony, the signing of the Mayflower Compact near Provincetown, and the role of the indigenous Wampanoag Tribes in the realization of the settlement.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Plymouth 400th Anniversary Commemorative Coin Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Plymouth 400th Anniversary Commemorative Coin Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Plymouth 400th Anniversary Commemorative Coin Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2017-12-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-12-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="4539"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-12-04T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Plymouth 400th Anniversary Commemorative Coin Act of 2017

This bill directs the Department of the Treasury to issue up to 100,000 $5 gold coins, 500,000 $1 silver coins, and 750,000 half-dollar clad coins emblematic of the landing and settlement of Plymouth Colony, the signing of the Mayflower Compact, and the role of the indigenous Wampanoag tribes in the realization of the settlement.

These coins may be issued only during a one-year period beginning January 1, 2020.

Sales of such coins shall include specified surcharges, which shall be paid by Treasury as follows:

 30% to Plymouth 400, Inc.; 5% to Plimoth Plantation, Inc.; 20% to the Mashpee Wampanoag Tribe; 5% to the Wampanoag Tribe of Gay Head (Aquinnah); 30% to the General Society of Mayflower Descendants; 5% to the Pilgrim Society; and 5% to Provincetown 400.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
