<amendment session="114" chamber="h" number="1156" updated="2019-04-11T15:40:30Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5278" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2016-06-09T17:07:43-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001250"/>
  <offered datetime="2016-06-09"/>
  <description>Manager's amendment makes technical and clarifying changes as well as providing for 4 substantive elements: 1) the bill contains an opt-in provision for other territories but if a court finding removes the opt-in language for being unconstitutional, the amendment adds reverse severability provisions that would reinstate the opt-in for the other territories; 2) amendment contains a funding mechanism so that the oversight board can be up and running; 3) amendment provides the ability for the oversight board to have the authority to review and rescind any laws passed by the territory between May 4 and the date of its full appointment of membership if those actions alter the priorities of repayment and move things around in a controversial way; and 4) amendment provides a timetable allowing the President to have the appointment of the board in place by Sept. 15, 2016.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 printed in House Report 114-610 to make technical and cross reference corrections in the bill.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2016-06-09T17:07:43-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Bishop (UT) amendment (A001) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-06-09T17:05:36-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Bishop (UT).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3627-3628" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3627-3628" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-09"/>
    <action datetime="2016-06-09T17:05:36-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Bishop (UT).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3627-3628" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3627-3628" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-09T17:07:43-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-09T17:07:43-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Bishop (UT) amendment (A001) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-09">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
