<amendment session="114" chamber="h" number="971" updated="2018-09-07T15:11:25Z">
  <amends type="h" number="3791" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2016-04-14T15:48:05-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000385"/>
  <offered datetime="2016-04-14"/>
  <description>Amendment sought to limit the asset threshold increase to $5 billion for bank holding companies and savings and loan holding companies which have submitted to the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System a credible plan to expand access to banking accounts and services, consumer and small business credit products, and bank branches in rural, low income, minority, and otherwise under served communities.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment No. 1 printed in Part B of House Report 114-489 to limit the asset threshold increase to $5 billion for bank holding companies and savings and loan holding companies which have submitted to the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System a credible plan to expand access to banking accounts and services, consumer and small business credit products, and bank branches in rural, low-income, minority, and otherwise under-served communities.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2016-04-14T15:48:05-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="147">
      <text>On agreeing to the Kelly (IL) amendment (A001) Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 165 - 253 (Roll no. 147).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-04-14T13:33:35-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Ms. Kelly (IL).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1697" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1697" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-14"/>
    <action datetime="2016-04-14T15:48:05-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed by House: On agreeing to the Kelly (IL) amendment (A001) Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 165 - 253 (Roll no. 147).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-14T15:48:05-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Kelly (IL) amendment (A001) Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 165 - 253 (Roll no. 147).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-14T15:48:05-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-14T13:33:35-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A001) offered by Ms. Kelly (IL).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1697" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1697" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-14">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
