<bill session="115" type="s" number="1126" updated="2019-04-18T16:36:09Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit certain Federal funds from being available to sanctuary jurisdictions that refuse to cooperate with the Federal Government on immigration matters or retaliate against border security contractors, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing the Border and Protecting Our Communities Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing the Border and Protecting Our Communities Act</title>
    <title type="display">Securing the Border and Protecting Our Communities Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001202"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2017-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2017-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Securing the Border and Protecting Our Communities Act

This bill prohibits any sanctuary jurisdiction from receiving any federal infrastructure or transportation funds authorized under: (1) the Transportation Investment Generating Economic Recovery (TIGER) discretionary grant program, (2) the Fostering Advancements in Shipping and Transportation for the Long-Term Achievement of National Efficiencies (FASTLANE) grant program, or (3) the surface transportation block grant program.

 Funds that are not allocated to a sanctuary jurisdiction because of such prohibition shall be available for activities carried out under the Secure Fence Act of 2006.

"Sanctuary jurisdiction" is defined as a state or state political subdivision that the Department of Justice determines has in effect a statute, ordinance, policy, or practice that: (1) prohibits or interferes with a government entity or official or a person sharing information with federal immigration authorities regarding an individual's immigration status; (2) prohibits any government entity or official from complying with a lawfully-issued Department of Homeland security detainer or notification request concerning the release of an alien; or (3) restricts a person's ability to bid for or be awarded a contract or otherwise retaliates against a person that assists in construction activity pursuant to the Secure Fence Act of 2006.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
