<bill session="113" type="h" number="1321" updated="2016-10-25T16:01:25Z">
  <state datetime="2013-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Paperwork Relief Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 44 of the United States Code, to provide for the suspension of fines under certain circumstances for first-time paperwork violations by small business concerns.</title>
    <title type="display">Small Business Paperwork Relief Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000622"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2013-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000292" joined="2013-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2013-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001191" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2013-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000011" joined="2014-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-21">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="identical" number="97"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-03-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Small Business Paperwork Relief Act of 2013 - Amends the Paperwork Reduction Act to direct agency heads not to impose civil fines for first-time paperwork violations by small business concerns unless there is potential for serious harm to the public interest, the detection of criminal activity would be impaired, the violation is not corrected within six months, the violation is a violation of internal revenue law or a law concerning the assessment or collection of any tax, debt, revenue, or receipt, or the violation presents a danger to the public health or safety. Permits an agency to determine that a fine should not be imposed for a violation that presents a danger to public health or safety if the violation is corrected within 24 hours after receipt by the small business owner of notification of the violation.

Makes this Act inapplicable to any violation by a small business of a requirement regarding the collection of information by an agency if the small business previously violated any requirement concerning the collection of information by that agency.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
