<bill session="114" type="h" number="3944" updated="2019-02-01T21:05:41Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Physician Assistant Higher Education Modernization Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to improve education opportunities for physician assistants, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Physician Assistant Higher Education Modernization Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001270"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001251" joined="2015-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000216" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2015-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2015-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2015-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Investment" code="HSED13" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Physician Assistant Higher Education Modernization Act of 2015

This bill amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to assist qualified individuals in receiving the education and training needed to become a physician assistant.

Students enrolled in physician assistant education programs are eligible for increased scholarship opportunities, increased unsubsidized loan limits, and loan forgiveness programs for those who serve in areas of national need upon graduation.

The bill provides educational institutions with the resources to keep up with the demand for new physician assistants. The Department of Education (ED) must:

 provide Historically Black Colleges and Universities and Predominantly Black Institutions with grants to fund physician assistant studies, prioritize the awarding of grants for physician assistant education programs that will benefit Hispanics and low-income students, and provide grants to prepare certified physician assistants to become faculty members in physician assistant education programs. In addition, ED is authorized to award grants for the improvement of technology in physician assistant education programs. ED may also create and expand physician assistant education programs at institutions in rural areas.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
