<bill session="114" type="h" number="4093" updated="2019-02-12T19:45:25Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Library of Congress Administrative Reform Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To revise certain administrative and management authorities of the Librarian of Congress, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Library of Congress Administrative Reform Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001227"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5227"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5264"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Books and print media"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Joint Committee on the Library"/>
    <term name="Libraries and archives"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Sound recording"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-19T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Library of Congress Administrative Reform Act of 2015

This bill authorizes the Library of Congress (LOC) to purchase, maintain, or replace reproducers for books published either in raised characters, on sound-reproduction recordings, or in any other form (currently limited to reproducers of sound-reproduction recordings) for the use of the blind and for other physically disabled U.S. residents.

The bill establishes the Library of Congress National Collection Stewardship Fund, whose amounts may be used directly for preparing collection materials for long-term storage.

The use of the LOC revolving fund associated with the national audiovisual conservation center shall include preservation and storage of audiovisual materials and associated collections.

Use of the LOC revolving fund currently devoted to the gift shop, decimal classification, photo duplication, and related services shall extend to traveling exhibitions and exhibition materials as well as to training services.

The Federal Library and Information Network (FEDLINK) program shall provide specified services on behalf of tribal governments.

The types of gifts the LOC may accept shall include bequests of personal property, nonpersonal services, voluntary and uncompensated personal services, or securities.

The bill also provides for the continued service on the Joint Committee on the Library in a new Congress of Members of Congress who served on such Committee in a previous Congress.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
