<bill session="115" type="h" number="2912" updated="2019-04-18T16:11:19Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To expand the capacity and capability of the ballistic missile defense system of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing America's Missile Defense Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing America's Missile Defense Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Advancing America's Missile Defense Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000371" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001250" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001283" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000459" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000448" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000571" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000579" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001050" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001199" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000576" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001154" joined="2017-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Strategic Forces.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Strategic Forces" code="HSAS29" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="1196"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Advancing America's Missile Defense Act of 2017

This bill directs the Missile Defense Agency (MDA) to use Department of Defense (DOD) policies to accelerate the development, testing, and fielding of the redesigned kill vehicle, the multi-object kill vehicle, the C3 booster, a space-based sensor layer, an airborne laser on unmanned aerial vehicles, and an additional missile defense site, including the completion of any outstanding environmental impact statements for an additional missile defense site on the east coast or in the midwest regions of the United States.

DOD shall, subject to National Missile Defense funding, increase the number of U.S. ground-based interceptors by 28.

The MDA shall report to Congress on: (1) infrastructure requirements to increase the number of ground-based interceptors at Missile Field 1 and Missile Field 2 at Fort Greely to 20 ground-based interceptors each, (2) increasing the capacity of the ground-based mid-course defense element of the ballistic missile defense system, (3) the status of the integrated layers of missile defense radars, and (4) a revised missile defense testing campaign plan that accelerates the development and deployment of new missile defense technologies.

DOD, by December 31, 2021, shall: (1) execute any requisite construction to ensure that such missile fields or alternative fields at Fort Greely are capable of supporting and sustaining additional ground-based interceptors, (2) deploy 14 additional ground-based interceptors to field 1 or an alternative field at as soon as technically feasible, and (3) identify a ground-based interceptor stockpile storage site for a minimum of 14 ground-based interceptors.

The MDA shall develop, test, and deploy a highly reliable space-based missile defense sensor architecture for the ground-based midcourse defense system that provides specified functions and capabilities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
