<bill session="114" type="sr" number="564" updated="2018-06-02T06:21:45Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution condemning North Korea's fifth nuclear test on September 9, 2016.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution condemning North Korea's fifth nuclear test on September 9, 2016.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2016-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2016-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2016-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2016-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2016-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2016-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2016-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2016-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5849-5850" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Condemns the North Korean regime for continuing its dangerous provocations. Calls on: (1) such regime to unconditionally abandon its nuclear weapons and missile programs, and (2) China to exercise its leverage to halt such programs.

Reaffirms the U.S. commitment to defending allies in the region, including through deployment of a Terminal High Altitude Area Defense battery to South Korea and through joint U.S.-Japan efforts to develop the next generation of missile defense interceptors. Reinforces longstanding U.S. commitments to provide extended deterrence to South Korea and Japan.

Expresses support for ongoing efforts to strengthen the U.S.-South Korea alliance, to defend the alliance against provocations by North Korea, and to protect U.S. Armed Forces stationed on the Korean Peninsula.

Calls on all Security Council members to pass new measures under Article 41 of the United Nations Charter, including:

 stricter measures to eliminate exceptions in current Security Council resolution sanctions; further restrictions on imports and exports of such sectoral commodities as coal, iron, and precious metals and the prohibition on fuel oil exports to North Korea; elimination of access to international financial markets and banking for entities involved in North Korea's nuclear and ballistic missile programs; restrictions on the use of North Korean subcontractors in global supply chains; restrictions on the supply of aviation fuel and a ban on civilian aviation; a ban on bulk cash transfers to and from North Korea; prevention of the use of North Korean labor in third-country projects and agreements; and a downgrading of North Korean diplomatic representation.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
