<bill session="114" type="s" number="834" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:35Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the law relating to sport fish restoration and recreational boating safety, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Sport Fish Restoration and Recreational Boating Safety Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sport Fish Restoration and Recreational Boating Safety Act</title>
    <title type="display">Sport Fish Restoration and Recreational Boating Safety Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2015-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2015-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2015-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-03-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-07-23">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Thune with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 114-91.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-07-23" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="162">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 162.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-23T12:16:26Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Sport Fish Restoration and Recreational Boating Safety Act

(Sec. 3) This bill amends the Dingell-Johnson Sport Fish Restoration Act to reauthorize the Sport Fish Restoration and Boating Trust Fund through FY2023.

The bill revises the formula used to distribute funds from the trust fund. Amounts are set aside through FY2023 for Coast Guard recreational boating safety personnel and activities and the National Recreational Boating Survey.

(Sec. 4) The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend trust fund transfer restriction exceptions until October 1, 2023.

(Sec. 5) The bill revokes a limitation on the amount the Coast Guard is authorized to allocate for national boating safety activities of national nonprofit public service organizations.

(Sec. 7) The National Boating Safety Advisory Council is extended through FY2023.

(Sec. 8) The bill amends the Coastal Wetlands Planning, Protection and Restoration Act to require the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers to report on the effectiveness of coastal wetlands restoration projects in improving the quality of fish and wildlife habitat conditions in Louisiana.

(Sec. 9) The U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service must evaluate and report its administrative services for the trust fund each year.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-91</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
