<bill session="114" type="s" number="3187" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:39Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase the authorization of the National Transportation Safety Board through fiscal year 2020, to require the NTSB to investigate major oil and other hazardous materials derailments, to expand the Secretary of Transportation's emergency order authority, and to require the Secretary of Transportation to establish a volatility standard for crude oil transported by rail.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mandate Oil Spill Investigations and Emergency Rules (MOSIER) Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="display">Mandate Oil Spill Investigations and Emergency Rules (MOSIER) Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001176"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2016-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB)"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Mandate Oil Spill Investigations and Emergency Rules (MOSIER) Act of 2016

This bill reauthorizes through FY2020 the National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB). A specified amount is set-aside for costs to carry out railroad accident investigations and investigations of significant railroad incidents.

The bill requires the NTSB to investigate derailments involving a significant release of hazardous materials into the environment within close proximity to communities, personal property, or critical landscapes.

The bill expands the authority of the Department of Transportation (DOT) to issue emergency orders for unsafe occurrences causing, or potentially causing, an emergency or reoccurring situation involving a hazard of death, personal injury, or significant harm to the environment.

DOT shall establish and enforce a national standard for the maximum volatility of crude oil to be permitted to be shipped by rail based on the safest practicable standard.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
