<bill session="114" type="h" number="5200" updated="2019-05-09T22:56:58Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Defense to submit to Congress a report on cooperation between Iran and the Russian Federation.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Iran-Russia Cooperation Reporting Act</title>
    <title type="display">Iran-Russia Cooperation Reporting Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000602"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000563" joined="2016-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Europe, Eurasia, and Emerging Threats.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Middle East and North Africa.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Middle East, North Africa and International Terrorism" code="HSFA13" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Europe, Eurasia, Energy and the Environment" code="HSFA14" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4909"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2943"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Lebanon"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Persian Gulf"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Iran-Russia Cooperation Reporting Act

This bill directs the Department of Defense to report to Congress annually (as long as the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action [JCPA] is in effect) on cooperation between Iran and Russia and how and to what extent such cooperation affects U.S. national security and strategic interests. (The JCPA is the agreement reached by China, France, Germany, Russia, the United Kingdom, the United States, the European Union, and Iran to ensure that Iran's nuclear program will be exclusively peaceful).

The report shall include matters relating to:

 Iran's space and ballistic missile programs; overlapping Russia-Iran interests in Latin America; the intelligence-sharing center established by Iran, Russia, and Syria in Baghdad, Iraq; naval cooperation between Iran and Russia and the long-term consequences of Russia's naval presence in the Eastern Mediterranean and Iran's naval presence in the Persian Gulf; how cooperation between Iran and Russian has increased with respect to the JCPA; the likelihood of Iran adopting the Russian model of hybrid warfare against potential targets such as the Gulf Cooperation Council states; Russian cooperation with Hezbollah in Syria, Lebanon, and Iraq; and a list of weapons the sale of which by Russia to Iran would violate United Nations Security Council resolutions imposing an arms embargo on Iran.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
