<bill session="114" type="h" number="5647" updated="2019-01-09T21:26:32Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to treat certain ride-sharing services provided by transportation network companies as excludable transportation fringe benefits, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to treat certain ride-sharing services provided by transportation network companies as excludable transportation fringe benefits, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001187"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2016-07-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6008"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to treat any qualified ride-sharing service provided after the date of the enactment of this bill and before June 1, 2017, as a qualified transportation fringe benefit that is excluded from an employee's gross income.

A qualified ride-sharing service is transportation provided through a transportation network company if:

 the transportation is in connection with travel between the employee's residence and place of employment, both of which are located within the Washington Metropolitan Area; the employee is an employee of a government agency and receives transit benefits from the agency; and the transportation is through the use of services that utilize innovative mobility technologies to provide alternatives to driving alone. The benefit is subject to a limit on the aggregate amount of certain transportation fringe benefits that may be excluded from gross income.

During the period beginning with the enactment of this bill and ending on the earlier of June 1, 2017, or the completion of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority's maintenance program (commonly referred to as "SafeTrack"), agencies that provide transit benefits to employees must provide benefits for using transportation network companies within the Washington Metropolitan Area in the same manner as benefits are provided for using public transportation services in the area.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
