<bill session="114" type="h" number="2709" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:13Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Professional's Access To Health Workforce Integration Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award grants for career support for skilled internationally educated health professionals.</title>
    <title type="display">Professional's Access To Health Workforce Integration Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000486"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4010-4011"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5475"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Professional's Access To Health Workforce Integration Act of 2015

Directs the Department of Health and Human Services, acting through the Bureau of Health Workforce within the Health Resources and Services Administration, the National Institute on Minority Health and Health Disparities, or the Office of Minority Health (HHS), to award grants to eligible entities to:

 provide services to assist unemployed and underemployed skilled immigrants residing in the United States, who have legal, permanent work authorization and who are internationally educated health professionals, in entering into and advancing in the American health workforce with employment matching their health professional skills, education, and expertise; provide training opportunities to reduce barriers to entry and advancement in the health workforce for skilled, internationally educated immigrants; educate employers regarding the abilities and capacities of internationally educated health professionals; assist in the evaluation of foreign credentials; and facilitate access to contextualized and accelerated courses on English as a second language. Includes as an eligible entity a clinical, public health, or health services organization, a community-based or nonprofit entity, an academic institution, a faith-based organization, a state, county, or local government, or an Area Health Education Center that submits an application that meets HHS requirements.

Defines "health professional" as an individual trained for employment or intended employment in specified fields, including public health, health management, dentistry, health administration, medicine, nursing, pharmacy, psychology, social work, psychiatry, and other mental and behavioral health, allied health, and community health or wellness work.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
