<bill session="114" type="sr" number="152" updated="2018-06-02T06:16:48Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution recognizing threats to freedom of the press and expression around the world and reaffirming freedom of the press as a priority in efforts of the United States Government to promote democracy and good governance.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution recognizing threats to freedom of the press and expression around the world and reaffirming freedom of the press as a priority in efforts of the United States Government to promote democracy and good governance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2015-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2480" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="France"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Expresses concern about the threats to freedom of the press and expression around the world following World Press Freedom Day on May 3, 2015.

 Commends journalists and media workers for promoting government accountability, defending democratic activity, and strengthening civil society.

 Pays tribute to journalists who have lost their lives carrying out their work.

Calls on governments abroad to implement United Nations General Assembly Resolution 163 (2013).

Condemns actions around the world that suppress freedom of the press.

Reaffirms the centrality of freedom of the press to U.S. efforts to support democracy, mitigate conflict, and promote good governance.

Calls on the President and the Secretary of State to:

 improve the means by which the U.S. government identifies, publicizes, and responds to threats against freedom of the press; urge foreign governments to conduct investigations and adjudications of the perpetrators of attacks against journalists; and highlight the issue of threats against freedom of the press.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
