<bill session="115" type="s" number="1975" updated="2019-04-18T16:39:43Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-10-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate additions to the Rich Hole Wilderness and the Rough Mountain Wilderness of the George Washington National Forest, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Virginia Wilderness Additions Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Virginia Wilderness Additions Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Virginia Wilderness Additions Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000384"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2017-10-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-10-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6465" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2099"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-10-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Virginia Wilderness Additions Act of 2017

This bill adds specified additional lands in the George Washington National Forest (a part of the George Washington and Jefferson National Forests in Virginia, West Virginia, and Kentucky) to the Rough Mountain Wilderness and the Rich Hole Wilderness.

The Department of Agriculture (USDA) may use motorized equipment and mechanized transport in the Rich Hole addition until it is incorporated into the Rich Hole Wilderness in order to enhance natural ecosystems by implementing certain activities to improve water quality and aquatic passage, as set forth in the Forest Service document titled "Decision Notice for the Lower Cowpasture Restoration and Management Project" and dated December 2015.

In carrying out such water quality and aquatic passage improvement activities, USDA must use the minimum tool or administrative practice necessary when using such equipment and transport with the least amount of adverse impact on wilderness character and resources.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
