<bill session="114" type="h" number="4492" updated="2018-11-21T20:31:10Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sound of Freedom Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the approval authority for National Guard flyovers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Sound of Freedom Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000614"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000799" joined="2016-02-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Readiness" code="HSAS03" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4909"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-08T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Sound of Freedom Act

This bill states that it shall be Department of Defense (DOD) policy that flyovers of public events in support of community relations activities may only be flown as part of an approved training mission at no additional expense to the federal government.

The Adjutant General of a state in which an Army National Guard or Air National Guard unit is based shall be the approval authority for all Air National Guard and Army National Guard flyovers in that state, including any flyover request in any civilian domain at a non-aviation related event.

DOD shall maintain records of flyover requests and approvals in a publicly accessible database updated annually.

"Flyover" means aviation support:

 in which a straight and level flight limited to one pass by a single military aircraft, or by a single formation of four or fewer military aircraft of the same type, from the same military department over a predetermined point on the ground at a specific time; that does not involve aerobatics or demonstrations; and that uses bank angles of up to 90 degrees if required to improve spectator visibility of the aircraft.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
