<bill session="114" type="h" number="3204" updated="2019-04-11T15:42:41Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to reduce the testing requirements for part A of title I of such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tackling Excessive Standardized Testing Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TEST Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">TEST Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000057"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Tackling Excessive Standardized Testing Act of 2015 or the TEST Act of 2015

This bill amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to lower the frequency with which students must take the tests used to determine whether they are making adequate yearly progress (AYP) toward state academic achievement standards in mathematics and reading or language arts. Under current law, students must take such tests in both subjects in each of grades 3 through 8. The bill maintains testing in grades 3 through 8 but authorizes a public school to&#160;limit testing: (1)&#160;in mathematics, to even-numbered&#160;grades or, if the school is at the 15th percentile or above for mathematics in the state or its students are making appropriate progress toward state mathematics achievement standards,&#160;to grades 4 and 8 only; and (2)&#160;in reading or language arts, to odd-numbered grades or, if the school is at the 15th percentile or above for reading or language arts or its students are making appropriate progress toward state reading or language arts achievement standards,&#160;to grades 3 and 7 only.

Limited English proficient students who are in their first 12 months of enrollment in a public school are excluded from the determination as to whether students are making AYP toward state academic achievement standards.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
