<bill session="114" type="s" number="1595" updated="2018-06-02T06:56:01Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Individuals From Mass Aerial Surveillance Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to describe the authority under which Federal entities may use mobile aerial-view devices to surveil, protect individual and collective privacy against warrantless governmental intrusion through the use of mobile aerial-view devices, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Protecting Individuals From Mass Aerial Surveillance Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2015-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4251-4252" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3962"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting Individuals From Mass Aerial Surveillance Act of 2015

Prohibits a federal entity from using unmanned aircraft&#160;or other mobile aerial-view devices (MAVDs) to: (1)&#160;surveil property, persons, or their effects; or&#160;(2) gather evidence pertaining to known or suspected criminal conduct, or conduct that violates a statute or regulation.

Sets forth exceptions that allow MAVDs to be used by federal entities to:

 surveil national borders to prevent or deter illegal entry of persons or illegal substances; prevent imminent danger of death or serious bodily harm to a specific individual, counter an imminent risk of a terrorist attack by a specific individual or organization, prevent imminent destruction of evidence, or counter an imminent or actual escape of a criminal or terrorist suspect; monitor or research environmental, geologic, or weather-related damage and events, including forest fires, erosion, floods, wildlife, habitats, or illegal vegetation on public lands; or acquire information about an individual who consents to the use of an MAVD. Allows law enforcement parties to use an MAVD to surveil specific property, persons, or their effects pursuant to a search and seizure warrant.

Prohibits a federal entity actor from making an intentional effort to identify an individual from, or associate an individual with, the information collected under certain exceptions to the prohibition on the use of MAVDs. Bars disclosure of collected information except to another federal entity or state, tribal, or local government agency that agrees to be bound by the restrictions in this Act.

Prohibits federal entities from: (1) soliciting or awarding contracts to surveil by MAVD for a federal entity, unless the federal entity has existing authority for such surveillance; or (2) purchasing information obtained from MAVD surveillance by a nonfederal entity if such information contains personal information, except with the consent of the affected persons.

Prohibits this Act from being construed to preempt any state law regarding the use of MAVDs exclusively within the borders of that state.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
