<bill session="114" type="h" number="5286" updated="2018-11-21T20:31:10Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VA Construction and Lease Authorization, Health, and Benefits Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To make certain improvements in the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">VA Construction and Lease Authorization, Health, and Benefits Enhancement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001144"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4892"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1769"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3484"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4590"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4591"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5548"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="901"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2013"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6245"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3367"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6220"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Alternative treatments"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="France"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Maine"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="South Carolina"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-19T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">VA Construction and Lease Authorization, Health, and Benefits Enhancement Act

This bill authorizes the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to enter into Veterans Care Agreements with certain providers to furnish hospital care, medical services, or extended care to eligible veterans if: (1) furnishing such care and services at VA facilities or under otherwise authorized contracts or sharing agreements with non-VA facilities is impracticable or inadvisable because of the veteran's medical condition, the travel involved, or the nature of the care or services required; and (2) the hospital care or medical services are not otherwise available from a non-VA health care provider.

 The VA shall ensure that each VA medical facility and community based outpatient clinic hosts a community meeting on improving VA health care.

 The VA shall begin a three-year pilot program to assess the feasibility of using wellness-based programs to complement veterans pain management and related health care services.

As part of the VA's hiring process for health care providers, the VA shall require from each medical board that licensed the provider information on any license violation and any settlement agreement for a medical disciplinary charge.

 The VA shall provide information on any violation of a medical license by a VA health care provider to each medical board licensing that provider.

 The VA may carry out specified major medical facility projects in California, Maryland, and Washington. Project appropriations are authorized.

 The VA may carry out specified major medical facility leases in Michigan, Alabama, Massachusetts, South Carolina, Florida, Colorado, Virginia, California, Montana, Georgia, Maine, and North Carolina.

The Veterans' Benefits Programs Improvement Act of 1991 is amended to: (1) authorize the VA to sell Pershing Hall, in Paris, France, and transfer to the purchaser all right, title, and interest of the United States in the property; and (2) direct the VA to return to the entity from which the United States acquired Pershing Hall any personal property in the VA's possession, including memorabilia regarding General Pershing and the American Expeditionary Forces in France during World War I.

The VA may carry out specified leases at the VA's West Los Angeles Campus in Los Angeles, California.

The VA shall select a VA medical center to serve as the national center for research on the diagnosis and treatment of health conditions of the biological children or grandchildren of individuals exposed to toxic substances while serving as members of the Armed Forces that are related to such exposure.

 The Department of Defense shall conduct and make public a declassification review to determine what information may be made publicly available related to any known incident in which at least 100 members of the Armed Forces were exposed to a toxic substance that resulted in at least one case of a disability that an occupational medicine specialist has determined to be credibly associated with such substance.

The VA shall pay additional compensation to a veteran who is paid disability compensation for the anatomical loss, or the permanent or static loss of use, of one or more creative organs. (Creative organs are those involved in reproduction.)

The VA shall implement an information technology system that supports the program of comprehensive assistance for family caregivers.

 The cost-of-living adjustment for disability compensation is extended through FY2027.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
