<bill session="113" type="h" number="4358" updated="2016-10-25T16:12:06Z">
  <state datetime="2014-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, to convey a parcel of land in St. Charles County, Missouri, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To authorize the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, to convey a parcel of land in St. Charles County, Missouri, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000569"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-04-01T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Directs the Chief of Engineers to convey U.S. interest in approximately 84 of the approximately 227 acres of land leased from the Corps of Engineers by Ameren Corporation for the Portage Des Sioux Power Plant in St. Charles County, Missouri (federal land) to such Corporation upon conveyance to the United States of the Corporation's interest in approximately 68 acres of land in Jersey County, Illinois (non-federal land).

Authorizes the Chief to only accept conveyance of the non-federal land by warranty deed. Directs the Chief to convey the federal land to Ameren Corporation by quitclaim deed. Requires Ameren Corporation to make a cash payment to the United States if the appraised fair market value of the federal land exceeds that of the non-federal land.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
