<amendment session="113" chamber="h" number="64" updated="2016-10-25T16:33:25Z">
  <amends type="h" number="1062" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2013-05-17T13:00:11-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001060"/>
  <offered datetime="2013-05-17"/>
  <description>Amendment expresses the sense of Congress that rules adopted by the Public Company Accounting Oversight Board (PCAOB) comply with the same standards that are required of the SEC; and requires the SEC to ensure that any rules adopted by the Municipal Securities Rulemaking Board (MSRB) and other national securities associations comply with the standards set forth in the bill.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 2 printed in House Report 113-60 to express the sense of Congress that rules adopted by the Public Company Accounting Oversight Board (PCAOB) comply with the same standards required of the SEC. Requires the SEC to ensure that any rules adopted by the Municipal Securities Rulemaking Board (MSRB), and other national securities associations comply with the standards set forth in the bill.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2013-05-17T13:00:11-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="157">
      <text>On agreeing to the Hurt amendment (A002) Agreed to by recorded vote: 233 - 163 (Roll no. 157).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17T12:14:02-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Hurt.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2744-2745, H2747" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2744" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17"/>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17T13:00:11-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Hurt amendment (A002) Agreed to by recorded vote: 233 - 163 (Roll no. 157).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17T13:00:11-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17T13:00:11-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17T12:14:02-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Hurt.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2744-2745, H2747" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2744" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
