<bill session="114" type="h" number="6434" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:37Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-12-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FIRST Cap Profits Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Flood Insurance Reimbursement Standards Transparency Cap Profits Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for more transparent and appropriate reimbursement of insurers participating in the Write Your Own program under the National Flood Insurance Program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">FIRST Cap Profits Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000188" joined="2016-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000096" joined="2016-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000604" joined="2016-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2016-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-12-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Flood Insurance Reimbursement Standards Transparency Cap Profits Act of 2016 or the FIRST Cap Profits Act of 2016

This bill requires the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) and the property and casualty insurance companies participating in the "Write Your Own" (WYO) flood insurance program under the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012 (Biggert-Waters Act) to implement and comply with the program's oversight and expense reimbursement requirements within one year after enactment of this bill. (The WYO program is a cooperative undertaking between the insurance industry and the Federal Insurance and Mitigation Administration that allows participating property and casualty insurance companies to write and service standard flood insurance policies.)

The Biggert-Waters Act is amended to require FEMA to prohibit reimbursements to WYO insurers from exceeding 110% of the aggregate amount of the insurer's actual expenses for selling, writing, and servicing flood insurance policies and adjusting flood claims on behalf of the National Flood Insurance Program.

The National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 is amended to require courts to award litigation costs to plaintiffs who prevail in civil actions for fraud or misrepresentation by an insurance company participating in the WYO program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
