<bill session="114" type="s" number="1549" updated="2018-06-02T06:55:12Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Care Planning Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for advanced illness care coordination services for Medicare beneficiaries, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Care Planning Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000805"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2015-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2015-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2015-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2015-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2015-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Care Planning Act of 2015

 Amends titles XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSAct) to cover advanced illness planning and coordination services furnished to an eligible individual with progressive illness, including Alzheimer's disease, by a hospice or other provider through an interdisciplinary team.

Amends SSAct title XI with respect to the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation and its selection for Phase I testing of innovative payment and service delivery models to reduce Medicare and Medicaid expenditures while preserving or enhancing the quality of care. Adds a model for payments to providers that furnish advanced illness care coordination services to eligible individuals who are entitled to, or enrolled for, benefits under Medicare part A (Hospital Insurance) and enrolled under part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance), but not enrolled under Medicare part C (Medicare+Choice).

Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Department of Health and Human Services, in awarding grants, contracts, or agreements under provisions for quality measure development, to give priority to the development of quality measures that allow the assessment of various specified factors including the effectiveness, patient-centeredness (and, where relevant, family caregiver-centeredness), and accuracy of care plans, including documentation of individual goals, preferences, and values.

Amends SSAct title XVIII (Medicare) to require inclusion of information on advanced care planning materials in the "Medicare and You Handbook."

Revises requirements for the use under Medicare of advanced directives, portable treatment orders, and other treatment directions from an individual or legally authorized representative.

Amends the Assisted Suicide Funding Restriction Act of 1997 with respect to advanced directives.

Establishes additional requirements under Medicare for hospitals, skilled nursing facilities, home health agencies, and hospice programs with respect to completion before discharge of care plan documentation.

Authorizes the Secretary to award grants to certain entities to:

 develop online training modules, decision support tools, and instructional materials for individuals, family caregivers, and health care providers; establish a website and telephone hotline to disseminate such resources and any materials designed by the HHS Center for Faith-Based and Neighborhood Partnerships for faith communities; and conduct a national public education campaign to raise public awareness of advance care planning and advanced illness care.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
