<bill session="115" type="s" number="1599" updated="2019-04-18T16:38:08Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Labor to award grants for promoting industry or sector partnerships to encourage industry growth and competitiveness and to improve worker training, retention, and advancement.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Building U.S. Infrastructure by Leveraging Demands for Skills</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Building U.S. Infrastructure by Leveraging Demands for Skills</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BUILDS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BUILDS Act</title>
    <title type="display">BUILDS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000384"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2017-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4117-4118" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="4942"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="6623"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational guidance"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Building U.S. Infrastructure by Leveraging Demands for Skills or the BUILDS Act

This bill requires the Department of Labor to award implementation or renewal grants, for up to three years and on a competitive basis, to eligible industry or sector partnerships to achieve certain strategic objectives with respect to targeted infrastructure industries (e.g., transportation, construction, energy, information technology, or utilities industries).

Such strategic objectives must include:

 recruiting key stakeholders in the targeted infrastructure industries; identifying the training needs of multiple businesses in such industries; facilitating actions that lead to economies of scale by aggregating multiple businesses' training and education needs; helping grant recipients who provide career and technical education and training in aligning curricula, entrance requirements, and programs to the targeted infrastructure's needs and required credentials; providing information on grant activities to state agencies to enable them to inform unemployment compensation recipients of employment and training opportunities; and helping partner businesses to attract potential workers from a diverse jobseeker base.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
