<amendment session="113" chamber="h" number="625" updated="2016-10-25T16:38:51Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4486" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2014-04-30T19:03:07-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000933"/>
  <offered datetime="2014-04-30"/>
  <description>Amendment sought to strike section 411 from the bill which prohibits the use of funds to construct, renovate, or expand any facility in the United States, its territories, or possessions to house any individual detained at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, for the purposes of detention or imprisonment in the custody or under the control of the Department of Defense.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 5 printed in the Congressional Record to strike section 411 from the bill which prohibits the use of funds appropriated to be used to construct, renovate, or expand any facility in the United States, its territories, or possessions to house any individual detained at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, for the purposes of detention or imprisonment in the custody or under the control of the Department of Defense.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2014-04-30T19:03:07-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="185">
      <text>On agreeing to the Moran amendment (A008) Failed by recorded vote: 168 - 249 (Roll no. 185).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30T16:16:31-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A008) offered by Mr. Moran.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3337-3339, H3355-3356" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3337" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30"/>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30T19:03:07-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30T19:03:07-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30T19:03:07-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Moran amendment (A008) Failed by recorded vote: 168 - 249 (Roll no. 185).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30T16:16:31-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A008) offered by Mr. Moran.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3337-3339, H3355-3356" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3337" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
