<bill session="115" type="h" number="7037" updated="2019-04-18T16:28:07Z">
  <state datetime="2018-10-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-10-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to allow the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to provide capitalization grants to States to establish revolving funds to provide funding assistance to reduce flood risks, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">State Flood Mitigation Revolving Fund Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">State Flood Mitigation Revolving Fund Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">State Flood Mitigation Revolving Fund Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001111"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000581" joined="2018-11-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000816" joined="2018-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000808" joined="2018-11-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-10-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-10-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1507"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-10-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">State Flood Mitigation Revolving Fund Act of 2018

This bill amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to permit the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to provide capitalization grants to states to establish revolving funds to address flood risks. Revolving funds may be used to provide: (1) financial assistance to participants in the National Flood Insurance Program, including homeowners, businesses, nonprofit organizations, and local governments; or (2) support for leveraged loans or state bonds. Financial assistance may be used for elevation projects, flood-proofing activities, relocation or removal of buildings, environmental restoration, acquiring property, obtaining protective easements, and other activities identified by FEMA.

States must annually submit to FEMA a plan that identifies the intended uses of the state loan fund.

States may provide additional subsidies to low-income homeowners and recipients of financial assistance in low-income areas.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
