<bill session="114" type="s" number="2815" updated="2019-01-09T21:26:37Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-16">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Semiquincentennial Commission Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">United States Semiquincentennial Commission Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the United States Semiquincentennial Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">United States Semiquincentennial Commission Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000461" joined="2016-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2016-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2016-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16">
      <text>Senate Committee on the Judiciary discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4263-4265" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2016-06-16" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4263-4265" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-20T14:02:33-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="4875"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-16T14:28:52Z" status="Passed Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

United States Semiquincentennial Commission Act of 2016

(Sec. 4) This bill establishes the United States Semiquincentennial Commission to plan, develop, and coordinate the commemoration of U.S. history leading up to the 250th anniversary of the founding of the United States.

(Sec. 5) The Commission shall: (1) prepare an overall program for the commemoration; (2) plan, encourage, develop, and coordinate observances and activities commemorating the historic events associated with the Semiquincentennial; (3) emphasize the planning of events in locations of historical significance to the United States; (4) give special emphasis to the role of persons and locations with significant impact on U.S. history beginning on the date of execution of the Declaration of Independence and to the ideas associated with that history; and (5) submit to the President a comprehensive report that includes its specific recommendations for such commemoration.

(Sec. 6) The Department of the Interior shall study and report to the Commission on appropriate actions that might be taken to further preserve and develop historic sites and battlefields to ensure that fitting observances and exhibits may be held at such sites during the celebration.

 The Federal Council on the Arts and the Humanities, the National Endowment for the Arts, the National Endowment for the Humanities, the Library of Congress, the Smithsonian Institution, and the National Archives shall cooperate with the Commission. The Secretary of State shall coordinate the participation of foreign nations in the celebration.

(Sec. 9) All expenditures of the Commission shall be made solely from donated funds and from funds specifically appropriated for the Commission.

The Commission shall seek to enter into an arrangement with USA 250, Incorporated, to house the administrative offices of the Commission, assume responsibility for Commission funds, and provide financial and administrative services.

The Commission shall submit a report annually on its activities, including an accounting of funds received and expended.

(Sec. 10) The Commission shall terminate on December 31, 2027.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
