<amendment session="113" chamber="h" number="67" updated="2016-10-28T20:40:27Z">
  <amends type="h" number="3" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2013-05-22T18:04:04-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000215"/>
  <offered datetime="2013-05-22"/>
  <description>Amendment sought to add a finding that the reliance on oil sands crudes for transportation fuels would likely result in an increase in incremental greenhouse gas emissions in the United States equivalent to approximately that of 4.3 million passenger vehicles. The amendment also sought to provide that the bill would not go into effect unless the President found that TransCanada or tar sands producers could fully offset the additional greenhouse gas emissions produced annually.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 2 printed in House Report 113-88 to add a finding that "the reliance on oil sands crudes for transportation fuels would likely result in an increase in incremental greenhouse gas emissions" in the United States, resulting in additional greenhouse gas emissions equal to 4.3 million passenger vehicles. Also provides that the bill will not go into effect unless the President finds that TransCanada or tar sands producers will fully offset the additional greenhouse gas emissions.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2013-05-22T18:04:04-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="170">
      <text>On agreeing to the Waxman amendment (A002) Failed by recorded vote: 146 - 269 (Roll no. 170).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22T16:16:11-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Waxman.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2877-2878, H2887" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2877" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22"/>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22T18:04:04-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22T18:04:04-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22T18:04:04-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Waxman amendment (A002) Failed by recorded vote: 146 - 269 (Roll no. 170).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22T16:16:11-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Waxman.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2877-2878, H2887" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2877" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
