<bill session="114" type="s" number="2978" updated="2018-06-02T07:45:42Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect Continuing Physician Education and Patient Care Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XI of the Social Security Act to exempt certain transfers used for educational purposes from manufacturer transparency reporting requirements.</title>
    <title type="display">Protect Continuing Physician Education and Patient Care Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001261"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="293"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Scientific communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting Continuing Physical Education and Patient Care Act

 This bill amends title XI (General Provisions, Peer Review, Administrative Simplification) of the Social Security Act to exempt from required manufacturer transparency reporting to the Department of Health and Human Services any transfer of value to a covered recipient of peer-reviewed journals, journal reprints, journal supplements, conference reports, and medical textbooks that directly benefit patients or are intended for patient use.

The bill also excludes from such mandatory reporting any indirect payment or transfer of value to a covered recipient who is a physician:

 for speaking at, or preparing educational materials for, an educational event for physicians or other health care professionals that does not commercially promote a covered drug, device, biological, or medical supply; or that serves the sole purpose of providing the physician with medical education, such as the tuition required to attend an educational event or any materials given physicians at such an event.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
