<bill session="114" type="h" number="4999" updated="2018-11-21T20:31:12Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Value Based Defense Procurement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure the effective and appropriate use of the Lowest Price Technically Acceptable source selection process.</title>
    <title type="display">Promoting Value Based Defense Procurement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001292"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001105" joined="2016-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2016-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2016-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000804" joined="2016-04-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2943"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2826"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Promoting Value Based Defense Procurement Act

This bill directs the Department of Defense (DOD) to use Lowest Price Technically Acceptable (LPTA) source selection criteria for new solicitations only in situations in which:

 DOD is able to clearly describe the minimum requirements expressed in terms of performance objectives, measures, and standards that will be used to determine offer acceptability; DOD would realize no, or minimal, value from a contract proposal exceeding minimum technical or performance requirements; the proposed technical approaches will require no, or minimal, subjective judgment of competing proposals; a review of technical proposals other than the lowest bidder's would result in no, or minimal, benefit to DOD; and the contracting officer has included a justification for the use of LPTA evaluation methodology if the contract is predominately for the acquisition of information technology services, systems engineering and technical assistance services, or other knowledge-based professional services. LPTA source selection criteria shall be avoided when the procurement is predominately for the acquisition of information technology services, systems engineering and technical assistance services, audit or audit readiness services, or other knowledge-based professional services.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
