<bill session="114" type="h" number="3869" updated="2018-08-16T22:36:55Z">
  <state datetime="2015-12-10T16:09:31-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-12-10T16:09:31-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">State and Local Cyber Protection Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">State and Local Cyber Protection Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">State and Local Cyber Protection Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require State and local coordination on cybersecurity with the national cybersecurity and communications integration center, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to assist State and local coordination on cybersecurity with the national cybersecurity and communications integration center, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">State and Local Cyber Protection Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001073"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001189" joined="2015-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000601" joined="2015-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2015-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001193" joined="2015-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000238" joined="2015-12-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-04">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-11-04" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-12-03">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 114-363.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-12-03" calendar="Union" number="276">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 276.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-12-10T16:01:06-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Hurd (TX) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-10T16:01:32-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9255-9257" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-10T16:01:34-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3869.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2015-12-10T16:09:31-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9255" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-12-10T16:09:34-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-10T16:09:36-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2665"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6381"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-12-10T14:02:52Z" status="Passed House amended">State and Local Cyber Protection Act of 2015

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Department of Homeland Security's (DHS's) national cybersecurity and communications integration center (NCCIC) to assist state and local governments with cybersecurity by:

 upon request,&#160;identifying system vulnerabilities and information security protections&#160;to address unauthorized access, use, disclosure, disruption, modification, or destruction of information collected or maintained by, or information systems used or operated by, state or local governments or other organizations or contractors on their behalf; providing via a web portal updated resources and guidelines related to information security; coordinating through national associations to implement information security tools and policies to ensure the resiliency of state and local information systems; providing training on cybersecurity, privacy, and civil liberties; providing requested technical assistance to deploy technology that continuously diagnoses and mitigates cyber threats and to conduct threat and vulnerability assessments; coordinating vulnerability disclosures under standards developed by the National Institute of Standards and Technology; and ensuring that state and local governments are aware of DHS resources and other federal tools to ensure the security and resiliency of federal civilian information systems. The NCCIC's&#160;privacy and civil liberties training must include:&#160;(1) reasonable limits on the receipt, retention, use, and disclosure of information associated with specific persons that is not necessary for cybersecurity purposes; (2) data integrity standards requiring the prompt removal and destruction of obsolete or erroneous names and personal information that is unrelated to the risk or incident information; and (3) safeguards and confidentiality protections for&#160;cyber threat indicators and defensive measures, including information that is proprietary or business-sensitive that may be used to identify specific persons from unauthorized access or acquisition.

The NCCIC must seek feedback from state and local governments on the effectiveness of such activities and provide such information to Congress.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-363</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
