<bill session="114" type="s" number="2834" updated="2018-06-02T07:16:54Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Getting Results through Enhanced Accountability and Transparency Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Getting Results through Enhanced Accountability and Transparency Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the Governmentwide management of unnecessarily duplicative Government programs and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Getting Results through Enhanced Accountability and Transparency Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2016-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2016-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2016-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2016-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-05-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-12-09">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-12-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="722">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 722.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3011"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="5033"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-09T17:30:20Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Getting Results through Enhanced Accountability and Transparency Act of 2016

(Sec. 3) This bill requires that the Government Accountability Office's (GAO's) annual report on its routine investigations to identify programs, agencies, offices, and initiatives with unnecessarily duplicative goals and activities aggregate separately estimates of related costs for instances of actual and potential unnecessary duplication and other potential cost savings and revenue collection.

(Sec. 4) When executive agencies (with certain exceptions) conduct their systemic review of operations on a continuing basis, the purpose of their reviews must include: (1) improving agency performance toward their mission, (2) informing learning and decision-making processes, (3) assessing opportunities to improve coordination within the agency and with other agencies, and (4) identifying employees who cause their units to be outstanding toward achieving the agency's mission.

Chief operating officers' responsibilities are expanded to include: (1) improving evaluation and risk management; (2) addressing crosscutting program and management issues, including opportunities to improve coordination and address unnecessary duplication, using an enterprise risk management approach; (3) overseeing agency-specific efforts to improve management of mission-oriented components and units; and (4) coordinating with mission-related components, units, and support functions at their agency and the major components of their agency.

The Office of Management and Budget's (OMB's) federal government performance plan submitted with each budget must provide plans to address management challenges concerning unnecessary duplication. Agency performance plans for each program activity set forth in the budget must include planned actions and performance goals for resolving such challenges.

The OMB's federal government priority goals must include mission support for financial, human capital, information technology, procurement, and real estate management. The OMB must consider GAO recommendations when developing or adjusting such goals. Performance improvement officers must collaborate with the heads of agency components and mission support functions when they advise on strategic planning. Their advice must include performance evaluation and risk management.

The Performance Improvement Council's (PIC's) functions are expanded to include: (1) resolving government-wide issues relating to coordination and unnecessary duplication; (2) facilitating the exchange of performance improvement practices with state and local governments and other nonfederal stakeholders; and (3) coordinating with interagency mission support councils. PIC must also publish annual reports describing its structure, budgets, funding, staffing, and activities.

The chief operating officers of agencies must publish all of the plans and reports produced for Congress with citations to the relevant statutory requirements.

Agencies must submit to Congress statements regarding the actions they have taken in response to recommendations in the GAO's: (1) annual report on unnecessarily duplicative goals and activities; and (2) High Risk list of fraud, waste, abuse, and mismanagement.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
