<bill session="114" type="h" number="1436" updated="2019-05-09T23:32:57Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cow Creek Umpqua Land Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require that certain Federal lands be held in trust by the United States for the benefit of the Cow Creek Band of Umpqua Tribe of Indians, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Cow Creek Umpqua Land Conveyance Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000791" joined="2015-04-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indigenous Peoples of the United States" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="815"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Cow Creek Umpqua Land Conveyance Act 

 Requires all interest of the United States in approximately 17,519 acres of land (Council Creek land) to be held in trust for, and to be part of the reservation of, the Cow Creek Band of Umpqua Tribe of Indians.

Applies federal law relating to the export of unprocessed logs harvested from federal land to any unprocessed logs that are harvested from such land. Prohibits gaming on such land. Requires any forestry activity on such land to be managed in accordance with applicable federal laws.

Directs the Department of Agriculture and the Department of the Interior to identify any land conveyed under this Act that is Oregon and California Railroad grant land. Directs Interior to: (1) identify public domain land in Oregon that is approximately equal in acreage and condition to such Oregon and California Railroad grant land, and (2) reclassify the public domain land as Oregon and California Railroad grant land.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
