<bill session="115" type="h" number="2548" updated="2019-04-18T16:09:06Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize the programs and activities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">FEMA Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">FEMA Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FEMA Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FEMA Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">FEMA Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001269"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2017-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2017-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001154" joined="2017-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-24">
      <text>Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-05-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 115-191, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23">
      <text>Committee on Natural Resources discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23">
      <text>Committee on Financial Services discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-06-23" calendar="Union" number="130">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 130.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2825"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-23T13:04:32Z" status="Reported to House amended, Part I">FEMA Reauthorization Act of 2017

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Post-Katrina Emergency Management Reform Act of 2006 to reauthorize the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) through FY2020.

(Sec. 3) The National Advisory Council shall: (1) begin a comprehensive study relating to disaster costs and losses and federal disaster assistance within 30 days of this bill's enactment; and (2) convene to evaluate disaster costs and losses and federal disaster assistance within 120 days of enactment, including consideration of trends and contributing factors, and disaster roles and responsibility.

The council shall develop recommendations to reduce disaster costs and losses in the United States and to more efficiently and effectively deliver federal disaster assistance.

(Sec. 4) The bill amends the Implementing Recommendations of the 9/11 Commission Act of 2007 to reauthorize through FY2020 the Center for Domestic Preparedness and the other members of the National Domestic Preparedness Consortium.

(Sec. 5) FEMA shall be responsible for the nation's efforts to reduce the loss of life and property, and to protect the nation, from an earthquake, tsunami, or combined earthquake and tsunami event by developing the ability to prepare and plan for, mitigate against, respond to, recover from, and more successfully adapt to such an event.

(Sec. 6) The non-federally funded actions of private parties or state, local, or tribal governments on state, local, tribal, and private land, and the effects of those actions, shall not be attributed to FEMA's actions under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973, the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012, and the Homeowner Flood Insurance Affordability Act of 2014 for purposes of the Endangered Species Act. Such actions that may influence private actions do not create a federal nexus for the purpose of applying the requirements of such Act.

(Sec. 7) The bill makes technical amendments to the Homeland Security Act of 2002 and the Post-Katrina Emergency Management Reform Act of 2006.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-191</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
