<bill session="114" type="h" number="1724" updated="2018-06-02T02:39:41Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transportation Funds Exemption Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 23, United States Code, to reduce Federal spending on surface transportation programs by limiting State and local taxation on purchases of construction materials made with funds made available from the Highway Trust Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Transportation Funds Exemption Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000821"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Highways and Transit" code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Transportation Funds Exemption Act of 2015

This bill prohibits the Department of Transportation from approving a federal-aid highway project in a state for a fiscal year if in the previous fiscal year state or local sales taxes were collected on covered purchases of construction materials made, in whole or in part, with federal funds.

The term "covered purchase" means:

 a purchase of construction materials used and consumed during the construction of a project or incorporated into the constructed, reconstructed, or improved product or facility; but excludes a purchase of equipment, heavy equipment, mechanized vehicles, and construction materials not fully consumed during the construction of a project.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
