<amendment session="115" chamber="h" number="445" updated="2018-09-19T13:31:40Z">
  <amends type="h" number="3354" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2017-09-14T11:36:07-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <offered datetime="2017-09-13"/>
  <description>Amendment provides additional funding to the Taxpayer Advocate Service for the purpose of assisting the parents of a deceased child, when that child's information has been stolen and used on personal income taxes filed with the IRS, when the parent or guardian of record must report the identity theft of their deceased child's information.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 223 printed in House Report 115-297 to provide additional funding to the Taxpayer Advocate Service for the purpose of assisting the parents of a deceased child, when that child's information has been stolen and used on personal income taxes filed with the IRS, when the parent or guardian of record must report the identity theft of their deceased child's information.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2017-09-14T11:36:07-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="526">
      <text>On agreeing to the Jackson Lee amendment (A173) Agreed to by recorded vote: 265 - 143 (Roll no. 526).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-09-13T16:45:35-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A173) offered by Ms. Jackson Lee.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7360-7362" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7360" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-13"/>
    <action datetime="2017-09-14T11:36:07-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-14T11:36:07-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-14T11:36:07-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Jackson Lee amendment (A173) Agreed to by recorded vote: 265 - 143 (Roll no. 526).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-13T16:45:35-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A173) offered by Ms. Jackson Lee.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7360-7362" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7360" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-13">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
