<bill session="114" type="h" number="5713" updated="2018-11-21T21:26:01Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-21T14:53:20-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-09-21T14:53:20-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sustaining Healthcare Integrity and Fair Treatment Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Sustaining Healthcare Integrity and Fair Treatment Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Sustaining Healthcare Integrity and Fair Treatment Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the extension of certain long-term care hospital Medicare payment rules, clarify the application of rules on the calculation of hospital length of stay to certain moratorium-excepted long-term care hospitals, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Sustaining Healthcare Integrity and Fair Treatment Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000462"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000096" joined="2016-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 114-761, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Commerce discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-09-20" calendar="Union" number="594">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 594.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20T17:24:57-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Tiberi moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20T17:25:10-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5685-5688" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20T17:25:12-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5713.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20T17:34:12-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-21T14:46:36-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5739-5740" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="530" datetime="2016-09-21T14:53:20-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 420 - 3 (Roll no. 530).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 09/20/2016 H5685-5687" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-09-21T14:53:21-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5614"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="34"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5723"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Cell biology and embryology"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-21T13:54:17Z" status="Passed House amended">Sustaining Healthcare Integrity and Fair Treatment Act of 2016

This bill amends titles XVIII (Medicare) and XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act, among other Acts,&#160;to modify provisions related to long-term care hospital (LTCH) payments under Medicare.

(Sec. 101) The bill amends the Medicare, Medicaid, and SCHIP Extension Act of 2007 to revise the applicability of&#160;certain Medicare payment rules exempting LTCHs from negative payment adjustments for admissions from certain co-located hospitals beyond specified thresholds. These rules shall apply for an additional period beginning on October 1, 2016.

(Sec. 102) In addition, the bill amends the Pathway for SGR Reform Act of 2013 to expand to all LTCHs the application of a payment rule that requires the exclusion of certain patients for purposes of calculating length of stay. Under current law, the payment rule&#160;applies&#160;only to a hospital that was classified as an LTCH as of a specified date.

(Sec. 103) The bill removes certain hospitals specializing in neoplastic disease from their classification as LTCHs for purposes of Medicare payment.

(Sec. 104) With specified exceptions, current law applies certain payment limits&#160;to inpatient services for LTCHs that do not meet&#160;specified discharge requirements. The bill: (1)&#160;establishes a new temporary exception to these limits for certain spinal cord specialty hospitals, and (2) expands an existing temporary exception with respect to certain discharges involving severe wounds.

(Sec. 201) Current law allows the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services to impose a temporary moratorium on the enrollment of new providers under Medicare, Medicaid, or the Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP) if necessary to combat fraud, waste, or abuse. With specified exceptions, the bill prohibits payment under these programs to new providers in areas subject to such temporary moratorium.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-761</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
