<bill session="115" type="s" number="3795" updated="2019-04-18T16:47:00Z">
  <state datetime="2018-12-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Employee Retirement and Income Security Act of 1974 and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the electronic delivery of pension plan information.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Receiving Electronic Statements To Improve Retiree Earnings Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Receiving Electronic Statements To Improve Retiree Earnings Act</title>
    <title type="display">Receiving Electronic Statements To Improve Retiree Earnings Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2018-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2018-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000300" joined="2018-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2018-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2018-12-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-12-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="4610"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-12-19T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Receiving Electronic Statements To Improve Retiree Earnings Act 

This bill amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) and the Internal Revenue Code to authorize the electronic delivery of pension plan documents required to be furnished to a plan participant, beneficiary, or other individual.

The system for furnishing such a document must: (1) be designed to result in effective access to the document, (2) permit the recipient to select the electronic means through which the document is received or request paper documents, and (3) protect the confidentiality of personal information.

An annual paper notice must be provided describing:

 the selection of electronic means for furnishing documents, the right to modify the selection or to elect to receive paper versions of the documents at no additional direct cost and how to make the election, and any election that has been made to receive paper documents. An electronically furnished document must be prepared and furnished in a manner that is consistent with the style, format, and content requirements for the document. It must also include a notice that apprises the individual of the significance of the document when it is not otherwise reasonably evident as transmitted.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
