<bill session="114" type="h" number="4318" updated="2019-02-12T19:45:27Z">
  <state datetime="2016-01-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 40, United States Code, to permit commercial filmmaking and photography on the United States Capitol grounds, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend title 40, United States Code, to permit commercial filmmaking and photography on the United States Capitol grounds, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-01-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E7"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Photography and imaging"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
    <term name="U.S. Capitol"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-01-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Authorizes the Chief of the U.S. Capitol Police to:

 issue a permit authorizing a person to engage in appropriate commercial filmmaking and photography activity on the Capitol grounds, except for certain Capitol buildings, structures, and areas, so long as the person only engages in that activity on a day on which neither House of Congress is in session; and require the person to whom the permit is issued, under its terms and conditions, to pay an appropriate fee to cover any costs incurred by the Architect of the Capitol (AOC) resulting from the issuance. Considers the activity and fee appropriate only if:

 the activity is similar to the types of commercial activity permitted in Union Square before its transfer of jurisdiction and control to the AOC under the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2012, and the fee is similar to the fee collected by the Director of the National Park Service for commercial activity permitted in Union Square before the transfer. Requires the Chief to transfer the fees to the Capitol Trust Account established under the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2014.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
