<bill session="114" type="s" number="2467" updated="2018-06-02T07:14:24Z">
  <state datetime="2016-01-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-01-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-01-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Patient Safety Improvement Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reduce health care-associated infections and improve antibiotic stewardship through enhanced data collection and reporting, the implementation of State-based quality improvement efforts, and improvements in provider education in patient safety, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Patient Safety Improvement Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000802"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2016-04-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-01-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Surgery and anesthesia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-01-27T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Patient Safety Improvement Act of 2016

This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), in collaboration with the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ) and stakeholders, to develop a framework to improve the consistency and reliability of hospital data on health care-associated infections. AHRQ must establish a pilot program to test collection and reporting of health care-associated infections data by additional health facilities.

The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must support: (1) state-based collaboratives implementing infection prevention, control, and surveillance; and (2) state medical boards that require health care professionals to complete coursework or training in patient safety topics.

This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) and title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to require participating hospitals to: (1) transmit information about a patient's infection to the patient and the patient's other health care providers, and (2) require new members of a participating hospital's board to receive training on patient safety topics.

The CDC must: (1) issue an electronic form for providers to use to transmit information about infections, and (2) support and conduct antibiotic stewardship activities.

The Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services must require that acute care hospitals report antibiotic use and antimicrobial resistance.

Patient safety organizations may collect patient-reported information. AHRQ must research best practices for enabling this collection of information and establish a public website to access data from the network of patient safety databases.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
