<bill session="114" type="h" number="6517" updated="2018-11-21T20:31:10Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Increasing New recruit Focus On Receiving Mental healthcare Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">INFORM Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to post at certain locations the average national wait times for veterans to receive an appointment for health care at medical facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">INFORM Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000799" joined="2016-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5726"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-08T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Increasing New recruit Focus On Receiving Mental healthcare Act or the INFORM Act

This bill urges the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to ensure that preventing veteran suicide and providing veterans access to mental health care is its top reform priority.

The VA shall, every 30 days, determine and provide to the Department of Defense, with respect to the previous year:

 the average national wait times (in days) for veterans enrolled in the VA health care system to receive appointments for mental health care and primary health care at VA medical facilities, the average time for the VA to process a claim for disability compensation, and the average time for the VA to decide an appeal of such a claim. The VA shall place a sign displaying the most current such times in a conspicuous location at each military entrance processing station.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
