<bill session="114" type="s" number="1799" updated="2018-06-02T06:57:49Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Bank Sensible Regulation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide authority for certain depository institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Community Bank Sensible Regulation Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001035"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5173-5174" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2132"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1910"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Community Bank Sensible Regulation Act of 2015

 This bill amends the following Acts governing insured depository institutions to authorize the respective regulatory agencies to exempt from their regulatory purview depository institutions having less than $10 billion in total assets after the agencies have considered specified factors:

 the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (insured depository institutions), the Revised Statutes (national banks), the Home Owners' Loan Act (savings associations, savings and loan holding companies, and mutual holding company), the Federal Reserve Act (state member banks), and the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (bank holding companies). When issuing an exemption from a provision or rule the regulatory agencies must consider the extent to which:

 the provision or rule would impose an unnecessary or undue burden or cost on the depository institution; the provision or rule is unnecessary or unwarranted to promote the safety and soundness of the depository institution; and the exemption is necessary, appropriate, or consistent with the public interest. The asset threshold of such depository institutions shall increase annually at a percentage equal to the percentage change in the total aggregate assets of insured depository institutions for each 12-month period ending in December of each year, rounded to the nearest $10 million.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
