<bill session="114" type="h" number="1843" updated="2018-06-02T03:21:01Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a pilot program to improve access to supportive services and community coordination for families of disabled veterans.</title>
    <title type="display">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a pilot program to improve access to supportive services and community coordination for families of disabled veterans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000581"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001281" joined="2015-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2015-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2015-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2015-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2015-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2015-10-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to carry out a three-year pilot program with community partners (private nonprofit organizations) to provide intensive community care coordination and supportive services to disabled veteran families who lack access to VA or other direct wellness services.

Authorizes such services to include:

 care coordination and case management services; outreach services; assistance in obtaining VA benefits, including vocational and rehabilitation counseling, employment and training service, educational assistance, and health care services; assistance in obtaining and coordinating the provision of other public benefits provided in federal, state or local agencies or other community partners, including marriage counseling, services for children, suicide prevention, substance abuse awareness and treatment, mental health awareness and treatment, financial counseling, anger management counseling, domestic violence awareness and prevention, employment assistance, transportation services, child care, housing counseling, preparing and updating family care plans, development of strategies for living with a veteran with post-traumatic stress disorder or traumatic brain injury, and accessing emergency financial assistance through philanthropic efforts; and providing direct services that are necessary to improve the well-being and address the needs of the disabled veteran families but are otherwise unavailable through existing public or private programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
