<bill session="114" type="s" number="2484" updated="2018-06-02T07:14:29Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CONNECT for Health Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Creating Opportunities Now for Necessary and Effective Care Technologies (CONNECT) for Health Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend titles XVIII and XI of the Social Security Act to promote cost savings and quality care under the Medicare program through the use of telehealth and remote patient monitoring services, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">CONNECT for Health Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2016-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2016-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2016-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2016-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2016-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2016-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2016-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2016-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2016-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2016-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2016-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2016-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2016-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2016-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2016-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000127" joined="2016-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2016-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2016-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="4442"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-02T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Creating Opportunities Now for Necessary and Effective Care Technologies (CONNECT) for Health Act or the CONNECT for Health Act

This bill amends titles XI (General Provisions) and&#160;XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to expand and modify the use of telehealth and remote patient monitoring services under Medicare.

The bill establishes a telehealth and remote patient monitoring services "bridge" demonstration waiver program, through which the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) shall waive certain limitations as a condition of Medicare payment to eligible providers of&#160;telehealth services.

CMS&#160;shall also waive such limitations as a condition of Medicare payment&#160;for telehealth services with respect to&#160;providers participating in qualifying alternative payment models.&#160;

With regard to individuals with certain chronic conditions, telehealth services shall be covered under Medicare as medical and other health services, rural health clinic services, or federally qualified health center (FQHC) services, as the case may be.

A&#160;Medicare beneficiary determined to have end stage renal disease (ESRD) and receiving home dialysis may elect to receive certain required monthly ESRD-related visits via telehealth if the beneficiary receives an in-person examination at least once every three months.

For purposes of Medicare payment for telehealth services: (1) a rural health clinic or FQHC may&#160;serve as&#160;a distant site whose clinician furnishes&#160;such services, and (2) certain requirements for originating sites shall not apply with respect to specified stroke-related services or to specified Native American health service facilities.

A Medicare Advantage (MA) plan may use telehealth services to provide benefits under the original Medicare fee-for-service program option. Specified limitations are waived with regard to such services furnished under an MA plan.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
