<amendment session="115" chamber="h" number="559" updated="2019-06-13T20:34:07Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2018-04-26T16:10:09-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001292"/>
  <offered datetime="2018-04-26"/>
  <description>At the end of title V, add the following:    SEC. XX. NATIONAL CAPITAL REGION HELICOPTER FLIGHT PATHS.    (a) In General- With respect to the National Capital Region, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall review and revise helicopter flight paths, including those used by the Department of Defense and all military helicopters, identifying and issuing new official paths for areas in which helicopters may be able to fly at higher altitudes. ***.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 67 printed in Part A of House Report 115-650 to require the FAA to review and revise helicopter flight paths for all helicopters, including military helicopters, flying in the National Capital Region--identifying and issuing new official paths if helicopters are able to fly at higher altitudes.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2018-04-26T16:10:09-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="fail">
      <text>On agreeing to the Beyer amendment (A014) Failed by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T15:28:37-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A014) offered by Mr. Beyer.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3670-3677" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3670" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26"/>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T15:28:37-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A014) offered by Mr. Beyer.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3670-3677" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3670" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T16:10:09-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T16:10:09-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Beyer amendment (A014) Failed by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
