<bill session="115" type="h" number="3974" updated="2019-04-18T16:16:09Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-10-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To limit the use of taxpayer dollars on non-commercial flights for cabinet officials, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">JETS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">JETS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Justifiable and Efficient Transportation Substitutes Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Justifiable and Efficient Transportation Substitutes Act</title>
    <title type="display">JETS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000371"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-10-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-10-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Justifiable and Efficient Transportation Substitutes Act or the JETS Act

This bill prohibits the use of federal funds for the travel expenses of any cabinet official on: (1)&#160;a non-commercial, private, chartered flight; or (2) any plane owned, operated, rented or leased by the government. The prohibition must continue until the President prescribes guidelines to be published in the Federal Register describing prohibited and permissible travel by a cabinet official.

With regard to permissible travel under the guidelines:&#160;

 scheduling requirements may not be cited except in the case of travel to or from a region covered by&#160;a declaration of an emergency or&#160;a major disaster, or for reasons of national security; the unavailability of commercially-available flights may be cited if it is accompanied by a written finding by the President or the Chief of Staff to the President&#160;issued on a case-by-case basis; and no comprehensive waiver may be allowed for a cabinet official. After the date of publication of the guidelines, any travel by a cabinet official otherwise prohibited must be disclosed to the General Services Administration (GSA). GSA must publish information on the disclosed travel on its public website.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
