<bill session="114" type="h" number="1472" updated="2019-02-12T19:45:38Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Modernization Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Modernization Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a modernized national Integrated Public Alert and Warning System, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Modernization Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001269"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001154" joined="2015-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15">
      <text>Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-04-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-12-30">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 114-900.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-12-30" calendar="Union" number="711">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 711.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1180"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1738"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-30T14:33:01Z" status="Reported to House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Modernization Act of 2015

 This bill directs the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to modernize and implement the integrated public alert and warning system of the United States to ensure that the President is able, under all conditions, to alert governmental authorities and the civilian population in areas endangered by disasters, including by:

 establishing common alerting and warning protocols, standards, terminology, and operating procedures for such system; including in such system the capability to adapt the distribution and content of communications on the basis of geographic location, risks, or personal user preferences and to alert individuals with disabilities and individuals with access and functional needs; ensuring that training, tests, and exercises are conducted for such system; establishing and integrating into the National Incident Management System a comprehensive and periodic training program to instruct and educate federal, state, tribal, and local government officials in the use of the Common Alerting Protocol enabled Emergency Alert System; and ensuring that the system is resilient, secure, and can withstand acts of terrorism and other external attacks. The system shall:

 incorporate multiple communications technologies, be designed to incorporate future technologies for communicating directly with the public to provide alerts to the largest portion of the affected population feasible and to improve the ability of remote areas to receive alerts, promote local and regional partnerships to enhance community preparedness and response, provide redundant alert mechanisms, and protect individual privacy. FEMA must: (1) submit a detailed plan to implement the system, including a time line, a spending plan, and recommendations for any additional authority necessary; and (2) establish the Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Advisory Committee to develop recommendations for the system.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-900</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
