<bill session="115" type="h" number="3159" updated="2019-04-18T16:12:20Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reduce the taxable estate by the value of certain family-owned business interests.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Family Business Preservation Estate Tax Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Family Business Preservation Estate Tax Act</title>
    <title type="display">Family Business Preservation Estate Tax Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000460"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Transfer and inheritance taxes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Family Business Preservation Estate Tax Act 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the estate tax, to allow the value of the taxable estate to be reduced by the adjusted value of family-owned business interests that: (1) are included in determining the value of the gross estate, and (2) are acquired by or passed to an heir from the decedent.

The deduction may not exceed the greater of: (1) the basic exclusion amount in effect for the calendar year that includes the death of the decedent ($5.49 million for 2017), or (2) the value of farmland which constitutes the family-owned business interest.

The bill imposes a specified additional estate tax if, within 10 years of the decedent's death and before the heir's death: (1) material participation requirements are not met with respect to the family-owned business interest, (2) the heir disposes of any portion of the family-owned business interest (other than by a disposition to a member of the heir's family or through a qualified conservation contribution), (3) the heir loses U.S. citizenship or ceases to be a lawful permanent resident and the interest was not acquired or is not held in a qualified trust, or (4) the principal place of business of a trade or business of the family-owned business ceases to be located in the United States.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
