<bill session="113" type="s" number="1157" updated="2016-10-25T16:25:15Z">
  <state datetime="2013-06-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize the Rivers of Steel National Heritage Area, the Lackawanna Valley National Heritage Area, the Delaware and Lehigh National Heritage Corridor, and the Schuylkill River Valley National Heritage Area.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to reauthorize the Rivers of Steel National Heritage Area, the Lackawanna Valley National Heritage Area, the Delaware and Lehigh National Heritage Corridor, and the Schuylkill River Valley National Heritage Area.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-93.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks" code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="identical" number="2360"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="5205"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-06-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amends the Steel Industry American Heritage Area Act of 1996 to extend through FY2023 the authority of the Secretary of the Interior to make grants or provide other assistance for the Rivers of Steel National Heritage Area in Pennsylvania.

 Amends the Lackawanna Valley National Heritage Area Act of 2000 to extend through FY2023 the authority of the Secretary to provide grants or other assistance for the Lackawanna Valley National Heritage Area in Pennsylvania.

Amends the Delaware and Lehigh Navigation Canal Heritage Corridor Act of 1988 to extend through FY2023: (1) the authorization of appropriations for the management action plan respecting the Delaware and Lehigh National Heritage Corridor in Pennsylvania, and (2) the authority of the Secretary to provide financial assistance for the Corridor.

Amends the Schuylkill River Valley National Heritage Area to extend through FY2023 the authority of the Secretary to make grants or provide other assistance for the Schuylkill River Valley National Heritage Area in Pennsylvania.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
