<bill session="114" type="s" number="1063" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:53Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Energy Efficiency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title VI of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to establish a Federal energy efficiency resource standard for electricity and natural gas suppliers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">American Energy Efficiency Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000457"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3426"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2089"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">American Energy Efficiency Act 

This bill amends the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to prescribe a federal energy efficiency resource standard for retail electricity and natural gas suppliers.

The Secretary of Energy is directed to implement a program which establishes:

 measurement and verification procedures and standards that count only measures and savings that are additional to business-as-usual customer purchase practices; certain requirements governing retail electricity suppliers and retail natural gas suppliers; other requirements governing applications for, and implementation of, delegated state administration; and rules to govern transfers of electricity or natural gas savings between suppliers and third-party efficiency providers serving the same state and between suppliers and third-party efficiency providers serving different states. Mandatory performance standards for 2017-2030 are prescribed for retail energy suppliers. No standards for any subsequent year may be lower than the standard for 2030.

Retail electricity and natural gas suppliers are subject to monetary penalties for failure to document the adequate savings required by this Act.

The Secretary may delegate to a state responsibility for administering this Act within its territory upon determining that it will meet or exceed the energy efficiency required by this Act.

The Secretary must: (1) review state implementation of this Act, every two years, in approximately one-half of the states; and (2) take certain measures where deficiencies are found.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
