<bill session="114" type="s" number="2076" updated="2019-03-03T14:41:01Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a task force to review policies and measures to promote, and to develop best practices for, reduction of short-lived climate pollutants, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Super Pollutants Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Super Pollutants Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001169"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2015-09-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="India"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Lighting, heating, cooling"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-24T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Super Pollutants Act of 2015

This bill requires the President to establish the Interagency Task Force on Short-Lived Climate Pollutant Mitigation. The Task Force must report on federal agencies' plans for reducing those pollutants, including: (1) black carbon (soot emissions), (2) methane, and (3) hydrofluorocarbons with high global warming potential (high-GWP HFC).

The Department of State must develop a comprehensive plan to reduce black carbon emissions from international shipping, which must include a roadmap toward helping countries reduce fine-particle emissions from shipping. While acting as chairperson of the Arctic Council, the Secretary of State must: (1) lead an effort to reduce black carbon through an Arctic-wide aspirational black carbon goal, and (2) encourage observers of that Council to adopt national black carbon emissions reduction goals and mitigation plans.

The U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) must: (1) prioritize black carbon mitigation activities as part of aid distribution activities; (2) give special emphasis to projects that produce substantial environmental, gender, livelihood, and public health benefits; and (3) work with the Global Alliance for Clean Cookstoves to help developing nations establish thriving markets for clean and efficient cooking solutions.

The State Department must provide technical assistance to aid international efforts in reducing black carbon emissions from diesel trucks, 2-stroke engines, diesel generators, and industrial processes.

The Department of Energy (DOE) and the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) must: (1) evaluate the availability of high-GWP HFC alternatives, and (2) report on a plan for revising regulatory barriers that prevent the use of those alternatives.

The bill amends the Clean Air Act to prohibit the manufacture of any uncharged hydrochlorofluorocarbon-22 air-conditioning condensing equipment for residential use. The EPA must study and report on the most effective method to minimize the inadvertent release of HFC-134a from automotive air conditioning recharge kits when the recharge container is not being used.

The State Department, DOE, the EPA, and the Department of Commerce must provide to other countries technical guidance on containing emissions from gas drilling, landfills, coal mining, and agriculture.

The Government Accountability Office must identify: (1) the types of equipment throughout the production value chain that are most likely to have high leak rates, and (2) voluntary efforts on replacing or monitoring those types of equipment.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
