<bill session="114" type="h" number="5841" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:47Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish a population based payment demonstration project under which Patient Care Networks are paid prospective monthly capitated payments for coordinated care furnished to Medicare beneficiaries.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish a population based payment demonstration project under which Patient Care Networks are paid prospective monthly capitated payments for coordinated care furnished to Medicare beneficiaries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000376"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000015" joined="2016-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to establish a five-year, population-based payment demonstration project through which provider networks are prospectively paid monthly capitated payments for coordinated care furnished to Medicare beneficiaries.

To be eligible to participate in the project, a provider network must:

 be an integrated care system that provides Medicare services directly; include physicians in group practice arrangements, a federally qualified health center, and at least one hospital; enter into, and be responsible for making payments to providers under,&#160;appropriate contractual arrangements; be accountable for the quality, cost, and overall care of the network's participating beneficiaries; enter into a participation agreement with the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS); and meet other specified requirements. CMS shall establish a process&#160;for prospectively assigning Medicare fee-for-service beneficiaries to a participating provider network. This process must allow beneficiaries to opt out of such assignment.

The bill limits Medicare payment for out-of-network services furnished to a participating beneficiary.

To calculate payments to participating networks, CMS shall: (1)&#160;determine a base annual prospective population health budget, (2)&#160;adjust such budget&#160;to account for&#160;the number and characteristics of participating beneficiaries with respect to each network, and (3) annually update the budget to account for population changes&#160;and Medicare program growth.

The bill establishes certain limits on total program expenditures for the program's initial three years.

CMS may expand the project's duration and scope under specified circumstances.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
