<bill session="115" type="h" number="3043" updated="2019-06-13T17:59:45Z">
  <state datetime="2017-11-08T17:03:46-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-11-08T17:03:46-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To modernize hydropower policy, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Hydropower Policy Modernization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Hydropower Policy Modernization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Hydropower Policy Modernization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Hydropower Policy Modernization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hydropower Policy Modernization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hydropower Policy Modernization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Hydropower Policy Modernization Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001159"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-06-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-10-31">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 115-377, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-31">
      <text>Committee on Oversight and Government discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-10-31" calendar="Union" number="277">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 277.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-11-06T19:20:25-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 607 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3043 and H.R. 3441. Measure will be considered read. The resolution provides for one hour of debate on H.R. 3043. The resolution makes in order only those further amendments printed in the report and one motion to recommit with or without instructions. Also, the resolution provides for one hour of debate on H.R. 3441 with one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08T13:43:08-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 607.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8614-8641" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08T13:43:13-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3043 and H.R. 3441. Measure will be considered read. The resolution provides for one hour of debate on H.R. 3043. The resolution makes in order only those further amendments printed in the report and one motion to recommit with or without instructions. Also, the resolution provides for one hour of debate on H.R. 3441 with one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08T13:43:26-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 607 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08T13:43:28-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Randy Hultgren to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08T13:43:57-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 3043.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08T14:53:15-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 607, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Grothman amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08T14:58:52-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 607, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Babin amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08T15:05:32-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 607, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jenkins (WV) amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08T15:10:11-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 607, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rush amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08T15:19:07-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Rush amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Rush demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08T15:19:33-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Upton moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08T15:19:44-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08T15:19:52-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 3043 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08T16:31:04-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8641-8642" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08T16:31:20-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08T16:31:34-05:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question on adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08T16:56:06-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 3043.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08T16:56:23-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08T16:57:07-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="620" datetime="2017-11-08T17:03:46-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 257 - 166 (Roll no. 620).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8630-8633" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08T17:03:48-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2274"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="724"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1460"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="unknown" number="607"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h481"/>
    <amendment number="h480"/>
    <amendment number="h479"/>
    <amendment number="h478"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2017-11-08T15:28:41Z" status="Passed House amended">Hydropower Policy Modernization Act of 2017

(Sec.2)This bill designates the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) as the lead agency for coordinating all federal authorizations and reviews related to hydropower license applications, including compliance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.FERC must establish a process to set a schedule for the review and disposition of each federal authorization following the filing of an application for a license.

The bill expands the definition of "renewable energy" to include electric energy generated from hydropower projects.The bill authorizes FERC to extend the length of time of preliminary permits and to extend the time limit that a licensee has to commence construction on a hydropower project.

(Sec.3)The bill authorizes the use of trial-type hearings to resolve disputes related to a hydropower license application. Under certain circumstances, the hearing may be demanded by applicants or other parties for any disputed issues of material fact.

FERC must consult with federal and state agencies and the public to compile best practices for performing studies and environmental reviews in connection with the timely and efficient completion of hydropower license proceedings.

The bill creates a process to approve license amendments for qualifying hydropower projects.

(Sec.5)The Department of Commerce and the Department of the Interior must consider the threat of invasive species when prescribing a fishway. (Fishways are structures placed on or around constructed barriers to give fish the opportunity to migrate.)

(Sec.6) FERC may examine the license for any project that is located in an area that was declared to be a disaster area in 2017.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-377</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
