<bill session="113" type="h" number="1685" updated="2016-10-25T16:02:33Z">
  <state datetime="2013-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Broadband Adoption Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to reform and modernize the Universal Service Fund Lifeline Assistance Program.</title>
    <title type="display">Broadband Adoption Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001163"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001251" joined="2013-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001066" joined="2014-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000197" joined="2013-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000482" joined="2013-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2013-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2013-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2013-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001166" joined="2013-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2013-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000215" joined="2013-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2013-04-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Communications and Technology" code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates and fees"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-04-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Broadband Adoption Act of 2013 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to direct the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to adopt a final rule establishing support for broadband under the Universal Service Fund Lifeline Assistance Program to enable qualifying low-income customers residing in urban and rural areas to purchase broadband service at reduced charges by reimbursing providers who elect to participate in the program for each such customer served.

Establishes a program model under which qualifying individuals may elect to apply support from the Lifeline program to basic telephone service, voice telephony service, or broadband service, whether each service is purchased stand-alone or in a bundle.

Authorizes the FCC to determine whether state matching funds may be provided as a condition of eligibility for low-income households within such state.

Requires the program to be technology neutral to promote competition from service providers.

Requires a broadband service provider that is not an eligible telecommunications carrier to obtain FCC authorization to participate in the program.

Directs the FCC to: (1) adopt regulations to prevent duplicative Lifeline subsidies from being awarded to an individual eligible household, and (2) establish a national database to determine consumer eligibility. Limits qualifying individuals to only one Lifeline program support amount per eligible household.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
