<bill session="114" type="h" number="1629" updated="2019-04-11T15:41:45Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Energy Conservation Policy Act to encourage the increased use of performance contracting in Federal facilities.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Savings Through Public-Private Partnerships Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Energy Savings Through Public-Private Partnerships Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000378"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000129" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2015-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy" code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="858"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="8"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Energy Savings Through Public-Private Partnerships Act of 2015

 This bill amends the National Energy Conservation Policy Act to revise requirements for energy savings performance and utility energy service contracts (performance contracts). (These contracts allow federal agencies to work with private contractors on energy efficiency upgrades to federal facilities.)

Each federal facility energy manager must provide an explanation regarding life cycle cost-effective measures that have not been implemented as part of the web-based compliance certification system. (Life cycle costs are the total cost of owning, operating, and maintaining a building over its useful life.)

The Department of Energy (DOE) must report to the President and Congress on each agency's performance contracts, including their investment value and their energy savings.

The energy conservation measures that may be contained in performance contracts are expanded by including those involving energy consuming devices and required support structures.

Agencies may not limit recognition of operation and maintenance savings associated with energy systems that were modernized or replaced with energy conservation measures and water conservation measures (e.g. lower energy and water bills due to energy efficiency and conservation measures).

Agencies may sell or transfer energy savings and apply the proceeds to fund a performance contract.

The energy savings that may be contained in performance contracts are expanded to include: (1) the use, sale, or transfer of energy incentives, rebates, or credits (including renewable energy credits) from governments or utilities; and (2) any revenue generated from a reduction in energy or water use, more efficient waste recycling, or additional energy generated from more efficient equipment.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
