<bill session="115" type="s" number="588" updated="2019-07-18T05:27:21Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Securities and Exchange Commission to clarify what constitutes a general solicitation under the Federal securities laws, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HALOS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HALOS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Angels Lead Our Startups Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Angels Lead Our Startups Act</title>
    <title type="display">HALOS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001169"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001071" joined="2018-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001069" joined="2017-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2017-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2017-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2017-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000461" joined="2017-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-26">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 115-354.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="79"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-09T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Helping Angels Lead Our Startups Act or the HALOS Act

This bill directs the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to revise Regulation D, which exempts certain offerings from SEC registration requirements but prohibits general solicitation or general advertising with respect to such offerings. Specifically, this prohibition shall not apply to events with specified kinds of sponsors, including "angel investor groups" unconnected to broker-dealers or investment advisers, where presentations or communications are made by or on behalf of an issuer but:

 the advertising does not refer to any specific offering of securities by the issuer; the sponsor does not provide investment recommendation or advice to attendees, engage in investment negotiations with attendees, charge certain fees, or receive certain compensation; and no specific information regarding a securities offering is communicated beyond&#160;the type and amount of securities being offered, the amount of securities already subscribed for, and the intended use of proceeds from the offering.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
