<bill session="114" type="h" number="1097" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:17Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ban Insider Trading Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to prohibit trading on material inside information.</title>
    <title type="display">Ban Insider Trading Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000562"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1173"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-26T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Ban Insider Trading Act of 2015

This bill amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to make it unlawful to purchase or sell any security, or securities-based swap agreement, that is based upon information that the person knows (or should know) is material inside information.

"Inside information" is defined as information that is nonpublic and obtained:

 illegally, directly or indirectly from an issuer who expects either confidentiality or that it will only be used for a legitimate business purpose, or in violation of a fiduciary duty. "Material information" is defined as information relating to an issuer or to a security which, if it were made public, would likely have a significant effect upon the security's price.

Subjects a person to liability to prosecution for trading in prohibited securities while in possession of material nonpublic information if the person, without a legitimate business purpose, discloses intentionally to another person information that the discloser knows (or should know) is material inside information.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
