<bill session="114" type="s" number="2295" updated="2018-06-02T07:12:02Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Liberty Through Strength Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend the termination date for the authority to collect certain records and make permanent the authority for roving surveillance and to treat individual terrorists as agents of foreign powers under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Liberty Through Strength Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001095"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2015-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000542" joined="2015-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2015-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2015-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2016-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2015-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000355" joined="2015-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2015-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2015-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2015-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2015-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001141" joined="2015-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2048"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2344"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4270"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-17T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Liberty Through Strength Act

This bill amends the USA FREEDOM Act of 2015 to postpone amendments to the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (FISA) that: (1) require the Federal Bureau of Investigation to use specific selection terms when applying for FISA court orders requiring the production of business records or other tangible things for an investigation to obtain foreign intelligence information not concerning a U.S. person or to protect against international terrorism or clandestine intelligence activities; (2) establish additional requirements for production on an ongoing basis of call detail records relating to an authorized investigation to protect against international terrorism; and (3) authorize the Department of Justice to require the emergency production of tangible things without first obtaining a court order. The bill postpones the effective date of these amendments, which are currently scheduled to take effect 180 days after the USA FREEDOM Act was enacted on June 2, 2015, to: (1) January 31, 2017; or (2) the date that the President certifies to Congress that such amendments will have no operational impacts on the intelligence community.

The bill also amends the USA PATRIOT Improvement and Reauthorization Act of 2005 and the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 to make permanent expiring FISA authorities concerning: (1) roving electronic surveillance orders, and (2) a revised definition of "agent of a foreign power" that includes any non-U.S. persons who engage in international terrorism or preparatory activities (commonly referred to as the "lone wolf" provision).</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
