<bill session="113" type="h" number="3863" updated="2016-10-25T16:10:07Z">
  <state datetime="2014-01-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sound Regulation Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to establish uniform requirements for thorough economic analysis of regulations by Federal agencies based on sound principles, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Sound Regulation Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000755"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2014-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000621" joined="2014-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000461" joined="2014-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000448" joined="2014-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2014-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000567" joined="2014-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001052" joined="2014-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001059" joined="2014-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000376" joined="2014-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000362" joined="2014-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2014-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000592" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001192" joined="2014-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000063" joined="2014-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" code="HSJU05" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2099"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-01-14T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Sound Regulation Act of 2014 - Establishes additional requirements for rulemaking under the Administrative Procedure Act (APA), including:

 identification by a federal agency, in the context of a coherent conceptual framework and supported with objective data,&#160;of the nature and significance of the market failure, regulatory failure, or other problem that necessitates regulatory action and why other alternatives, such as market forces or&#160;state or local regulations, could not&#160;address the problem better than federal regulation;&#160; establishment by an agency&#160;of an achievable objective for its regulatory action; development of at least three regulatory options, in addition to not regulating, that the agency estimates will provide the greatest benefits for the least cost in meeting the regulatory objective; an estimate by each agency&#160;of the costs and benefits of each regulatory option developed, at least to the extent the agency is able to exclude options whose costs exceed their benefits, and rank such options by cost from lowest to highest; publication for public comment of all analyses, documentation, and data relating to the requirements of this Act for a public comment period of at least 30 days; establishment, by rule, of the specific cost-benefit analysis methodology appropriate to the functions and responsibilities of the agency and establishment of an appropriate period for review of new rules to assess their cost-effectiveness; and justification of why the agency does not select the least-cost regulatory option as its proposed rule. Requires the Comptroller General (GAO), for purposes of congressional review, to examine and report on: (1)&#160;each agency cost-benefit analysis for compliance with the requirements of this Act, including&#160;the agency methodology for such analysis; (2) risk analysis pertaining to the cost-benefit analysis; and (3) agency quadrennial regulatory reviews for consistency with the requirements of this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
