<bill session="114" type="h" number="6253" updated="2018-11-21T20:31:18Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CERT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Collaborating for Economic Reintegration of Troops Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish an advisory commission to examine licensing and certification challenges confronting members of the Armed Forces and their spouses upon post-service entry into the civilian workforce and to make recommendations to Congress for the development of a new class of uniform veteran's certifications for selected occupations that can be accepted by States and United States territories.</title>
    <title type="display">CERT Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2016-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-10-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-10-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Collaborating for Economic Reintegration of Troops Act or the CERT Act

This bill establishes the Commission on Veteran Certification Standards which shall:

 examine the challenges confronting members of the Armed Forces and their spouses upon post-service entry into the civilian workforce; determine best state practices and evaluate efforts to assist members of the Armed Forces in obtaining professional credentials to facilitate the transfer of military skills and certifications to civilian settings; identify industries and jobs that can most benefit from military experience; develop recommended Blue Star credentialing standards and design evaluation criteria that the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs can use to evaluate state and territory utilization of such standards; and develop related administrative recommendations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
