<bill session="113" type="h" number="972" updated="2018-06-05T16:08:51Z">
  <state datetime="2013-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preserving Freedom from Unwarranted Surveillance Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect individual privacy against unwarranted governmental intrusion through the use of the unmanned aerial vehicles commonly called drones, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Preserving Freedom from Unwarranted Surveillance Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001189"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001271" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001053" joined="2013-04-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, And Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1016"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-03-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Preserving Freedom from Unwarranted Surveillance Act of 2013 - Prohibits a person or entity acting under the authority of the United States from using a drone to gather evidence or other information pertaining to criminal conduct or regulatory violations except to the extent authorized in a warrant issued under the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure.

Defines a "drone" as any powered, aerial vehicle that does not carry a human operator, uses aerodynamic forces to provide vehicle lift, and can fly autonomously or be piloted remotely, be expendable or recoverable, and carry a lethal or nonlethal payload.

Exempts from such prohibition the use of drones to: (1) patrol national borders to prevent or deter illegal entry of any immigrants or illegal substances, (2) prevent imminent danger to life or serious damage to property or to forestall the imminent escape of a suspect or destruction of evidence when drones are used by a law enforcement party under exigent circumstances, or (3) counter a high risk of a terrorist attack by a specific individual or organization based on credible intelligence determined by the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS).

Authorizes civil actions by aggrieved parties.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
