<bill session="113" type="h" number="2488" updated="2016-10-25T16:05:04Z">
  <state datetime="2013-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rogue Wilderness Area Expansion Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To expand the Wild Rogue Wilderness Area in the State of Oregon, to make additional wild and scenic river designations in the Rogue River area, to provide additional protections for Rogue River tributaries, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Rogue Wilderness Area Expansion Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2013-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2013-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001180" joined="2013-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="353"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1784"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="4"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2734"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-06-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Rogue Wilderness Area Expansion Act - Adds specified federal land managed by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) in the Wild Rogue Wilderness as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System.

Requires the part of the Rogue River, which lies within the Wild Rogue Wilderness, including the Wilderness additions, and was designated under the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act as a component of the System in 1968, to be managed as a wild river.

Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to add specified segments of creeks to the designation of the Rogue River in Oregon as a component of the national wild and scenic rivers system.

Prohibits: (1) the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) from licensing the construction of any dam, water conduit, reservoir, powerhouse, transmission line, or other project works affecting specified stream segments; and (2) any federal department or agency from assisting in the construction of any water resources project affecting any such segment, except for maintaining or repairing existing projects.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
