<bill session="114" type="s" number="1974" updated="2018-06-02T06:59:10Z">
  <state datetime="2015-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Relationship Lending Preservation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection to amend its regulations relating to qualified mortgages, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Relationship Lending Preservation Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001069"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2015-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-08-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-08-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6388-6389" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-08-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Relationship Lending Preservation Act of 2015

This bill directs the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau to issue regulations to include as a qualified mortgage any mortgage loan that: (1) is extended by a creditor that, together with its affiliates, has less than $10 billion in total consolidated assets and is a member of a Federal Home Loan Bank; (2) meets qualifying criteria of the Truth in Lending Act; (3) is eligible to be purchased by a Bank pursuant to its underwriting and documentation requirements; and (4) is eligible to be purchased and is held by a Bank pursuant to regulations of the Federal Housing Finance Agency.

The Bureau shall assess these regulations, addressing, among other relevant factors, their usage by community financial institutions, their impact on access to residential mortgage loans, and whether the Banks actually have established underwriting and documentation requirements.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
