<bill session="114" type="sr" number="333" updated="2018-06-02T06:18:48Z">
  <state datetime="2015-12-10">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-12-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution to direct the Senate Legal Counsel to appear as amicus curiae in the name of the Senate in Bank Markazi, The Central Bank of Iran v. Deborah D. Peterson, et al. (S. Ct.)</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution to direct the Senate Legal Counsel to appear as amicus curiae in the name of the Senate in Bank Markazi, The Central Bank of Iran v. Deborah D. Peterson, et al. (S. Ct.)</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000355"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000146" joined="2015-12-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2015-12-10" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8619" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S8610" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-12-10T14:18:52Z" status="Passed Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded becasue action occurred on the measure.)

Directs the Senate Legal Counsel to appear as amicus curiae on behalf of the Senate in the case of Bank Markazi, The Central Bank of Iran v. Deborah D. Peterson, et al., to defend the constitutionality of section 502 of the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012.

(Sec. 502 of that Act makes available for attachment, with respect to judgments against Iran for damages for personal injury or death caused by an act of torture, extrajudicial killing, aircraft sabotage, or hostage-taking, or the provision of material support or resources for such an act, any financial asset that is: (1) property in the United States of a foreign securities intermediary doing business in the United States, (2) a blocked asset that is property identified in and the subject of proceedings in Peterson et al. v. Islamic Republic of Iran et al., and (3) equal in value to a financial asset of Iran that such foreign securities intermediary or a related intermediary holds abroad.)</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
