<bill session="114" type="s" number="1031" updated="2018-06-02T06:45:41Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">WIOA Technical Amendments Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act to improve the Act.</title>
    <title type="display">WIOA Technical Amendments Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001111"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000360" joined="2015-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="1124"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="National Council on Disability"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">WIOA Technical Amendments Act

This bill amends the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (WIOA) to revise requirements for local workforce development area boards involved in statewide workforce investment activities as well as youth, adult, and dislocated worker employment and training activities.

A state may use as an alternative workforce development board only a local entity (including a local council, regional workforce development board, or similar entity) that was in existence the day before enactment of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998. Currently such an alternative local entity is eligible for designation as a local workforce development board if it has been in existence as late as the day before the enactment of the WIOA on July 22, 2014.

Certain technical amendments are made to performance accountability requirements for statewide and local workforce investment programs.

The Department of Labor shall ensure that states receive an allotment for a fiscal year for adult employment and training activities and for dislocated worker employment and training activities and statewide workforce investment activities equal to at least 90% of the state's allotment for the preceding fiscal year.

This bill amends the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 with respect to the terms of service requirements for members of the National Council on Disability, making them (unchanged in detail) effective only as of July 21, 2014.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
