<bill session="114" type="h" number="4890" updated="2018-11-09T00:09:27Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-21T11:13:01-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-04-21T11:13:01-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To impose a ban on the payment of bonuses to employees of the Internal Revenue Service until the Secretary of the Treasury develops and implements a comprehensive customer service strategy.</title>
    <title type="display">To impose a ban on the payment of bonuses to employees of the Internal Revenue Service until the Secretary of the Treasury develops and implements a comprehensive customer service strategy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2016-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 24 - 15.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-04-18">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 114-501.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-18" calendar="Union" number="383">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 383.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-04-18T18:59:51-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 688 Reported to House. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Resolution provides for the consideration of H.R. 4890 and H.R. 3724.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-21T09:58:10-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 688.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1905-1908, H1908-1911" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-21T09:58:15-04:00">
      <text>Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Resolution provides for the consideration of H.R. 4890 and H.R. 3724.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-21T09:58:55-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 688 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-21T09:58:56-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Rodney Davis to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-21T09:59:19-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 4890.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-21T10:31:34-04:00">
      <text>RISING INFORMALLY - The Committee of the Whole rose informally to receive a message. Subsequently the Committee resumed its' sitting.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-21T10:40:51-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 688, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Meehan amendment No. 1 printed in House Report 114-503.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-21T10:43:59-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 688, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Sanford amendment No. 2 printed in House Report 114-503.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-21T10:50:12-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 4890.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-21T10:50:49-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1910" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-21T10:51:22-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1909" label="text of measure in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="162" datetime="2016-04-21T11:13:01-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 260 - 158 (Roll no. 162).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-04-21T11:13:03-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="114" relation="unknown" number="688"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Employee performance"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h981"/>
    <amendment number="h980"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2016-04-21T13:46:04Z" status="Passed House amended">(Sec. 1) This bill prohibits the Department of the Treasury from paying a bonus, award, or similar cash payment to any Internal Revenue Service (IRS) employee until Treasury develops and submits to Congress a comprehensive customer service strategy that has been reviewed and approved by the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration.

 The strategy must include: (1) appropriate telephone and correspondence levels of service; (2) a thorough assessment of which services the IRS can shift to self-service options; and (3) proposals to improve customer service over the short-term, the medium-term, and the long-term.

In developing the strategy, Treasury must consult with the National Taxpayer Advocate.

Treasury must submit semiannual reports to Congress on the status of its customer service strategy and actions taken to improve customer service.

(Sec. 2) No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available to carry out this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-501</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
