<bill session="113" type="h" number="85" updated="2018-06-05T15:57:51Z">
  <state datetime="2013-04-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To create the Office of Chief Financial Officer of the Government of the Virgin Islands, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To create the Office of Chief Financial Officer of the Government of the Virgin Islands, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000380"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-24">
      <text>Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-04-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-06-17">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-110.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-06-17" calendar="Union" number="78">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 78.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" code="HSII22" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1237"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2200"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-06-17T12:59:34Z" status="Reported to House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Requires the Governor of the Virgin Islands to appoint a Chief Financial Officer, with the advice and consent of the Legislature of the Virgin Islands, from a list required by this Act. States that, if the Legislature has not confirmed a nominee within 90 days, the Governor shall appoint an Acting Chief Financial Officer until the Legislature consents to a Chief Financial Officer. Requires the Virgin Islands Chief Financial Officer Search Commission to appoint an Acting Chief Financial Officer from the list, until a Chief Financial Officer is appointed, if one has not been appointed within 180 days. Requires any Acting Chief Financial Officer serving in that capacity for 180 consecutive days to become the Chief Financial Officer.

Sets forth the Chief Financial Officer's duties.

Directs the Board of Elections of the Virgin Islands, as part of the regularly scheduled, islands-wide election in the Virgin Islands closest to the expiration of the fourth year of the five-year term of the Chief Financial Officer, to hold a referendum to determine whether the position of Chief Financial Officer shall be made a permanent part of the executive branch of the government of the Virgin Islands.

Establishes the Virgin Islands Chief Financial Officer Search Commission to recommend at least three candidates for the Chief Financial Officer position. Terminates the Commission upon the nomination and confirmation of the Chief Financial Officer.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 113-110</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
