<bill session="114" type="h" number="1207" updated="2019-02-08T20:13:06Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Healthy Fisheries through Better Science Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act to require the Secretary of Commerce to develop a plan to conduct stock assessments for all stocks of fish for which a fishery management plan is in effect under that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Healthy Fisheries through Better Science Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000804"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water, Oceans, and Wildlife" code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-02T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Healthy Fisheries through Better Science Act

This bill amends the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act&#160;to require the Department of Commerce to develop and publish a plan to conduct stock assessments for all stocks of fish for which a fishery management plan is in effect. A "stock assessment" is an evaluation of the past, present, and future status of a stock of fish, including: (1) a range of life history characteristics, including the stock's geographical boundaries, age, growth, natural mortality, sexual maturity and reproduction, feeding habits, and habitat preferences; and (2) fishing for the stock. The plan must be developed and published on the same schedule as required for the fisheries research strategic plan.

The plan must: (1) establish schedules for conducting initial stock assessments and updating previously conducted assessments, and (2) identify data and analysis that would reduce uncertainty in and improve the accuracy of future stock assessments. A stock assessment is not required for a stock of fish in the plan if Commerce determines that the assessment is not necessary and justifies the determination in the Federal Register notice.

Commerce must develop and publish in the Federal Register guidelines to incorporate data, analysis, and stock assessments from nongovernmental sources into fisheries management decisions and to establish a registry of information providers. Commerce and Regional Fishery Management Councils must use all data and analyses that meet the guidelines published as the best scientific information available in fisheries management decisions, unless otherwise determined by the science and statistical committees of the Councils.

Commerce may not collect certain fishing permit fees and North Pacific Council fisheries research plan implementation fees before identifying the costs that will be recovered by such fee.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
