<bill session="114" type="h" number="5956" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:47Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">YOUTH Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Youth Opioid Use Treatment Help Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to better address substance use and substance use disorders among young people.</title>
    <title type="display">YOUTH Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001101"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001275" joined="2016-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000287" joined="2016-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2016-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000486" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2016-12-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-08T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Youth Opioid Use Treatment Help Act of 2016 or the YOUTH Act

This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to revise and reauthorize through FY2022 grants for substance abuse treatment services for children and adolescents. The grant program is expanded to cover young adults.

The Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ) must award grants for demonstration programs to: (1) expand access to medication-assisted treatment for opioid use disorders among adolescents and young adults, or (2) create and distribute for pediatric health care providers resources on medication-assisted treatment training and implementation.

AHRQ must report on the demonstration programs and the availability of medication-assisted treatment for adolescents and young adults. The report must include recommendations for ensuring such treatment is accessible.

The Government Accountability Office must study how federal agencies are addressing substance use and substance use disorders among adolescents and young adults.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
