<amendment session="114" chamber="h" number="527" updated="2019-04-11T15:39:37Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2042" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2015-06-24T16:56:55-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000515"/>
  <offered datetime="2015-06-24"/>
  <description>Amendment sought to require a Governor's determination to include certification that the inapplicability of a state or federal plan will not have a significant adverse effect on costs associated with a state's plan to respond to extreme weather events associated with human-caused climate change, including flooding, intense storms, frequent wildfires, and increased drought.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 2 printed in House Report 114-177 to require a governor's determination and shall also include certification that the inapplicability of a state or federal plan will not have a significant adverse effect on costs associated with a State's plan to respond to extreme weather events associated with human-caused climate change, including flooding, intense storms, frequent wildfires, and increased drought.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2015-06-24T16:56:55-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="382">
      <text>On agreeing to the Rush amendment (A002) Failed by recorded vote: 182 - 243 (Roll no. 382).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-06-24T15:44:54-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Rush.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4626-4627, H4630-4631" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4626" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-24"/>
    <action datetime="2015-06-24T15:44:54-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Rush.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4626-4627, H4630-4631" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4626" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-24T16:56:55-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-24T16:56:55-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-24T16:56:55-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Rush amendment (A002) Failed by recorded vote: 182 - 243 (Roll no. 382).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-24">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
