<bill session="114" type="s" number="1569" updated="2019-04-11T15:42:24Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require a review of the adequacy of existing procedures to ensure at least one employee of the personal office of each Senator serving on a committee that requires access to top secret and sensitive compartmented information may obtain the security clearances necessary for the employee to have access to such information.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to require a review of the adequacy of existing procedures to ensure at least one employee of the personal office of each Senator serving on a committee that requires access to top secret and sensitive compartmented information may obtain the security clearances necessary for the employee to have access to such information.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2015-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2015-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill requires the Director of Senate Security, in coordination with the Director of National Intelligence and the Chairperson of the Suitability and Security Clearance Performance Accountability Council, to:

 review whether procedures in effect enable one Senate employee designated by each Member of the Senate, who serves on specified Senate committees or subcommittees, to obtain security clearances necessary for access to classified national security information, including top secret and sensitive compartmentalized information, if the Senate employee meets the criteria for such clearances; and issue guidelines on establishment and implementation of new procedures if the Director, in coordination with the Director of National Intelligence and the Chairperson, determines current procedures are inadequate.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
