<bill session="113" type="h" number="5357" updated="2016-10-25T16:16:03Z">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Saint Francis Dam Disaster National Memorial Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize a national memorial to commemorate those killed by the collapse of the Saint Francis Dam on March 12, 1928, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Saint Francis Dam Disaster National Memorial Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000508"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2014-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-07-31T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Saint Francis Dam Disaster National Memorial Act - Establishes: (1) the Saint Francis Dam Disaster National Memorial at the Saint Francis Dam site in Los Angeles County, California, to honor the victims of the Saint Francis Dam disaster of March 12, 1928; (2) the Saint Francis Dam Disaster National Monument; and (3) the Saint Francis Dam Advisory Commission.

Requires the Commission to:

 report recommendations for the planning, design, construction, and long-term management of the Memorial; advise the Secretary of the Interior on the boundaries of the Memorial; and consult and coordinate with the Saint Francis Dam Task Force and the state of California to support the efforts of the Task Force to commemorate the disaster. Terminates the Commission upon dedication of the completed Memorial.

Authorizes the Secretary to:

 provide assistance to the Commission and the Task Force, participate in the formulation of plans for the design of the Memorial, acquire lands for the Memorial, accept funds raised by the Commission for construction of the Memorial, construct the Memorial, and administer the Memorial as a unit of the National Park System. Requires the Secretary to: (1) manage the Monument in a manner that conserves, protects, and enhances its resources; and (2) develop a management plan for the Monument.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
