<bill session="114" type="s" number="1100" updated="2018-08-16T23:01:10Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prescribed Burn Approval Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require State and local government approval of prescribed burns on Federal land during conditions of drought or fire danger.</title>
    <title type="display">Prescribed Burn Approval Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001069" joined="2016-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred sequentially to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry by unanimous consent with instructions that if the bill is reported by that Committee, the bill be referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-16">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6029"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3395"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Prescribed Burn Approval Act of 2015

Bars any federal agency from authorizing a prescribed burn on federal land if, for the county or contiguous county in which the federal land is located, the grassland fire danger index indicates a high, very high, or extreme danger of grassland fire or the Forest Service has declared a very high or extreme fire danger, unless the agency obtains prior approval from the applicable state government and local fire officials.

Makes a federal agency that authorizes a prescribed burn liable for any damage to private property, notwithstanding the Federal Tort Claims Act or any state law.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
