<bill session="113" type="s" number="2150" updated="2016-10-25T16:29:23Z">
  <state datetime="2014-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Independent Innovator and Repurposing Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to advance the public health by encouraging independent innovators to pursue drug repurposing research and develop new treatments and cures by providing appropriate intellectual property protections for those innovations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Independent Innovator and Repurposing Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2014-03-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="identical" number="4287"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-03-24T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Independent Innovator and Repurposing Act - Establishes procedures under which the term of an unexpired patent claiming a method of using a biological product shall be extended for five years from its original expiration date.

 Requires an application for such an extension to demonstrate that: (1) the patent was issued to an independent innovator, and (2) the owner of record is the independent innovator or a small business (with fewer than 500 employees and which is not affiliated with the holder of the marketing application approved under licensing requirements of the Public Health Service Act for the commercial marketing of such biological product) in which the independent innovator has an ownership interest.

Defines "independent innovator" as a person or entity that obtains a method of use patent for a biological product and is not, at the time of invention or patent filing, affiliated with the holder of an approved application for the commercial marketing of the product.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
