<bill session="115" type="s" number="2340" updated="2019-04-18T16:41:11Z">
  <state datetime="2018-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Federal Labor-Management Partnership Council.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Labor-Management Partnership Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Labor-Management Partnership Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Federal Labor-Management Partnership Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2018-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2018-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2018-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2018-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2018-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2018-01-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-01-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="4878"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-01-25T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Federal Labor-Management Partnership Act of 2018

This bill establishes the Federal Labor-Management Partnership Council to: (1) advise the President on matters involving labor-management relations in the executive branch; (2) collect and disseminate information about and provide guidance on partnership efforts in the executive branch, including the results of those efforts; and (3) use the expertise of individuals, both inside and outside the federal government, to foster partnership arrangements in the executive branch.

 The head of each agency that is subject to authority permitting employees of the agency to select an exclusive representative shall take the following actions: (1) create labor-management partnerships by forming labor-management committees or councils at appropriate levels, or adapting existing committees or councils if such groups exist; (2) involve employees and employee representatives as full partners with management representatives to improve the civil service to better serve the public and carry out the mission of the agency; (3) provide systemic training of appropriate agency employees (including line managers, first-line supervisors, and labor organization representatives) in consensual methods of dispute resolution; (4) allow employees and employee representatives to have pre-decisional involvement in all workplace matters to the fullest extent practicable, without regard to whether those matters are negotiable subjects of bargaining; and (5) evaluate progress and improvements in organizational performance resulting from labor-management partnerships.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
