<bill session="114" type="s" number="190" updated="2018-08-16T23:11:03Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Imported Seafood Safety Standards Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to ensure the safety of imported seafood.</title>
    <title type="display">Imported Seafood Safety Standards Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000127"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-06">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Hearings"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Seafood"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-20T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Imported Seafood Safety Standards Act

Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to prohibit the importation of any seafood from a foreign country unless the country complies with U.S. standards for seafood manufacturing, processing, and holding. Requires an annual inspection of each foreign facility that exports seafood to the United States to ensure compliance with U.S. standards. Requires periodic follow-up inspections of foreign facilities as determined necessary by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA).

Requires the FDA to inspect and test not less than 20% of all imported seafood each year and the first 15 shipments of seafood imported from a new exporter. Sets forth procedures in the event an exporter fails to meet inspection or test requirements.

Directs the FDA to refuse entry of all seafood shipments from a country that repeatedly fails to meet inspection or testing requirements and establish exporter fees as necessary.

Requires the detention or destruction of imported seafood that fails to meet safety standards unless the shipment meets criteria for re-export.

Allows importation of seafood at only those U.S. ports of entry that have the personnel trained to conduct the applicable testing and inspections.

Prohibits making a knowingly false statement with respect to a test or inspection under this Act or knowingly misbranding any seafood imported under this Act. Establishes a civil penalty for violations.

Authorizes the FDA to establish a program under which a state may conduct inspection, testing, and certification of U.S. seafood imports.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
