<bill session="114" type="s" number="756" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:19Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-14">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Syrian War Crimes Accountability Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Syrian War Crimes Accountability Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Syrian War Crimes Accountability Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require a report on accountability for war crimes and crimes against humanity in Syria.</title>
    <title type="display">Syrian War Crimes Accountability Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2015-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2015-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2015-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2015-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2015-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2015-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-06-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-06-11">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Corker without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-06-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="117">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 117.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2015-07-14" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5088-5089" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5088-5089" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-07-15">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-15T12:06:54-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-14T15:40:37Z" status="Passed Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the Senate reported version is repeated here.)

Syrian War Crimes Accountability Act of 2015 

(Sec. 3) Declares that Congress:

 condemns the ongoing violence, use of chemical weapons, targeting of civilian populations, and systematic gross human rights violations carried out by government of Syria and pro-government forces under the direction of President Bashar al-Assad, as well as abuses committed by extremist groups and other combatants involved in the civil war in Syria; supports the people of Syria seeking democratic change; urges all parties to the conflict to halt attacks on civilians; calls on the President to support efforts in Syria and on the part of the international community to ensure accountability for war crimes and crimes against humanity committed during the conflict; and calls for a United Nations Security Council investigation into gross violations of human rights and war crimes committed during the Syrian conflict. (Sec. 4) Requires the Department of State to report to Congress regarding war crimes and crimes against humanity in Syria, including descriptions of:

 violations of internationally recognized human rights, war crimes, and crimes against humanity perpetrated during the civil war in Syria; and efforts by the Department and the U.S. Agency for International Development to ensure accountability for violations of internationally recognized human rights, international humanitarian law, and crimes against humanity perpetrated in Syria by the regime of President Bashar al-Assad, violent extremist groups, and other combatants involved in the conflict.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
