<bill session="114" type="h" number="4776" updated="2018-11-21T20:17:18Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Landslide Loss Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a national program to identify landslide hazards and reduce loss from landslides, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">National Landslide Loss Reduction Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000617"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2016-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2016-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2016-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001064" joined="2016-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2016-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000368" joined="2016-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2016-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2016-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2016-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2016-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2016-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000510" joined="2016-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001193" joined="2016-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Environment" code="HSSY18" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Earth sciences"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">National Landslide Loss Reduction Act

This bill requires the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) to establish a national program to identify landslide hazards and reduce losses from landslides.

The USGS shall:

 develop a national strategy for research on landslides and landslide hazards; develop and maintain a landslide hazard assessment system and a national landslide hazard inventory database; in coordination with state geological surveys, conduct federal-state working groups to establish regional priorities for identifying, mapping, and assessing hazards and develop and implement guidelines for geologists and geological and geotechnical engineers; compile, maintain, and evaluate data on landslide hazard stabilization and reduction of losses and on the nationwide impact of landslides on health and safety, the economy, and the environment; and in coordination with the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), the National Weather Service (NWS), the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), and state geological surveys, develop and disseminate guidelines and training materials (in coordination with specified entities) for planners and decision makers on the use of the system and reducing losses from landslides. NOAA and the NWS shall develop and disseminate landslide-related curricula and training modules for state and local officials and emergency managers.

The bill establishes an Interagency Coordinating Committee on Landslides and an Advisory Committee on Landslides.

 The Department of the Interior shall make grants to support: (1) state and local government efforts to map and assess landslide hazards; and (2) efforts by institutions of higher education, state and local governments, and nongovernmental entities to research landslides.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
