<bill session="113" type="h" number="2985" updated="2016-10-25T16:06:50Z">
  <state datetime="2013-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Combination Drug Development Incentive Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to provide incentives for the development of new combination drugs.</title>
    <title type="display">Combination Drug Development Incentive Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000556" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001179" joined="2014-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001142" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000018" joined="2013-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Product development and innovation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-08-02T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Combination Drug Development Incentive Act of 2013 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to the five-year bar on a new drug application (or abbreviated drug application) by anyone that has not obtained a right of reference or use from the original and approved drug approval applicant by or for whom investigations under the original, subsequently approved application were conducted.

Applies this five-year bar, and the requirement of a grant of a right of reference or use, with respect to an approved drug application (or abbreviated drug application) if: (1) the application contains reports of new clinical investigations (other than bioavailability studies) essential to the approval of the application and conducted or sponsored by the applicant, (2) the application is for a drug which contains a combination of active ingredients (combination drug), and (3) no such combination of active ingredients has been approved in any other application.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
