<bill session="115" type="s" number="1597" updated="2019-04-18T16:38:07Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to permit the Secretary of the Treasury and the Commissioner of the Social Security Administration to disclose certain return information related to identity theft, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Social Security Identity Defense Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Social Security Identity Defense Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Social Security Identity Defense Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000293"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Social Security Identity Defense Act of 2017 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to require the Department of the Treasury and the Social Security Administration (SSA) to disclose certain tax return information in cases of identity theft.

If Treasury believes that there has been a fraudulent use of a Social Security number on a statement submitted regarding wages paid to employees, Treasury must disclose to the individual who was validly assigned the Social Security number: (1) that there is reason to believe that there has been a fraudulent use of such account number in an employment context, and (2) other information that Treasury determines would be helpful and appropriate to provide to a victim of identity theft.

If the SSA believes that the Social Security number included on such a statement is not the correct number for an employee, the SSA must provide a notification to the employer that includes: (1) the name of the employee and the Social Security number included on the statements, and (2) relevant information regarding the availability of the Social Security Number Verification Service.

The bill also imposes new criminal and civil penalties for tax-related identity theft and misappropriation of tax identification numbers.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
