<bill session="113" type="h" number="3516" updated="2016-10-25T16:08:47Z">
  <state datetime="2013-11-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans and Armed Forces Health Promotion Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve health care furnished by the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Department of Defense by increasing access to complementary and alternative medicine and other approaches to wellness and preventive care, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Veterans and Armed Forces Health Promotion Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000577"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000292" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000455" joined="2014-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2014-01-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2014-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000385" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000188" joined="2014-01-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001171" joined="2014-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000185" joined="2013-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000599" joined="2013-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001170" joined="2013-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000467" joined="2013-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000465" joined="2013-12-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="852"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Alternative treatments"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-11-15T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans and Armed Forces Health Promotion Act of 2013 - Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to jointly develop and implement: (1) a plan to expand materially and substantially the scope of research and education on, and delivery of holistic care that includes, the integration of appropriate complementary and alternative medicine interventions in the delivery of health care to veterans and members of the Armed Forces at military medical treatment facilities; and (2) a three-year pilot program to establish not fewer than five jointly-operated medical treatment and research facilities.

Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out: (1) a 3-year pilot program, through the Office of Patient Centered Care and Cultural Transformation of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), to assess the feasibility and advisability of establishing not fewer than 10 complementary and alternative medicine centers within VA medical centers to promote the use and integration of complementary and alternative medicine services for mental health diagnoses and pain management; (2) a 3-year pilot program, through grants to nonprofit entities, to assess the feasibility and advisability of using wellness programs at VA facilities to complement the provision of mental health care to veterans and family members eligible for counseling; (3) a 3-year pilot program, through the National Center for Preventive Health, to assess the feasibility and advisability of promoting health in covered veterans at not less than 15 VA medical centers through support for fitness center membership or medical nutrition therapy; and (4) a 2-year pilot program under which the Secretary makes grants to nonprofit veterans services organizations (VSOs) to upgrade VSO community facilities into health and wellness centers in at least 10 different geographic locations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
