<bill session="113" type="h" number="5754" updated="2016-10-25T16:17:25Z">
  <state datetime="2014-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Evidence-Based Policymaking Commission Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Commission on Evidence-Based Policymaking, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Evidence-Based Policymaking Commission Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000570"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="identical" number="2952"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="General taxation matters"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Policy sciences"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-11-20T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Evidence-Based Policymaking Commission Act of 2014 - Establishes in the executive branch a Commission on Evidence-Based Policymaking. Directs the Commission to conduct a comprehensive study of the data inventory, data infrastructure, and statistical protocols related to federal policymaking and the statistical and programmatic agencies responsible for maintaining that data to:

 determine the optimal arrangement for which administrative data on federal programs and tax expenditures and related data series may be integrated and made available to facilitate program evaluation, policy-relevant research, and cost-benefit analyses by qualified researchers and institutions; make recommendations on how data infrastructure and protocols should be modified to best fulfill those objectives; and make recommendations on how best to incorporate outcomes measurement, institutionalize randomized controlled trials, and rigorous impact analysis into program design. Requires the Commission to consider if and how to create a clearinghouse for program and survey data.

Terminates the Commission not later than 18 months after enactment of this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
