<bill session="114" type="h" number="3996" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:21Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-20">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Surface Transportation Extension Act of 2015, Part II</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Surface Transportation Extension Act of 2015, Part II</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Surface Transportation Extension Act of 2015, Part II</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Surface Transportation Extension Act of 2015, Part II</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide an extension of Federal-aid highway, highway safety, motor carrier safety, transit, and other programs funded out of the Highway Trust Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Surface Transportation Extension Act of 2015, Part II</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001154"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000755" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000263" joined="2015-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, Ways and Means, Natural Resources, and Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, Ways and Means, Natural Resources, and Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, Ways and Means, Natural Resources, and Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, Ways and Means, Natural Resources, and Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, Ways and Means, Natural Resources, and Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16T19:23:21-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Hardy moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16T19:23:51-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8213-8217" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16T19:23:53-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3996.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2015-11-16T19:29:29-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8213-8216" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16T19:29:31-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-17">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="2015-11-19" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8126" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-11-19">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2015-11-19">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2015-11-20" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="114-87" type="public" datetime="2015-11-20">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 114-87.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-21T04:59:58Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the House passed version is repeated here.)

Surface Transportation Extension Act of 2015, Part II

(Sec. 1) This bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to reduce the amount apportioned for a surface transportation program, project, or activity for FY2016 by amounts apportioned or allocated pursuant to the Surface Transportation Extension Act of 2015 for the period from October 1, 2015, through November 20, 2015.

TITLE I--SURFACE TRANSPORTATION PROGRAM EXTENSION

Subtitle A--Federal-Aid Highways

(Sec. 1001) The Highway and Transportation Funding Act of 2014 is amended to continue from October 1, 2015, through December 4, 2015, and appropriations are authorized through that period for, specified federal-aid highway programs under:

 the Moving Ahead for Progress in the 21st Century Act (MAP-21), the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (SAFETEA-LU) Technical Corrections Act of 2008, SAFETEA-LU, the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century (TEA-21), the National Highway System Designation Act of 1995, the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 (ISTEA), and other specified law. Funding for such programs shall be subject generally to the same manner of distribution, administration, limitation, and availability for obligation, but at a specified pro rata of the total amount, as funds authorized for appropriation out of the Highway Trust Fund (HTF) for such programs and activities for FY2014.

MAP-21 is amended to authorize appropriations out of the general fund of the Treasury for the Tribal High Priority Projects program for the same period.

The obligation ceiling for federal-aid highway and highway safety construction programs shall be $7,134,218,915 for the same period.

(Sec. 1002) Appropriations are authorized from the HTF (other than the Mass Transit Account) for administrative expenses of the federal-aid highway program for the same period.

Subtitle B--Extension of Highway Safety Programs

(Sec. 1101) Authorization of appropriations shall be extended for the same period for National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) safety programs, including:

 highway safety research and development, national priority safety programs, the National Driver Register, the High Visibility Enforcement Program, and NHTSA administrative expenses. SAFETEA-LU is amended to extend for the same period high-visibility traffic safety law enforcement campaigns under the High Visibility Enforcement Program.

There shall be set aside a specified amount of the total apportionment to states for highway safety programs for a cooperative program to research and evaluate priority highway safety countermeasures for the same period.

(Sec. 1102) Authorization of appropriations shall be extended for the same period for Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA) programs, including:

 motor carrier safety grants, FMCSA administrative expenses, commercial driver's license program improvement grants, border enforcement grants, performance and registration information system management grants, commercial vehicle information systems and networks deployment grants, safety data improvement grants, a set-aside for high priority activities that improve commercial motor vehicle safety and compliance with commercial motor vehicle safety regulations, a set-aside for new entrant motor carrier audit grants, FMCSA outreach and education, and the commercial motor vehicle operators grant program. (Sec. 1103) The Dingell-Johnson Sport Fish Restoration Act is amended to continue, for the same period, the authorized distribution of funds for coastal wetlands, recreational boating safety, projects under the Clean Vessel Act of 19921, boating infrastructure projects, and the National Outreach and Communications Program.

Subtitle C--Public Transportation Programs

(Sec. 1201) The apportionment of nonurbanized (rural) area formula grants shall be extended for the same period for competitive grants and formula grants for public transportation on Indian reservations.

(Sec. 1202) The apportionment of urbanized area formula grants shall be extended for the same period for passenger ferry projects.

(Sec. 1203) Authorization of appropriations shall be extended for the same period from the HTF Mass Transit Account for:

 formula grants for public transportation, including allocations for specified projects; research, development demonstration, and deployment projects; the transit cooperative research program; technical assistance and standards development grants; human resources and training grants; capital investment grants; and administrative expenses. (Sec. 1204) Allocations of certain amounts shall be made for the same period to states and territories for formula bus and bus facilities grants.

Subtitle D--Hazardous Materials

(Sec. 1301) Authorization of appropriations shall be made for the same period for hazardous materials (hazmat) transportation safety projects.

 DOT is authorized to make certain expenditures, including an amount for hazmat training grants, from the Hazardous Materials Emergency Preparedness Fund for the same period.

TITLE II--REVENUE PROVISIONS

(Sec. 2001) The Internal Revenue Code is amended to extend through December 4, 2015, the authority for expenditures from: (1) the HTF Highway and Mass Transit Accounts, (2) the Sport Fish Restoration and Boating Trust Fund, and (3) the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
