<bill session="114" type="s" number="2919" updated="2019-03-03T14:41:08Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to provide greater flexibility to States in carrying out the Disabled Veterans' Outreach Program and employing local veterans' employment representatives, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">State Outreach for Local Veterans Employment Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="display">State Outreach for Local Veterans Employment Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000461"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2016-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 114-702.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="5190"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">State Outreach for Local Veterans Employment Act of 2016

This bill prohibits the Department of Labor from rejecting a disabled veterans training and employment outreach plan submitted by a state based solely on which agency the state selected to carry out the plan.

Labor shall encourage each state to: (1) colocate its disabled veterans outreach program specialists and local veterans employment representatives with one or more one-stop centers, and (2) tailor its plan to meet the employment and training needs of in-state veterans.

If a plan addresses a significant employment barrier, a state may propose such barriers as appropriate in order to allow additional categories of veterans to receive outreach and local veterans employment representative services.

 Labor shall, if it objects to only a portion of a state's plan: (1) approve those portions of the plan that it does not object to, (2) submit to the state an explanation of which portions were not approved and why, and (3) allow the state to submit revisions to such portions for approval.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
