<bill session="114" type="h" number="1765" updated="2019-02-12T19:45:23Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to submit a report regarding certain plans regarding assistance to applicants and grantees during the response to an emergency or disaster.</title>
    <title type="display">To require the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to submit a report regarding certain plans regarding assistance to applicants and grantees during the response to an emergency or disaster.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001053"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1471"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Directs the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to report to Congress regarding its plans to provide: (1) consistent guidance to applicants on FEMA disaster funding procedures during the response to an emergency or disaster, (2) appropriate record maintenance and transfer of documents to new teams during staff transitions, and (3) accurate assistance to applicants and grantees to ease the administrative burden throughout the process of obtaining and monitoring assistance.

Requires the report to: (1) include a plan for implementing operating procedures and document retention requirements to ensure the maintenance of appropriate records throughout the life cycle of the emergency or disaster; and (2) identify new technologies to aid the disaster workforce in partnering with state, local, and tribal governments and private nonprofits in the wake of a disaster or emergency to educate, assist, and inform applicants on the status of their applications and projects.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
