<bill session="113" type="h" number="1575" updated="2016-10-25T16:02:13Z">
  <state datetime="2014-07-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Kelsey Smith Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Kelsey Smith Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to require a provider of a commercial mobile service or an IP-enabled voice service to provide call location information concerning the user of such a service to law enforcement agencies in order to respond to a call for emergency services or in an emergency situation that involves risk of death or serious physical harm.</title>
    <title type="display">Kelsey Smith Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000290" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000602" joined="2013-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-01-02">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 113-729, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-02">
      <text>Referred sequentially to the House Committee on the Judiciary for a period ending not later than Jan. 2, 2015 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendments as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(l) of rule X.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-02">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-01-02" calendar="Union" number="560">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 560.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Communications and Technology" code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="identical" number="721"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-02T12:27:53Z" status="Reported to House amended, Part I">Kelsey Smith Act - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require a provider of a commercial mobile service or an IP-enabled voice service to furnish call location information concerning the telecommunications device of a user of such service at the request of an investigative or law enforcement officer.

Requires such a request to be accompanied by a sworn written statement from such officer stating facts that support that officer's probable cause to believe that disclosure without delay is required: (1) by an emergency involving risk of death or serious physical injury, or (2) in order to respond to the user's call for emergency services. Requires the law enforcement agency of such officer, within 48 hours after the officer makes such a request, to request a court order stating whether such officer had probable cause to believe that such conditions existed at the time of the request.

Shields a telecommunications carrier from any cause of action in any court or any civil or administrative proceeding commenced by a governmental entity for providing call location information in good faith in accordance with this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 113-729</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
