<bill session="114" type="h" number="5570" updated="2019-02-13T17:31:23Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Western Colorado Wilderness Study Area Release Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To release a Wilderness Study Area administered by the Bureau of Land Management in Jackson County, Colorado, that was not found suitable for wilderness designation, and to release residual Wilderness Study Area acreage in Mesa and Delta Counties, Colorado, that were excluded from their respective wilderness designations from continued management for wilderness characteristics.</title>
    <title type="display">Western Colorado Wilderness Study Area Release Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000470"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Western Colorado Wilderness Study Area Release Act

This bill releases the following areas in Colorado from further review for designation as wilderness: (1) any public lands in the North Sand Hills Instant Study Area, (2) any portions of the Dominguez Canyon Wilderness Study Area within the Dominguez-Escalante National Conservation Area not designated as wilderness, and (3) any portions of the Black Ridge Canyons Wilderness Study Area within the McInnis Canyons National Conservation Area not designated as wilderness.

The bill states that in areas in which the Colorado River is used as a reference for defining the boundary of McInnis Canyons National Conservation Area, the boundary shall: (1) be located at the edge of the river, and (2) change according to the river's level.

The bill prohibits the inclusion of any portion of the Colorado River, regardless of its level, within the conservation area.

The Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 is amended to authorize the Department of the Interior to enter into land exchanges within the conservation area which would enhance the values for which it was established.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
