<bill session="113" type="s" number="2239" updated="2016-10-25T16:29:44Z">
  <state datetime="2014-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Social Security Identity Defense Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to permit the Secretary of the Treasury to disclose certain return information related to identity theft, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Social Security Identity Defense Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000293"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2014-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="926"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-04-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Social Security Identity Defense Act of 2014 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to require the Secretary of the Treasury to make certain disclosures to individuals who were validly assigned a social security account number and to the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) if the Secretary determines that there is a substantial likelihood that there has been a fraudulent use of such account number in the employment context. Authorizes the FBI Director to disclose information received from the Secretary to federal, state, and local law enforcement officials, provided such an official enters into a memorandum of understanding regarding the confidentiality of such information, but restricts the use of such information to carrying out criminal investigations or prosecutions.

Requires employers who have been notified of suspected misuse of an employee's social security account number to cease including such account number on statements provided to such employee.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
