<bill session="114" type="s" number="2574" updated="2018-06-02T07:15:03Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Modernizing the Interstate Placement of Children in Foster Care Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title IV of the Social Security Act to require States to adopt a centralized electronic system to help expedite the placement of children in foster care or guardianship, or for adoption, across State lines, and to provide grants to aid States in developing such a system, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Modernizing the Interstate Placement of Children in Foster Care Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2016-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2016-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2016-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2016-02-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="4472"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3065"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-24T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Modernizing the Interstate Placement of Children in Foster Care Act

This bill amends part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of title IV of the Social Security Act to require the procedures a state must have in effect for the orderly and timely interstate placement of children to include a centralized electronic case processing system.

Grants are authorized for development of a centralized electronic system to expedite the interstate placement of children in foster care, guardianship, or adoptive homes.

Discretionary funding shall be continued through FY2017 to promote safe and stable families.

The Department of Health and Human Services shall reserve $5 million of the amount made available for such grants for FY2017, which reserved amount shall remain available through FY2021.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
