<amendment session="113" chamber="h" number="1141" updated="2016-10-25T13:06:47Z">
  <amends type="hj" number="124" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2014-09-17T17:08:07-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000508"/>
  <offered datetime="2014-09-16"/>
  <description>Amendment authorizes the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of State, to train and equip appropriately vetted elements of the Syrian opposition and other appropriately vetted Syrian groups or individuals; strengthens congressional oversight by requiring detailed reports (including progress reports) on the plan, vetting process, and procedures for monitoring unauthorized end-use of provided training and equipment; requires the President to report on how this authority fits within a larger regional strategy; allows DOD to submit a reprogramming request to Congress should the President request DOD funds to execute this authority; and permits the Secretary of Defense to accept foreign contributions.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment printed in Part B of H.Res. 722 to authorize the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of State, to train and equip appropriately vetted elements of the Syrian opposition and other appropriately vetted Syrian groups or individuals. Additionally, the amendment strengthens congressional oversight by requiring detailed reports, including progress reports, on the plan, vetting process, and procedures for monitoring unauthorized end-use of provided training and equipment. It also requires the President to report on how this authority fits within a larger regional strategy. The amendment allows the Department of Defense (DOD) to submit a reprogramming request to Congress should the President request DOD funds to execute this authority and permit the Secretary of Defense to accept foreign contributions.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2014-09-17T17:08:07-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="507">
      <text>On agreeing to the McKeon amendment (A001) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 273 - 156 (Roll no. 507).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17T16:40:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment (A001) pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7659-7660" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16T15:06:40-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. McKeon.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7556-7557" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7556-7557" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16"/>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17T17:08:07-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to by House: On agreeing to the McKeon amendment (A001) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 273 - 156 (Roll no. 507).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17T17:08:07-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17T17:08:07-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the McKeon amendment (A001) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 273 - 156 (Roll no. 507).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16T15:06:40-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. McKeon.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7556-7557" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7556-7557" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
