<bill session="114" type="s" number="2298" updated="2018-06-02T07:12:03Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mens Rea Reform Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to specify the state of mind required for conviction for criminal offenses that lack an expressly identified state of mind, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Mens Rea Reform Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2015-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2015-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000603" joined="2015-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2015-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-20">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-18T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Mens Rea Reform Act of 2015

This bill amends the federal criminal code to establish a default intent (state of mind)standardfor a federal criminal offense, unless the provision of law that defines such offense specifically provides otherwise.

A federal criminal offense conviction under the default standard requires proof beyond a reasonable doubtthat a defendant acted intentionally and willfully with respect to each element of the offense.If a state of mind is not specified for an element of the offense, it must be shown that the defendant acted willfully. A person who acts "willfully" does so with the knowledge that the conduct is unlawful. The bill sets forth certain exceptions where the default standard shall not apply.

Additionally, the bill requires that when a provision of lawidentifies an intentstandard but does not specify which elements of the offense the standard applies to, the identified standard must apply to all elements of the offense.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
