<bill session="114" type="h" number="3794" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:28Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nonprofit Property Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Liability Risk Retention Act of 1986 to expand the types of commercial insurance authorized for risk retention groups serving nonprofit organizations and educational institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Nonprofit Property Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000593"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000593" joined="2015-10-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Nonprofit Property Protection Act

This bill:

 amends the Liability Risk Retention Act of 1986 to rename it the Risk Retention Act of 1986; and exclude from "commercial insurance" covered by the Act any health, life, or disability insurance or workers compensation insurance or express contractual obligations owed to a consumer as a result of a personal, family, or household transaction, where the consumer pays a separate consideration for the express contractual obligation. The bill expands the kinds of state laws pertaining to business insurance from which a risk retention group shall be exempt to include laws pertaining to other lines of commercial insurance offered by a risk retention group to an entity organized and operated exclusively as a federal tax-exempt nonprofit charitable or educational institution, as long as the group meets specified criteria.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
