<bill session="115" type="h" number="3281" updated="2019-04-18T16:12:54Z">
  <state datetime="2018-07-12T17:24:30-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-07-12T17:24:30-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to facilitate the transfer to non-Federal ownership of appropriate reclamation projects or facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Reclamation Title Transfer and Non-Federal Infrastructure Incentivization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Reclamation Title Transfer and Non-Federal Infrastructure Incentivization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Reclamation Title Transfer and Non-Federal Infrastructure Incentivization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Reclamation Title Transfer and Non-Federal Infrastructure Incentivization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reclamation Title Transfer and Non-Federal Infrastructure Incentivization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reclamation Title Transfer and Non-Federal Infrastructure Incentivization Act</title>
    <title type="display">Reclamation Title Transfer and Non-Federal Infrastructure Incentivization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000564"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001059" joined="2017-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-07-26" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 17 - 12.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-09-27">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 115-334.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-09-27" calendar="Union" number="242">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 242.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-07-10T18:38:30-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 985 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 50 and H.R. 3281. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 50 under a structured rule and H.R.3281 under a closed rule. Each measure is allowed one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-11T14:38:51-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 985 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-12T15:14:05-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 985.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6154-6160" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-12T15:14:10-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 50 and H.R. 3281. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 50 under a structured rule and H.R.3281 under a closed rule. Each measure is allowed one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-12T15:14:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 3281.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-12T15:56:04-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-12T15:56:31-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Huffman moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6160" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-12T15:56:50-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Huffman motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to add a section at the end of the bill entitled "Prohibition Against Conflict of Interest".</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-12T16:00:41-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-12T16:01:08-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Huffman motion to recommit with instructions, the Chair put the question on the motion to recommit, and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Huffman demanded the yeas and nays, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the motion to recommit until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-12T16:46:08-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6161-6162" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-12T17:16:32-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 187 - 230 (Roll no. 324).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="325" datetime="2018-07-12T17:24:30-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 233 - 184 (Roll no. 325).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6155-6156" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-07-12T17:24:32-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-16">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="procedurally-related" number="985"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-09-27T13:26:46Z" status="Reported to House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Reclamation Title Transfer and Non-Federal Infrastructure Incentivization Act

(Sec. 3) This bill authorizes the Department of the Interior to convey U.S. interest in an eligible reclamation project or facility to an agency of a state political subdivision, a joint action or powers agency, a water users association, or an Indian tribe or tribal utility authority that holds a water service contract for such property and that has the capacity to continue to manage the property for the same purposes for which it has been managed under reclamation law, if: (1) Interior notifies Congress in writing of the proposed conveyance at least 90 days in advance, and (2) Congress does not pass a joint resolution disapproving the conveyance. A facility that generates hydropower marketed by a power marketing administration shall not be eligible for such conveyance.

An entity that operates and maintains an eligible facility at the time Interior attempts to facilitate its conveyance shall have the right of first refusal to receive the conveyance.

(Sec. 4) Criteria for determining whether facilities are eligible for title transfer shall include: (1) the transfer will not have an unmitigated significant effect on the environment, (2) the qualifying entity intends to use the property for substantially the same purposes the property is being used for at the time Interior evaluates the potential transfer, and (3) the qualifying entity agrees to provide the United States the equivalent of the present value of any repayment obligation or other income stream the United States derives from the assets to be transferred.

(Sec. 5) No conveyance under this bill may adversely impact power rates or repayment obligations.

(Sec. 9) Interior shall submit, as part of its annual budget submission to Congress: (1) a description of the actions taken to implement this bill, and (2) a list of conveyances made or initiated by Interior or a qualifying entity under this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-334</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
