<bill session="114" type="s" number="503" updated="2018-06-02T06:33:41Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Haitian Partnership Renewal Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act to extend trade preferences for certain articles imported from Haiti and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Haitian Partnership Renewal Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000032"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Haiti"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-12T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Haitian Partnership Renewal Act

This bill amends the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act to extend: (1) the 60% applicable percentage requirement for duty-free entry of apparel articles assembled in Haiti and imported from Haiti or the Dominican Republic to the United States, and (2) duty-free entry of such articles through December 19, 2030.

Duty-free entry for woven articles and certain knit articles assembled in Haiti and imported from Haiti or the Dominican Republic to the United States is extended through September 30, 2030.

The special duty-free rules for Haiti are extended through September 30, 2030.

The transition period treatment of certain textile and apparel articles is extended through September 30, 2030.

Duty-free coverage is provided:

 for certain footwear, travel goods, leather wearing apparel, and lamps, lighting, and other electrical components that undergo a change in Haiti and are imported directly from Haiti or the Dominican Republic; and through September 30, 2030, for a qualifying wire harness automotive component that is the product or manufacture of Haiti and is imported directly from Haiti.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
