<bill session="114" type="h" number="3201" updated="2019-02-14T23:34:23Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">New American Success Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To support the integration of immigrants to the United States into the economic, social, cultural, and civic life of their local communities and the Nation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">New American Success Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001097"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000287" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001107" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000617" joined="2016-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000535" joined="2016-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000435" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000510" joined="2016-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000131" joined="2016-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Citizenship" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">New American Success Act of 2015 

 This bill states that it is U.S. policy to promote the civic, linguistic, and economic integration of immigrants and their young children into the United States. The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) shall award Initial Entry, Adjustment, and Citizenship Assistance grants to units of local government, community-based organizations, or public or private nonprofit organizations that provide direct assistance to immigrants to the United States.

Such grants shall be available for 10 fiscal years beginning with FY2018.

Assistance shall be available to a non-citizen who is seeking: (1) permanent residency or naturalization, or (2) relief from removal in order to remain lawfully in the United States.

 DHS may make grants on a competitive basis to state or local governments to improve the economic, linguistic, and civic integration of immigrants and their children. Such grants shall be available for 10 fiscal years beginning with FY2018.

The bill establishes in the Treasury the Integration Success Fund.

The Immigration and Nationality Act is amended to revise the waiver of the English language naturalization requirement for senior individuals.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
