<bill session="114" type="h" number="4359" updated="2019-01-09T21:26:42Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-26T17:59:49-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-04-26T17:59:49-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-01-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Administrative Leave Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Administrative Leave Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Administrative Leave Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to provide that Federal employees may not be placed on administrative leave for more than 14 days during any year for misconduct or poor performance, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Administrative Leave Reform Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001076"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-01-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-01">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-03-01" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-04-25">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 114-520.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-25" calendar="Union" number="400">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 400.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-04-26T17:49:17-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Chaffetz moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-26T17:49:30-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1981-1983" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-26T17:49:32-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4359.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2016-04-26T17:59:49-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1981" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-04-26T17:59:51-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-27">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4953"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4909"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Employee performance"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-26T12:57:17Z" status="Passed House amended">Administrative Leave Reform Act

(Sec. 2) This bill prohibits placing a federal employee on administrative leave, or any other paid non-duty status without charge to leave, for more than 14 total days for reasons relating to misconduct or performance.

After an employee has been placed on administrative leave for 14 days, the employing agency: (1) shall return the employee to duty status, utilizing telework if available, and assign the employee to duties if such employee is not a threat to safety, the agency mission, or government property; or (2) may place an employee who is found to be such a threat on extended administrative leave for additional periods of not more than 30 days each.

For any additional period of 30 days granted to the employee after the initial 30-day extension, the agency shall submit a report containing:

 the title, position, office or agency subcomponent, job series, pay grade, and salary of the employee; a description of the employee's work duties; the reason for the administrative leave; an explanation as to why the employee is such a threat; an explanation as to why the employee is not able to telework or be reassigned to another position within the agency; the status of any pending related investigation and a certification that such additional time is needed; and the results of a completed investigation and the reason that the employee remains on administrative leave. An investigative entity must certify to the applicable agency that such additional time is needed and include an estimate of the length of such additional time.

 An agency may not grant such additional period of administrative leave to an employee on or after 30 days following the completion of a related investigation.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-520</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
