<bill session="114" type="s" number="2065" updated="2018-06-02T07:10:02Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Working Student Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to increase the income protection allowances.</title>
    <title type="display">Working Student Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2015-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2015-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2015-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="4433"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Working Student Act of 2015 

This bill amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to modify the income protection allowance levels used to calculate a student's expected family contribution and need for financial assistance. (An income protection allowance is an amount for basic living expenses that is protected from being considered income available for postsecondary educational expenses.)

 Specifically, the bill increases, in academic year 2016-2017, income protection allowance levels for students who are dependent, independent without non-spouse dependents (e.g., children), and independent with non-spouse dependents to reduce such students' income available (and increase need for financial assistance) to cover postsecondary educational expenses.

 The Department of Education must, in subsequent years, adjust the income protection allowance levels for inflation.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
