<bill session="113" type="h" number="3566" updated="2016-10-25T16:09:05Z">
  <state datetime="2013-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Domestic Violence Criminal Disarmament Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to provide for a grant program regarding firearms.</title>
    <title type="display">Domestic Violence Criminal Disarmament Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001160"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001101" joined="2014-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000290" joined="2013-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000462" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001050" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2013-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2013-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000385" joined="2013-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2014-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001188" joined="2014-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2014-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000523" joined="2014-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000480" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000797" joined="2014-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-11-20T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Domestic Violence Criminal Disarmament Act of 2013 - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to authorize the Attorney General to reserve not more than 5% of Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program funds for one or more states that have demonstrated that such a state has adopted policies, procedures, protocols, laws or regulations pertaining to the possession or transfer of firearms or ammunition that:

 impose restrictions and penalties substantially similar to or more comprehensive than those under federal criminal code provisions prohibiting the sale or other disposition of a firearm or ammunition to a person who has been convicted of domestic violence or who is subject to a protective order with respect to an intimate partner; require state and local courts to: (1) consider whether such person possesses firearms that have been or are likely to be used to threaten, harass, menace, or harm the victim or the victim's child or may otherwise pose a danger to the victim; and (2) order the seizure or surrender of firearms and ammunition from such person; are designed to ensure that state or local law enforcement execute the seizure or surrender of authorized firearms and ammunition when such person is reported to possess firearms that are obtained or possessed illegally; provide for the seizure or surrender of authorized firearms and ammunition and the return of such firearms and ammunition in a manner that protects the safety of victims of such persons; and give state and local law enforcement the authority, to the extent allowable under federal laws and the U.S. Constitution, to seize firearms or ammunition when responding to domestic violence situations where there is probable cause to believe such firearms and ammunition are contraband, illegally in the possession of the offender, have been or are likely to be used to threaten, harass, menace, or harm the victim, or may otherwise pose a danger to the victim.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
