<bill session="115" type="h" number="5231" updated="2019-04-18T16:21:03Z">
  <state datetime="2018-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 39, United States Code, to prohibit a Member or Member-elect of Congress from mailing as franked mail any material with a photographic image, to establish an annual limit on the amount of funds which may be expended on franked mail by a Member or Member-elect of Congress, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Free Campaigns for Congress Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Free Campaigns for Congress Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">No Free Campaigns for Congress Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000608"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-03-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-03-08T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">No Free Campaigns for Congress Act of 2018

This bill excludes from treatment as franked mail material transmitted by a Member of Congress, or a Member-elect, that includes a photograph or photographic representation, other than as an electronic communication.

 The total amount that may be spent for the costs of franked mail sent by any Member or Member-elect may not exceed $10,000 during a calendar year or during a fiscal year in the case of the House of Representatives or the Senate, respectively.

The bill bans mass mailings postmarked at any time during an election year.

The franking privilege may not be used for mail that is purely related to a campaign for election for office.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
