<bill session="114" type="s" number="3273" updated="2019-03-03T14:41:17Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make technical corrections to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alaska Native Claims Settlement Improvement Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="display">Alaska Native Claims Settlement Improvement Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2016-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 114-509.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2386"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2387"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="872"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1955"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3004"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5909"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6115"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Alaska Native Claims Settlement Improvement Act of 2016 

This bill amends the Barrow Gas Field Transfer Act of 1984 to require the Department of the Interior to convey to the Ukpeagvik Inupiat Corporation, an Alaska Native village corporation, sand and gravel deposits underlying a surface estate owned by the corporation.

 Interior must grant the Shishmaref Native Corporation, a village corporation, an easement between Shishmaref, Alaska, and the area of Ear Mountain, Alaska.

Shee Atika Incorporated, an urban Native corporation, may opt to receive credits from the Department of Agriculture (USDA) for the sale of Cube Cove in Admiralty Island, Alaska, that may be used to acquire federal property sold at public sales.

The bill authorizes a land exchange between the USDA and the Sealaska Corporation, an Alaska Native regional corporation.

Cook Inlet Region, Inc., a regional corporation, may satisfy its claim land under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (ANCSA).

The bill amends ANCSA to require Interior to convey: (1) a surface estate to Kian Tr'ee Corporation, a village corporation, for the Native village of Canyon Village; and (2) a subsurface estate to Doyon Limited, a regional corporation.

Upon application by the village of Kaktovik or Nagamut, Interior must convey land within the National Wildlife Refuge System to the village.

The bill makes land held by Alaska Native corporations subject to the National Historic Preservation Act, the Tribal Forest Protection Act, and the Native American Graves Protection and Repatriation Act.

Native residents of the villages of Haines, Ketchikan, Petersburg, Tenakee, and Wrangell, Alaska, may organize as urban corporations. Upon incorporation, Interior must offer each corporation 23,040 acres of land.

Alaska Native veterans who served during the Vietnam War may receive an allotment of federal land.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
