<bill session="114" type="s" number="10" updated="2019-05-09T23:15:21Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-01">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-12-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-12-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the consideration of a definition of anti-Semitism for the enforcement of Federal antidiscrimination laws concerning education programs or activities.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Anti-Semitism Awareness Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="display">Anti-Semitism Awareness Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2016-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2016-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2016-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2016-12-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-12-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2016-12-01" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6649-6650" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6650" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-12-02">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-02T11:39:43-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="6421"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-01T16:14:59Z" status="Passed Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Anti-Semitism Awareness Act of 2016

(Sec. 4) This bill requires the Department of Education, when reviewing whether there has been a violation of title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (prohibits discrimination on the basis of race, color, or national origin in programs and activities receiving federal financial assistance) based on an individual's actual or perceived shared Jewish ancestry or Jewish ethnic characteristics, to consider the definition of "anti-Semitism" as part of its assessment of whether the alleged practice was motivated by anti-Semitic intent.

For purposes of this bill, the definition of "anti-Semitism" is the definition set forth by the Special Envoy to Monitor and Combat Anti-Semitism of the Department of State in the Fact Sheet issued on June 8, 2010, as adapted from the Working Definition of Anti-Semitism of the European Monitoring Center on Racism and Xenophobia (now known as the European Union Agency for Fundamental Rights).

(Sec. 5) Nothing in this bill shall be construed to diminish or infringe upon any right protected under the First Amendment to the Constitution.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
