<bill session="114" type="s" number="3153" updated="2018-06-02T07:47:07Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TAILOR Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Taking Account of Institutions with Low Operation Risk Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies to take risk profiles and business models of institutions into account when taking regulatory actions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">TAILOR Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000605"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2016-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2016-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2896"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="National Credit Union Administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Taking Account of Institutions with Low Operation Risk Act of 2016 or the TAILOR Act of 2016

This bill requires the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the National Credit Union Administration, and the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, for any rule, regulation, or guidance, to: (1) consider the risk profile and business models of individual financial institutions and those of similar type that are subject to the regulatory action; and (2) tailor the action so that it limits the regulatory impact on an individual or type of institution as is appropriate for the risk profile and business model involved.

In carrying out such requirements, each such agency shall consider:

 whether it is necessary to apply such regulatory action to accomplish policy objectives; the impact of such action on the ability of such institutions to flexibly serve their customers and local markets; the aggregate impact of all applicable regulatory actions on such ability; the potential impact of implementing the action upon efforts to tailor it; and the statutory provision authorizing the action, the congressional intent of such provision, and the policy objectives sought by the agency in implementing it. The bill requires: (1) each such agency to report on the specific actions taken to tailor its regulatory actions pursuant to this bill, and (2) the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council to report on the extent to which each such agency differs in the treatment of similarly situated institutions.

Each agency shall: (1) conduct a review of all final regulations issued pursuant to statutes enacted between July 21, 2010, and the date of this bill's enactment, and (2) apply this bill's requirements to such regulations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
