<bill session="114" type="h" number="3358" updated="2019-02-14T23:34:23Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prevent Repeat Offenders Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to ensure that sex offenders to be released from the custody of Immigration and Customs Enforcement are registered on sex offender registry, and relevant State, tribal, and local authorities are notified of their release, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Prevent Repeat Offenders Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000375"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000386" joined="2015-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Citizenship" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Prevent Repeat Offenders Act of 2015

This bill amends the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act to direct the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to ensure that: (1) any alien who is required to register under such Act is registered in the National Sex Offender Registry and is informed of the registration requirements under such Act before such alien may be released from the custody of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE), and (2) the release of such an alien is conditioned on such alien's registration in each jurisdiction required by such Act.

DHS is also required to ensure that the chief law enforcement officer of each jurisdiction in which such an alien resides and the agency responsible for the receipt or maintenance of sex offender registration information in such jurisdiction are promptly notified when such an alien is: (1) taken into custody by ICE, (2) released from ICE custody, or (3) removed from the United States.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
