<bill session="114" type="h" number="4248" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:33Z">
  <state datetime="2015-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FSOC Designation Review Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Financial Stability Act to revise the reevaluation procedures with respect to determinations by the Financial Stability Oversight Council that a nonbank financial company shall be supervised by the Board of Governors and shall be subject to prudential standards.</title>
    <title type="display">FSOC Designation Review Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000796"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001072" joined="2016-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001193" joined="2016-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001137" joined="2016-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001182" joined="2016-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000606" joined="2016-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001157" joined="2015-12-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Financial Stability Oversight Council"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-12-15T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">FSOC Designation Review Act 

This bill amends the Financial Stability Act of 2010 to revise requirements for reevaluation and reaffirmation of determinations by the Financial Stability Oversight Council (FSOC) that the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System supervise and regulate U.S. or foreign nonbank financial companies.

The FSOC shall reevaluate such a determination not only annually (as under current law) but also upon the request of a nonbank financial company based on its representation that there has been a material change in its operations or activities or a material change in regulatory or market conditions.

FSOC must give the company as part of a reevaluation:

 a confidential written analysis of the specific elements of the company's exposures or activities that would be relevant to the FSOC's reevaluation; and opportunity to submit written materials in response, including a plan to obtain rescission of the determination or other materials relevant to the assessment. The FSOC's written analysis must assess with particularity the company's vulnerability to financial distress, including consideration of its leverage, liquidity risk, and maturity mismatch, and existing regulatory scrutiny of the company.

Following a reevaluation the FSOC shall vote whether to reaffirm the determination; but if two-thirds of the voting members do not vote in favor of reaffirmation, the determination in question shall be rescinded immediately, subject at company option to judicial review. (Currently a determination is automatically reaffirmed upon reevaluation unless by a two-thirds vote the FSOC rescinds it.)</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
