<bill session="113" type="h" number="5698" updated="2016-10-25T16:17:13Z">
  <state datetime="2014-11-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-11-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Secret Service Accountability and Improvement Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To create an independent advisory panel to comprehensively assess the leadership structure, protocols, training, tools, and capabilities of the United States Secret Service and make recommendations to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of the Service, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">United States Secret Service Accountability and Improvement Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001157"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-11-13T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">United States Secret Service Accountability and Improvement Act of 2014 - Establishes in the legislative branch an independent advisory panel to: (1) examine the efficiency and effectiveness of the leadership structure, protocols, training, tools, and capabilities of the Department of Homeland Security's (DHS) mission to protect national leaders, visiting heads of state and government, designated sites, and special events of national significance; and (2) make recommendations to improve the overall efficiency and effectiveness of the United States Secret Service.

Directs the panel to assess the current leadership structure, protocols, training, tools, and capabilities of the Service, including assessing:

 the unity of effort between the divisions of the Service, law enforcement agencies, and other components of DHS related to the protective and investigative missions; the impact of Service personnel culture on its effectiveness and efficiency; the impact any leadership or security deficiencies have on the threat from acts of terrorism or other security incidents; identification of all security breaches at locations under Service protection in the past five years; the extent to which current resources provide for accomplishing its mission, and the effectiveness of communications and dissemination of homeland security information within the Service and with other law enforcement entities in routine and emergency situations. Sets forth reporting requirements, including requiring the final report to identify lessons learned regarding Service leadership issues and to include recommendations for improving efficiency and effectiveness, improving unity of effort, eliminating barriers to effective communications, identifying and mitigating culture issues that detract from its mission, and mitigating risks based on past security breaches.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
