<bill session="113" type="s" number="807" updated="2016-10-25T16:23:47Z">
  <state datetime="2013-04-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Plain Writing Act for Regulations of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require that Federal regulations use plain writing that is clear, concise, and well-organized, and follows other best practices appropriate to the subject or field and intended audience.</title>
    <title type="display">Plain Writing Act for Regulations of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001170"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1557"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-04-24T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Plain Writing Act for Regulations of 2013 - Requires the head of each executive agency to: (1) implement a program for using plain writing in drafting agency regulations, (2) designate a senior official to oversee the implementation of plain writing requirements, (3) certify to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) that each agency rule has been reviewed for compliance with such requirements, and (4) publish annual reports on agency compliance with such requirements on the agency's website.

Requires: (1) the Director of OMB to develop and issue guidance to agencies for implementing plain writing requirements and publish certifications of agency compliance with such requirements on the OMB's website, and (2) the Comptroller General (GAO) to report to Congress on the extent to which regulations are using plain writing and the impact of plain writing requirements on the rulemaking process.

Prohibits judicial review of compliance or noncompliance with any provision of this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
