<bill session="114" type="h" number="137" updated="2018-11-21T20:50:18Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Designating Requirements On Notification of Executive-ordered Strikes Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DRONES Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require an adequate process in preplanned lethal operations that deliberately target citizens of the United States or citizens of strategic treaty allies of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">DRONES Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000056"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committees on Intelligence (Permanent Select), and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committees on Intelligence (Permanent Select), and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committees on Intelligence (Permanent Select), and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Designating Requirements On Notification of Executive-ordered Strikes Act or the DRONES Act

Prohibits a federal department or agency or the Armed Forces from deliberately targeting a citizen of the United States or of a strategic treaty ally in a pre-planned lethal operation unless such operation is planned and executed pursuant to a written determination signed personally by the President: (1) confirming the status of the targeted citizen as an enemy combatant, and (2) authorizing the deliberate lethal targeting based on an articulated need for the use of lethal force.

Requires the President, within 30 days after making such a determination, to submit a report to specified congressional committees: (1) certifying that the timing and details of the operation were approved personally by the President, and (2) detailing the information used to determine that the targeted citizen is an enemy combatant and the reasons why lethal force was necessary.

Prohibits this Act from being construed to authorize such lethal targeting of&#160;such a citizen inside any location under U.S. jurisdiction.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
