<bill session="113" type="s" number="2845" updated="2016-10-25T16:32:22Z">
  <state datetime="2014-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Southern Prairie Potholes National Wildlife Refuge Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Southern Prairie Potholes National Wildlife Refuge.</title>
    <title type="display">Southern Prairie Potholes National Wildlife Refuge Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000206"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Iowa"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-09-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Southern Prairie Potholes National Wildlife Refuge Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish the approximately 23,500-acre Southern Prairie Potholes National Wildlife Refuge in Iowa. Authorizes the Secretary to acquire land and water within the boundaries of the Refuge from willing sellers.

Lists as purposes of the Refuge to: (1) enhance opportunities for outdoor recreation; (2) provide for the restoration or preservation of Refuge land to native wetland and grassland habitats and landscapes; (3) provide for the restoration and conservation of native plants and animal communities; (4) provide critical travel and nesting habitat for migratory birds; (5) provide opportunities to private landowners to access assistance for the voluntary restoration of land for the benefit of fish and wildlife; and (6) facilitate the education of the public about nature, the environment, and the conservation of the natural resources.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) administer all land, water, and interests therein acquired under this Act in accordance with the National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act of 1966; (2) ensure that hunting, fishing, wildlife observation and photography, and environmental education and interpretation are the priority public uses of the Refuge; and (3) encourage the use of volunteers and facilitate partnerships to promote public awareness, conservation, and priority uses of Refuge resources.

.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
