<bill session="114" type="h" number="1865" updated="2019-02-13T17:31:11Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Central Coast Heritage Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To designate certain Federal lands in California as wilderness, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Central Coast Heritage Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001036"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2015-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000598" joined="2016-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2016-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000030" joined="2015-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2016-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2016-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2016-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2016-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2016-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001163" joined="2016-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001166" joined="2016-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2016-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000599" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000030" joined="2016-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2016-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001175" joined="2016-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2016-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="1423"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Central Coast Heritage Protection Act

 This bill designates specified Bureau of Land Management (BLM) and National Forest System lands in California as wilderness areas and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System.

It also designates certain land in Los Padres National Forest in California, comprising approximately 2,174 acres, as the Machesna Mountain Potential Wilderness Area, which shall be incorporated into the Machesna Mountain Wilderness Area.

Specified segments of the Indian, Mono, Matilija, Sespe, and Piru Creeks and Sisquoc River in California are designated as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System.

Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest in California, comprising approximately 41,617 acres, is designated as the Fox Mountain Potential Wilderness Area, which shall be incorporated into the San Rafael Wilderness.

This bill designates specified land: (1) in Los Padres National Forest, comprising approximately 18,666 acres, as the Condor Ridge Scenic Area; and (2) in Los Padres National Forest and in the BLM Bakersfield Field Office, comprising approximately 15,846 acres, as the Black Mountain Scenic Area.

The Condor Trail in Monterey County, California, is designated as the Condor National Recreation Trail.

The Department of Agriculture shall study: (1) connecting the northern and southern parts of the Los Padres National Forest using a trail corridor across parts of the Northern and Southern Santa Lucia Mountains of the Southern California Coastal Range; and (2) nonmotorized recreation trail opportunities (including mountain bicycling) on land not designated as wilderness by this Act within the Santa Barbara, Ojai, and Mt. Pinos ranger districts.

The Forest Service shall study the feasibility of opening a new trail, for vehicles measuring 50 inches or less, connecting Forest Service Highway 95 to the existing off-highway vehicle trail system in the Ballinger Canyon off-highway vehicle area.

Indian tribes shall be assured access to the wilderness areas, scenic areas, and potential wilderness areas designated by this Act for traditional cultural and religious purposes.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
