<bill session="115" type="h" number="4629" updated="2019-04-18T16:18:57Z">
  <state datetime="2017-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Department of Transportation to issue regulations to require enhanced security measures for shipments of security sensitive material, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Save Our Communities from Risky Trains Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Save Our Communities from Risky Trains Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Save Our Communities from Risky Trains Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-12-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1687-1688"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-12-12T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Save Our Communities from Risky Trains Act of 2017&#160;

This bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to issue regulations to require enhanced security measures for shipments of security sensitive material.

DOT shall designate a material, or a group or class of material, as security sensitive if it determines that transporting such material in commerce poses a significant risk to national security due to its potential use in an act of terrorism.

Each railroad carrier transporting security sensitive material shall:

 compile material route and storage pattern information, and submit to DOT a written rail transportation route and storage pattern security risk analysis and an alternative route and storage pattern analysis. Railroad carriers shall use the route and storage pattern that, based on the analyses, best reduces the risk, including consequences, of a terrorist attack on, or derailment of, a shipment of security sensitive material transported through or near an area of concern (i.e., urban areas).

Each railroad carrier shall review once every five years any changes affecting the security movements of such material.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
