<bill session="114" type="s" number="899" updated="2018-06-02T06:44:47Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Afterschool and Workforce Readiness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 in order to focus on career readiness, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Afterschool and Workforce Readiness Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001230"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Afterschool and Workforce Readiness Act

Amends part A (Teacher and Principal Training and Recruiting Fund) of title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to define a "workforce critical subject" as an academic or career and technical education subject, such as:

 any subject found in the science, technology, engineering, and mathematics fields; any other subject identified by a state as being critical to the state's current and emerging workforce needs. Requires a state's application for a grant under part A to recruit, train, and retain highly qualified teachers and principals to describe all of the subjects the state identifies as workforce critical subjects.

Amends part B (21st Century Community Learning Centers) of title IV of the ESEA to require states that receive a part B allotment to consider, in evaluating subgrant applications, the likelihood that a subgrant applicant's community learning center will help secondary school students achieve career competencies, complete internships or apprenticeships, or participate in work-based learning opportunities. (Subgrants are awarded on a competitive basis to local educational agencies, community-based organizations, and other public or private entities to establish or expand before school, after school, and summer recess community learning center programs.)

Authorizes subgrantees to establish community learning center programs that partner with in-demand fields of the local workforce or build career competencies and career readiness.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
