<bill session="114" type="sr" number="381" updated="2018-06-02T06:19:20Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution honoring the memory and legacy of Michael James Riddering and condemning the terrorist attacks in Ouagadougou, Burkina Faso on January 15, 2016.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution honoring the memory and legacy of Michael James Riddering and condemning the terrorist attacks in Ouagadougou, Burkina Faso on January 15, 2016.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2016-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2016-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1139" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-04-28">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Corker without amendment and with a preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="448">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 448.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Burkina Faso"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-28T13:45:22Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Condemns the terrorist attacks in Ouagadougou, Burkina Faso, on January 15, 2016.

 Honors the memory of Michael James Riddering, the U.S. citizen who was killed in the terrorist attack on the Cappuccino Cafe on January 15, 2016, in Ouagadougou.

Recognizes the dedication of Michael James Riddering, who moved halfway across the world to work with orphans and widows in order to help them improve their lives and contribute to their communities.

Extends condolences and prayers to Michael James Riddering's family, friends, and colleagues and to the individuals touched by his life.

Pledges to work to counter violent extremism, including through education and community development, in the United States and abroad.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
