<bill session="114" type="s" number="1819" updated="2018-06-02T06:57:59Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing Military Personnel Response Firearm Initiative Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SEMPER FI Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve security at Armed Forces recruitment centers.</title>
    <title type="display">SEMPER FI Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2015-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2015-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2015-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001141" joined="2015-08-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="3139"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Securing Military Personnel Response Firearm Initiative Act or SEMPER FI Act

This bill directs the Secretary concerned to authorize an eligible member of the Armed Forces assigned to an Armed Forces recruitment center to carry a service-issue sidearm as a personal- or force-protection measure while on duty at the recruiting center, notwithstanding any federal, state, or local law or Department of Defense policy to the contrary.

In lieu of authorizing eligible members of the Armed Forces to carry a service-issue sidearm, or in addition, the Secretary concerned may implement additional security measures for Armed Forces recruitment centers, including improved structural security measures.

This Act shall not be interpreted to grant any member of the Armed Forces the authority to conduct civilian law enforcement functions within U.S. territory.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
