<bill session="113" type="s" number="2269" updated="2016-10-25T16:29:53Z">
  <state datetime="2014-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Partnerships to Transform Opportunities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to prepare individuals with multiple barriers to employment to enter the workforce by providing such individuals with support services, job training, and education, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Promoting Partnerships to Transform Opportunities Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000039"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="546"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Adult education and literacy"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Financial literacy"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-04-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Promoting Partnerships to Transform Opportunities Act - Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to direct the Secretary of Labor to make competitive grants to, or enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with, eligible institutions, preferably in partnership with a nonprofit organization, to provide support services, job training, and education to individuals with multiple barriers to employment, including underrepresented minorities, to help prepare them to enter the workforce.

Defines "eligible institution" to mean a historically Black college or university, a Hispanic-serving Institution, a Tribal College or University, or a Predominantly Black Institution.

Requires an eligible institution to submit a program plan to the Secretary in order to receive a grant or enter into such a contract or cooperative agreement.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
