<bill session="114" type="s" number="1885" updated="2018-06-02T06:58:34Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veteran Housing Stability Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the provision of assistance and benefits to veterans who are homeless, at risk of becoming homeless, or occupying temporary housing, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Veteran Housing Stability Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2016-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2015-11-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6182-6183" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-06">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Veteran Housing Stability Act of 2015

This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to provide:

 intensive case management interventions for veterans enrolled in the VA's homeless registry and the annual patient enrollment system, and case management services to improve housing retention by veterans who were previously homeless and are transitioning to permanent housing and veterans who are at risk of becoming homeless. The VA housing assistance program is expanded to include: (1) veterans and their families who are at risk of becoming homeless, and very low-income veteran families; and (2) assistance for acquiring and transitioning to, and maintaining occupancy in, permanent housing.

The VA shall:

 conduct outreach to realtors, landlords, property management companies, and developers to educate them about the housing needs of veterans and the benefits of having veterans as tenants; and establish and operate a National Center on Homelessness Among Veterans which shall carry out research into the causes of and contributing factors to veteran homelessness, assess the effectiveness of VA homeless veterans programs, and serve as a center for the exchange of information regarding activities carried out by the VA and by other federal and non-federal entities for veteran homelessness. Each year the VA shall review each grant recipient and eligible entity that received a per diem payment for furnishing services to homeless veterans to evaluate its performance with respect to:

 the success of the grant recipient or eligible entity in assisting veterans to obtain, transition into, and retain permanent housing; and increasing the income of veterans by helping them obtain either employment or appropriate income-related benefits.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
