<bill session="114" type="s" number="2564" updated="2019-06-21T11:07:13Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-27">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modernize prior legislation relating to Dine College.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Dine College Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Dine College Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="display">Dine College Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000444"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2016-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2016-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2016-02-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-13">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 114-326.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-11-15">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Barrasso without amendment. With written report No. 114-373.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-11-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="666">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 666.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-11-15T13:42:33Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Dine College Act of 2016

(Sec. 5) This bill requires the Department of the Interior to conduct a survey and study of all capital projects and facility needs of Dine College, a tribal community college in the Navajo Nation in Arizona. Interior must report the results and include views or recommendations submitted by the college or the Navajo Nation and Interior's recommendations.

Prior to the survey and study, Dine College must identify for Interior renovations and repairs necessary to meet health and safety standards and other requirements.

(Sec. 6) Interior must make grants to Dine College for activities including construction, operation and maintenance, education, summer programs, student services, and college expansion.

(Sec. 7) Amounts made available to Dine College under this bill are treated as non-federal, private funds for the purposes of any federal law that requires the use of non-federal or private funds.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-373</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
