<bill session="114" type="s" number="2255" updated="2018-06-02T07:11:41Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Debt Collection Abuse Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act to restrict the debt collection practices of certain debt collectors.</title>
    <title type="display">Stop Debt Collection Abuse Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2015-11-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5434"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stop Debt Collection Abuse Act of 2015

This bill amends the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act to redefine: (1) "debt" to include any obligation or alleged obligation of a consumer to pay a loan, an overpayment, a fine, penalty, a fee, or other money to a federal agency and that is at least 180 days past due; and (2) "debt collector" to include any person who regularly collects debts owed or allegedly owed to a federal agency.

A federal agency that is a creditor may sell or transfer a debt to a debt collector beginning 180 days after the obligation or alleged obligation arises.

The Act is further amended by making the collection of any amount (including any interest, fee, charge, or expense incidental to the principal obligation) an unfair practice unless:

 the amount is expressly authorized by the agreement creating the debt or permitted by law (as under current law); or in the case of a debt owed a federal agency, the collection charge is reasonable in relation to actual collection costs, is authorized by a contract between the debt collector and the federal agency, and does not exceed 10% of the amount the debt collector collects. The Government Accountability Office must study the use of debt collectors by state and local government agencies.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
