<bill session="115" type="s" number="2169" updated="2019-04-18T16:40:31Z">
  <state datetime="2017-11-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-11-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-11-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a new higher education data system to allow for more accurate, complete, and secure data on student retention, graduation, and earnings outcomes, at all levels of postsecondary enrollment, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student Right to Know Before You Go Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student Right to Know Before You Go Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Student Right to Know Before You Go Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2017-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2018-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2017-11-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-11-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="4479"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-11-29T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Student Right to Know Before You Go Act of 2017

This bill requires the National Center for Education Statistics to establish and maintain a new higher education data system. The center must use the system to calculate student education, debt-related, and earning metrics (e.g., student graduation rates, transfer rates, rates of continuation to subsequent levels of education, dropout rates, loan debt amounts, loan repayment rates, and debt-to-earnings ratios) for each institution of higher education (IHE) that participates in federal student aid programs. The metrics must be disaggregated and separately provided on the basis of specified categories.

The system must meet requirements for minimizing privacy and security risks.

The bill provides for the transition from the existing Integrated Postsecondary Education Data System to the new higher education data system.

The Department of Education (ED) must publish the metrics and post the metrics on its website. Within five years, an IHE that participates in federal student aid programs must display links on its website to ED's website that provides metrics data.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
