<bill session="115" type="h" number="6182" updated="2019-04-18T16:25:24Z">
  <state datetime="2018-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to codify President Trump's "Affording Congress an Opportunity to Address Family Separation Executive Order", and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Codifying President Trump's Affording Congress an Opportunity to Address Family Separation Executive Order Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Codifying President Trump&#8217;s Affording Congress an Opportunity to Address Family Separation Executive Order Act</title>
    <title type="display">Codifying President Trump's Affording Congress an Opportunity to Address Family Separation Executive Order Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000615"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-06-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Citizenship" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Readiness" code="HSAS03" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-06-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Codifying President Trump's Affording Congress an Opportunity to Address Family Separation Executive Order Act

This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to codify policies relating to the separation of alien family members who enter the United States illegally.

The bill requires the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to maintain custody of alien families during the pendency of any criminal improper entry or other immigration proceedings. DHS may not detain an alien family together when detention of an alien child with the child's parent would pose a risk to the child's welfare.

The Department of Defense shall provide new and existing facilities for the housing and care of alien families. Executive departments and agencies shall also provide appropriate facilities for the housing and care of alien families pending court proceedings for improper entry.

The Department of Justice shall (1) file a request to modify an existing settlement agreement to permit the detention of alien families together during improper entry criminal or removal proceedings, and (2) prioritize the adjudication of cases involving detained family.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
