<bill session="114" type="h" number="4160" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:24Z">
  <state datetime="2015-12-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-12-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Broadband Infrastructure Investment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 to increase regional telecommunications development, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Rural Broadband Infrastructure Investment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000623" joined="2016-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2016-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000636" joined="2016-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000368" joined="2016-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000127" joined="2015-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2016-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2016-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001185" joined="2016-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000473" joined="2016-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2015-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2016-02-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commodity Exchanges, Energy, and Credit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Commodity Exchanges, Energy, and Credit" code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Communications and Technology" code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-12-02T20:21:16Z" status="Introduced in House">Rural Broadband Infrastructure Investment Act 

This bill amends the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 to authorize the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to provide additional loans and grants for the development of telecommunications and broadband services in rural areas.

USDA may give preference to loan applications for projects that support the development of telecommunications services in rural areas on a multijurisdictional basis.

In evaluating applications, USDA must consider whether:

 the project was developed through the collaboration and participation of multiple stakeholders in the service area; the applicant understands the regional resources that could support the project, including natural resources, human resources, infrastructure, and financial resources; and the project has clear objectives and a means to establish performance measures. For the purpose of loans, loan guarantees, and grants, a rural area is any area of the United States not included within the boundaries of any incorporated or unincorporated city, village, or borough having a population in excess of 20,000 inhabitants.

USDA may provide grants, in addition to loans and loan guarantees permitted under current law, for the construction, improvement, and acquisition of facilities and equipment for broadband service in rural areas. In providing loans, loan guarantees, and grants, USDA may give priority to multijurisdictional projects for the development of broadband service in rural areas that are developed through the collaboration and participation of multiple stakeholders in the service area.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
