<bill session="115" type="h" number="1756" updated="2019-04-18T16:05:38Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of the Interior to conduct offshore oil and gas Lease Sale 220 as soon as practicable, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Virginia Jobs and Energy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Virginia Jobs and Energy Act</title>
    <title type="display">Virginia Jobs and Energy Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001105"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000568" joined="2017-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000804" joined="2017-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Virginia Jobs and Energy Act

This bill directs the Department of the Interior to conduct an oil and gas lease sale off the coast of Virginia within one year, and conduct at least two lease sales in the area during the 2017-2022 Outer Continental Shelf Oil and Gas Leasing Program. During each of Interior's five-year leasing programs, two lease sales must be conducted off the coast of Virginia.

The bill prohibits oil or natural gas exploration, development, or production off the Virginia coast that would conflict with a military operation.

The bill allocates 37.5% of new leasing revenues received each fiscal year by the federal government for payment to states affected with respect to the leases that generate these revenues.Additionally, the bill sets forth the minimum and maximum revenues that an affected state may receive.

Interior must require any applicant seeking to conduct an offshore meteorological site testing and monitoring project to obtain a permit and right-of-way.(An offshore meteorological site testing and monitoring project is carried out on or in the waters of the outer Continental Shelf to test or monitor weather using towers, buoys, or other temporary ocean infrastructure).These projects shall be exempt from environmental impact statement requirements under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
