<bill session="114" type="sr" number="506" updated="2018-06-02T06:21:09Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-06">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-07-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate in support of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization and the NATO summit to be held in Warsaw, Poland from July 8-9, 2016, and in support of committing NATO to a security posture capable of deterring threats to the Alliance.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate in support of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization and the NATO summit to be held in Warsaw, Poland from July 8-9, 2016, and in support of committing NATO to a security posture capable of deterring threats to the Alliance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2016-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2016-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2016-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4413-4414" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-06-23" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-06-27">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Corker with amendments and with an amended preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-06-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="529">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 529.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2016-07-06" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate with amendments and an amended preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4836-4837" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4836-4837" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4836" label="text as reported in Senate"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Georgia (Republic)"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Poland"/>
    <term name="Romania"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-06T13:47:02Z" status="Passed Senate amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the Senate on June 27, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Recognizes the men and women who have served to safeguard the freedom and security of the United States and the transatlantic alliance.

 Encourages alliance members at the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Warsaw Summit to promote unity and ensure a robust security posture in the face of the complex and changing security environment confronting NATO.

 Urges all NATO members to invest at least 2% of GDP in defense spending and carry an equitable burden in supporting NATO's resource requirements and defense capabilities, including an increased forward defense posture in NATO frontline states.

 Reaffirms the Senate's commitment to NATO's collective security.

 Welcomes the progress of NATO's ballistic missile defense mission and the achievement of recent U.S. milestones in this area through the partnership of allies, including Romania and Poland.

 Recognizes:

 Georgia's troop contributions to missions abroad and its ongoing efforts to strengthen its democratic and military institutions for NATO accession; and the ongoing work of NATO's Resolute Support Mission in Afghanistan and the significant commitment NATO allies and coalition partners have dedicated to Afghanistan since 2001, including the 1,134 troops who have lost their lives in that conflict.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
