<bill session="114" type="s" number="2060" updated="2018-06-02T07:10:01Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing FASD Research, Prevention, and Services Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize and extend the Fetal Alcohol Syndrome prevention and services program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Advancing FASD Research, Prevention, and Services Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2015-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Hereditary and development disorders"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Advancing FASD Research, Prevention, and Services Act

This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to revise and extend the Fetal Alcohol Spectrum Disorders (FASD) programs (as renamed under this Act, previously the Fetal Alcohol Syndrome and Fetal Alcohol Effect programs). The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must: (1) carry out research on FASD; (2) facilitate surveillance, public health research, and prevention of FASD; and (3) continue the Interagency Coordinating Committee on Fetal Alcohol Syndrome.

HHS must provide financial assistance to: (1) establish or expand state FASD programs; (2) implement best practices to educate children with FASD and educate members of the criminal justice system and adoption or foster care agency officials on FASD; (3) provide transitional services for those affected by prenatal alcohol exposure; (4) develop public service announcements on the risks associated with alcohol consumption during pregnancy; (5) increase awareness of FASD in federally qualified health centers; and (6) provide respite care for caretakers, recruit mentors, and provide educational and supportive services to families of individuals with FASD.

The Government Accountability Office must make recommendations regarding the responsibilities of federal entities regarding FASD.

The Office of Special Education and Rehabilitative Services of the Department of Education must conduct training on FASD surveillance and disseminate best practices in the education and support of children with FASD.

The Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention of the Department of Justice must: (1) implement FASD screening procedures, (2) conduct training on surveillance and on identification and support of individuals with FASD, and (3) study the inadequacies of the current system.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
