<bill session="115" type="h" number="4902" updated="2019-04-18T16:19:59Z">
  <state datetime="2018-01-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-01-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-01-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Water Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Act of 2014 to provide to State infrastructure financing authorities additional opportunities to receive loans under that Act to support drinking water and clean water State revolving funds to deliver water infrastructure to communities across the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing Required Funding for Water Infrastructure Now Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing Required Funding for Water Infrastructure Now Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SRF WIN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SRF WIN Act</title>
    <title type="display">SRF WIN Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2018-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2018-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000533" joined="2018-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000464" joined="2018-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2018-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000563" joined="2018-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2018-04-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-01-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Environment and Climate Change" code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="2364"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-01-30T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Securing Required Funding for Water Infrastructure Now Act or the SRF WIN Act

This bill amends the Water Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Act of 2014 (WIFIA) to allow the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to provide additional financial assistance (e.g., low-interest loans) through FY2023 to state infrastructure financing authorities for drinking water state revolving funds (SRFs) and clean water SRFs to carry out certain water and wastewater infrastructure projects.

For projects funded under this bill, the EPA: (1) must expedite their application and review process, (2) may provide up to 100% of the project costs, and (3) must provide financial assistance based on need and give equal consideration to drinking water projects and wastewater projects. Total financial assistance provided under this bill may not exceed $7 billion per state.

The bill authorizes the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers and the EPA to provide financial assistance under WIFIA to carry out projects for flood damage reduction, storm damage reduction, environmental restoration, or navigation improvement to certain waterways. Under current law, such financial assistance may be provided to only pilot projects.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
