<bill session="114" type="sr" number="81" updated="2018-06-02T06:15:58Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-12">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that children trafficked for sex in the United States should not be treated or regarded as child prostitutes because there is no such thing as a "child prostitute", only children who are victims or survivors of rape and sex trafficking.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that children trafficked for sex in the United States should not be treated or regarded as child prostitutes because there is no such thing as a "child prostitute", only children who are victims or survivors of rape and sex trafficking.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000555"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2015-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2015-02-12" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1011" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="text as passed Senate CR S1009"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-12T12:57:08Z" status="Passed Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Encourages: (1) all federal entities to treat children trafficked for sex as victims or survivors of rape and sex trafficking; and (2) lawmakers, law enforcement, the media, and the public to reframe the trafficking of children for sex as an act of violence against children.

Expresses support for: (1) efforts to arrest and prosecute sex traffickers and buyers of children trafficked for sex in accordance with applicable state and federal sex trafficking statutes and state child protection laws; (2) survivors of child sex trafficking and efforts to raise awareness of the comprehensive services necessary to heal from the trauma of sexual violence and exploitation; and (3) ending the demand for children in the commercial sex market by ensuring that children in the United States are not for sale and that any person who is trafficking or purchasing a child for sex is punished under the full force of the law.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
