<bill session="114" type="s" number="449" updated="2018-06-02T06:33:19Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reduce recidivism and increase public safety.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to reduce recidivism and increase public safety.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000449"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="467"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2123"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-11T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Directs the Attorney General to: (1) evaluate best practices used for the reentry of federal prisoners released from custody, (2) select an appropriate number of federal judicial districts to conduct federal reentry demonstration projects using such best practices, and (3) report on the impact of reentry of prisoners on communities in which a disproportionate number of individuals reside upon release from incarceration.

Amends the federal criminal code to require a presentence report to include: (1) information about the defendant's history of substance abuse and addiction; (2) information about the defendant's service in the Armed Forces and veteran status; and (3) a detailed plan that the probation officer determines will reduce the likelihood that the defendant will abuse drugs or alcohol, will reduce the defendant's likelihood of recidivism by addressing the defendant's specific recidivism risk factors, and will assist the defendant in preparing for reentry into the community.

Requires the Administrative Office of the United States Courts to: (1) establish a five-year recidivism reduction and recovery enhancement pilot program, premised on high-intensity supervision and the use of sanctions for noncompliance with program rules; and (2) conduct an evaluation of the pilot program and report to Congress on the results of the evaluation. Sets forth requirements for participation in the pilot program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
