<amendment session="115" chamber="h" number="546" updated="2019-06-13T20:34:07Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2018-04-26T13:39:57-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001154"/>
  <offered datetime="2018-04-26"/>
  <description>Page 8, strike lines 19 through 22 and insert the following:    (b) Authorized Expenditures- Section 48101(c) of title 49, United States Code, is amended--    (1) in the subsection heading by striking `Automated Surface Observation***.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 printed in Part A of House Report 115-650 to improve aviation safety by addressing issues such as airline engines, air ambulances, certification processes, and airspace operations. Adjusts FAA authorization levels to conform with updated CBO baseline for FY 2018. Makes counter-UAS systems AIP eligible. Continues the contract weather observer program and requires the Secretary to define the roles and responsibilities of the FAA Tech Center. Reforms and provides transparency to FAA organization and programs. Addresses consumer concerns, including sexual misconduct on flights, treatment of passengers with disabilities, and harmonization of service animal standards. Improves the Airport Investment Partnership Program.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2018-04-26T13:39:57-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Shuster amendment (A001) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T13:29:40-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Shuster.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3636-3643" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3636-3642" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26"/>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T13:29:40-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Shuster.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3636-3643" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3636-3642" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T13:39:57-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T13:39:57-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Shuster amendment (A001) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
