<bill session="115" type="h" number="4813" updated="2019-04-18T16:19:40Z">
  <state datetime="2018-01-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-01-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-01-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study to evaluate the role of unlicensed spectrum in offloading broadband traffic, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">WIFI STUDy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">WIFI STUDy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wireless Internet Focus on Innovation in Spectrum Technology for Unlicensed Deployment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wireless Internet Focus on Innovation in Spectrum Technology for Unlicensed Deployment Act</title>
    <title type="display">WIFI STUDy Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001106"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-01-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Communications and Technology" code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-01-17T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Wireless Internet Focus on Innovation in Spectrum Technology for Unlicensed Deployment Act or the WIFI STUDy Act

This bill requires the Government Accountability Office to study: (1) the role of unlicensed spectrum in the development of the proliferation of Internet-connected devices and in managing Internet protocol traffic on licensed wireless networks, (2) the economic benefits that WiFi provides in assisting with Internet traffic management, and (3) the potential avenues and barriers to broad deployment of gigabit WiFi service in spectrum bands below 6 gigahertz at a scale that allows for rapid expanded use of new consumer devices.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
