<bill session="114" type="h" number="1428" updated="2019-05-09T23:15:19Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-24">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-02-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Judicial Redress Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Judicial Redress Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Judicial Redress Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Judicial Redress Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Judicial Redress Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Judicial Redress Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Judicial Redress Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To extend Privacy Act remedies to citizens of certified states, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2015-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000445" joined="2015-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000467" joined="2015-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-16">
      <text>Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-09-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-10-20">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 114-294, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-20">
      <text>Committee on Oversight and Government discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-10-20" calendar="Union" number="223">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 223.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-10-20T16:01:15-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Goodlatte moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-20T16:01:27-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6985-6988" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-20T16:01:28-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1428.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2015-10-20T16:17:34-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6985-6986" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-10-20T16:17:36-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-21">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-01-28">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Grassley with an amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-02-01" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="356">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 356.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2016-02-09" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S756-757" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S756-757" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-02-10">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-10T17:38:26-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Goodlatte asked unanimous consent that the House agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H694" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="without objection" type="pingpong" datetime="2016-02-10T17:38:28-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion that the House agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H694" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-02-10T17:38:29-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2016-02-12">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2016-02-24" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="114-126" type="public" datetime="2016-02-24">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 114-126.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="1600"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-25T04:59:58Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since&#160;it was reported to the Senate on February 1, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)&#160; Judicial Redress Act of 2015

(Sec. 2) This bill authorizes the Department of Justice (DOJ) to designate foreign countries or regional economic integration organizations whose natural citizens may bring civil actions under the Privacy Act of 1974 against certain U.S. government agencies for purposes of accessing, amending, or redressing unlawful disclosures of records transferred from a foreign country to the United States to prevent, investigate, detect, or prosecute criminal offenses.

The citizens of such countries or organizations may bring a civil action against: (1) U.S. agencies that intentionally or willfully violate conditions for disclosing records without the consent of the individual to whom the record pertains; and (2) U.S. agencies designated by DOJ, with the concurrence of the agency, that refuse an individual's request to review or amend his or her records.

DOJ, with the concurrence of the Department of State, the Department of the Treasury, and the Department of Homeland Security, may designate countries or organizations whose citizens may pursue such civil remedies if the person's country or organization: (1) has appropriate privacy protections for sharing information with the United States, as provided for in an agreement with the United States or as determined by DOJ; (2) permits the transfer of personal data for commercial purposes between its territory and the United States; and (3) has DOJ-certified data transfer policies that do not impede U.S. national security interests.

A country's designation may be revoked if it: (1) is not complying with a privacy protection agreement, (2) no longer has appropriate privacy protections for sharing information, (3) fails to meet requirements for transfers of personal data for commercial purposes, (4) no longer meets the DOJ's transfer policy certification requirements, or (5) impedes the transfer of information to the United States (for purposes of reporting or preventing unlawful activity) by a private entity or person.

DOJ's designations are exempt from judicial or administrative review.

The U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia is granted exclusive jurisdiction over any claim arising under this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-294</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
