<bill session="114" type="s" number="918" updated="2018-06-02T06:44:55Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Notice for Organizations That Include Charities is Essential (NOTICE) Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Notice for Organizations That Include Charities is Essential (NOTICE) Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide notice to charities and other nonprofit organizations before their tax-exempt status is automatically revoked.</title>
    <title type="display">Notice for Organizations That Include Charities is Essential (NOTICE) Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Hatch. With written report No. 114-28.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-04-14" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="51">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 51.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="811"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="400"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-14T15:18:26Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Notice for Organizations That Include Charities is Essential (NOTICE) Act

(Sec. 2) Amends the Internal Revenue Code to require the Department of the Treasury to notify any tax-exempt organization, not later than 300 days after such an organization fails to file its annual tax return or other required information for 2 consecutive years, that: (1) the Internal Revenue Service has no record of its return or&#160;information&#160;for 2 consecutive years, and (2) a penalty will occur if the organization fails to file&#160;its&#160;return or&#160;information by the next filing deadline.&#160;Allows the reinstatement of the tax-exempt status of such an organization without the requirement of an application if: (1) the organization demonstrates to the satisfaction of Treasury that it did not receive the notice required by this Act, and (2) it files an annual return or required&#160;information for the current year. Makes this Act applicable to notices and returns required to be filed after December 31, 2014.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-28</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
