<bill session="115" type="h" number="6707" updated="2019-04-18T16:27:05Z">
  <state datetime="2018-09-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-09-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-09-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish certain standards for the adjudication of United States passport applications, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Western Hemisphere Travel Initiative Improvement Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Western Hemisphere Travel Initiative Improvement Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Western Hemisphere Travel Initiative Improvement Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000581"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000297" joined="2018-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000585" joined="2018-09-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-09-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-09-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Western Hemisphere Travel Initiative Improvement Act of 2018

 This bill establishes certain standards for U.S. passport applications.

 The Department of State shall adjudicate U.S. passport applications in an individualized, evidence-based manner based on an assessment of individual circumstances and evidence. An applicant's race, ethnicity, or ancestry may not be considered in such adjudicatory process.

The bill requires that:

 an applicant establish U.S. citizenship or nationality by a preponderance of the evidence, and a determination that an applicant has not met such evidentiary burden state in writing the reasons for the determination and be provided to the applicant in a timely manner. A birth certificate signed by a person authorized under state law to sign such a document, or a previously-issued U.S. passport, shall constitute prima facie evidence of U.S. citizenship or nationality and, absent individualized evidence that a birth did not take place in the United States, shall satisfy the preponderance of the evidence standard.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
