<bill session="113" type="h" number="799" updated="2018-06-05T16:05:09Z">
  <state datetime="2013-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fisheries Disaster Relief and Research Investment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide exclusive funding to support fisheries and the communities that rely upon them, to clear unnecessary regulatory burdens and streamline Federal fisheries management, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Fisheries Disaster Relief and Research Investment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000266"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001069" joined="2013-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000375" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000559" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000562" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000594" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2013-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" code="HSII22" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-02-15T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Fisheries Disaster Relief and Research Investment Act - Amends the Saltonstall-Kennedy Act to revise the program under which the Secretary of Commerce provides financial assistance for fisheries research and development projects. Directs each Regional Fishery Management Council to establish a fishery investment committee to: (1) develop a regional fishery investment plan identifying research, conservation, management needs, and actions to rebuild and maintain healthy fish populations and sustainable fisheries; and (2) make recommendations to the Council on grant applications and projects to implement the respective plans.

Requires that such plans be revised, approved by the relevant Council, and submitted to the Secretary at least once every five years.

Directs the Secretary to establish an annual competitive grant program to advance regional priorities included in such plans. Makes state, federal, regional, or private entities or persons eligible for such funding. Requires that preference be given to public-private partnerships.

Specifies that national fisheries investment program funds be used by the Secretary for research and investment that supports rebuilding and maintaining healthy U.S. fish populations and promotes sustainable fisheries. (Currently, such funds are used for harvesting, processing, marketing, and other associated infrastructures.)

Allocates monies to each Council and marine fisheries commissions.

Designates an amount to be distributed among eligible recipients of assistance for commercial fishery failures and fishery disasters declared by the Secretary in 2012 under specified provisions of the Interjurisdicitional Fisheries Act and the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act.

Limits to a specified percentage the monies authorized to offset receipts for National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) operations, research, and facilities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
