<bill session="115" type="s" number="1408" updated="2019-04-18T16:37:20Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance effective prosecution and defense in courts-martial, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to enhance effective prosecution and defense in courts-martial, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2017-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1519"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to require of detailed trial and defense counsel in a court-martial that there be adequate supervision and oversight to ensure effective prosecution and defense in the court-martial.

The military department concerned may assign the function of supervising and overseeing prosecution or defense in courts-martial by less experienced judge advocates to civilian employees of the department or the Department of Homeland Security, as applicable, who have extensive litigation experience.

The bill revises requirements concerning pilot programs on the professional development process for judge advocates to direct the military department concerned to assess the feasibility and advisability of a military justice career track for judge advocates under the department's jurisdiction.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
