<bill session="114" type="h" number="5677" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:37Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">U.S.-Israel Partnership to Hold Iran Accountable Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the United States-Israel joint commission to address Iranian compliance with the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action.</title>
    <title type="display">U.S.-Israel Partnership to Hold Iran Accountable Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000599"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">U.S.-Israel Partnership to Hold Iran Accountable Act

This bill authorizes the Department of State to establish a joint commission with Israel to address Iranian compliance with the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPOA).

The commission should:

 support professional dialogues to detect and respond to JCPOA violations by Iran; coordinate subcabinet level political discussions on contingency responses to such violations and responses to Iran's destabilizing, non-nuclear activities, including missile launches, support for terrorism, and human rights violations; and coordinate technical discussions among the State Department, the Department of the Treasury, the Department of Energy, and counterpart Israeli ministries on technical aspects of JCPOA implementation. The bill expresses the sense of Congress that:

 Israeli officials who are counterparts to specified U.S. officials should be appointed as commission members; the President should ensure commission participation by senior officials in the Executive Office of the President and counterparts in the Office of the Prime Minister of Israel; and the Department of Defense should conduct joint military planning with Israel based on commission-identified contingency scenarios, such as responding to the detection of a covert Iranian enrichment facility, new Iranian weaponization efforts, or other clear indicators that Iran has begun a nuclear weapon breakout.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
