<bill session="114" type="s" number="326" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:54Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stewardship End Result Contracting Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 to provide cancellation ceilings for stewardship end result contracting projects, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Stewardship End Result Contracting Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000444"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2015-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2015-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2015-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2015-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2015-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2015-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2015-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2015-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2015-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2015-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2015-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2015-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-30T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stewardship End Result Contracting Improvement Act

Amends the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 to authorize the Forest Service and the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) to obligate funds to cover any potential cancellation or termination costs (cancellation ceiling) in stages that are economically or programmatically viable with respect to an agreement or contract for a stewardship end result contracting project. Requires the Forest Service and BLM to submit written notice to Congress and the Office of Management and Budget 30 days before entering into a multiyear agreement or contract that includes a cancellation ceiling exceeding $25 million if proposed funding for the costs of cancelling the agreement or contract up to the ceiling is not included.

Allows the Forest Service and BLM, if the offset value of the forest products to be removed exceeds the value of the resource improvement treatments, to: (1) use the excess to satisfy any outstanding liabilities for cancelled agreements or contracts; or (2) if there are no such outstanding liabilities, apply the excess to other authorized stewardship projects.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
