<amendment session="113" chamber="h" number="1086" updated="2016-10-25T16:45:52Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5016" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2014-07-16T15:02:43-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001064"/>
  <offered datetime="2014-07-15"/>
  <description>Amendment to prohibit use of funds with respect to specified States, to penalize a financial institution solely because the institution provides financial services to an entity that is a manufacturer, producer, or a person that participates in any business or organized activity that involves handling marijuana or marijuana products and engages in such activity pursuant to a law established by a State or local government and engages in such activity pursuant to a law established by a State or local government.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment to prohibit use of funds with respect to specified States, to penalize a financial institution solely because the institution provides financial services to an entity that is a manufacturer, producer, or a person that participates in any business or organized activity that involves handling marijuana or marijuana products and engages in such activity pursuant to a law established by a State or local government and engages in such activity pursuant to a law established by a State or local government.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2014-07-16T15:02:43-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="418">
      <text>On agreeing to the Heck (WA) amendment (A034) Agreed to by recorded vote: 231 - 192 (Roll no. 418).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6326" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15T19:11:42-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A034) offered by Mr. Heck (WA).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6275-6276" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6275" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15"/>
    <action datetime="2014-07-16T15:02:43-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-16T15:02:43-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-16T15:02:43-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Heck (WA) amendment (A034) Agreed to by recorded vote: 231 - 192 (Roll no. 418).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6326" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15T19:11:42-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A034) offered by Mr. Heck (WA).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6275-6276" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6275" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
