<bill session="114" type="h" number="4964" updated="2019-02-14T23:25:28Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Directed Energy Weapon Systems Acquisition Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to provide for the rapid acquisition of directed energy weapons systems by the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Directed Energy Weapon Systems Acquisition Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000564"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000559" joined="2016-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emerging Threats and Capabilities.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Intelligence and Emerging Threats and Capabilities" code="HSAS26" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="2778"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Directed Energy Weapon Systems Acquisition Act of 2016

This bill amends the Bob Stump National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2003 to state that, if supplies or support services are urgently needed to eliminate a deficiency in directed energy weapon systems, the Department of Defense (DOD) may use specified rapid acquisition procedures to acquire and deploy needed offensive or defensive directed energy weapon systems capabilities, supplies, and associated support services.

"Directed energy weapon system" means military action using highly focused sound, electromagnetic, or particle-beam energy to incapacitate, damage, or destroy enemy equipment, facilities, or personnel.

The bill redesignates DOD's High Energy Laser Joint Technology Office as the Joint Directed Energy Program Office.

The Office shall: (1) develop a strategic plan for development and transition of directed energy weapons capabilities, and (2) use new and revised DOD policies to accelerate the development and transition of directed energy capabilities toward fielding.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
