<bill session="113" type="h" number="4161" updated="2016-10-25T16:11:21Z">
  <state datetime="2014-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">21st Century STEM for Underrepresented Students Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To encourage and further research on the engagement of underrepresented youth in the STEM fields.</title>
    <title type="display">21st Century STEM for Underrepresented Students Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000797"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000377" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000382" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000808" joined="2014-12-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Research and Technology" code="HSSY15" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1486"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="4186"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-03-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">21st Century STEM for Underrepresented Students Act - Requires the Director of the National Science Foundation (NSF) to provide merit-reviewed, competitive grants for research on programming that engages underrepresented students in grades kindergarten through 8 in STEM (science, technology, engineering, and mathematics) in order to prepare these groups to pursue undergraduate and graduate degrees or careers in STEM.

Requires such grants to be used toward research to advance the engagement of these students in STEM through providing before-school, after-school, out-of-school, or summer activities designed to encourage interest, engagement, and skills development of underrepresented students in STEM.

Requires the Director to give priority to applicants which, for the purpose of grant activity, include or partner with a nonprofit, nongovernmental organization that has extensive experience and expertise in increasing the participation of underrepresented students in STEM.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
