<bill session="114" type="hr" number="57" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:12Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Urging the Secretary of State that in 2015, a year of significant anniversaries for the Jewish people, United States embassies in appropriate countries should commemorate this anniversary year with significant public events including the message that the opportunities for remembrance and reflection contained in these anniversaries are applicable to all peoples.</title>
    <title type="display">Urging the Secretary of State that in 2015, a year of significant anniversaries for the Jewish people, United States embassies in appropriate countries should commemorate this anniversary year with significant public events including the message that the opportunities for remembrance and reflection contained in these anniversaries are applicable to all peoples.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000522"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000055" joined="2015-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2015-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2015-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000563" joined="2015-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001187" joined="2015-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001188" joined="2015-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2015-01-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Africa, Global Health, Global Human Rights and International Organizations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Africa, Global Health, Global Human Rights and International Organizations" code="HSFA16" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Germany"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
    <term name="World history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-27T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Urges the Administration to continue efforts to combat anti-Semitism globally.

 Urges the Secretary of State that in 2015, a year of significant anniversaries for the Jewish people, U.S. embassies should observe these anniversaries with public events.

Calls on the Broadcasting Board of Governors to observe these anniversaries with significant programming.

 Expresses sympathy to the families of all those who suffered due to the Nuremberg laws and during the Holocaust.

Expresses appreciation to governments, groups, and individuals that will appropriately mark these anniversaries and work to promote inter-ethnic and interreligious reconciliation.

Appreciates the role of the Holy See in combating religious intolerance and religious discrimination and acknowledges the role of the Nostra Aetate proclamation of Pope Paul VI in fostering interreligious dialogue

Condemns all forms of anti-Semitic abuses that are ongoing throughout the world, whether committed by governments or by other persons or groups, particularly in the forms of denying or minimizing the Holocaust and other crimes of Nazi Germany.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
