<bill session="114" type="h" number="2598" updated="2018-06-02T04:22:31Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lucid Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 23, United States Code, to establish requirements relating to marijuana-impaired driving, to direct the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration to issue comprehensive guidance on the best practices to prevent marijuana-impaired driving, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Lucid Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000598"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000593" joined="2015-06-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Highways and Transit" code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-01T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Lucid Act of 2015

Makes eligible for federal-aid highway project grants a state whose law legalizes the possession or use of marijuana with or without medical justification only if that state:

 has in effect a law prohibiting an individual from driving or being in actual physical control of a motor vehicle while impaired by marijuana, and enforces that law using training and methods for determining cognitive or physical marijuana impairment. Exempts those states from specified administrative penalties.

Revises the terms "driving while intoxicated" and "driving under the influence" to accord with this Act. Subjects repeat offenders to minimum civil and criminal penalties for driving a motor vehicle while impaired by marijuana in those states.

Directs the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration to:

 study through scientific testing the extent to which marijuana impairs an individual's ability to drive a motor vehicle; and issue a report, and make it available electronically to the public, with recommendations to states on how to prevent marijuana-impaired driving.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
