<bill session="114" type="s" number="1690" updated="2019-03-29T05:23:23Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Mountains to Sound Greenway National Heritage Area in the State of Washington.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Mountains to Sound Greenway National Heritage Area Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mountains to Sound Greenway National Heritage Area Act</title>
    <title type="display">Mountains to Sound Greenway National Heritage Area Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2015-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-09-06">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski with amendments. With written report No. 114-317.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-09-06" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="590">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 590.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks" code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2900"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-06T15:11:11Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Mountains to Sound Greenway National Heritage Area Act

(Sec. 4) This bill establishes the Mountains to Sound Greenway National Heritage Area in the state of Washington. The bill designates the Mountains to Sound Greenway Trust as the local coordinating entity for the heritage area, which shall prepare and submit a management plan for it.

(Sec. 6) The Mountains to Sound Greenway Trust shall not use federal funding made available under this bill for the acquisition of real property or any interest in real property.

(Sec. 8) Nothing in this bill:

 abridges the rights of any public or private property owners; alters any adopted land use regulations, approved land use plans, or other regulatory authorities of any federal, state, tribal, or local agencies; conveys any land use or other regulatory authority to the Mountains to Sound Greenway Trust; or alters, modifies, diminishes, or extinguishes any Indian tribe's treaty rights within the heritage area. (Sec. 10) The bill authorizes appropriations.

The federal cost share of any activity carried out under this bill shall be 50% of that activity's total cost.

The authority of Department of the Interior to furnish assistance under this bill terminates 15 years after this bill's enactment.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-317</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
