<bill session="114" type="s" number="542" updated="2018-06-02T06:38:47Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Counterterrorism Border Security Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance the homeland security of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Counterterrorism Border Security Enhancement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000542"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2015-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2015-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2015-12-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Espionage and treason"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Libya"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Pakistan"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-24T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Counterterrorism Border Security Enhancement Act

 Directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to conduct an assessment (which shall focus on the visa waiver program requirements for travelers and program countries) and report to Congress regarding: (1) needed border security and entry procedures improvements in response to homeland threats from the Islamic State in Iraq and Syria (ISIS), and (2) growing participation by U.S. and European nationals as foreign fighters in Syria and Iraq and in terrorist activity.

Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act regarding the visa waiver program to: (1) expand pre-travel clearance procedures; and (2) increase information-sharing requirements, including suspension of countries not fully cooperating with such requirements.

Directs the Department of State to submit a plan to Congress for training consular officers on visa interviewing techniques that emphasizes counterterrorism efforts.

Directs DHS, the State Department, and the Attorney General (DOJ) to submit to Congress a plan for: (1) increasing the scrutiny of U.S. citizens who have recently traveled to Syria, Iraq, Afghanistan, Pakistan, or Libya; and (2) enhancing DOJ and other federal agency capabilities to investigate, arrest, and prosecute U.S. citizens suspected of engaging in terrorist acts or involvement with a terrorist organization.

Authorizes the State Department to revoke and confiscate any passport issued to a U.S. citizen who is suspected of, or who has demonstrated an intent to engage in, terrorist activities.

Amends the federal criminal code to include adherence to terrorist organizations within the definition of "treason."</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
