<bill session="114" type="h" number="2465" updated="2018-06-02T03:42:40Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student Veterans Housing Support Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to make certain improvements to the monthly housing stipend payable under the Post-9/11 Educational Assistance Program of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</title>
    <title type="display">Student Veterans Housing Support Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000296"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001245" joined="2015-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000565" joined="2015-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Student Veterans Housing Support Act

This bill provides a full monthly housing stipend, eliminating the current 50% stipend, for a veteran pursuing a program of education on a more than half-time basis solely through distance learning.

An individual pursuing a degree program on a more than half-time basis shall receive a monthly housing stipend for the month immediately preceding the first month of the program, and in an amount equal to one for a month during which the individual pursues the program.

Housing allowances paid to veterans and eligible persons enrolled in courses may continue during periods:

 when the schools are temporarily closed; between consecutive school terms where such veterans or persons transfer from one approved educational institution to another approved educational institution if the period between such consecutive terms does not exceed 30 days; or between school terms if the period between them does not exceed 8 weeks, and both the preceding and following terms are not shorter than such period, or if the period falls between consecutive spring and fall semesters and the eligible veteran or person resides during such period within the educational institution's ZIP code area. Benefits provided under this Act shall be in addition to any other veterans' educational benefits provided to an individual.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
