<bill session="115" type="h" number="4262" updated="2019-04-18T16:17:31Z">
  <state datetime="2017-11-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-11-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-11-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize members and former members of the uniformed services who are entitled to veterans disability compensation to continue to participate in the Thrift Savings Plan through the deduction and deposit of a percentage of their veterans disability compensation to the Thrift Savings Fund.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Financial Independence for Disabled Veterans Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Financial Independence for Disabled Veterans Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Financial Independence for Disabled Veterans Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000819"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000614" joined="2018-02-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-11-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-11-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Financial Independence for Disabled Veterans Act of 2017

This bill requires the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board to prescribe regulations to permit continued participation in the Thrift Savings Plan (TSP) by a member of the uniformed services after such member's discharge or release from service if such individual is entitled to veterans disability compensation.

For purposes of provisions regarding TSP contributions, such individual's monthly veterans disability compensation shall be deemed to be his or her basic pay for a monthly pay period, but such individual's contribution shall not require or authorize a matching government contribution.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
