<bill session="114" type="h" number="4845" updated="2019-02-01T21:05:43Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disabled Veterans Student Loan Protection Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the student loan forgiveness program in the Higher Education Act of 1965 to include a greater number of disabled veterans and to facilitate the automatic transfer to the Secretary of Education of information regarding veterans eligible for student loan forgiveness, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Disabled Veterans Student Loan Protection Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001185"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001269" joined="2016-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Investment" code="HSED13" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Disabled Veterans Student Loan Protection Act of 2016

This bill amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to modify the federal student loan discharge process for a veteran who has a total and permanent disability.

Specifically, it directs the Department of Education (ED) to establish a system to automatically transmit, from the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) or the Department of Defense (DOD), an applicable determination of unemployability or assignment of a service-connected disability rating of 100%.

ED must accept, as sufficient documentation of a borrower's total and permanent disability, a determination of unemployability by the VA or an assignment of a service-connected disability rating of 100% by the VA or DOD that is transmitted in accordance with such system.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
