<bill session="113" type="s" number="2847" updated="2016-10-25T16:32:23Z">
  <state datetime="2014-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Economic Development Through Tribal Land Exchange Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for certain land to be taken into trust for the benefit of the Morongo Band of Mission Indians, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Economic Development Through Tribal Land Exchange Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000711"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="4867"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-09-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Economic Development Through Tribal Land Exchange Act - Requires the Secretary of the Interior, upon receipt of confirmation that Lloyd L. Fields has executed and deposited with an escrow holder in California a deed conveying title to certain lands designated on the Morongo Indian Reservation, County of Riverside, State of California Land Exchange Map (dated May 22, 2014) as "Fields lands" to the United States in trust for the exclusive use and benefit of the Morongo Band of Mission Indians, and upon receipt by Fields of confirmation that the Secretary has executed and deposited with such escrow holder a patent conveying title to lands designated as "Morongo lands" to Fields and a specified easement to the city of Banning in Riverside County in California for a public right-of-way, to instruct such escrow holder to cause: (1) the patent to the Morongo lands to be recorded and issued to Fields, (2) such easement to be recorded and issued to the city, and (3) the deed to the Fields lands to be delivered to the Secretary.

Instructs the Secretary, after completion of such transfers and as soon as practicable after receipt of confirmation that the city has vacated its interest in land designated as "Banning land," to cause such land to be held in trust for the Tribe subject to: (1) any valid existing rights of any third parties, and (2) legal review and approval of the form and content of all instruments of conveyance.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
