<bill session="115" type="s" number="2666" updated="2019-04-18T16:42:37Z">
  <state datetime="2018-04-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-04-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-04-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve assistance provided by the Hollings Manufacturing Extension Partnership to small manufacturers in the defense industrial supply chain on matters relating to cybersecurity, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhance Cybersecurity for Small Manufacturers Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhance Cybersecurity for Small Manufacturers Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Enhance Cybersecurity for Small Manufacturers Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2018-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2018-04-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-04-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="5517"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-04-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Enhance Cybersecurity for Small Manufacturers Act of 2018

This bill directs the Hollings Manufacturing Extension Partnership (MEP) of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST), in partnership with the Department of Defense (DOD), to address the lack of awareness of cybersecurity threats among small manufacturers in the defense industrial supply chain.

The MEP shall help small manufacturers conduct voluntary self-assessments in order to understand operating environments, cybersecurity requirements, and existing vulnerabilities.

NIST shall transfer its technology and techniques through MEP centers to small manufacturers to implement security measures to protect defense information.

DOD shall establish a cyber counseling certification program, or approve a similar existing program, to certify small business professionals and DOD acquisition staff to furnish cyber planning assistance to small manufacturers in the defense industrial supply chain.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
