<bill session="114" type="h" number="5521" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:36Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reigning In of Governmental Hostility To Sovereignty at the CFPB Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RIGHTS at the CFPB Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 to authorize private parties to compel the Bureau to seek sanctions by filing civil actions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">RIGHTS at the CFPB Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001189"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5983"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Reigning In of Governmental Hostility To Sovereignty at the CFPB Act of 2016 or the RIGHTS at the CFPB Act of 2016

This bill amends the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 to authorize any person who is a party to an adjudicative administrative proceeding brought by the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB), and against whom an order imposing a cease and desist order or a penalty may be issued at the proceeding's conclusion, to require the CFPB to terminate the proceeding. The termination request must be made within 20 days after the person receives notice of the proceeding.

If such a person does require the CFPB to terminate a proceeding, the CFPB may still bring a civil action against the person for the same remedy that might be imposed.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
