<bill session="115" type="h" number="3905" updated="2019-06-17T18:19:38Z">
  <state datetime="2017-11-30T13:51:18-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-11-30T13:51:18-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require congressional approval of any mineral withdrawal or monument designation involving the National Forest System lands in the State of Minnesota, to provide for the renewal of certain mineral leases in such lands, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Minnesota's Economic Rights in the Superior National Forest Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Minnesota&#8217;s Economic Rights in the Superior National Forest Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Minnesota's Economic Rights in the Superior National Forest Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Minnesota&#8217;s Economic Rights in the Superior National Forest Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Minnesota's Economic Rights in the Superior National Forest Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Minnesota&#8217;s Economic Rights in the Superior National Forest Act</title>
    <title type="display">Minnesota's Economic Rights in the Superior National Forest Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000294"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2017-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000587" joined="2017-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000258" joined="2017-10-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-10-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08">
      <text>Subcommittee on Federal Lands Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-11-08" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 17 - 13.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-11-21">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 115-422.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-11-21" calendar="Union" number="312">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 312.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-11-28T18:53:38-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 631 Reported to House. The rules provides 1 hour of general debate on both bills. For H.R. 3017, the bill is closed to amendments. For H.R. 3905, the rule provides for a specified amendment. The rule also provides for one motion to recommit with or without instructions on each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-29T14:22:09-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 631 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-29T15:21:04-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 631.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9498-9512" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H9498-9499" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-29T15:21:09-05:00">
      <text>The rules provides 1 hour of general debate on both bills. For H.R. 3017, the bill is closed to amendments. For H.R. 3905, the rule provides for a specified amendment. The rule also provides for one motion to recommit with or without instructions on each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-29T15:22:51-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 3905.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-29T16:16:23-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed with debate on H.R. 3905.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-29T16:28:57-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 631, the House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Grijalva amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-29T16:38:45-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-29T16:39:33-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - Pursuant to clause 1(c) of rule 19, further consideration of H.R. 3905 is postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-30T13:17:21-05:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - Pursuant to clause 1(c) of rule 19, the House resumed with further consideration of H.R. 3905.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9535-9536" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="643" datetime="2017-11-30T13:51:18-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 216 - 204 (Roll no. 643).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-11-30T13:51:19-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-01">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="procedurally-related" number="631"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h487"/>
    <amendment number="h486"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2017-11-30T13:39:46Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Minnesota's Economic Rights in the Superior National Forest Act

(Sec. 2) This bill declares that minerals with the National Forest System (NFS) lands in Minnesota shall not be subject to withdrawal from disposition under U.S. mineral and geothermal leasing laws unless such withdrawal is approved by an Act of Congress.

(Sec. 3) The bill prohibits any extension or establishment of national monuments on NFS lands in Minnesota except by express authorization of Congress.

(Sec. 4) The bill declares that certain mineral leases issued within the exterior boundaries of NFS lands in Minnesota are indeterminate preference right leases that shall be: (1) issued for an initial 20-year period; and, (2) after such period, shall be renewable for 10-year periods if the lessee has complied with the terms and conditions of the lease during the 20-year period and on the condition that, at the end of each 10-year renewal period, Interior may readjust lease terms and conditions to encourage production or to address changing conditions within the lease area.

Interior may: (1) suspend operations under a lease when the lease can only be operated at a loss due to market conditions or when operations are interrupted by strikes; and (2) issue permits for the use of surface lands subject to, but not included in, the lease for the exploration, development, and use of the deposits covered by the lease.

This bill applies to all such mineral leases within the exterior boundaries of NFS lands in Minnesota, including: (1) leases that are not effective as of enactment of this bill; and (2) the existing hard rock mineral leases for Superior National Forest identified as MNES-01352 and MNES-01353.

The National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA) shall also apply to all such mineral leases within those boundaries. In the case of the renewal of such hard rock mineral leases, the Bureau of Land Management must complete the pending environmental assessment under NEPA within 30 days of this bill's enactment.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-422</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
