<bill session="114" type="h" number="5099" updated="2018-06-02T05:06:32Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-16">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">CHIP IN for Vets Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Communities Helping Invest through Property and Improvements Needed for Veterans Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">CHIP IN for Vets Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Communities Helping Invest through Property and Improvements Needed for Veterans Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">CHIP IN for Vets Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Communities Helping Invest through Property and Improvements Needed for Veterans Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">CHIP IN for Vets Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Communities Helping Invest through Property and Improvements Needed for Veterans Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a pilot program on partnership agreements to construct new facilities for the Department of Veterans Affairs.</title>
    <title type="display">Communities Helping Invest through Property and Improvements Needed for Veterans Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000373"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000449" joined="2016-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001172" joined="2016-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000799" joined="2016-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000066" joined="2016-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-09-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-11-14">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 114-814.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-11-14" calendar="Union" number="638">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 638.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-12-07T14:22:52-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Roe (TN) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-07T14:23:01-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7303-7304" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-07T14:23:03-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5099.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2016-12-07T14:42:52-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7303-7304" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-12-07T14:42:53-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="2016-12-10" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7128-7131" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-12-12">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2016-12-15">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2016-12-16" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="114-294" type="public" datetime="2016-12-16">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 114-294.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2958"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-17T04:59:58Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the House on December 7, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Communities Helping Invest through Property and Improvements Needed for Veterans Act of 2016 or the CHIP IN for Vets Act of 2016

(Sec. 2) This bill authorizes the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to carry out a five-year pilot program under which it may accept up to five donations by non-federal entities of: (1) real property that includes a constructed facility or that is to be used as the site of a facility constructed by the entity, and (2) a facility to be constructed by the entity on real property of the VA.

A donation must be: (1) a property for which funds have been appropriated for a VA facility project or a property that is identified as meeting a need of the VA as part of its long-range capital planning process and that is the location for a VA facility project that is included on the Strategic Capital Investment Planning process priority list; and (2) donated pursuant to a formal agreement with the VA for a VA facility project in an amount acceptable to the VA at no additional cost to the federal government.

Such a formal agreement must provide for: (1) the donation of real property that includes a constructed facility; or (2) the construction of a facility on VA real property or on real property donated to the VA by the entity. An agreement that provides for the construction of a facility shall require the entity to:

 conduct all necessary environmental and historic preservation due diligence, comply with all local zoning requirements, obtain all required construction permits, use construction standards required of the VA when designing, repairing, altering, or building the facility, and provide the real property, improvements, goods, or services in a manner sufficient to complete the construction at no additional cost to the federal government. The VA may not: (1) pay rent, usage fees, or any other amounts to an entity for the use or occupancy of real property donated under this bill; and (2) provide funds to help the entity finance, design, or construct such a facility that are in addition to those appropriated for the facility as of the date of the donation agreement.

An entity that: (1) is donating a facility constructed by the entity shall be required to provide other funds in addition to the amounts provided by the VA that are needed to complete construction of the facility; and (2) seeks to donate real property shall submit an application to address needs relating to VA facilities, including health care needs, identified in its Construction and Long-Range Capital Plan in such manner as the VA may require.

The VA shall include in the annual budget submitted to Congress by the President information regarding real property donated under the pilot program and the status of facility projects relating to that property.

 The Government Accountability Office shall report to Congress every two years until the program ends on the donation agreements under the program.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-814</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
