<bill session="114" type="h" number="6500" updated="2018-11-09T00:09:18Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Moving Housing Forward Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a Mortgage Credit Risk Sharing Pilot Program at Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Moving Housing Forward Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000620"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001083" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001047" joined="2016-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-08T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Moving Housing Forward Act of 2016

This bill directs the Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA) to require the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac) to establish a pilot program that shares with the private sector the credit risk on a pool of single-family residential mortgage loans that back securities on which Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac guarantee the timely payment of principal and interest.

The bill expresses the sense of Congress that credit risk transfer transactions should be encouraged that: (1) reduce taxpayer exposure to credit risk assumed by Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac, and (2) do not expose Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac to excessive counterparty risk that persons contractually obligated to them will fail to perform their obligations.

After the pilot program is executed for three years, the FHFA must examine the economics of developing it into a continuous risk sharing program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
