<bill session="114" type="s" number="14" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:01Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Scofield Land Transfer Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain interest in Federal land acquired for the Scofield Project in Carbon County, Utah.</title>
    <title type="display">Scofield Land Transfer Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5780"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Scofield Land Transfer Act 

This bill establishes a framework to settle trespass and encroachment issues on federal land in Carbon County, Utah acquired for the Scofield Reservoir. It gives the Department of Interior authority to convey fee interest or life estates in property above the normal water surface elevation in exchange for the fair market value, an agreement to waive liability claims, and flood easements.

Interior also has authority to convey to the county roads that extend to the shoreline of Scofield Reservoir.

Funds received as consideration for conveyance under this Act must be deposited in the Scofield Reservoir Fund (established under this Act), and used to: (1) monitor and enforce certain requirements regarding maintaining access to, and eliminating encroachment and private exclusive use of, the federal land surrounding the Scofield Reservoir; and (2) provide enhanced recreation opportunities at the Reservoir.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
