<bill session="114" type="s" number="2284" updated="2018-06-02T07:11:58Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Syrian Refugee Verification and Safety Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to suspend the admission and resettlement of aliens seeking refugee status because of the conflict in Syria until adequate protocols are established to protect the national security of the United States and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Syrian Refugee Verification and Safety Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2015-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2015-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2015-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2015-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2015-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2016-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2015-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8022-8023" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="4048"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-17T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Syrian Refugee Verification and Safety Act

This bill declares that: (1) no alien who is a refugee because of the conflict in Syria (covered alien) may be admitted to the United States as a refugee, (2) no funds may be expended to process refugee applications for covered aliens, and (3) no funds may be expended by the Department of State or the Department of Health and Human Services to resettle covered aliens in the United States.

These restrictions shall remain in effect until 30 days after the President certifies to Congress regarding:

 protocols and interagency coordination to adjudicate such U.S. admissions and resettlement; evaluation and review of such protocols and coordination by the Inspector General of the Intelligence Community; State Department submission to Congress of an updated Congressional Presentation Document of the Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration for Fiscal Year 2016 that reflects security or other risks posed by covered aliens; and a State Department briefing to Congress on the increase in covered aliens seeking refugee admission and so admitted, including information on any terrorist conduct. This certification: (1) may not be submitted to Congress before 270 days, and (2) shall not have any effect if Congress enacts into law a joint resolution of disapproval within 15 days.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
