<amendment session="114" chamber="h" number="6" updated="2019-02-06T22:37:27Z">
  <amends type="h" number="240" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2015-01-14T11:17:15-05:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000055"/>
  <offered datetime="2015-01-14"/>
  <description>Amendment prevents use of any funds to: (1) carry-out the Executive actions announced on November 20, 2014 to grant deferred action to certain unlawful aliens and for other purposes, or four of the "Morton Memos" on prosecutorial discretion and immigration enforcement priorities issued in 2011 and 2012 that effectively prevent certain classes of unlawful aliens from being removed from the country; 2) declares that no funds may be used to carry-out any substantially similar policies to those defunded; 3) declares that the policies defunded and any substantially similar policies have no statutory or constitutional basis and therefore no legal effect; and 4) provides that no funds may be used to grant any Federal benefit to any alien as a result of the policies defunded.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 printed in Part B of House Report 114-2 to prevent any funds from whatever source to be used to carry-out (1) the Executive actions announced on November 20, 2014 to grant deferred action to certain unlawful aliens and for other purposes, and (2) four of the `Morton Memos' on prosecutorial discretion and immigration enforcement priorities issued in 2011 and 2012 that effectively prevent certain classes of unlawful aliens from being removed from the country. 2) Declares that no funds may be used to carry-out any substantially similar policies to those defunded. 3) Declares that the policies defunded and any substantially similar policies have no statutory or constitutional basis and therefore no legal effect. 4) Provides that no funds may be used to grant any Federal benefit to any alien as a result of the policies defunded.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2015-01-14T11:17:15-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="29">
      <text>On agreeing to the Aderholt amendment (A001) Agreed to by recorded vote: 237 - 190 (Roll no. 29).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-01-14T09:18:35-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Aderholt.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H374-379, H388-389" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H374-375" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-14"/>
    <action datetime="2015-01-14T11:17:15-05:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Aderholt amendment (A001) Agreed to by recorded vote: 237 - 190 (Roll no. 29).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-14T11:17:15-05:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-14T11:17:15-05:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-14T09:18:35-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Aderholt.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H374-379, H388-389" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H374-375" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-14">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
