<bill session="114" type="h" number="5064" updated="2019-04-11T15:40:29Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-21T20:15:51-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-09-21T20:15:51-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Act to allow small business development centers to assist and advise small business concerns on relevant cyber security matters, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Improving Small Business Cyber Security Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Improving Small Business Cyber Security Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Small Business Cyber Security Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="display">Improving Small Business Cyber Security Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001083" joined="2016-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001103" joined="2016-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000266" joined="2016-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2016-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001107" joined="2016-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001073" joined="2016-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000386" joined="2016-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2016-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000387" joined="2016-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000583" joined="2016-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001188" joined="2016-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000604" joined="2016-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000600" joined="2016-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000586" joined="2016-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000602" joined="2016-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2016-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000081" joined="2016-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2016-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Security Technologies.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-06-08" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-07-01">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 114-654, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-21T19:55:01-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Chabot moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-21T19:55:06-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5776-5779" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-21T19:55:10-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5064.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2016-09-21T20:15:51-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5776-5777" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-09-21T20:15:53-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Innovation" code="HSHM08" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3024"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4909"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2943"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-21T13:51:50Z" status="Passed House amended">Improving Small Business Cyber Security Act of 2016

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Small Business Act to authorize the Small Business Administration (SBA) to make grants to small business development centers (SBDCs) in furtherance of a Small Business Development Center Cyber Strategy to be developed by the SBA and the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) after the Government Accountability Office (GAO) issues a report that reviews federal cybersecurity resources aimed at assisting small businesses.

SBDCs shall have access to cybersecurity specialists to counsel their small business clients.

(Sec. 3) The Homeland Security Act of 2002 and the Small Business Act are amended to allow DHS and other federal agencies coordinating with DHS to leverage SBDCs to disseminate cybersecurity risk information and other homeland security information to help small businesses in developing cybersecurity infrastructure, threat awareness, and employee training programs.

(Sec. 5) The GAO's cyber resources report must include: (1) an accounting, description, and assessment of the utilization of federal programs that provide cybersecurity assistance to small businesses; and (2) an assessment of whether the resources are duplicative of other programs or accessible to small businesses.

The strategy must include:

 plans for leveraging SBDCs into existing federal cyber programs to assist small businesses; methods for the provision of counsel and assistance to improve small businesses' cyber security infrastructure, threat awareness, and training programs for employees, including agreements with Information Sharing and Analysis Centers to gain awareness of actionable threat information that may be beneficial to small businesses; and an analysis of how SBDCs can leverage federal programs and develop partnerships with federal, state, and local governments and private entities to improve cyber support services to small businesses. The SBA's and DHS's strategy must be developed in consultation with entities representing SBDC concerns and submitted to Congress.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-654</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
