<bill session="114" type="h" number="4419" updated="2019-01-09T21:26:34Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-14">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">District of Columbia Judicial Financial Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">District of Columbia Judicial Financial Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">District of Columbia Judicial Financial Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">District of Columbia Judicial Financial Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">District of Columbia Judicial Financial Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To update the financial disclosure requirements for judges of the District of Columbia courts.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To update the financial disclosure requirements for judges of the District of Columbia courts and to make other improvements to the District of Columbia courts.</title>
    <title type="display">District of Columbia Judicial Financial Transparency Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E83"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-09-13">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 114-745.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-09-13" calendar="Union" number="578">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 578.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20T14:53:30-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Carter (GA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20T14:54:12-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5664-5665" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20T14:54:14-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4419.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20T15:00:55-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22T17:44:07-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5839-5840" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="551" datetime="2016-09-22T17:50:15-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 414 - 0 (Roll no. 551).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 09/20/2016 H5664-5665" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22T17:50:16-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22T17:50:19-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2016-11-29" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6575" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-11-30">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2016-12-02">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2016-12-14" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="114-257" type="public" datetime="2016-12-14">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 114-257.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2966"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="State and local courts"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-15T04:59:59Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it passed the House on September 22, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

District of Columbia Judicial Financial Transparency Act 

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the District of Columbia Code to revise the financial disclosure requirements for District of Columbia judges. The revisions establish new dollar thresholds and requirements for reporting to the District of Columbia Commission on Judicial Disabilities and Tenure the financial interests of the judges and specified family members with respect to:

 income; dividends, rents, interest, and capital gains; liabilities; gifts; real and personal property; honoraria; expense accounts or reimbursements for expenses; and waivers or partial waivers of fees or charges. The financial disclosure reports must be available for public inspection and copying, unless revealing personal and sensitive information could endanger the judge or a family member. A report may be redacted only: (1) to the extent necessary to protect the individual or family member, and (2) as long as the danger to the individual exists.

(Sec. 3) The Probate Divisions of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia may use magistrate judges. (Sec. 4) DC courts may accept payment of fines, fees, escrow payments, restitution, bonds, and other payments by credit card or electronic funds transfer. The executive officer of the courts may contract with a bank or credit card vendor, or other third party provider, to accept such payments, making every effort to find the lowest cost vendor among them. (Sec. 5) The maximum amount in controversy for cases under the Small Claims and Conciliation Branch of DC Superior Court shall increase from $5,000 to $10,000. (Sec. 6) Each chief judge of the Superior Court or of the Court of Appeals, as appropriate, may delegate to an active or senior judge (in the court in which the chief judge sits) the authority to approve any compensation for court-appointed criminal defense or child abuse and neglect attorneys exceeding the usual maximum.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-745</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
