<bill session="114" type="s" number="3259" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:39Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish scientific standards and protocols across forensic disciplines, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Forensic Science and Standards Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="display">Forensic Science and Standards Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5795"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Forensic Science and Standards Act of 2016

 This bill establishes a National Forensic Science Research Initiative, carried out by the Office of Science and Technology Policy, to improve, expand, and coordinate federal research in forensic sciences.

The bill establishes a National Forensic Science Coordinating Office to coordinate with relevant federal agencies in the development of: (1) a unified federal research strategy; and (2) any necessary programs, policies, and budgets to support implementation of the research strategy.

The National Science Foundation (NSF) shall contract with the National Research Council to develop a report: (1) identifying the most critical challenges in forensic science that require further research, and (2) making recommendations for research to address those challenges.

The bill states that each external forensic science research grant awarded by a federal agency under this bill shall be subject to a specified competitive merit-review process.

 The NSF shall:

 award forensic science basic research grants to improve the foundation and practice of forensic science; support one or more forensic science research centers; and conduct a comprehensive evaluation of the NSF's full portfolio of forensic science research and education grants every four years. The National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) shall establish: (1) a competitively selected Center of Excellence focusing on measurement sciences, technology, and standards in forensic science; and (2) scientific area committees to identify gaps in and opportunities for standards development in the forensic sciences.

 NIST and the Department of Justice (DOJ) shall establish a National Commission on Forensic Science to advise the agencies participating in the unified federal research strategy and review recommendations on standards development in forensic science.

DOJ shall:

 encourage the broad adoption of forensic science standards, requiring each DOJ laboratory, and encouraging other federal forensic laboratories, to adopt these standards; promote accreditation and certification based on forensic science standards; and promote recommendations made by the National Commission on Forensic Science.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
