<bill session="114" type="h" number="5158" updated="2018-11-09T00:09:21Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Make America Competitive Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a conditional 10 percent rate of tax for certain businesses.</title>
    <title type="display">Make America Competitive Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001180"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3083"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Make America Competitive Act of 2016

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow corporations to elect a 10% tax rate on their taxable income if such corporations: (1) offer their full-time employees group health insurance coverage, (2) offer such employees a defined contribution pension plan, (3) provide their employees with regular pay increases, and (4) make additional social security contributions for employees who do not have a defined benefit pension plan. Such corporations may also elect to repatriate their current and accumulated foreign earnings at a 5% tax rate.

The bill amends title II (Old-Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act to increase the primary insurance amount (the retirement benefit a social security recipient would receive if benefits are taken at normal retirement age) of employees for whom additional social security contributions are made under this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
