<bill session="114" type="h" number="761" updated="2019-02-13T17:31:08Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Berryessa Snow Mountain National Monument Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To designate the Berryessa Snow Mountain National Monument in the State of California, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Berryessa Snow Mountain National Monument Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000460"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2015-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2015-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001163" joined="2015-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water, Oceans, and Wildlife" code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="393"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Berryessa Snow Mountain National Monument Act

 Establishes the Berryessa Snow Mountain National Monument to consist of federal land and interests in federal land within Colusa, Glenn, Lake, Mendocino, Napa, Solano, and Yolo Counties in California.

 Continues to provide historical and adequate access to private inholdings within the exterior boundaries of the Monument.

Requires a comprehensive plan for the protection and management of the federal lands included within the Monument. Requires such plan to: (1) include a weed management component, (2) include a native fish passage and habitat quality improvement component, and (3) include a component that deals with public safety and environmental clean-up issues associated with illegal marijuana production.

Permits grazing in the Conservation Area: (1) to continue, if established before this Act's enactment; (2) if not established before enactment, only to the extent that it is consistent with the purposes for which the Monument was established; or (3) through issuing annual targeted permits for the control of noxious weeds, fire suppression, or to provide other ecological benefits.

Establishes the Berryessa Snow Mountain National Monument Advisory Council to advise with respect to the preparation and implementation of the management plan for the Monument. Requires the appointment of one Council member to represent Native American tribes.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
