<bill session="114" type="s" number="802" updated="2018-06-02T06:43:53Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-12">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Girls Count Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Girls Count Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Girls Count Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Girls Count Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Girls Count Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development to provide assistance to support the rights of women and girls in developing countries, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Girls Count Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2015-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2015-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2015-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2015-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-05-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-05-21">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Corker with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-05-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="91">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 91.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2015-05-23" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3317-3318" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S3317-3318" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-05-26">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-26T15:02:06-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-26T15:14:56-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-01T19:46:08-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Chabot moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-01T19:46:24-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3624-3627" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-01T19:46:26-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 802.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote2" datetime="2015-06-01T19:58:23-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3624-3625" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-06-01T19:58:25-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2015-06-03">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2015-06-12" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="114-24" type="public" datetime="2015-06-12">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 114-24.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2100"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-13T03:59:59Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the Senate on May 21, 2015. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Girls Count Act of 2015

(Sec. 3) This bill states that it is U.S. policy to:

 encourage countries to support the rule of law and ensure girls and boys of all ages are able to fully participate in society, including by providing birth certifications and other official documentation; enhance training and capacity-building in key developing countries, local nongovernmental organizations, and other civil society organizations in the design, implementation, and monitoring of programs to address the needs of birth registries in countries where girls are systematically under counted; and incorporate into the design, implementation, and evaluation of policies and programs measures to evaluate the impact on girls of such policies and programs. (Sec. 4) Authorizes the Secretary and the Administrator of the U.S. Agency for International Development to support:

 programs that contribute to improved civil registration and vital statistics systems with a focus on birth registration; programs that build the capacity of developing countries' national and local legal and policy frameworks to prevent discrimination against girls in gaining access to birth certificates; and programs and key ministries to increase property rights, social security, home ownership, land tenure security, inheritance rights, access to education, and economic and entrepreneurial opportunities, particularly for women and girls. Authorizes the Secretary and the Administrator to coordinate with multilateral organizations and private sector and civil society organizations to advocate for the registration and documentation of all girls and boys in developing countries.

(Sec. 5) Directs the Secretary and the Administrator to include in relevant evaluations and reports to Congress the following information:

 a breakdown of U.S. foreign assistance beneficiaries by age, gender, marital status, location, and school enrollment status; a description of how U.S. foreign assistance benefits girls; and specific information on programs that address the particular needs of girls.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
