<bill session="113" type="s" number="2231" updated="2016-10-25T16:29:42Z">
  <state datetime="2014-04-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medical Evaluation Parity for Servicemembers Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MEPS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to provide an individual with a mental health assessment before the individual enlists in the Armed Forces or is commissioned as an officer in the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">MEPS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000449"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2014-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2014-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000361" joined="2014-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000461" joined="2014-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2014-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="4305"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-04-09T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Medical Evaluation Parity for Servicemembers Act of 2014 or the MEPS Act - Directs the Secretary of the military department concerned to: (1) provide an individual with a mental health assessment before such individual enlists, or is commissioned as an officer, in the Armed Forces; and (2) use assessment results as a baseline for any subsequent mental health examination. Prohibits such Secretary from considering the results of such assessment in determining the assignment or promotion of a member of the Armed Forces.

Requires the National Institute of Mental Health of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to submit to Congress and the Secretary of Defense (DOD) a report on preliminary mental health assessments of members, including recommendations regarding: (1) establishing such an assessment to bring mental health screenings to parity with physical screenings of members; and (2) the composition of the assessment, best practices, and how to track assessment changes relating to traumatic brain injuries, post-traumatic stress disorder, and other conditions.

Requires the Secretary concerned to provide a comprehensive physical examination and a mental health screening to each member who, after a period of active duty of more than 180 days, is undergoing separation from the Armed Forces and is not otherwise provided such examination or screening in connection with such separation from either DOD or the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA).

Directs the Secretary of Defense to submit to Congress an assessment of DOD's capacity to provide each member who is undergoing separation an electronic copy of the member's service treatment record at the time of separation.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
