<bill session="114" type="s" number="2500" updated="2018-06-02T07:14:34Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Care Premium Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the establishment of a health insurance premium reduction program to ensure that health insurance premiums remain low for American families.</title>
    <title type="display">Health Care Premium Reduction Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001267"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-04T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Health Care Premium Reduction Act

This bill amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to require the Department of Health and Human Services to award grants to states to support the purchase of private health insurance by consumers and to stabilize health insurance premiums. Priority is given to states with the highest health insurance premiums and such states may be provided bonus payments.

States must use grants to:

 reduce health insurance premiums through activities such as cost-sharing programs to reduce deductibles and out-of-pocket expenses; increase the number of individuals with health insurance; review premium rates to determine unreasonable premium increases and facilitate reduction of such rates; and address health insurance affordability, quality, and accessibility through a waiver of health coverage requirements.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
