<bill session="114" type="h" number="1584" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:45Z">
  <state datetime="2015-12-02">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-12-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CARDER Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cybercrime Anti-Resale Deterrent and Extraterritoriality Revision Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide greater extraterritorial criminal jurisdiction over certain credit card and other access device fraud offenses.</title>
    <title type="display">CARDER Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000559"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000445" joined="2015-07-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-30">
      <text>Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-02">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-12-02" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1704"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="754"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-24T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Cybercrime Anti-Resale Deterrent and Extraterritoriality Revision Act of 2015 or the CARDER Act of 2015 

Amends the federal criminal code to extend extraterritorially the application of penalties for fraud offenses involving an access device issued, owned, managed, or controlled by a financial institution, account issuer, credit card system member, or other entity organized under the laws of the United States or any U.S. state or territory. (An access device is any card, code, electronic serial number, telecommunications service, or other means of account access that can be used to initiate a transfer of funds or to obtain money, goods, or services.) Removes a condition under current law that subjects a person to such penalties only if the underlying articles, property, or proceeds are held within or have transferred through U.S. jurisdiction.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
