<bill session="114" type="s" number="1696" updated="2018-08-16T22:54:07Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ocmulgee Mounds National Historical Park Boundary Revision Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Ocmulgee Mounds National Historical Park Boundary Revision Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to redesignate the Ocmulgee National Monument in the State of Georgia, to revise the boundary of that monument, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Ocmulgee Mounds National Historical Park Boundary Revision Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2015-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-09-06">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski with amendments. With written report No. 114-318.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-09-06" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="591">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 591.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks" code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="482"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-06T15:12:00Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Ocmulgee Mounds National Historical Park Boundary Revision Act of 2016

(Sec. 3) This bill redesignates the Ocmulgee National Monument in Georgia as the Ocmulgee Mounds National Historical Park. (Sec. 4) The bill adjusts the boundary of the Historical Park to include approximately 2,100 acres.

(Sec. 5) The Department of the Interior may acquire lands and interests within the boundary of the historical park by donation, purchase from a willing seller, or exchange.

Interior shall administer any acquired land as part of the historical park.

(Sec. 6) Interior shall conduct a special resource study of the Ocmulgee River corridor between the cities of Macon, Georgia, and Hawkinsville, Georgia, to determine:

 the national significance of the study area; the suitability and feasibility of adding land in the study area to the National Park System; and the methods and means for the protection and interpretation of the study area by the National Park Service, other federal, state, or local government entities, or private or nonprofit organizations.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-318</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
