<bill session="113" type="s" number="733" updated="2016-10-25T16:22:39Z">
  <state datetime="2013-04-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Exascale Computing for Science, Competitiveness, Advanced Manufacturing, Leadership, and the Economy Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ExaSCALE Computing Leadership Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Department of Energy High-End Computing Revitalization Act of 2004 to improve the high-end computing research and development program of the Department of Energy, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">ExaSCALE Computing Leadership Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000360"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2013-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001049" joined="2013-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2013-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2013-04-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-04-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Exascale Computing for Science, Competitiveness, Advanced Manufacturing, Leadership, and the Economy Act of 2013 or ExaSCALE Computing Leadership Act of 2013 - Renames the Department of Energy High-End Computing Revitalization Act of 2004 as the Exascale Computing for Science, Competitiveness, Advanced Manufacturing, Leadership, and the Economy Act of 2013.

Defines "exascale computing" as computing through the use of a computing machine that performs near or above 10 to the 18th power floating point operations per second.

Directs the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to: (1) conduct a research program to develop exascale computing machines to promote DOE missions; (2) establish national laboratory-industry partnerships for the research and development of exascale computing machines across all applicable DOE agencies; (3) implement the program through an integration of application, computer science, and computer hardware architecture using public-private partnerships to ensure that exascale computing machines are capable of solving DOE target applications and scientific problems; and (4) use existing funds to carry out the program.

Authorizes appropriations for FY2014-FY2016.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
