<bill session="114" type="h" number="5466" updated="2019-02-14T23:25:27Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Aeronautics Innovation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To secure the United States technological edge in commercial and military aviation.</title>
    <title type="display">Aeronautics Innovation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000387"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001103" joined="2016-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2016-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000295" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2016-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000560" joined="2016-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000168" joined="2016-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001187" joined="2016-07-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emerging Threats and Capabilities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Space.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Space and Aeronautics" code="HSSY16" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Intelligence and Emerging Threats and Capabilities" code="HSAS26" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Aeronautics Innovation Act

This bill expresses the sense of Congress that development of high-risk, precompetitive aerospace technology for use in commercial and military aircraft is a fundamental National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) role.

NASA shall establish the following programs to demonstrate innovative advances in aeronautics and aviation:

 a low-boom supersonic aircraft program, three subsonic flight programs, and an unmannned aircraft (drone) operations program. NASA shall establish a pilot program to allow it to experiment with the crowdsourcing of early stage experimental aerospace vehicle design work to increase the speed, range, safety, and affordability of supersonic or hypersonic aircraft.

The bill expresses the sense of Congress that hypersonic technologies and weapons will play an increasingly important role in our national security.

The John Warner National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2007, as amended, is further amended to revise the responsibilities of the Department of Defense (DOD) Joint Technology Office on Hypersonics in carrying out the DOD program on hypersonics to include developing a well-defined path for hypersonic technologies to transition to operational capabilities for the warfighter.

The bill revises requirements for the Joint Technology Office roadmap for DOD hypersonics programs.

DOD shall appoint an individual recognized in the field of hypersonics to serve as Director of the Joint Technology Office.

The Office of Science and Technology Policy, through the National Science and Technology Council, shall ensure that federal hypersonics research, development, testing, and evaluation activities are coordinated pursuant to a disciplined investment plan.

The Air Force Office of Scientific Research, the Office of Naval Research, and the appropriate Department of the Army science and technology entities may make grants to research institutions for research and development of hypersonics technology and related education and training.

NASA shall establish a 21st Century Aeronautics Capabilities Initiative to ensure that it possesses the infrastructure capabilities necessary to conduct proposed flight research demonstration projects.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
