<bill session="114" type="h" number="5227" updated="2019-02-12T19:45:27Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Library of Congress Modernization Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Library of Congress Modernization Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the National Library Service for the Blind and Physically Handicapped to provide playback equipment in all forms, to establish a National Collection Stewardship Fund for the processing and storage of collection materials of the Library of Congress, and to provide for the continuation of service of returning members of Joint Committee on the Library at beginning of a Congress.</title>
    <title type="display">Library of Congress Modernization Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001150"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001227" joined="2016-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001045" joined="2016-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-25">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on House Administration. H. Rept. 114-706, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-25">
      <text>House Committee on Transportation Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Sept. 30, 2016.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-28">
      <text>Committee on Transportation discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-09-28" state="REPORTED" calendar="Union" number="624">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 624.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4093"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Architect of the Capitol"/>
    <term name="Books and print media"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Joint Committee on the Library"/>
    <term name="Libraries and archives"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-25T14:08:28Z" status="Reported to House without amendment, Part I">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Library of Congress Modernization Act of 2016

(Sec. 2) This bill authorizes the Library of Congress to purchase, maintain, or replace reproducers for books published either in raised characters, on sound-reproduction recordings, or in any other form (currently limited to reproducers of sound-reproduction recordings) for the use of the blind and for other physically disabled U.S. residents.

(Sec. 3) The bill establishes the Library of Congress National Collection Stewardship Fund, whose amounts may be used for:

 preparing collection materials for long-term storage; and transferring amounts to the Architect of the Capitol for designing, constructing, altering, upgrading, and equipping collections preservation and storage facilities for the Library of Congress, or for acquiring real property by lease for the preservation and storage of Library of Congress collections. The Library of Congress shall report a plan for expenditures from the fund in its first five fiscal years of operation.

(Sec. 4) The bill requires continued service on the Joint Committee on the Library in a new Congress, until new committee members are appointed, of Members of Congress who served on such Committee in the previous Congress.

The bill also sets forth requirements for determining who shall serve as Chairman of the Joint Committee on the Library before its first organizational meeting in a new Congress.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-706</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
