<bill session="114" type="h" number="2856" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:41Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Citizen Empowerment Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to establish certain procedures for conducting in-person or telephonic interactions by Executive branch employees with individuals, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Citizen Empowerment Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000290"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001283" joined="2015-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000576" joined="2015-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000168" joined="2015-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="278"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Citizen Empowerment Act of 2015

Requires any executive agency employee who is conducting an in-person or a telephonic interview, audit, investigation, inspection, or other official interaction with an individual relating to a possible violation of federal law that could result in the imposition of civil or criminal fines or penalties or the collection of unpaid tax to allow such individual to make an audio recording of the interaction.

Permits the employee conducting the interaction to record it if the employee: (1) informs the individual of the recording prior to or at the initiation of the interaction, and (2) provides the individual with a transcript of the recording at such individual's expense.

Requires the employee conducting an initial in-person or telephonic interview or other interaction to provide to the individual a verbal or written notice of such individual's rights.

Exempts from the application of this Act any in-person or telephonic interview or other interaction that: (1) is likely to include the discussion of classified material or information that would endanger public safety if released publicly; or (2) if released, would endanger an ongoing criminal investigation being conducted by a federal law enforcement officer.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
