<bill session="114" type="s" number="3505" updated="2018-06-02T07:48:57Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-12-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-12-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bankruptcy Fairness Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require analysis of various bankruptcy proposals in order to determine whether those proposals would reduce systemic risk and moral hazard, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Bankruptcy Fairness Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2016-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2016-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2016-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2016-12-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-12-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6760" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Bankruptcy Fairness Act of 2016 

This bill requires the Administrative Office of the U.S. Courts, the Executive Office for U.S. Trustees, and the Federal Judicial Center to jointly develop and periodically update recommendations regarding the judicial expertise that is required to oversee the bankruptcy process for financial companies and other specified issues related to the bankruptcy process.

After the recommendations are submitted, the U.S. Supreme Court must issue a rule that provides for the orderly appointment of a bankruptcy judge or district court judge with expertise in the resolution of financial companies under the federal bankruptcy code to oversee a bankruptcy case involving a financial company.

The bill amends the federal bankruptcy code to permit specified financial regulators to raise, appear, and be heard on any issues in a bankruptcy case or proceeding in which the debtor is a financial company.

The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation must nominate five disinterested individuals to serve as trustees for a financial company debtor. The U.S. trustee must appoint one of the nominees as a trustee, and the trustee is exempt from the requirements for residency or an office in the judicial district where the case is pending.

The Office of Financial Research must submit to Congress a report summarizing and evaluating various analytical works that examine bankruptcy policies. The report must address the effectiveness of the bankruptcy code, a bridge company study, a financing and liquidity study, and a master netting agreement study. It must also include recommendations regarding any legislative or regulatory changes that could address gaps or vulnerabilities identified.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
