<bill session="114" type="h" number="5958" updated="2019-02-06T22:37:48Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making supplemental appropriations for fiscal year 2016 for Zika response and preparedness.</title>
    <title type="display">Making supplemental appropriations for fiscal year 2016 for Zika response and preparedness.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001102"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001107" joined="2016-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000296" joined="2016-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000368" joined="2016-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001144" joined="2016-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000600" joined="2016-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000593" joined="2016-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000808" joined="2016-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-08T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill provides FY2016 supplemental appropriations to the Departments of Health and Human Services (HHS) and State to prevent, prepare for, and respond to the Zika virus.

The bill specifies permissible uses for the funds and designates the funds as an emergency requirement. The emergency funding is exempt from discretionary spending limits and is only available if the President subsequently designates the funds as an emergency requirement.

The bill provides appropriations to HHS for:

 the Health Resources and Services Administration, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the National Institutes of Health, and the Public Health and Social Services Emergency Fund within the Office of the Secretary. For the State Department, the bill provides appropriations for:

 the Administration of Foreign Affairs, the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), Bilateral Economic Assistance, International Security Assistance, and Multilateral Assistance. The bill sets forth congressional notification and reporting requirements that apply to the funds. It also provides funds to the Government Accountability Office for the oversight of activities funded by this bill.

 The bill also rescinds specified unobligated balances of funds that were previously provided to USAID to prevent, prepare for, and respond to the Ebola virus.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
