<bill session="114" type="h" number="3719" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:44Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STOP ABUSE Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop the Overdose Problem Already Becoming a Universal Substance Epidemic Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the comprehensive approach to eradication of the heroin epidemic, to develop the best practices in law enforcement and prescription medication prescribing practices, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">STOP ABUSE Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000570"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001260" joined="2016-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001083" joined="2016-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000619" joined="2016-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2015-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000382" joined="2015-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000560" joined="2016-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000611" joined="2015-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2015-12-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7013"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1725"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-08T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop the Overdose Problem Already Becoming a Universal Substance Epidemic Act of 2015 or the STOP ABUSE Act of 2015

This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services to convene an interagency task force to develop, solicit input on, disseminate information about, and study implementation of best practices for pain management and prescription of pain medication.

It amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to authorize the Department of Justice to award grants:

 to implement comprehensive community-wide prevention strategies to address a rapid increase or high rate of opioid or prescription drug abuse; and to develop, implement, or expand treatment alternative to incarceration programs. This bill limits an individual's civil liability for harm caused by the emergency administration of an opioid overdose reversal drug (e.g., naloxone) if the individual:

 works or volunteers at an opioid overdose program and provides the drug, as a part the program, to an authorized individual who administers it; or administers the drug after obtaining it from a health care professional or as part of an opioid overdose program, or administers it pursuant to a prescription, and was educated on its administration. It amends the Controlled Substances Act to require an opioid treatment program that closes on any day to make arrangements for each patient to receive treatment during the closure, as necessary.

The bill reauthorizes the High Intensity Drug Trafficking Areas program through FY2020.

It amends the National All Schedules Prescription Electronic Reporting Act of 2005 to include as a specified purpose of state-administered controlled substance monitoring systems ensuring that appropriate authorities have access to prescription history information for investigations.

The bill amends the Public Health Service Act to revise and reauthorize through FY2020 the controlled substance monitoring program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
