<bill session="114" type="s" number="1568" updated="2018-06-02T06:55:27Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-15">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend the authorization to carry out the replacement of the existing medical center of the Department of Veterans Affairs in Denver, Colorado, to authorize transfers of amounts to carry out the replacement of such medical center, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to extend the authorization to carry out the replacement of the existing medical center of the Department of Veterans Affairs in Denver, Colorado, to authorize transfers of amounts to carry out the replacement of such medical center, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000562"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2015-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2015-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2015-06-11" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4116" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4116" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-06-12T09:02:18-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-12">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-12T14:27:07-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Coffman asked unanimous consent to take from the Speaker's table and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-12T14:27:08-04:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4336-4337" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="without objection" type="vote2" datetime="2015-06-12T14:28:17-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4337" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-06-12T14:28:18-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2015-06-15">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2015-06-15" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="114-25" type="public" datetime="2015-06-15">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 114-25.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-16T03:59:58Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of Senate passed version is repeated here.)

Amends the Construction Authorization and Choice Improvement Act to remove the FY2015 limitation on, and increase the amount authorized for, the replacement of the existing Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Center in Denver, Colorado.

(Sec. 2) Authorizes the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to transfer specified amounts of the unobligated balances available to the VA for FY2015 from the following appropriations accounts to the Construction, Major Projects account to carry out the major medical facility construction project in Denver:

 Medical Services, to be derived from amounts available for the Human Capital Investment Plan; Medical Support and Compliance, to be derived from amounts available for such Plan; Medical Facilities, to be derived from amounts available for green energy projects of the VA and human capital investment plans; National Cemetery Administration, to be derived from amounts available for such Plan; General Administration, to be derived from amounts available for the Office of the Secretary; General Operating Expenses, Veterans Benefits Administration, to be derived from amounts available for such Plan; Information Technology Systems, to be derived from amounts available for such Plan; and Construction, Minor Projects, to be derived from amounts available for minor construction projects at the staff offices of the VA. Authorizes the VA to transfer specified amounts of the unobligated balances available in the VA's revolving supply fund and in the VA's Franchise Fund to the Construction, Major Projects account to carry out the Denver project.

Requires funds transferred under this Act to remain available until September 30, 2016.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
