<bill session="114" type="s" number="1349" updated="2018-06-02T06:53:40Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NOTICE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Notice of Observation Treatment and Implication for Care Eligibility Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">NOTICE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Notice of Observation Treatment and Implication for Care Eligibility Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to require hospitals to provide certain notifications to individuals classified by such hospitals under observation status rather than admitted as inpatients of such hospitals.</title>
    <title type="display">NOTICE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2015-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2015-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-06-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-07-30">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Reported by Senator Hatch without amendment. With written report No. 114-107.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-07-30" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="186">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 186.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="876"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-30T13:32:34Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Notice of Observation Treatment and Implication for Care Eligibility Act or the NOTICE Act 

(Sec. 2) This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to require a hospital or critical access hospital with an agreement with the Secretary of Health and Human Services to give each individual who receives observation services as an outpatient for more than 24 hours an adequate oral and written notification within 36 hours after beginning to receive them which:

 explains the individual's status as an outpatient and not as an inpatient and the reasons why; explains the implications of that status on services furnished (including those furnished as an inpatient), in particular the implications for cost-sharing requirements and subsequent coverage eligibility for services furnished by a skilled nursing facility; includes appropriate additional information; is written and formatted using plain language and made available in appropriate languages; and is signed by the individual or a person acting on the individual's behalf (representative) to acknowledge receipt of the notification, or if the individual or representative refuses to sign, the written notification is signed by the hospital staff who presented it.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-107</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
