<bill session="114" type="h" number="5882" updated="2019-02-13T17:31:24Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Freedom Riders National Historical Park Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Freedom Riders National Historical Park in Anniston, Alabama, as a unit of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Freedom Riders National Historical Park Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000575"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Freedom Riders National Historical Park Act

This bill establishes the Freedom Riders National Historical Park in Anniston, Alabama, for the purposes of: (1) arranging for an internationally significant place for public education focused on the Freedom Riders (civil rights activists who rode a Greyhound bus attacked and burned in Anniston on May 14, 1961), civil rights, and the burning of the Freedom Riders' bus; and (2) preserving such historical site for the heritage of that area and as a tourist destination.

The park shall be located at 1031 Gurnee Avenue in downtown Anniston at the Greyhound Bus Station site where the attack began and includes the site of the original bus station.

The Department of the Interior may acquire additional buildings, assets, lands, and interests for addition to the park.

Interior shall complete a general management plan for the park.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
