<bill session="114" type="h" number="1917" updated="2018-11-09T00:08:52Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Truth, Transparency, Accountability, and Fairness in Trade Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Trade Act of 1974 to establish congressional procedures for the termination of economically harmful free trade agreements, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Truth, Transparency, Accountability, and Fairness in Trade Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2015-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2015-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000216" joined="2015-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001038" joined="2015-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2015-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000127" joined="2015-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2015-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2015-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Trade" code="HSWM04" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Truth, Transparency, Accountability, and Fairness in Trade Act

This bill amends the Trade Act of 1974 to require the Department of Labor to make a joint annual report to Congress with the U.S. International Trade Commission on the operation of the trade agreements program during the preceding calendar year, including specified information about each free trade agreement in effect.

Any free trade agreement or portion of it that provides for the termination of portions shall cease to be effective with respect to the United States if annual reports on it show as a result of the agreement or a portion of it any:

 export disruption (declining U.S. exports to, and rising U.S. imports from, a country party to the agreement), either overall or for a specific commodity or industry, in three consecutive calendar years or in three calendar years during a consecutive five-calendar year period; labor disruption (an increase of 5% or more in the number of applications for adjustment assistance for workers and firms), either overall or with respect to a specific good or industry, in each of three consecutive calendar years or in each of three calendar years during a consecutive five-calendar year period; or trade balance disruption (an increase of 5% or more in the U.S. trade deficit in goods with respect to a country party to the agreement) in each of three consecutive calendar years or in each of three calendar years during a consecutive five-calendar year period. A termination bill, relating to such circumstances, must be enacted into law to effect a termination of the free trade agreement or a portion of it.

Fast track procedures are prescribed for congressional consideration of a termination bill.

The United States Trade Representative shall:

 take specified enforcement actions against any country party to a free trade agreement if it has implemented a tariff or nontariff barrier by reason of enactment into law of a bill terminating the agreement in whole or in part, and ensure that any free trade agreement entered into on or after enactment of this Act is negotiated in a form that provides for the termination with respect to the United States of specific portions of it.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
