<bill session="115" type="h" number="5629" updated="2019-04-22T20:05:01Z">
  <state datetime="2018-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Crop Insurance Act and Food Security Act of 1985 to enact reforms to farm subsidies and crop insurance called for in President Trump's budget for fiscal year 2019.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">President Trump's Farm Bill Reforms Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">President Trump's Farm Bill Reforms Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">President Trump's Farm Bill Reforms Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000190"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2018-04-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-04-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">President Trump's Farm Bill Reforms Act of 2018 

This bill modifies several Department of Agriculture (USDA) programs to reduce farm subsidies and revise eligibility requirements.

The bill includes provisions that:

 reduce crop insurance premium subsidies; eliminate the separate payment limitation for peanuts; terminate the use of commodity certificates to pay off marketing assistance loans; eliminate crop insurance premium subsidies and payments under conservation and commodity programs for farms with annual adjusted gross incomes that exceed $500,000; prohibit more than one person in a farming operation from qualifying as a farm manager actively engaged in farming for the purposes of receiving payments under USDA commodity programs; and limit the average rate of return for private insurance companies participating in the Federal Crop Insurance Program to 12% of retained premiums.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
