<bill session="113" type="s" number="2092" updated="2016-10-25T16:29:10Z">
  <state datetime="2014-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Opioid Overdose Reduction Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide certain protections from civil liability with respect to the emergency administration of opioid overdose drugs.</title>
    <title type="display">Opioid Overdose Reduction Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000361" joined="2014-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-14">
      <text>Committee on United States Senate Caucus on International Narcotics Control. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SCNC" name="Senate Senate Narcotics Caucus" activity="Hearings"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="identical" number="4288"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-03-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Opioid Overdose Reduction Act of 2014 - Exempts from liability for harm caused by the emergency administration of an opioid overdose drug:

 a health care professional who prescribes or provides such a drug to an individual at risk of experiencing an opioid overdose, or to another person in a position to assist such individual, if the individual has been educated about opioid overdose prevention and treatment by the health care professional or as part of a government opioid overdose program; a person who provides such a drug for emergency administration to an individual authorized to receive it as part of an opioid overdose program; and a person who provides for emergency administration of such a drug to an individual who reasonably appears to have suffered an overdose from heroin or another opioid if such person obtained such drug from a health care professional or as part of an opioid overdose program and was educated by such professional or program in the proper administration of such drug. Makes such exemptions inapplicable if the harm was caused by gross negligence or reckless misconduct.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
