<bill session="113" type="s" number="2526" updated="2016-10-25T16:31:07Z">
  <state datetime="2014-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Commonsense Legislative Exceptional Events Reforms Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Clean Air Act with respect to exceptional event demonstrations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Commonsense Legislative Exceptional Events Reforms Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000444"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001141" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000127" joined="2014-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3900-3901"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="4957"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-06-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Commonsense Legislative Exceptional Events Reforms Act of 2014 - Amends the Clean Air Act to revise the requirements for regulations that govern the review and handling of air quality monitoring data influenced by exceptional events. (The Environmental Protection Agency [EPA] may exclude monitored exceedances of the National Ambient Air Quality Standards from consideration when designating an area as nonattainment, redesignating an area as nonattainment, or reclassifying an existing nonattainment area to a higher classification if a state demonstrates that an exceptional event caused the exceedances.)

 Requires the criteria used to determine if an exceptional event was demonstrated to be specific in order to minimize the discretion of the EPA in approving or disapproving the demonstration.

 Requires the EPA to make a determination within 90 days after the submission of a petition by a state of an exceptional event demonstration. Considers the demonstration approved if the EPA does not make a determination by that deadline.

 Requires a determination to be based on a preponderance of the evidence and to accord substantial deference to the findings of the state exceptional event demonstration. Establishes an appeal process for reviewing a disapproval of a demonstration.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
