<bill session="114" type="h" number="3334" updated="2018-06-02T04:40:16Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Families Flying Together Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to issue regulations with respect to ensuring families are able to sit together on flights, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Families Flying Together Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000619"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2015-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Aviation" code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Families Flying Together Act of 2015

This bill directs the Department of Transportation to issue regulations directing each air carrier to: (1) establish a policy to ensure that a family that purchases tickets for a flight is seated together during that flight, and (2) make the policy available to the public on the air carrier's website. The bill defines "family" to mean a grouping of individuals that includes, at a minimum: (1) a child age 12 years or younger, and (2) an individual age 18 years or older who is responsible for accompanying that child.

The bill makes it an unfair or deceptive practice for any ticket agent, air carrier, foreign air carrier, or other person offering to sell tickets for air transportation to fail to disclose, prior to an individual's purchase of more than one ticket for a covered flight that includes a ticket for a minor, a notification that: (1) it is not possible to assign two or more seats together on at least one of the flights selected,&#160;and (2) the individual may not be able to sit next to other members of his or her travel party even if he or she is traveling with a minor. The term "covered flight" is defined as a flight for which: (1) a purchaser of a ticket may specify an advance seat assignment, with or without the assessment of any charge or fee; and (2) two or more laterally adjacent seats are not available for advance assignment.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
