<bill session="115" type="h" number="7274" updated="2019-04-18T16:28:47Z">
  <state datetime="2018-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide an incentive for firearm owners to sell their firearms safely and responsibly.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keeping Guns From Criminals Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keeping Guns From Criminals Act</title>
    <title type="display">Keeping Guns From Criminals Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001292"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-12-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-12-12T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Keeping Guns From Criminals Act

This bill amends the federal criminal code to modify the criminal liability standard for certain firearm sales or transfers.

Current law makes it a crime for any person to knowingly sell or transfer a firearm to a prohibited person (i.e., a person who is prohibited from possessing or receiving a firearm). This legislation eliminates the "knowingly" standard to impose criminal liability on any person who sells or transfers a firearm to a prohibited person, regardless of whether such seller or transferor knows that the buyer is a prohibited person.

A defendant seller or transferor may assert as an affirmative defense against prosecution evidence to prove that the buyer or recipient passed a background check or possessed a valid concealed carry permit in the state of transfer.

The affirmative defense does not apply if defendant knew or had reasonable cause to believe the buyer or recipient was a prohibited person.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
