<bill session="114" type="sr" number="173" updated="2018-06-02T06:17:09Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-06">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution condemning atrocities committed by Bashar al-Assad of Syria and his regime, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution condemning atrocities committed by Bashar al-Assad of Syria and his regime, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000146"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2015-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2015-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000355" joined="2015-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2015-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2015-05-06" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2696-2697" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2693-2694" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-06T17:16:20Z" status="Passed Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Condemns the actions of Bashar al-Assad and his regime for committing brutal acts of violence against the Syrian people, for committing systematic murder, torture, rape and enforced disappearance against the Syrian people, and for using weapons of mass destruction including chemical weapons against the Syrian people.

 Condemns the loss of innocent civilian life during the course of the civil war in Syria.

 Supports the diplomatic efforts of the international coalition to drive Bashar al-Assad from office and preserve the government institutions required to restore Syria's stability.

Objects to any role for Bashar al-Assad in any final settlement to the civil war.

States that nothing in this resolution shall be construed as an authorization for the use of military force.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
