<bill session="114" type="s" number="815" updated="2018-08-16T22:54:11Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cow Creek Umpqua Land Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Western Oregon Tribal Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the conveyance of certain Federal land in the State of Oregon to the Cow Creek Band of Umpqua Tribe of Indians.</title>
    <title type="display">Western Oregon Tribal Fairness Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2015-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1664" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1665" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 114-380.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-09-08">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 114-345.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-09-08" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="620">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 620.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="1436"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2791"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-08T14:20:40Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Western Oregon Tribal Fairness Act

TITLE I--COW CREEK UMPQUA LAND CONVEYANCE

(Sec. 102) This bill requires that 17,519 acres of land be held in trust for, and be part of the reservation of, the Cow Creek Band of Umpqua Tribe of Indians. This land is taken into trust when the Department of the Interior and the tribe enter an agreement that secures existing Interior access to the land.

(Sec. 104) Federal law applies to the export of unprocessed logs harvested from this land and to forest management on this land. Gaming on this land is prohibited. This land is not subject to the land use planning requirements of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 or the Act of August 28, 1937.

(Sec. 105) Interior must reclassify public domain land as Oregon and California Railroad grant land in equal acreage as grant land held in trust as part of this land.

TITLE II--OREGON COASTAL LAND CONVEYANCE

(Sec. 202) This bill requires that 14,742 acres of land be held in trust for, and be part of the reservation of, the Confederated Tribes of Coos, Lower Umpqua, and Siuslaw Indians. This land is taken into trust when Interior and the tribes enter an agreement that secures existing Interior access to the land and secures access for activities including land management, surveys, and transit of public vehicles.

(Sec. 204) Federal law applies to the export of unprocessed logs harvested from this land and to forest management on this land. Gaming on this land is prohibited. This land is not subject to the land use planning requirements of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 or the Act of August 28, 1937.

(Sec. 205) Interior must reclassify public domain land as Oregon and California Railroad grant land in equal acreage as grant land held in trust as part of this land.TITLE III--AMENDMENTS TO COQUILLE RESTORATION ACT

(Sec. 301) This bill amends the Coquille Restoration Act to remove the requirement that Interior manage the Coquille Forest in accordance with state and federal forestry and environmental protection laws. Federal law applies to the export of unprocessed logs harvested from this land. Sales of timber from this land must be advertised, offered, and awarded according to competitive bidding practices.

This bill strikes a provision giving the U.S. District Court for the District of Oregon jurisdiction over certain actions concerning the Coquille Forest and limiting remedies to equitable relief.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-345</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
