<bill session="114" type="h" number="1067" updated="2019-01-09T21:25:59Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">U.S. Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to extend the temporary expansion of the United States Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims, to ensure that judges of the United States Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims may enroll in the Federal Employee Group Life Insurance program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">U.S. Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims Reform Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001106"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000581" joined="2015-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-25T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">U.S. Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims Reform Act

 This bill extends the temporary expansion of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims.

 Specified recall provisions for retired Court judges are amended, including changing the recall period from 90 days in a calendar year to 90 days.

 A regular service judge and a retired judge shall be treated as an employee for government life insurance purposes.

 Regular service judges, retired recall eligible judges, and certain retired but not recall-eligible judges may purchase up to an additional year of service credit for each year of federal judicial service completed.

The salary of Court judges is set at the rate applicable to federal appellate court judges. (Currently, their salary is set at the rate applicable to federal district court judges.)</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
