<bill session="115" type="s" number="1535" updated="2019-04-18T16:37:50Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to improve, expand, and extend the credit for carbon dioxide sequestration.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Furthering carbon capture, Utilization, Technology, Underground storage, and Reduced Emissions Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FUTURE Act</title>
    <title type="display">FUTURE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001069"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000607" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2017-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2256"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3761"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Furthering carbon capture, Utilization, Technology, Underground storage, and Reduced Emissions Act or the FUTURE Act

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend and modify the tax credit for carbon dioxide sequestration. The bill modifies the credit to apply it to carbon oxide sequestration. (Carbon oxide refers to any of the three oxides of carbon: carbon dioxide, carbon monoxide, and carbon suboxide.)

The bill also:

 allows certain new industrial or direct air capture facilities to qualify for the credit if construction begins before January 1, 2024; allows qualified projects to claim the credit for 12 years, beginning on the date the equipment was originally placed in service; increases the separate credit amounts, with respect to projects placed in service upon or after the enactment of this bill, that apply to captured carbon oxide that is: (1) disposed of in secure geological storage, and (2) used as a tertiary injectant in an enhanced oil or natural gas recovery project and disposed of in secure geological storage; expands the purposes for which captured carbon oxide may be used; establishes separate carbon oxide capture thresholds for electricity generating facilities, direct air capture facilities, and facilities used for other purposes; specifies that the 75 million metric ton cap on the carbon dioxide that may qualify for the credit applies to carbon oxide and only to projects placed in service before the enactment of this bill; and allows the credit to be transferred from the entity that owns and uses the capture equipment to the entity that disposes of or uses the carbon oxide.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
