<bill session="114" type="h" number="3932" updated="2019-01-09T21:10:00Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ECONOMICS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Continued Operations and No Other Major Incidents, Closures, or Slowdowns Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Labor Management Relations Act, 1947, to provide for the mandatory appointment of a board of inquiry into slow-downs, strikes, or lock-outs when certain specified events occur, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">ECONOMICS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000189"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001077" joined="2015-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2015-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2015-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2015-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001159" joined="2015-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000578" joined="2015-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001180" joined="2015-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001189" joined="2015-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001187" joined="2015-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000031" joined="2015-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000129" joined="2015-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000791" joined="2015-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000813" joined="2015-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000018" joined="2015-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1602"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" code="HSED02" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" code="HSPW07" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Ensuring Continued Operations and No Other Major Incidents, Closures, or Slowdowns Act or the ECONOMICS Act

This bill amends the Labor Management Relations Act, 1947 to direct the President to appoint a board of inquiry within 10 days after any of the following events occur:

 the U.S. Census Bureau reports that the monthly Import or Export Vessel Value decreased by 20% or more in any one month from the previous month in any one of the four metric identification regions into which each U.S. maritime port shall be classified; a slow-down or a threatened or actual strike or lock-out takes place at four or more port facilities in any one of the four metric identification regions; or a slow-down or a threatened or an actual strike or lock-out occurs in which the total number of employees actively involved at the affected port facilities in any one of the four metric identification regions, is 6,000 or greater. The Department of Transportation shall classify the nation's maritime ports as belonging to one of these four metric identification regions: (1) West Coast, (2) East Coast, (3) Gulf Coast, and (4) Great Lakes.

A board of inquiry must report to the President within 10 days after its appointment on whether the slow-down or threatened or actual strike or lock-out contributed to the occurrence of the event.

The Bureau of Transportation Statistics shall collect the following data relating to activity at port facilities in the United States: (1) the average number of lifts per hour of containers by crane, (2) the average cargo container dwell time, (3) the average truck times at ports, and (4) the average rail time at ports.

The Bureau shall report to Congress recommendations on whether such conditions exist requiring the appointment of such a board.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
