<bill session="115" type="h" number="3506" updated="2019-04-18T16:14:00Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To sunset new Federal regulatory rules after 3 years, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Article I Restoration Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Article I Restoration Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Article I Restoration Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000599"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Antitrust, Commercial, and Administrative Law" code="HSJU05" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Article I Restoration Act of 2017

This bill requires any covered rule issued by an executive agency after&#160;this bill's enactment to sunset three years after its effective date unless specifically reauthorized by Congress.

A "covered rule" does not include a rule:

 issued in accordance with specified formal rulemaking provisions of the Administrative Procedure Act; issued with respect to a military or foreign affairs function of the United States; that the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs certifies is necessary for the enforcement of federal criminal laws; that is limited to agency organization, management, or personnel matters; or that is necessary due to an imminent threat to human health or safety or any other emergency. An agency may not reissue, enforce, revise, or take other regulatory action related to a covered rule that has sunset.

The Office of Management and Budget or the relevant agency may oversee the sunset of covered rules.

If the agency that issues covered rules wants to request a reauthorization for such rules, such agency shall, by the December 1 that is one year before the rule is scheduled to sunset, submit to Congress a report that includes: (1) a justification for such reauthorization, (2) any related covered rules, and (3) any recommendation or request made by the chair or ranking member of an appropriate committee.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
