<bill session="114" type="s" number="1550" updated="2019-01-09T21:26:40Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-14">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Program Management Improvement Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Program Management Improvement Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Program Management Improvement Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Program Management Improvement Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Program Management Improvement Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Program Management Improvement Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 31, United States Code, to establish entities tasked with improving program and project management in certain Federal agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Program Management Improvement Accountability Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2015-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001069" joined="2015-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-06-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-11-03">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 114-162.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-11-03" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="288">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 288.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-11-19">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8171-8173" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-19">
      <text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8171-8172" label="text of committee substitute as amended"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2015-11-19" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8172-8173" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-11-20">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-30T14:06:09-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-05-17">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-06-21">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 114-637.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-06-21" calendar="Union" number="495">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 495.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20T15:16:28-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Carter (GA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20T15:17:06-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5668-5670" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20T15:17:09-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 1550.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20T15:26:16-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22T17:37:50-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5839" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="550" datetime="2016-09-22T17:44:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_BACK:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 404 - 11 (Roll no. 550).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 09/20/2016 H5668-5669" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22T17:44:01-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-26">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendment to Senate bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-30">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="pingpong" datetime="2016-11-30" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Senate agreed to House amendment to Senate bill by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-12-01">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2016-12-05">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2016-12-14" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="114-264" type="public" datetime="2016-12-14">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 114-264.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2144"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2943"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2873"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2016-12-15T04:59:59Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the House on September 22, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Program Management Improvement Accountability Act

(Sec. 2) This bill establishes as additional functions of the Deputy Director for Management of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) requirements to:

 adopt and oversee implementation of government-wide standards, policies, and guidelines for program and project management for executive agencies; chair the Program Management Policy Council (established by this Act); establish standards and policies for executive agencies consistent with widely accepted standards for program and project management planning and delivery; engage with the private sector to identify best practices in program and project management that would improve federal program and project management; conduct portfolio reviews to address programs identified as high risk by the Government Accountability Office (GAO); conduct portfolio reviews of agency programs at least annually to assess the quality and effectiveness of program management; and establish a five-year strategic plan for program and project management. The bill exempts the Department of Defense (DOD) from such provisions to the extent that they are substantially similar to: (1) federal provisions governing the defense acquisition workforce; or (2) policy, guidance, or instruction of DOD related to program management.

The head of each federal agency that is required to have a Chief Financial Officer shall designate a Program Management Improvement Officer to implement agency program management policies and develop a strategy for enhancing the role of program managers within the agency. The OMB must submit a report containing such strategy within one year after enactment of this bill. The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics shall be considered the Program Management Improvement Officer for DOD.

The Program Management Policy Council is established within OMB to act as the principal interagency forum for improving agency practices related to program and project management.

The Office of Personnel Management must issue regulations that: (1) identify key skills and competencies needed for an agency program and project manager, (2) establish a new job series or update and improve an existing job series for program and project management within an agency, and (3) establish a new career path for program and project managers.

The GAO must issue a report within three years of enactment, in conjunction with its high risk list, examining the effectiveness of the following (as required or established under this Act) on improving federal program and project management:

 the standards, policies, and guidelines for program and project management; the strategic plan; Program Management Improvement Officers; and the Program Management Policy Council.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-162</report>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-637</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
