<bill session="113" type="s" number="2356" updated="2016-10-25T16:30:13Z">
  <state datetime="2014-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mojave National Preserve Boundary Adjustment Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to adjust the boundary of the Mojave National Preserve.</title>
    <title type="display">Mojave National Preserve Boundary Adjustment Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000146" joined="2014-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-23">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-493.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks" code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-05-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Mojave National Preserve Boundary Adjustment Act of 2014 - Transfers administrative jurisdiction of 525 acres of land from the National Park Service to the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) for a rail project. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to acquire by donation approximately four acres of land within or adjacent to the Mojave National Preserve in California to be used for mitigation for every one acre of land removed from the Preserve.

Requires the acquired land to become part of the Preserve.

Authorizes the Secretary to permit cattle grazing on the acquired land in accordance with applicable National Park Service laws and policies.

Provides for the transferred land to remain withdrawn from: (1) entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the general mining laws; and (3) the mining leases, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
