<bill session="114" type="h" number="4649" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:36Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Decade for the People of African Descent Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To support the International Decade for People of African Descent, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Decade for the People of African Descent Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001270" joined="2016-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2016-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2016-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2016-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2016-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000287" joined="2016-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001137" joined="2016-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2016-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001185" joined="2016-02-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-29T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Decade for the People of African Descent Act

This bill establishes within the Department of State an Office on the International Decade for People of African Descent which shall be headed by an Ambassador-at-Large for the International Decade for People of African Descent.

 The State Department, with the assistance of the Ambassador-at-Large, shall establish an Internet site containing major international documents relating to the International Decade for People of African Descent.

It is the sense of Congress that:

 U.S. diplomatic missions in countries may promote the International Decade for People of African Descent; and in allocating or recommending the allocation of funds or the recommendation of candidates for programs and grants, U.S. diplomatic missions should give consideration to those programs, initiatives, and candidates deemed to assist in the promotion of the International Decade for People of African Descent. The bill also establishes the U.S. Commission on the International Decade for People of African Descent, which shall: (1) promote the International Decade for People of African Descent; and (2) make policy recommendations to the President, the State Department, and Congress regarding matters involving the International Decade for People of African Descent.

It is the sense of Congress that there should be within the Executive Office of the President a Special Adviser to the President on the International Decade for People of African Descent, to serve as liaison with the Ambassador-at-Large for the International Decade, the commission, Congress, and nongovernmental organizations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
