<bill session="113" type="h" number="1076" updated="2016-10-25T16:00:32Z">
  <state datetime="2013-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to provide for savings to the Federal Government by permitting pass-through funding for State authorized public entity health benefits pools.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to provide for savings to the Federal Government by permitting pass-through funding for State authorized public entity health benefits pools.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001087" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000567" joined="2013-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000168" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000238" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000809" joined="2014-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-12">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-03-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) to allow a state-authorized public entity benefits pool to apply to the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) for pass-through funding with respect to health care benefits provided through the pool for coverage years beginning on or after January 1, 2014. Requires the Secretary to approve such a pool if the health care benefits provided through it will: (1) provide at least the essential health benefits, (2) provide coverage and cost-sharing protections against excessive out-of-pocket spending that are at least as affordable as the health insurance requirements of PPACA would provide, and (3) result in cost savings to the federal government because the cost of coverage through the pool is less than the cost of coverage through an exchange.

Treats an individual covered under such a plan as having minimum essential coverage for purposes of the Internal Revenue Code.

Requires the Secretary to provide for an alternative means by which an aggregate amount shall be paid to the pool annually based on the premium tax credits, cost-sharing reductions, and small business credits that would have been provided to an exchange plan.

Gives the Secretary 180 days to make a determination on an application under this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
