<bill session="114" type="s" number="304" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:34Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-13T17:48:56-04:00">PASSED:BILL</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-07-13T17:48:56-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve motor vehicle safety by encouraging the sharing of certain information.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Motor Vehicle Safety Whistleblower Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Conscience Protection Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Motor Vehicle Safety Whistleblower Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Motor Vehicle Safety Whistleblower Act</title>
    <title type="display">Conscience Protection Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2015-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2015-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2015-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2015-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2015-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2015-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2015-01-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S655-656" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-02-26" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-04-13">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Thune with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 114-13.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-04-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="36">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 36.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2015-04-28" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2487-2488" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2487-2488" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29T12:42:05-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-12T23:40:10-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 822 Reported to House. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Provides for consideration of the Senate amendment to the House amendment to S. 764. The resolution makes in order a motion that the House agree to the Senate amendment to the House amendment to S. 764.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13T14:44:37-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 822 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13T14:45:10-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mrs. Blackburn asked unanimous consent that the question of adopting a motion to recommit on S. 304 may be subject to postponement as though under clause 8 of rule 20. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13T14:45:34-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 822.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4844-4860" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13T14:45:39-04:00">
      <text>Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Provides for consideration of the Senate amendment to the House amendment to S. 764. The resolution makes in order a motion that the House agree to the Senate amendment to the House amendment to S. 764.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13T14:46:52-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on S. 304.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13T16:06:12-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13T16:06:40-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Wasserman Schultz moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4859" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4859" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13T16:06:54-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the motion to recommit with instructions, pending the reservation of a point of order. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to add a section to the bill prohibiting the provisions of section 3 from applying to the extent that such provisions would reduce access to health care services to prevent, prepare for, or respond to the Zika virus. The reservation was subsequently withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13T16:14:08-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the motion to recommit with instructions, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the motion, and by voice vote, announced that the nays had prevailed. Ms. Wasserman Shultz demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the motion until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13T17:36:37-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4866" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13T17:42:39-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 182 - 244 (Roll no. 442).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="443" datetime="2016-07-13T17:48:56-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 245 - 182 (Roll no. 443).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4844-4845" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13T17:48:58-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendment to Senate bill.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Consumer Protection and Commerce" code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="114" relation="procedurally-related" number="822"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4828"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2927"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1341"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2016-07-13T15:53:51Z" status="Passed House amended">Conscience Protection Act of 2016

(Sec. 3) This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to codify the prohibition against the federal government and state and local governments that receive federal financial assistance for health-related activities penalizing or discriminating against a health care provider based on the provider's refusal to be involved in, or provide coverage for, abortion. Health care providers include health care professionals, health care facilities, social services providers, health care professional training programs, and health insurers.

The Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Health and Human Services, in coordination with the Department of Justice (DOJ), must investigate complaints alleging discrimination based on an individual's religious belief, moral conviction, or refusal to be involved in an abortion.

DOJ or any entity adversely affected by such discrimination may obtain equitable or legal relief in a civil action. Administrative remedies do not need to be sought or exhausted prior to commencing an action or granting relief. Such an action may be brought against a governmental entity.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-13</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
