<bill session="114" type="h" number="4973" updated="2018-11-09T00:09:19Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Investing in Older Americans Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a work opportunity tax credit for the older long-term unemployed recipient, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Investing in Older Americans Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000822"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Investing in Older Americans Act of 2016 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to make the Work Opportunity Tax Credit (WOTC) permanent and expand it to include the hiring of older long-term unemployment recipients.

(The WOTC permits employers that hire individuals with certain personal characteristics to claim a tax credit equal to a portion of the wages paid to those individuals.)

A qualified older long-term unemployment recipient is an individual who is certified by the designated local agency as:

 being at least 55 years of age on the hiring date, and qualified as a long-term unemployment recipient under current law by being unemployed for at least 27 consecutive weeks and receiving state or federal unemployment compensation during that period. The bill limits to $14,000 the amount of the qualified first-year wages which may be taken into account under the WOTC for a qualified older long-term unemployment recipient.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
