<bill session="114" type="h" number="3796" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:24Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nursing Home Accountability Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 232 of the National Housing Act to provide that nursing homes receiving low ratings for purposes of the Medicare or Medicaid programs are ineligible for mortgage insurance under such section, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Nursing Home Accountability Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000819"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Nursing Home Accountability Act of 2015

This bill amends the National Housing Act to condition a nursing home's eligibility for a Section 232 loan upon its quality rating. (A Section 232 loan is insured by the Federal Housing Administration and may be used to finance or refinance the purchase, construction, or renovation of a nursing home or assisted living facility.)

A nursing home becomes ineligible for a Section 232 loan if, for any period of 30 or more consecutive months, the home achieves two or fewer stars under the five-star quality rating system established pursuant to the Social Security Act for purposes of the Medicare and Medicaid programs. However, a nursing home's eligibility shall be renewed if the home subsequently maintains a rating of three or more stars for a period of at least 30 consecutive months.

The bill does not affect existing mortgages.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
