<bill session="114" type="h" number="325" updated="2019-05-09T23:32:57Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Pribilof Islands Transition Act to require the Secretary of Commerce to provide notice of certification that no further corrective action is required at sites and operable units covered by the Pribilof Islands Environmental Restoration agreement, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pribilof Islands Transition Act Amendments of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Pribilof Islands Transition Act Amendments of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indigenous Peoples of the United States" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-13T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Pribilof Islands Transition Act Amendments of 2015

This bill amends the Fur Seal Act of 1966 to revise provisions concerning the disposal of federal property on the Pribilof Islands (a group of five islands off the coast of mainland Alaska named Saint Paul, Saint George, Walrus, Otter, and Sea Lion Rock), including by: (1) authorizing the Department of Commerce to transfer or exchange specified land on the Islands to the village corporations of Saint Paul and Saint George Islands, and (2) giving those village corporations the first priority right to acquire that land on their respective islands.

Commerce must promptly publish and submit to the Senate notice of certification that Alaska has confirmed that no further corrective action is required at sites and operable units covered by the Pribilof Islands Environmental Restoration Agreement between the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and Alaska.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
