<bill session="114" type="s" number="1607" updated="2018-06-02T06:56:12Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-07">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Independent Agency Regulatory Analysis Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Independent Agency Regulatory Analysis Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to affirm the authority of the President to require independent regulatory agencies to comply with regulatory analysis requirements applicable to executive agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Independent Agency Regulatory Analysis Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000449"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2015-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2015-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2016-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2016-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2015-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2015-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-16">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-10-07" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-12-09">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-12-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="721">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 721.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Housing Finance Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal Maritime Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="National Labor Relations Board (NLRB)"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC)"/>
    <term name="Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission"/>
    <term name="Postal Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
    <term name="Surface Transportation Board"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-09T17:28:57Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Independent Agency Regulatory Analysis Act of 2015

(Sec. 3) This bill authorizes the President to require an independent regulatory agency, while maximizing net benefits and considering costs, to comply with regulatory analysis requirements applicable to other federal agencies.

For any proposed or final economically significant rule (i.e., a rule that is likely to have an annual effect on the economy of $100 million or more or to adversely affect in a material way the economy, productivity, competition, jobs, the environment, public health or safety, or state, local, or tribal governments or communities), the President may require in independent regulatory agency to publish and provide the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs (OIRA) with: (1) an assessment of the costs and benefits of such rule, (2) an assessment of costs and benefits of alternatives to such rule, and (3) an explanation of why the planned regulatory action is preferable to identified alternatives.

The President may require: (1) such an agency to submit any proposed or final economically significant rule to OIRA for review; (2) OIRA to submit for inclusion in the rule making record its assessment of the extent to which the agency has complied with regulatory analysis requirements; and (3) that if OIRA does not complete such assessment within 90 days, such agency shall be deemed to have met the requirement for review and may publish the final rule without inclusion of an assessment in the rule making record.

(Sec. 4) Compliance of an independent regulatory agency with this bill's requirements shall not be subject to judicial review.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
