<bill session="113" type="h" number="3301" updated="2016-10-25T16:44:13Z">
  <state datetime="2014-06-24T18:18:01-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-06-24T18:18:01-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">North American Energy Infrastructure Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">North American Energy Infrastructure Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">North American Energy Infrastructure Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require approval for the construction, connection, operation, or maintenance of oil or natural gas pipelines or electric transmission facilities at the national boundary of the United States for the import or export of oil, natural gas, or electricity to or from Canada or Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">North American Energy Infrastructure Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000031"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000213" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001257" joined="2014-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2014-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001092" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001059" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000572" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000410" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000636" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000566" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001142" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001159" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000258" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000602" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000459" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000132" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000798" joined="2014-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000813" joined="2014-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000413" joined="2013-10-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-22">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-22">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by the Yeas and Nays: 19 - 10 .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-05-08" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 31 - 19.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 113-482, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19">
      <text>Committee on Transportation discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19">
      <text>Committee on Natural Resources discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-19" calendar="Union" number="358">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 358.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-06-23T19:17:05-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 636 Reported to House. For H.R. 6, one hour of general debate and amendments are confined to those printed in part A of the report accompanying this resolution. For H.R. 3301, one hour of general debate and amendments are confined to those printed in part B of the report accompanying this resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T13:56:32-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 636 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T14:43:17-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 636.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5665-5676" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T14:43:22-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 6 and H.R. 3301. For H.R. 6, one hour of general debate and amendments are confined to those printed in part A of the report accompanying the resolution. For H.R. 3301, one hour of general debate and amendments are confined to those printed in part B of the report accompanying the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T14:43:37-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 636 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T14:43:38-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Diane Black to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T14:43:45-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 3301.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T15:40:58-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 636, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pallone (NJ) part B amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T15:49:57-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Pallone part B amendment No. 1, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Pallone demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T15:50:48-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 636, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Waxman (CA) part B amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T15:57:58-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Waxman part B amendment No. 2, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Waxman demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T15:58:41-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 636, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Welch (VT) part B amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T16:08:22-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Welch part B amendment No. 3, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Welch demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T16:08:38-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Whitfield moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T16:08:53-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T16:09:06-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 3301 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T17:16:19-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5683-5688" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T17:16:31-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T17:16:48-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on adoption of amendments, which had been debated earlier, and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T17:54:27-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 3301.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T17:55:12-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5686" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T17:55:23-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5672" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T17:56:34-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Schneider moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5686-5687" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5686" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T17:56:56-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Schneider motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to add a new section titled Protecting the Great Lakes and Our Nation's Drinking Water Supply.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T18:02:51-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5687" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T18:09:45-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 185 - 227 (Roll no. 353).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5687" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="354" datetime="2014-06-24T18:18:01-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 238 - 173 (Roll no. 354).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T18:18:01-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="442">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 442.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Power" code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="113" relation="unknown" number="636"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="5360"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2823"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Maine"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="New Hampshire"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h958"/>
    <amendment number="h957"/>
    <amendment number="h956"/>
    <amendment number="h955"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2014-06-24T13:07:44Z" status="Passed House amended">North American Energy Infrastructure Act - (Sec. 3) Prohibits any person from constructing, connecting, operating, or maintaining a cross-border segment of an oil or natural gas pipeline or electric transmission facility at the national boundary of the United States for the import or export of oil, natural gas, or electricity to or from Canada or Mexico without obtaining a certificate of crossing under this Act.

Requires the Secretary of State, with respect to oil pipelines, or the Secretary of Energy (DOE), with respect to electric transmission facilities, to issue a certificate of crossing for the cross-border segment within 120 days after final action is taken under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA), unless it is not in U.S. public interest.

Directs DOE, as a condition of issuing a certificate, to require that the cross-border segment be constructed, connected, operated, or maintained consistent with the policies and standards of: (1) the Electric Reliability Organization and the applicable regional entity, and (2) any Regional Transmission Organization or Independent System Operator with operational or functional control over the segment.

 Exempts from such requirement any construction, connection, operation, or maintenance of a cross-border segment if: (1) it is operating for import, export, or electrical transmission upon the date of enactment of this Act; (2) the relevant permit or certificate of crossing has previously been issued under this Act; or (3) an permit application is pending on the date of enactment of this Act, until it is denied or July 1, 2016, whichever occurs first.

 Retains: (1) the requirement to obtain approval or authorization under the Natural Gas Act for the siting, construction, or operation of any facility to import or export natural gas, and (2) certain authority of the President under the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (EPCA).

(Sec. 4) Amends the Natural Gas Act to declare that no order of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) is required for the export or import of natural gas to or from Canada or Mexico.

 (Sec. 5) Amends the Federal Power Act to repeal the requirement that the transmission of electric energy to a foreign country necessitates prior authorization by FERC.

 (Sec. 6) Declares that no Presidential permit shall be necessary for the construction, connection, operation, or maintenance of an oil or natural gas pipeline or electric transmission facility, including any cross-border segment.

(Sec. 7) Declares that no certificate of crossing or permit shall be required for a modification to the construction, connection, operation, or maintenance of an oil or natural gas pipeline or electric transmission facility that: (1) operates for the import or export of oil or natural gas or the transmission of electricity to or from Canada or Mexico as of the date of enactment of this Act; (2) for which a permit for such construction, connection, operation, or maintenance has been issued; or (3) for which a certificate of crossing for the cross-border segment of the pipeline or facility has previously been issued.

(Sec. 8) Sets forth deadlines for rulemaking.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 113-482</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
