<bill session="115" type="h" number="1096" updated="2019-05-09T23:15:20Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 31, United States Code, to provide for transparency of payments made from the Judgment Fund.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Judgment Fund Transparency Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Judgment Fund Transparency Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Judgment Fund Transparency Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Judgment Fund Transparency Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Judgment Fund Transparency Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001192"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000369" joined="2017-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001250" joined="2017-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001248" joined="2017-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001076" joined="2017-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2017-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000299" joined="2017-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000576" joined="2017-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001177" joined="2017-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000588" joined="2017-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000580" joined="2017-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000470" joined="2017-02-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-06-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-10-16">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 115-348.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-10-16" calendar="Union" number="252">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 252.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="469"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="565"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="386"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-10-16T13:24:36Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">Judgment Fund Transparency Act of 2017

(Sec. 2) This bill requires the Department of the Treasury to disclose details regarding payments made from the Judgment Fund on or after January 1, 2016. (The Judgment Fund is a permanent and indefinite appropriation to pay judgments against the United States.)

Unless the disclosure is prohibited by law or a court order, Treasury must disclose to the public on a website:

 the agency or entity whose actions gave rise to the claim or judgment, the plaintiff or claimant, the counsel for the plaintiff or claimant, the amount paid representing principal liability and any amounts paid representing any ancillary liability, a description of the facts that gave rise to the claim, the agency that submitted the claim, and any information available on reports generated by the Judgment Fund Payment Search administered by Treasury. If the payment is made to a foreign state, Treasury must also disclose:

 the method of payment; the currency denomination used for the payment; and the name and location of each financial institution owned or controlled by a foreign state or an agent of a foreign state through which the payment passed, from which the payment was withdrawn, or that is holding the payment. By January 1, 2018, and annually thereafter, Treasury must disclose on the website: (1) the total amounts paid from the fund during the preceding year; and (2) the amounts paid during the preceding year for attorney fees, interest, and for all other payments.

No payments from the fund may be made to a state sponsor of terrorism or an organization that has been designated as a foreign terrorist organization under the Immigration and Nationality Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-348</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
