<bill session="113" type="h" number="4328" updated="2016-10-25T16:11:59Z">
  <state datetime="2014-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Johnson-O'Malley Supplemental Indian Education Program Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a program to award contracts to certain tribal organizations, Indian corporations, public school districts, and States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Johnson-O'Malley Supplemental Indian Education Program Modernization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001053"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2014-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational guidance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-03-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Johnson-O'Malley Supplemental Indian Education Program Modernization Act - Amends the Johnson-O'Malley Act to direct the Secretary of the Interior to enter into contracts with tribal organizations, Indian corporations, public school districts, or states to provide educational benefits to Indian students who attend public elementary or secondary schools.

Requires contract funds to be used for:

 remedial instruction, counseling, and cultural programs; science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) courses; important needs, such as school supplies and items that enable students to participate in curricular and extra-curricular programs; program activities that were available to Indian students under contracts entered into under the Act before October 1, 2012; targeted and culturally sensitive dropout prevention activities; and equipment to facilitate training for professional trade skills and intensified college preparation programs. Determines the amount of funds each contractor is to receive by: (1) determining the number of Indian students who were in average daily attendance and receiving a free public education in the public schools of the school districts served by the contractor in the preceding school year, and (2) providing the contractor a minimum amount for each of those students.

Authorizes the Secretary to give a contracting preference to a consortium of tribal organizations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
