<bill session="114" type="h" number="4453" updated="2018-06-02T04:53:25Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 to review the number of contracts for new disadvantaged small business concerns at certain airports with Disadvantaged Business Enterprises, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 to review the number of contracts for new disadvantaged small business concerns at certain airports with Disadvantaged Business Enterprises, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001160"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Aviation" code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill amends the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 to extend through FY2016 and periodically thereafter the requirement that the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Transportation report annually to Congress on the number of new small business concerns owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals, including those owned by veterans, that participated in the programs and activities of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA).

The list of the top 25 and bottom 25 large and medium hub airports giving disadvantaged small business concerns opportunities to participate in FAA programs and activities, which each such report must contain, shall be drawn only from large and medium hub airports with a disadvantaged business enterprise (DBE) program.

Beginning in FY2016, the FAA shall require airports to report annually on the number of new DBEs that were awarded a contract or concession.

The FAA shall update annually DBE-connect (or any other successor online reporting system) to include information on the number of new DBE and Airport Concession DBEs awarded a contract or concession for the first time at large and medium hub airports with a DBE program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
