<bill session="114" type="s" number="1989" updated="2018-06-02T06:59:14Z">
  <state datetime="2015-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Primary Care Enhancement Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve access to primary care services.</title>
    <title type="display">Primary Care Enhancement Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2015-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000127" joined="2016-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-08-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-08-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6015"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-08-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Primary Care Enhancement Act of 2015

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) permit an individual to pay primary care service arrangement costs from a health savings account; (2) allow an eligible taxpayer enrolled in a high-deductible health plan to take a tax deduction for cash paid into a health savings account, even if the taxpayer is simultaneously enrolled in a primary care service arrangement; and (3) for purposes of certain tax-deductible expenses for medical care, expand the definition of "medical care" to include periodic provider fees. A "primary care service arrangement" is an exchange of ongoing primary care services for a fixed periodic fee which is not billed to any third party on a fee-for-service basis.

The bill also amends title XI of the Social Security Act to require the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation (CMI) to test a primary care medical home model for payment and service delivery. Under this type of model, qualified direct primary care medical home practices are reimbursed a periodic fee for serving Medicare enrollees. In selecting qualified direct primary care medical home practices to participate, CMI shall give priority to practices seeking to enroll dual-eligible individuals.

CMI must conduct the model for at least three years, but, if specified conditions are met, CMI shall expand the model on a nationwide basis and a participating practice may continue permanently.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
