<bill session="114" type="h" number="5718" updated="2019-02-13T17:31:27Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Central Wasatch National Conservation and Recreation Area Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to acquire and to convey certain lands or interests in lands in Utah, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Central Wasatch National Conservation and Recreation Area Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000584" joined="2016-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001192" joined="2016-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation facilities"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Central Wasatch National Conservation and Recreation Area Act

This bill establishes the Central Wasatch National Conservation and Recreation Area in Utah, comprising approximately 79,109 acres of federal land in the Wasatch-Cache National Forest.

The Department of Agriculture (USDA) shall develop a comprehensive plan for the long-term management of the area.

The bill adjusts the boundaries of Mount Olympus, Twin Peaks, and Lone Peak Wildernesses.

The bill designates certain land in the forest as the Grandeur Peak-Mount Aire Wilderness and a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System.

The bill designates approximately 1,800 acres of federal land in the Wasatch-Cache National Forest as the White Pine Special Management Area.

The bill prohibits timber harvesting within the special management area.

The bill withdraws all federal land within the conservation and recreation area from: (1) all forms of entry, appropriation, and disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) disposition under the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.

USDA shall allow installation of access and avalanche control devices, excluding ski lifts, within or adjacent to the area.

The bill arranges for a potential land exchange involving specified National Forest System land and private ski areas in Utah.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
