<bill session="115" type="s" number="314" updated="2019-04-18T16:32:44Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance consumer rights relating to consumer report disputes by requiring provision of documentation provided by consumers.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FIX Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FIX Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FIX Credit Reporting Errors Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FIX Credit Reporting Errors Act</title>
    <title type="display">FIX Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2017-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">FIX Credit Reporting Errors Act or the FIX Act

This bill amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act with respect to the procedures followed by consumer reporting agencies when a consumer disputes the completeness or accuracy of information contained in the consumer's credit report.

Consumer reporting agencies are required to: (1) include all documentation provided by the consumer in the dispute notification furnished to any person who provided disputed information, and (2) consider such consumer documentation when conducting reinvestigations of disputed information.

A consumer reporting agency that operates as reseller is required to convey the notice of the dispute, together with all relevant information and documentation provided by the consumer, to each consumer reporting agency that provided the reseller with the information that is the subject of the dispute.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
