<bill session="114" type="h" number="4684" updated="2018-06-02T04:56:01Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veteran Urgent Access to Mental Healthcare Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to furnish mental health care to certain former members of the Armed Forces who are not otherwise eligible to receive such care, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Veteran Urgent Access to Mental Healthcare Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001077"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000373" joined="2016-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001106" joined="2016-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000571" joined="2016-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001048" joined="2016-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2016-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2016-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2016-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000170" joined="2016-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000602" joined="2016-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001193" joined="2016-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Veteran Urgent Access to Mental Healthcare Act

This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to establish a program to provide former members of the Armed Forces with: (1) an initial mental health assessment; and (2) health care services required to treat the former member's urgent mental health care needs, including risk of suicide or harming others.

 A former member of the Armed Forces is an individual who meets either of the following criteria:

 the individual is a former member of the Armed Forces, including the reserve components, who served in the active military, naval, or air service, and was discharged or released under a condition less than honorable (except a dishonorable or bad conduct discharge by reason of a general court martial), has applied for a character of service determination that has not yet been made, and is not otherwise eligible to enroll in the VA health care system by reason of such discharge or release; or the individual is a veteran not otherwise eligible for VA health care. The VA may provide such mental health care services pursuant to a contract with a qualified mental health professional if: (1) the receipt of mental health care services by an individual in VA facilities would be clinically inadvisable, or (2) VA facilities are not capable of furnishing such mental health care services to that individual economically because of geographical inaccessibility.

The VA shall seek to enter into a contract with an independent nongovernmental entity to study the effect combat service has had on suicide rates and serious mental health issues among veterans.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
