<amendment session="113" chamber="h" number="910" updated="2016-10-25T16:44:11Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4870" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2014-06-19T18:38:24-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000216"/>
  <offered datetime="2014-06-19"/>
  <description>At the end of the bill (before the short title), insert the following:    SEC.___. None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to enter into any contract with an incorporated entity if such entity's sealed bid or competitive proposal shows that such entity is incorporated or chartered in Bermuda or the Cayman Islands, and such entity's sealed bid or competitive proposal shows that such entity was previously incorporated in the United States.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment to prohibit the use of funds to enter into any contract with an incorporated entity if such entity's sealed bid or competitive proposal shows that such entity is incorporated or chartered in Bermuda or the Cayman Islands, and such entity's sealed bid or competitive proposal shows that such entity was previously incorporated in the United States.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2014-06-19T18:38:24-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the DeLauro amendment (A044) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19T18:32:16-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A044) offered by Ms. DeLauro.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5524-5525" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5524" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19"/>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19T18:38:24-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19T18:38:24-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the DeLauro amendment (A044) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19T18:32:16-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A044) offered by Ms. DeLauro.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5524-5525" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5524" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
