<bill session="115" type="h" number="3563" updated="2019-04-18T16:14:16Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to recognize the service of veterans of the armed forces by providing a more navigable and accommodating pathway for veterans honorably discharged from the United States military to naturalize and seek citizenship, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans' Pathway to Citizenship Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans&#8217; Pathway to Citizenship Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Veterans' Pathway to Citizenship Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001300"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001110" joined="2017-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000574" joined="2017-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000553" joined="2018-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2018-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2018-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2018-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2017-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2018-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2018-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Citizenship" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans' Pathway to Citizenship Act of 2017

This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide that a current or former member of the Armed Forces who would be eligible for naturalization but is not because of failure to complete a specified period of residence or physical presence within the United States or failure to maintain lawful permanent resident status shall be deemed to be a lawful permanent resident and to have fulfilled any residency and physical presence requirements solely for naturalization purposes.

 With respect to any such individual seeking naturalization: (1) a prior removal may be not taken into account for purposes of any immigration benefit or in determining deportability or inadmissibility, and (2) an offense for which a pardon was received may not be taken into account for naturalization purposes unless the offense was the same offense that caused the individual's separation from the Armed Forces in any manner other than honorable.

A military recruiter or officer overseeing an enlistment shall inform every recruit of, and the Department of Homeland Security shall provide every separating member of the Armed Forces with notice of, naturalization options and available naturalization assistance services.

In the case of a current or former member of the Armed Forces who would be eligible for naturalization but is not because of failure to timely file an application for naturalization, a subsequently filed naturalization application shall be reviewed as if it were timely filed. This provision is repealed one year after the date of enactment of the bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
