<bill session="114" type="h" number="4751" updated="2019-02-13T17:31:19Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Local Enforcement for Local Lands Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To terminate the law enforcement functions of the Forest Service and the Bureau of Land Management and to provide block grants to States for the enforcement of Federal law on Federal land under the jurisdiction of these agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Local Enforcement for Local Lands Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000369" joined="2016-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001250" joined="2016-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2016-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000570" joined="2016-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000573" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000584" joined="2016-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001177" joined="2016-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000189" joined="2016-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000588" joined="2016-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001192" joined="2016-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Conservation and Forestry" code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Local Enforcement for Local Lands Act of 2016

This bill declares that, by September 30, 2017, the Department of Agriculture (USDA) shall terminate the Forest Service Law Enforcement and Investigations unit and cease using Forest Service employees to perform law enforcement functions on federal lands.

Also by such date, the Department of the Interior shall terminate the Bureau of Land Management Office of Law Enforcement and cease using Interior employees to perform law enforcement functions on federal lands.

Nothing in this Act shall be construed as limiting the authority of Interior or USDA to authorize an employee of the Forest Service or the Bureau of Land Management to carry a firearm for protection while in the field.

For FY2018 and each fiscal year thereafter, Interior shall make a grant to each state, determined according to a specified formula, to permit the state, directly or through subgrants with units of local government in it, to maintain law and order on federal land, protect individuals and property on federal lands, and enforce federal law.

Any state or local government receiving the grant or subgrant shall enter into an agreement with Interior or USDA, as appropriate.

In any such agreement Interior or USDA must waive all civil claims against the state or local government, and indemnify that government and save it harmless from all claims by third parties for property damage or personal injury that may arise out of law enforcement functions performed under the agreement.

A law enforcement officer of a state or local government performing law enforcement functions pursuant to such an agreement shall not, except in certain circumstances, be deemed a federal employee with respect to hours of work, compensation rates, leave, unemployment compensation, and federal benefits, among other things.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
