<bill session="114" type="h" number="1351" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:17Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Homeowners' Defense Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a State-sponsored national catastrophic risk consortium to ensure the availability and affordability of homeowners' insurance coverage for catastrophic events.</title>
    <title type="display">Homeowners' Defense Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000808"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Homeowners' Defense Act of 2015

 Establishes the National Catastrophe Risk Consortium, as a non-federal, non-profit entity, to ensure the availability and affordability of homeowners' insurance coverage for catastrophic events.

Directs the Consortium to: (1) maintain an inventory of catastrophe risk obligations held by state reinsurance funds, state residual insurance market entities, and state-sponsored providers of natural catastrophe insurance; (2) issue, on a conduit basis, securities and other financial instruments linked to catastrophe risks insured or reinsured through Consortium members; (3) coordinate reinsurance contracts; (4) act as a centralized repository of state risk information accessible by certain private-market participants; and (5) establish a database to perform research and analysis that encourages standardization of the risk-linked securities market.

 Shields the federal government and the Consortium from liability for Consortium actions.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
