<bill session="114" type="h" number="548" updated="2019-01-09T21:09:43Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Certainty in Enforcement Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to exclude the application of such title to employment practices that are in compliance with Federal regulations, and State laws, in certain areas.</title>
    <title type="display">Certainty in Enforcement Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000798"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001067" joined="2015-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001048" joined="2015-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000592" joined="2015-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000475" joined="2015-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Workforce Protections" code="HSED10" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-27T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Certainty in Enforcement Act of 2015

Amends equal employment opportunity requirements under the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to deem an employer's, labor organization's, employment agency's, or joint labor management committee's consideration or use of credit or criminal records or information, as mandated by federal, state, or local law, to be job related and consistent with business necessity.

Declares that such use of credit or criminal records shall not be the basis of liability under any theory of disparate impact. (Currently, an unlawful employment practice based on disparate impact is established if a complaining party demonstrates that a respondent uses a particular employment practice that causes a disparate impact on the basis of race, color, religion, sex, or national origin and the respondent fails to demonstrate that the challenged practice is job related for the position in question and consistent with business necessity.)</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
