<bill session="114" type="h" number="1562" updated="2019-01-09T21:26:04Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-15T17:17:59-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-04-15T17:17:59-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Contracting and Tax Accountability Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Contracting and Tax Accountability Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Contracting and Tax Accountability Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the awarding of a contract or grant in excess of the simplified acquisition threshold unless the prospective contractor or grantee certifies in writing to the agency awarding the contract or grant that the contractor or grantee has no seriously delinquent tax debts, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Contracting and Tax Accountability Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001051" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001175" joined="2015-03-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-03-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 114-72.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-04-14" calendar="Union" number="52">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 52.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15T15:14:35-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Chaffetz moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15T15:14:48-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2241-2243" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15T15:14:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1562.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15T15:26:41-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15T17:11:53-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2251-2252" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="156" datetime="2015-04-15T17:17:59-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 424 - 0 (Roll no. 156).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2241-2242" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15T17:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-15T16:49:47Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the House reported version is repeated here.)

Contracting and Tax Accountability Act of 2015

(Sec. 2) Declares it the policy of the U.S. government that no government contracts or grants should be awarded to individuals or companies with seriously delinquent federal tax debts.

(Sec. 3) Requires the head of any executive agency that issues an invitation for bids or a request for proposals for a contract, or that offers a grant, in an amount greater than the simplified acquisition threshold, to require each person submitting a bid or proposal or grant application to: (1) certify that such person does not have a seriously delinquent tax debt, and (2) authorize the Department of the Treasury to disclose information limited to describing whether such person has a seriously delinquent tax debt. Subjects a person who has a seriously delinquent tax debt to a negative responsibility or high risk determination when applying for a federal contract or grant, or to suspension or debarment from the federal procurement process. Authorizes an agency head to waive a suspension or debarment proceeding for a person with a seriously delinquent tax debt upon a written finding of urgent and compelling circumstances significantly affecting the interests of the United States.

(Sec. 5) Defines "seriously delinquent tax debt" as a federal tax liability that has been assessed by the Internal Revenue Service and is collectible by levy or a court proceeding, except a tax debt: (1) that is being paid in a timely manner under an approved installment agreement or an offer-in-compromise, (2) for which a collection due process hearing has been requested or is pending; (3) for which a continuous levy has been issued or agreed to by an applicant for employment, or (4) with respect to which such a levy is released because it has been determined to be an economic hardship to the taxpayer.

(Sec. 6) Makes this Act applicable to contracts and grants awarded on or after 270 days after the enactment date of this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-72</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
