<bill session="113" type="sr" number="104" updated="2016-10-25T16:18:19Z">
  <state datetime="2013-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution supporting the goals and ideals of National Youth HIV &amp; AIDS Awareness Day.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution supporting the goals and ideals of National Youth HIV &amp; AIDS Awareness Day.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2013-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2013-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2013-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2846" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="113" relation="unknown" number="148"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="HIV/AIDS"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-04-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Expresses support for the goals and ideals of National Youth HIV &amp; AIDS Awareness Day. Encourages state and local governments to recognize and support such a day. Promotes effective and comprehensive HIV prevention education programs as a tool to ensure that all people in the United States are educated about HIV.

Urges youth-friendly and accessible health care services to better provide for the early identification of HIV through voluntary routine testing and to connect those in need to clinically and culturally appropriate care and treatment as early as possible.

Commends the work of AIDS service organizations, community and faith-based organizations, and school-based health centers that are providing youth-friendly, effective, prevention, treatment, care, and support services to young people living with and vulnerable to HIV/AIDS.

Recognizes the importance of interventions that address structural barriers faced by young people to living healthy lives. Prioritizes youth leadership and development in order to ensure youth involvement in decisions that impact their health and well-being and to provide the next generation of HIV/AIDS professionals as a necessary means to achieving an AIDS-free generation.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
