<bill session="114" type="h" number="4226" updated="2018-06-02T04:50:46Z">
  <state datetime="2015-12-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-12-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Agricultural Act of 2014 to provide relief for agricultural producers adversely impacted by the Oriental fruit fly.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Agricultural Act of 2014 to provide relief for agricultural producers adversely impacted by the Oriental fruit fly.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001107"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000600" joined="2015-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000575" joined="2015-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000296" joined="2016-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001191" joined="2015-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000583" joined="2016-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000435" joined="2015-12-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities and Risk Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="General Farm Commodities and Risk Management" code="HSAG16" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural insurance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Fruit and vegetables"/>
    <term name="Insects"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-12-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill amends the Agricultural Act of 2014 to require the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to reimburse producers on farms for losses that are due to the inability to plant, grow, or ship a crop to market due to a federal or state government quarantine to control the Oriental fruit fly.

The payments are limited to 70% of the market value of the affected crop and end as soon as possible once the producer is able to resume marketing a crop after the quarantine is lifted.

In implementing this bill, USDA must not discriminate against or penalize a producer that obtained, or did not obtain, crop insurance, noninsured crop disaster assistance, or similar risk protection for the same type of crop, except that assistance provided by this bill must be reduced by the amount of assistance provided for the same losses under any other federal law.

Producers receiving assistance under this bill must agree to obtain crop insurance, noninsured crop disaster assistance, or similar risk protection for the same type of crop for at least the next two crop years, if the insurance, assistance, or protection is available.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
