<bill session="114" type="h" number="5875" updated="2018-06-02T05:28:51Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish requirements for committees of the Senate and the Senate to consider and hold votes on nominations of individuals for appointments by the President, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To establish requirements for committees of the Senate and the Senate to consider and hold votes on nominations of individuals for appointments by the President, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001286" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000293" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000454" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000188" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000593" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2016-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill prescribes requirements and deadlines for Senate consideration and votes on nominations submitted by the President, including referrals of such nominations to a single Senate committee and jointly to more than one committee.

If each committee to which the nomination has been referred reports it favorably to the Senate or discharges it without recommendation, the Senate shall hold a vote on the nomination within 60 days after the last such committee reports or discharges it.

 If the President submits to the Senate the nomination of an individual for appointment to an office and it is not referred to any Senate committee, the Senate shall hold a vote on the nomination within 150 days.

 In the case of the nomination of an individual for appointment to the Supreme Court of the United States, a vote in the Senate on a motion to invoke cloture on a motion to proceed to consideration of the nomination shall be treated as a vote on the nomination for purposes of this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
