<bill session="115" type="s" number="942" updated="2019-06-17T18:45:43Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require a plan to combat international travel by terrorists and foreign fighters, accelerate the transfer of certain border security systems to foreign partner governments, establish minimum international border security standards, authorize the suspension of foreign assistance to countries not making significant efforts to comply with such minimum standards, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Counterterrorism Screening and Assistance Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Counterterrorism Screening and Assistance Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Counterterrorism Screening and Assistance Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2017-04-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Legislative Interest"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1196"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Counterterrorism Screening and Assistance Act of 2017

This bill expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the U.S. government must ensure that capacity-building assistance to combat terrorist travel is coordinated among agencies as well as with foreign implementing partners, and (2) such assistance should be prioritized for the highest-risk countries for travel by terrorists and foreign fighters.

The Department of State shall submit to Congress biennially a foreign partner engagement plan that catalogues existing capacity-building initiatives abroad to combat travel by terrorists and foreign fighters and identifies areas for adjustment to align efforts with risk-based priorities.

The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) and the State Department shall provide appropriate versions of the following systems to foreign governments:

 U.S. Customs and Border Protection's global travel targeting and analysis systems; and the State Department's watchlisting, identification, and screening systems. DHS may provide, with specified exceptions, excess DHS nonlethal equipment and supplies (as well as related training) to a foreign government if such action would:

 further U.S. homeland security interests; and enhance the recipient government's capacity to mitigate the threat of terrorism, infectious disease or natural disaster, protect lawful trade and travel, or enforce intellectual property rights. DHS shall notify Congress before providing such systems, equipment, or supplies.

The State Department: (1) shall report to Congress annually through 2022 on foreign government efforts to combat terrorist and foreign fighter travel and on U.S. actions to help countries comply with minimum standards for such efforts, and (2) may suspend non-humanitarian, non-trade-related foreign assistance to a country that is not making significant efforts to comply with such minimum standards.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
