<amendment session="115" chamber="h" number="688" updated="2019-06-13T18:15:03Z">
  <amends type="h" number="8" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2018-06-06T17:08:07-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000619"/>
  <offered datetime="2018-06-06"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 29 printed in Part A of House Report 115-711 to clarifiy that operation and maintenance of any project authorized under the Chief's Report for the Brandon Road Study is done at an 80/20 Federal/non-Federal cost share. Also requires the Corps, following construction of any project authorized under the Chief's Report for the Brandon Road Study, to consult with the governor of the state where the project is located and seek Congressional approval prior to implementing any additional technologies at the project. Also, it adds to the list of feasibility studies in the base bill the USACE must expedite completion of the Great Lakes Mississippi River Interbasin Study Brandon Road Study.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2018-06-06T17:08:07-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Davis, Rodney amendment (A028) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-06-06T17:01:59-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A028) offered by Mr. Davis, Rodney.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4828-4829" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4828" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-06"/>
    <action datetime="2018-06-06T17:01:59-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A028) offered by Mr. Davis, Rodney.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4828-4829" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4828" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-06T17:08:07-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-06T17:08:07-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Davis, Rodney amendment (A028) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-06">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
