<bill session="115" type="sr" number="360" updated="2019-04-18T16:30:04Z">
  <state datetime="2017-12-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-12-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-12-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution calling for international accountability for the crimes against humanity committed by the Burmese military against the Rohingya in Burma.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution calling for international accountability for the crimes against humanity committed by the Burmese military against the Rohingya in Burma.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2017-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2017-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2017-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2017-12-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-12-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Bangladesh"/>
    <term name="Burma"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-12-13T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Recognizes the adoption of the resolution on the situation of human rights of Rohingya Muslims and other minorities in Burma (Myanmar) by the United Nations (U.N.) Human Rights Council on December 5, 2017. Condemns the Burmese military for its atrocities against the Rohingya. Reaffirms the international prohibitions against the use of ethnic cleansing and crimes against humanity.

Urges the government of Burma to take specified steps, including allowing the U.N. Fact-Finding Mission to Myanmar to examine the human rights violations by military and security forces in Burma.

Calls for the U.N. to: (1) pass resolutions condemning the human rights violations by Burmese security forces against the Rohingya, and (2) establish an independent mechanism to assist individual criminal investigations and refer those responsible for atrocity crimes against the Rohingya to the International Criminal Court. Calls on the U.N. Security Council to impose a comprehensive arms embargo against Burma.

Urges:

 State Counsellor Aung San Suu Kyi to fully implement the Final Report of the Advisory Commission on Rakhine State, the Department of State and the Department of the Treasury to impose targeted sanctions and travel restrictions against senior leaders of the Burmese military implicated in atrocities, the international community to assist with the economic development of the Rakhine state, and the nations of the world to revoke travel visas for members of the Burmese military responsible for ethnic cleansing and crimes against humanity against the Rohingya.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
