<bill session="114" type="s" number="2360" updated="2018-08-16T22:54:07Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-29">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Omnibus Territories Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Omnibus Territories Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Omnibus Territories Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the administration of certain programs in the insular areas, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Omnibus Territories Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2015-12-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8439-8440" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-05">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 114-426.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-08-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski under authority of the order of the Senate of 07/14/2016 with an amendment. With written report No. 114-311.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-08-30" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="583">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 583.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2016-09-29" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6285" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-09-29">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-14T14:14:02-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-14T21:21:59-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4455"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marshall Islands"/>
    <term name="Micronesia"/>
    <term name="Palau"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-29T11:48:15Z" status="Passed Senate amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the Senate on August 30, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Omnibus Territories Act of 2015 

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 1982, to eliminate the restriction on the use of resettlement and relocation funds by people of the Bikini Atoll for resettlement and relocation to areas only within the Marshall Islands.

The bill limits eligibility for the funds to Bikini people living on Kili and Ejit Islands, but they may use the funds to relocate and resettle outside the Marshall Islands. The use of resettlement funds is subject to the condition that the Department of the Interior submit to Congress a resettlement plan developed in coordination with the Bikini Atoll leadership.

Annual fiscal year expenditures from the resettlement fund may not exceed 90% of its average annual earnings for the preceding five years unless for resettlement purposes outside of the Marshall Islands.

(Sec. 3) To provide and sustain air transportation in American Samoa between the islands of Tutuila and Manu'a, the Department of Transportation may renew a foreign air carrier's emergency air transportation exemption every 180 days (instead of the current 30-day renewal period that still applies to other areas).

(Sec. 4) The bill amends the REAL ID Act of 2005 to provide that citizens of the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, and the Republic of Palau who have been admitted as nonimmigrants pursuant to a Compact of Free Association are eligible for driver's licenses or personal identification cards.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-311</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
