<bill session="114" type="h" number="5910" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:37Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Economic Sanctions Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 31, United States Code, to establish within the Department of the Treasury an Economic Sanctions Strategy, Coordination, and Planning Group, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Improving Economic Sanctions Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001257" joined="2016-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001275" joined="2016-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001055" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000378" joined="2016-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Improving Economic Sanctions Act of 2016

This bill establishes within the Office of Terrorism and Financial Intelligence of the Department of the Treasury an Economic Sanctions Strategy, Coordination, and Planning Group. The group shall conduct contingency planning to enable the Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) to impose, monitor, and enforce a program of economic sanctions against a foreign country or entity pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act.

The group shall: (1) review OFAC economic sanctions programs to identify specific problems with such programs and general problems with U.S. economic sanctions policy, and (2) create a strategy to improve such programs and policy.

The Office of Terrorism and Financial Crimes shall coordinate the development of U.S. economic sanctions policy with the Departments of State, Defense, Justice, and Commerce; the National Security Council; and the Office of the Director of National Intelligence.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
