<bill session="114" type="s" number="1017" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:56Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Power Act to improve the siting of interstate electric transmission facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Federal Power Act to improve the siting of interstate electric transmission facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001046"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill amends the Federal Power Act to declare U.S. policy regarding the national interstate electricity transmission system, and to ensure that high-priority regional transmission (HPRT) projects are in the public interest.

The bill prohibits a project developer from seeking a certificate for construction without first seeking authorization under applicable state law.

The Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) may authorize HPRT project construction found to be required by public convenience and necessity if the state:

 fails to approve the project, rejects the project application, has no authority to approve the project siting, or authorizes the project subject to conditions that unreasonably interfere with an HPRT project. FERC is designated the lead agency to coordinate both federal authorizations and related environmental reviews for an HPRT project.

FERC shall: (1) coordinate the federal authorization and related environmental review process with any Indian tribe, multistate entity, or state agency responsible for separate permitting or environmental review of a project; and (2) ensure timely and efficient review and permit decisions.

FERC must incorporate into the certificate certain mitigation measures recommended by federal and state agencies, including affected Indian tribes.

Excludes from coverage by this Act Alaska, Hawaii, and the Electric Reliability Council of Texas.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
