<bill session="114" type="h" number="5431" updated="2018-06-02T05:15:48Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expanding Care for Female Veterans Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a pilot program to award grants to health care entities to lease, purchase, or build health care facilities for female patients to provide hospital care and medical services to qualified female veterans.</title>
    <title type="display">Expanding Care for Female Veterans Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000057"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000017" joined="2016-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-09T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Expanding Care for Female Veterans Act

This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to establish a three-year pilot program to award grants to health care entities to lease, purchase, or build health care facilities for female patients in order to provide hospital care and medical services to female veterans enrolled in the VA's patient enrollment system.

For purposes of providing such care and services, a facility leased, purchased, or built under the program shall be deemed to be: (1) a non-VA entity that may provide veterans hospital care and medical services as specified in the Veterans Access, Choice, and Accountability Act of 2014; or (2) if the authority to carry out the program is terminated, an entity otherwise authorized to provide hospital care and medical services pursuant to an agreement entered into by the VA.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
