<bill session="114" type="h" number="6218" updated="2019-02-13T17:31:23Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To clarify the boundary of Acadia National Park, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To clarify the boundary of Acadia National Park, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000611"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3027"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Maine"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill confirms that the boundary of Acadia National Park in Maine includes approximately 1,441 acres of land and interests in the Schoodic Peninsula.

The bill ratifies and approves:

 retroactive to September 26, 2013, the acquisition or purported acquisition by the United States of the land and interests in the Schoodic Peninsula, and any subsequent or purported alteration of the land or interests held or claimed by the United States in the peninsula (including conversion to fee simple interest) retroactive to whatever point an alteration occurred or may have occurred. The Department of the Interior may only acquire land or interests in land:

 within the boundaries of the park in accordance with specified law; and outside the boundaries of the park in Hancock County, Maine, in accordance with such law. Interior shall contribute a specified amount to a regional consortium which was established to improve the management of the disposal and recycling of solid waste and is composed of municipalities on, as well as near, Mount Desert Island.

 Interior shall reestablish and appoint members to the Acadia National Park Advisory Commission.

 Certain land in the park that was conveyed by Interior to the town of Tremont, Maine, shall no longer be used exclusively for school purposes, but for public purposes, subject to the conditions that: (1) use of the property (on such land) shall not degrade or adversely impact the park's resources or values; and (2) such land shall remain in public ownership for recreational, educational, or similar public purposes.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
