<amendment session="113" chamber="h" number="659" updated="2016-10-25T16:38:54Z">
  <amends type="h" number="10" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2014-05-09T11:53:04-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <offered datetime="2014-05-09"/>
  <description>Amendment sought to direct that Web site publications by charter schools contain material regarding student recruitment, orientation materials, enrollment criteria, student discipline policies, behavior codes, and parent contract requirements (including any financial obligations such as fees for tutoring, extra-curicular activities, etc.).</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 8 printed in House Report 113-444 to direct the website publication of materials on the websites of Charter Schools regarding student recruitment, orientation materials, enrollment criteria, student discipline policies, behavior codes, and parent contract requirements, which should include any financial obligations such as fees for tutoring, extra-curicular activity etc.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2014-05-09T11:53:04-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="213">
      <text>On agreeing to the Jackson Lee amendment (A007) Failed by recorded vote: 179 - 220 (Roll no. 213).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-05-09T10:44:57-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A007) offered by Ms. Jackson Lee.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4034-4037, H4041-4042" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4034" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-09"/>
    <action datetime="2014-05-09T11:53:04-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-09T11:53:04-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-09T11:53:04-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Jackson Lee amendment (A007) Failed by recorded vote: 179 - 220 (Roll no. 213).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-09T10:44:57-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A007) offered by Ms. Jackson Lee.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4034-4037, H4041-4042" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4034" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-09">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
