<bill session="115" type="s" number="377" updated="2019-04-18T16:32:55Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 to clarify report dates, modify the criteria for determinations of whether countries are meeting the minimum standards for elimination of trafficking, and highlight the importance of concrete actions by countries to eliminate trafficking, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Trafficking In Persons Report Integrity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Trafficking In Persons Report Integrity Act</title>
    <title type="display">Trafficking In Persons Report Integrity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2017-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2017-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2017-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2017-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2017-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-14T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Trafficking In Persons Report Integrity Act

This bill amends the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 to revise provisions regarding the Department of State's determination of whether countries are meeting the minimum standards for elimination of human trafficking, including provisions regarding: (1) the State Department's annual Trafficking in Persons Report, (2) additional requirements for meeting minimum standards, (3) actions against governments failing to meet minimum standards, (4) the tier ranking process for meeting such standards, and (5) congressional oversight of such process.

The President shall instruct the U.S. executive director of each multilateral development bank to: (1) support the U.S. policy goal of ending slavery and human trafficking and encourage other nations to adopt similar policies, (2) oppose, subject to a presidential waiver, loans or other programs (other than for humanitarian assistance) to Tier 3 and Tier 2 Watch List countries and channel funds from such countries to countries in better compliance with such standards, (3) propose that other institutions develop anti-human trafficking provisions in their project development, safeguards, procurement, and evaluation policies; (4) seek the adoption of policies and procedures providing governmental agencies and interested members of the public of member countries with access to human trafficking risk assessments; and (5) ensure that such an assessment accompanies loan proposals through the agency review process.

 The Department of the Treasury shall make available to multilateral development banks, without charge, U.S. government personnel to assist in developing anti-human trafficking provisions in project development.

 A Tier 3 country is a country the government of which does not fully meet the minimum standards and is not making significant efforts to do so.

A Tier 2 Watch List country is a country the government of which does not fully meet the minimum standards but is making significant compliance efforts and in which: (1) the number of victims of severe forms of trafficking is very significant or is significantly increasing, (2) there is a failure to provide evidence of increasing efforts to combat severe forms of trafficking in persons from the previous year, or (3) the compliance determination was based on the country's commitments to take additional steps over the next year.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
