<bill session="114" type="h" number="4187" updated="2019-01-29T22:16:14Z">
  <state datetime="2015-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Secure and Protect Americans' Data Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require certain entities who collect and maintain personal information of individuals to secure such information and to provide notice to such individuals in the case of a breach of security involving such information, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Secure and Protect Americans' Data Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001145"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001251" joined="2015-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000385" joined="2016-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000379" joined="2015-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000034" joined="2015-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2015-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001168" joined="2015-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2015-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2015-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Consumer Protection and Commerce" code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-12-08T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Secure and Protect Americans' Data Act

This bill requires the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to promulgate regulations requiring entities regulated by the FTC, common carriers, and nonprofit organizations to establish information security practices for the treatment and protection of personal information.

At least annually, such entities must evaluate their consumer privacy programs to make any appropriate adjustments for changing technologies, threats or vulnerabilities, or business arrangements.

The bill sets forth special procedures for information brokers to: (1) submit security policies to the FTC, (2) provide for post-breach audits, and (3) establish procedures for individuals to review and correct inaccuracies in their personal information. In lieu of procedures that allow individuals to dispute information, an information broker may provide individuals a means of expressing a preference not to have their information used for marketing purposes.

The bill prohibits information brokers from obtaining or disclosing personal information by false pretenses.

Within 10 days following discovery of a security breach, entities must notify:

 the FTC; the Federal Bureau of Investigation; the U.S. Secret Service; for common carriers, the Federal Communications Commission (FCC); and attorneys general of affected states. Within 30 days following a breach, entities must notify individuals who are U.S. citizens or residents whose personal information was, or is reasonably believed to have been, acquired or accessed by an unauthorized person, or used for an unauthorized purpose.

If an entity is required to notify more than 5,000 individuals, the entity must also notify major consumer reporting agencies. An entity must provide notices in print and broadcast media if the affected residents of a state exceed 5,000.

Notices must include information on affected individuals' entitlement to consumer credit reports or credit monitoring services.

The bill exempts entities from notification requirements if the data is unusable, unreadable, or indecipherable.

Entities complying with other federal laws that require substantially similar information security procedures or breach notifications are deemed to be in compliance with the FTC's procedures or the notification requirements of this Act.

Enforcement authority is provided to the FTC and states. States may obtain civil penalties for certain violations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
