<bill session="114" type="s" number="2025" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:36Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Oceans and Coastal Security Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote the protection and conservation of United States ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes ecosystems, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">National Oceans and Coastal Security Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000802"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Seashores and lakeshores"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Oceans and Coastal Security Act

This bill authorizes the Department of Commerce and the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation to establish the National Oceans and Coastal Security Fund as a tax exempt fund for supporting programs and activities to protect, conserve, and restore ocean and coastal resources and coastal infrastructure.

Donations from a foreign government may not be deposited into the fund.

Commerce must prioritize projects that have non-federal partners sharing the project costs.

According to a specified allocation formula, the Foundation must award a minimum percentage of funds as grants to eligible coastal states while awarding a lesser percentage of funds to entities including states, Indian tribes, regional bodies, associations, non-governmental organizations, and academic institutions.

The bill amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to require the President to ensure that a certain percent of offshore energy revenues are deposited into the fund.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
