<bill session="114" type="h" number="1110" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:38Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STOP Identity Theft Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stopping Tax Offenders and Prosecuting Identity Theft Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide effective criminal prosecutions for certain identity thefts, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">STOP Identity Theft Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000797"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000583" joined="2015-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-26T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Stopping Tax Offenders and Prosecuting Identity Theft Act of 2015 or the STOP Identity Theft Act of 2015

 Calls for the Attorney General to: (1) make use of all existing resources of the Department of Justice, including task forces, to bring more perpetrators of tax return identity theft to justice; and (2) take into account the need to concentrate efforts in areas of the country where the crime is most frequently reported, to coordinate with state and local authorities to prosecute and prevent such crime, and to protect vulnerable groups from becoming victims or otherwise being used in the offense.

Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) include organizations as victims for purposes of prohibitions against identity theft or aggravated identity theft, and (2) subject an identity theft offense committed during and in relation to tax fraud to a fine and/or up to 20 years' imprisonment.

Directs the Attorney General to report to the House and Senate Judiciary Committees on: (1) trends in the incidence of tax return identity theft, (2) recommendations on additional statutory tools that would aid in the effective prosecution of tax return identity theft, and (3) the status of implementing DOJ's March 2010 Audit Report 10-21 entitled "The Department of Justice's Efforts to Combat Identity Theft."</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
