<bill session="115" type="h" number="2454" updated="2019-07-15T21:58:09Z">
  <state datetime="2018-12-19">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a data framework to provide access for appropriate personnel to law enforcement and other information of the Department, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Department of Homeland Security Data Framework Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Department of Homeland Security Data Framework Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of Homeland Security Data Framework Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of Homeland Security Data Framework Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Homeland Security Data Framework Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Homeland Security Data Framework Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Department of Homeland Security Data Framework Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001073"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2017-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Counterterrorism and Intelligence.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12T12:59:09-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hurd moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12T12:59:21-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7243-7245" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12T12:59:23-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2454.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2017-09-12T13:05:27-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7243" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12T13:05:28-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-13">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-06">
      <text>Senate Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-06">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7371" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2018-12-06" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-12-10">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-12T14:20:20-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Hurd moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10129-10130" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-12T14:20:36-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the motion to suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment to H.R. 2454.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-12T14:25:42-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Hurd objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was considered as withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="pingpong" datetime="2018-12-12T16:16:20-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10152" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H10129" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-12-12T16:16:21-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2018-12-13">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2018-12-19" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="115-331" type="public" datetime="2018-12-19">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 115-331.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Intelligence and Counterterrorism" code="HSHM05" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2397"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4071"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2018-12-20T04:59:58Z" status="Public Law">Department of Homeland Security Data Framework Act of 2018

(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) develop a data framework to integrate existing DHS datasets and systems for access by authorized personnel in a manner consistent with relevant legal authorities and privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties protections; (2) ensure that all information of a DHS office or component that falls within the scope of the information sharing environment, and any information or intelligence relevant to priority mission needs and capability requirements of the homeland security enterprise, is included; and (3) ensure that the framework is accessible to DHS employees who have an appropriate security clearance, who are assigned to perform a function that requires access, and who are trained in applicable standards for safeguarding and using such information.

DHS shall: (1) issue guidance for DHS employees authorized to access and contribute to the framework that enforces a duty to share between DHS offices and components for mission needs; and (2) promulgate data standards and instruct DHS components to make available information through the framework in a machine-readable standard format.

DHS may exclude information that may:

 jeopardize the protection of sources, methods, or activities; compromise a criminal or national security investigation; be inconsistent with the other federal laws or regulations; or be duplicative or not serve an operational purpose. DHS shall incorporate into such framework systems capabilities for auditing and ensuring the security of information. Such capabilities shall include: (1) mechanisms for identifying insider threats and security risks; and (2) safeguards for privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties.

DHS shall ensure that, by two years after this bill's enactment, the framework has the ability to include appropriate information in existence within DHS to meet its critical mission operations.

DHS shall: (1) submit to Congress regular updates on the status of the data framework until it is fully operational, and (2) annually brief Congress on component use of such framework to support operations that disrupt terrorist activities and incidents in the homeland.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
