<bill session="113" type="h" number="1586" updated="2018-06-05T16:15:18Z">
  <state datetime="2013-04-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Hope for Uniform Recognition of Christian Heritage (CHURCH) Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Architect of the Capitol to acquire and place a historical plaque to be permanently displayed in National Statuary Hall recognizing the seven decades of Christian church services being held in the Capitol from 1800 to 1868, which included attendees James Madison and Thomas Jefferson.</title>
    <title type="display">Congressional Hope for Uniform Recognition of Christian Heritage (CHURCH) Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000552"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000213" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000266" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2013-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001176" joined="2013-04-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="U.S. Capitol"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-04-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Congressional Hope for Uniform Recognition of Christian Heritage (CHURCH) Act of 2013 - Requires the Architect of the Capitol (AOC) to enter into an agreement with a private entity for the design and fabrication of a historical plaque to be permanently displayed in National Statuary Hall recognizing the seven decades of Christian church services being held in the Capitol from 1800 to 1868.

Authorizes the AOC to use National Statuary Hall for a presentation ceremony for the plaque.

Requires the AOC upon receiving such plaque to display it permanently in a place of prominence in National Statuary Hall.

Requires that any obligations or expenditures by the AOC to carry out this Act be derived from pre-existing funds available to the AOC as of enactment of this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
