<bill session="113" type="s" number="2944" updated="2016-10-25T16:32:44Z">
  <state datetime="2014-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Social Security for Nazis Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Social Security Act to provide for the termination of social security benefits for individuals who participated in Nazi persecution, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">No Social Security for Nazis Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2014-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2014-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000542" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2014-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2014-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2014-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000461" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2014-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2014-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="identical" number="5739"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-11-19T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">No Social Security for Nazis Act - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to consider the following individuals to be removed under the Immigration and Nationality Act and so to have their OASDI benefits terminated:

 an individual with respect to whom an order admitting the individual to citizenship has been revoked and set aside where such action is based on conduct relating to participation in Nazi persecution, concealment of a material fact about such conduct, or willful misrepresentation about such conduct; and an individual who, pursuant to a settlement agreement with the Attorney General (AG), has admitted to such conduct and has lost status as a U.S. national by renouncing that status. Requires such individuals to have been considered removed under such Act as of the date of the revocation, setting aside, or renunciation.

Prohibits such individuals from receiving other Social Security benefits based on the wages and self-employment income of any other individual.

Prohibits the payment to such individuals also of any benefits under SSA tile XVI (Supplemental Security Income) (SSI).

Requires the AG or the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to notify the Commissioner of Social Security of such revocations, setting asides, and renunciations of nationality.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
