<bill session="115" type="h" number="4881" updated="2019-04-18T16:19:54Z">
  <state datetime="2018-07-23T19:02:34-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-07-23T19:02:34-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To require the Federal Communications Commission to establish a task force for reviewing the connectivity and technology needs of precision agriculture in the United States.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Federal Communications Commission to establish a task force for meeting the connectivity and technology needs of precision agriculture in the United States.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Precision Agriculture Connectivity Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Precision Agriculture Connectivity Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Precision Agriculture Connectivity Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Precision Agriculture Connectivity Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Precision Agriculture Connectivity Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Precision Agriculture Connectivity Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Precision Agriculture Connectivity Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000566"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2018-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001294" joined="2018-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001284" joined="2018-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2018-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000568" joined="2018-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001053" joined="2018-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000565" joined="2018-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000569" joined="2018-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000791" joined="2018-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000066" joined="2018-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-01-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-13">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-13">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-07-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-07-18">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 115-837.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-07-18" calendar="Union" number="647">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 647.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-07-23T14:23:46-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Lance moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-23T14:24:01-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6595-6597" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-23T14:24:03-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4881.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-23T14:32:55-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-23T18:54:52-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6632-6633" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="367" datetime="2018-07-23T19:02:34-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 378 - 4 (Roll no. 367).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6595-6596" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-07-23T19:02:35-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-23T19:02:39-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Communications and Technology" code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="2343"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-07-23T14:16:56Z" status="Passed House amended">Precision Agriculture Connectivity Act of 2018

(Sec. 3) This bill requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to establish the Task Force for Reviewing the Connectivity and Technology Needs of Precision Agriculture in the United States.

 The task force's duties include:

 identifying and measuring current gaps in the availability of broadband Internet access service on agricultural land; developing policy recommendations to promote the rapid, expanded deployment of fixed and mobile broadband Internet access service on unserved agricultural land, with a goal of achieving reliable capabilities on 95% of agricultural land in the United States by 2025; promoting effective policy and regulatory solutions that encourage the adoption of broadband Internet access service on farms and ranches and promote precision agriculture; recommending specific new rules or amendments to existing FCC rules; recommending specific steps that the FCC should take to obtain reliable and standardized data measurements of the availability of broadband Internet access service as necessary to target funding support, from future FCC programs dedicated to the deployment of such service, to unserved agricultural land; and recommending specific steps that the FCC should consider to ensure that the expertise of the Department of Agriculture (USDA) and available farm data are reflected in such future FCC programs. USDA and the FCC shall jointly submit to the task force a list of all federal programs or resources available for the expansion of broadband Internet access service on unserved agricultural land.

The task force must submit annually to the FCC a report that details: (1) the status of fixed and mobile broadband Internet access service coverage of agricultural land; (2) the projected future connectivity need of agricultural operations, farmers, and ranchers; and (3) steps taken to accurately measure the availability of broadband Internet access service on agricultural land and the limitations of current measurement processes.

The FCC shall renew the task force every two years until it terminates on January 1, 2025.

(Sec. 4) No additional funds are authorized to carry out this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-837</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
