<bill session="114" type="h" number="6070" updated="2019-05-09T23:15:23Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fair Housing Act to better protect persons with disabilities and communities.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Recovery and Community Empowerment Act</title>
    <title type="display">Safe Recovery and Community Empowerment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000059" joined="2016-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001048" joined="2016-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000409" joined="2016-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000820" joined="2016-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Housing discrimination"/>
    <term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Safe Recovery and Community Empowerment Act

This bill amends the Fair Housing Act to authorize a local, state, or federal government body to:

 limit the number of residential recovery facilities within a particular area zoned for residential housing, provided that the limitation is necessary to preserve the residential character of the area, allows for a reasonable number of such facilities to be located within such area, and does not place an overall cap on their number within a municipality or state; and require a facility to obtain an operating license or use permit or satisfy a set of consumer protection standards. A residential recovery facility is a residence that provides housing to individuals in recovery from drug or alcohol addiction with the promise of providing a clean and sober environment in return for direct or indirect payment to an owner, operator, or compensated staff person.

Facilities receiving payments from a federal health care program, or via private insurance purchased on a federal exchange or federally subsidized, for either housing, recovery services, or testing or monitoring for drugs or alcohol, shall ensure that residents be provided a safe living environment completely free from illicit drugs, alcohol, firearms, harassment, abuse, or harm.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
