<bill session="114" type="s" number="362" updated="2018-06-02T06:32:57Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Government Employee Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 5, United States Code, to provide for investigative leave requirements with respect to Senior Executive Service employees, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Government Employee Accountability Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000575"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2015-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000542" joined="2015-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2015-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2015-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2015-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2015-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2015-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="722"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-04T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Government Employee Accountability Act

Sets forth guidelines for placing career employees of the Senior Executive Service (SES) on investigative leave. Defines "investigative leave" as a temporary absence without duty for disciplinary reasons, for not more than 90 days.

Authorizes a federal agency to: (1) place an SES employee on investigative leave, without loss of pay and without charge to annual or sick leave, only for alleged misconduct, neglect of duty, malfeasance, or misappropriation of funds; (2) place such employee on leave without pay if such employee's alleged conduct is determined to be serious or flagrant; or (3) remove such employee if such employee acted in a manner that endangers the interest of the agency mission.

Requires an agency to periodically review the investigation into the conduct of an SES employee placed on investigative leave and take certain actions with respect to such employee at the end of a period of investigative leave, including removal, suspension without pay, or reinstatement to duty. Grants an employee placed on investigative leave certain rights, including: (1) advance written notice of, and a reasonable time (not less than seven days) to answer, charges; (2) the right to be represented by an attorney; and (3) the right to appeal to the Merit Systems Protection Board.

Includes misappropriation of funds as a ground in suspending or reinstating an SES employee or placing such employee in another civil service position.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
