<bill session="114" type="h" number="5751" updated="2019-02-13T17:31:23Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Shiras Moose Protection and Recovery Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that any State whose wildlife agency has determined that a portion of the State is within the current range of the Shiras Moose may take management actions on certain Federal lands within that State to stem decline of that species' population in that State, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Shiras Moose Protection and Recovery Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000584" joined="2016-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2016-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001192" joined="2016-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000470" joined="2016-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000018" joined="2016-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Shiras Moose Protection and Recovery Act

This bill allows a state to take management actions on covered federal lands within its boundaries to stem the population decline of the Shiras Moose if a portion of the state is within the range of the moose, including by formulating a recovery plan that mitigates the population decline.

Upon request, the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (USFWS) must provide funding for state implementation of a plan from funds appropriated to the USFWS for implementing its Northern Rocky Mountain Gray Wolf Recovery Plan and any of its other gray wolf recovery or monitoring plans.

Utah and Colorado may manage Shiras Moose and their predators on federal, state, and private lands to prevent declines in moose populations within their respective state. They must collect, analyze, and disseminate data on the results of such management.

The Department of the Interior must issue as a final rule the draft rule entitled, "Removing the Gray Wolf (Canis lupus) From the List of Endangered and Threatened Wildlife and Maintaining Protections for the Mexican Wolf (Canis lupus baileyi) by Listing It as Endangered," as published on June 13, 2013.

The bill exempts the requirements and implementation of this bill from judicial review.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
