<bill session="114" type="h" number="1820" updated="2018-11-21T20:17:20Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-08">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to retire coal preference right lease applications for which the Secretary has made an affirmative commercial quantities determination, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to retire coal preference right lease applications for which the Secretary has made an affirmative commercial quantities determination, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000570"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2015-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-10-08" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-03-10">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 114-446.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-03-10" calendar="Union" number="341">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 341.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-10T14:38:38Z" status="Reported to House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of that version is repeated here.)

(Sec. 1) This bill authorizes the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) to provide bidding credits for a coal preference right lease applicant to acquire federal mineral rights if such applicant agrees to relinquish its rights to an existing coal lease on federal land. Bidding credits, which are fully transferable, are assigned a dollar value and can be used in lieu of cash to make certain payments to the federal government. The dollar value should be equal to the estimated fair market value of the existing lease being relinquished.

The BLM is required to provide payments, equal to 50% value of any bidding credit, to any state where federal mineral rights are being acquired through the use of bidding credits. Such payments are required to be derived from revenues obtained under federal mineral leases.

 A bidding credit terminates five years from its date of issue, not counting any period in which exercise of the bidding credit is precluded by law or suspension of the federal coal leasing program.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-446</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
