<bill session="115" type="s" number="2782" updated="2019-04-18T16:42:56Z">
  <state datetime="2018-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit covenants not to compete and require employers to notify employees of such prohibition, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Workforce Mobility Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Workforce Mobility Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Workforce Mobility Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001169"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2018-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2018-04-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="5631"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-04-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Workforce Mobility Act of 2018

This bill prohibits employers from entering into, enforcing, or threatening to enforce a covenant not to compete with any employee of such employer. A "covenant not to complete" is an agreement between an employer and employee that restricts such employee from performing, after the employment relationship terminates, any work for another employer for a specified period of time, any work in a specified geographical area, or any work for any other employer that is similar to the work performed for the employer who is a party to such agreement. A prohibition against a covenant not to compete does not preclude an agreement between and employer and employee not to share trade secrets.

The bill directs the Department of Labor to enforce this bill and impose a fine upon violators. An aggrieved party may file a civil action for actual and punitive damages, and for reasonable attorney's fees and costs if the action is successful.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
