<bill session="114" type="s" number="2058" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:39Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-01">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-12-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Commerce to maintain and operate at least one Doppler weather radar site within 55 miles of each city in the United States that has a population of more than 700,000 individuals, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by senate">A bill to require the Secretary of Commerce to study the coverage gaps of the Next Generation Weather Radar of the National Weather Service and to develop a plan for improving radar coverage and hazardous weather detection and forecasting.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Metropolitan Weather Hazards Protection Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Metropolitan Weather Hazards Protection Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">To require the Secretary of Commerce to study the coverage gaps of the Next Generation Weather Radar of the National Weather Service and to develop a plan for improving radar coverage and hazardous weather detection and forecasting.</title>
    <title type="display">To require the Secretary of Commerce to study the coverage gaps of the Next Generation Weather Radar of the National Weather Service and to develop a plan for improving radar coverage and hazardous weather detection and forecasting.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001135"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2015-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-12-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-09-15">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Thune with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 114-351.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-09-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="629">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 629.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-12-01">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6679-6680" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6679" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-01">
      <text>The committee substitute withdrawn by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6679" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2016-12-01" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-12-02">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-02T11:39:44-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="3538"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5089"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s5124"/>
    <amendment number="s5123"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2016-12-01T15:53:39Z" status="Passed Senate amended">(Sec. 1) This bill directs the Department of Commerce to complete, within 90 days after enactment of this bill, a study on gaps in the coverage of the Next Generation Weather Radar of the National Weather Service (NEXRAD).

 In conducting this study, Commerce shall identify areas in the United States with limited or no NEXRAD coverage below 6,000 feet above ground level of the surrounding terrain.

For those areas identified, Commerce shall also:

 identify the key weather effects for which prediction would improve with improved radar detection; identify additional sources of observations for high impact weather available and operational for such areas, including Terminal Doppler Weather Radar, air surveillance radars of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), and cooperative network observers; and assess the feasibility and advisability of efforts to integrate and upgrade federal radar capabilities in such areas that are not owned or controlled by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, including radar capabilities of the FAA and the Department of Defense. In addition, under such study Commerce shall:

 assess the feasibility and advisability of incorporating state-operated and other nonfederal radars into the operations of the National Weather Service; identify options to improve radar coverage in all of the areas identified as having limited or no NEXRAD coverage; and estimate the cost of, and develop a timeline for, carrying out each of the options identified. After completing the study, Commerce shall submit a plan for improving radar coverage in the identified areas by integrating and upgrading, where practicable, additional observation solutions to improve hazardous weather detection and forecasting.

Commerce shall seek third-party reviews on scientific methodology related to, and the feasibility and advisability of, implementing the plan to improve radar coverage, including the extent to which warning and forecast services of the National Weather Service would be improved by additional NEXRAD coverage.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-351</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
