<bill session="114" type="s" number="2831" updated="2018-08-16T23:11:09Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to provide priority for applicants for a license to operate as a small business investment company that are located in a disaster area.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to provide priority for applicants for a license to operate as a small business investment company that are located in a disaster area.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000127"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-05-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Reported by Senator Vitter with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-05-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="481">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 481.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1470"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-24T13:24:41Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">(Sec. 1) This bill amends the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to require the Small Business Administration (SBA) to give priority to small business investment company (SBIC) applications for licenses to operate in a declared major disaster area.

In calculating the outstanding leverage (debt) of one or more licensed SBICs in view of the maximum leverage allowed for debenture or loan guarantee purposes, the SBA shall not include the cost basis of any investment made by an SBIC in a small business concern in a major disaster area during the one-year period beginning on the date of the disaster declaration.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
