<bill session="113" type="h" number="5861" updated="2016-10-25T16:17:50Z">
  <state datetime="2014-12-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Guarding Our Great Lakes Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To control the spread of aquatic invasive species between the Great Lakes basin and the Mississippi River basin, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Guarding Our Great Lakes Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001271" joined="2014-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000355" joined="2014-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001038" joined="2014-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001058" joined="2014-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000376" joined="2014-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001150" joined="2014-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2014-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000480" joined="2014-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000467" joined="2014-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000031" joined="2014-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000798" joined="2014-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water, Power and Oceans" code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" code="HSII22" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="identical" number="3002"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Indiana"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Mississippi River"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-12-11T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Guarding Our Great Lakes Act - Requires the Chief of Engineers, the Director of the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (USFWS), the Director of the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS), the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), and each other applicable federal agency to take actions to prevent the transfer of aquatic invasive species, with a focus on Asian carp species, through the Brandon Road Lock and Dam on the Illinois River.

Directs the Chief to: (1) construct measures to prevent the upstream transfer of swimming aquatic invasive species through the Lock and Dam; and (2) submit a cost estimate for, and schedule for completion of, measures to be constructed.

Requires the Director of the USFWS to implement all appropriate measures in compliance with applicable state and federal law around the Lock and Dam to prevent the upstream and downstream transfer of swimming and floating aquatic invasive species, with a focus on Asian carp species.

Authorizes the Chief, the Director of the USFWS, and the Director of the USGS to acquire real estate to carry out this Act.

Directs the EPA Administrator, acting through the Great Lakes Interagency Task Force, to coordinate with the governor of Illinois, the city of Chicago, and the Metropolitan Water Reclamation District of Greater Chicago to carry out engineering and construction of flood mitigation and water quality measures on the Chicago Area Waterway System related to permanent prevention of the transfer of aquatic nuisance species between the Great Lakes and Mississippi River basins. Permits the federal share of the cost of a project to be up to 100%.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
