<bill session="114" type="hc" number="79" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:22Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-30T16:47:49-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-09-30T16:47:49-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Directing the Clerk of the House of Representatives to make corrections in the enrollment of H.R. 719.</title>
    <title type="display">Directing the Clerk of the House of Representatives to make corrections in the enrollment of H.R. 719.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000591"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-30T14:28:21-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 448 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Con. Res. 79 and H.R. 719. Rule provides for 20 minutes of debate on H. Con. Res. 79. Section 2 provides for one hour of debate on a motion for the House to agree to the Senate amendment to the House amendment to the Senate amendment to H.R. 719.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-30T15:55:57-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 448.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6738-6742" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-30T15:56:02-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Con. Res. 79 and H.R. 719. Rule provides for 20 minutes of debate on H. Con. Res. 79. Section 2 provides for one hour of debate on a motion for the House to agree to the Senate amendment to the House amendment to the Senate amendment to H.R. 719.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-30T15:56:28-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to H. Res. 448, the House proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on H. Con. Res. 79.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-30T16:18:52-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6741" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="527" datetime="2015-09-30T16:47:49-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 241 - 185, 1 Present (Roll no. 527).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6738" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-09-30T16:47:50-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="719"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3134"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="764"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1836"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="114" relation="unknown" number="448"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-30T14:46:51Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Directs the Clerk of the House of Representatives to make a correction in the enrollment of H.R. 719 (Continuing Appropriations Act, 2016) to add division titles and restrict funding for Planned Parenthood.

Prohibits, for a one-year period, federal funds from being provided to Planned Parenthood Federation of America, Inc., or any of its affiliates or clinics, for any purpose unless the entities certify that they will not perform abortions or provide funds to any entity that performs an abortion during the period. Includes exceptions for rape, incest, or a physical condition that endangers a woman's life unless an abortion is performed.

Requires the Department of Health and Human Services and the Department of Agriculture to seek repayment of federal assistance received by Planned Parenthood Federation of America, Inc., or any affiliate or clinic, if it violates the terms of the required certification.

Provides additional funding for community health centers for the one-year period and prohibits the funds from being used for abortions other than the exceptions described above.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
