<bill session="113" type="s" number="2991" updated="2016-10-25T16:32:55Z">
  <state datetime="2014-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Reauthorization Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act to promote sustainable conservation and management for the Nation's fisheries and the communities that rely on them, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Reauthorization Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001265"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2824"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-12-09T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Reauthorization Act of 2014 - Reauthorizes and revises the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (MSA), the Anadromous Fish Conservation Act, the Interjurisdictional Fisheries Act of 1986, the Atlantic Coastal Fisheries Cooperative Management Act, the Atlantic Striped Bass Conservation Act, the Yukon River Salmon Act of 2000, the Atlantic Tunas Convention Act of 1975, and the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act through FY2021. Reauthorizes the South Pacific Tuna Act of 1988. Reauthorizes the Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Convention Act of 1995 through FY2020.

 Extends permanently the authority of Washington, Oregon, and California to manage any Dungeness crab fishery that does not have a fishery management plan under the MSA and is in the exclusive economic zone adjacent to the state.

 Revises the MSA, including by:

 providing for the role of tribal governments in managing fish, adding subsistence fishing to the types of fishing managed under the Act, giving regional fishery management councils the authority to use alternative fishery management measures in a recreational fishery, providing for the management of depleted fisheries, increasing civil and criminal penalties, establishing a Fisheries Enforcement Fund, and revising requirements governing fishery management plans and regional fishery management councils.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
