<bill session="114" type="h" number="3762" updated="2018-06-04T17:55:47Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-02">VETOED:OVERRIDE_FAIL_ORIGINATING:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring Americans' Healthcare Freedom Reconciliation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Restoring Americans' Healthcare Freedom Reconciliation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Restoring Americans' Healthcare Freedom Reconciliation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for reconciliation pursuant to section 2002 of the concurrent resolution on the budget for fiscal year 2016.</title>
    <title type="official" as="agreed to by house and senate">To provide for reconciliation pursuant to section 2002 of the concurrent resolution on the budget for fiscal year 2016.</title>
    <title type="display">To provide for reconciliation pursuant to section 2002 of the concurrent resolution on the budget for fiscal year 2016.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000591"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-16">
      <text>The House Committee on the Budget reported an original measure, H. Rept. 114-293, by Mr. Price, Tom.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-10-16" state="REPORTED" calendar="Union" number="222">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 222.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-10-21T19:36:39-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 483 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3762 with 2 hours of general debate. The resolution provides that the amendment printed in the report shall be considered as adopted for H.R. 3762. The resolution waives clause 6(a) of rule XIII and provides that is shall be in order at any time on the legislative day of Oct. 22, 2015 or Oct. 23, 2015 for the Speaker to entertain motions to suspend the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-22T16:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 483 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-23T09:14:55-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 483.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7143-7164" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-23T09:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3762 with 2 hours of general debate. The resolution provides that the amendment printed in the report shall be considered as adopted for H.R. 3762. The resolution waives clause 6(a) of rule XIII and provides that it shall be in order at any time on the legislative day of Oct. 22, 2015 or Oct. 23, 2015 for the Speaker to entertain motions to suspend the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-23T09:15:18-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 483, the House proceeded with two hours of debate on H.R. 3762.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-23T11:27:50-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7163" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="568" datetime="2015-10-23T11:58:27-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 240 - 189 (Roll no. 568).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7143-7144" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-10-23T11:58:28-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-18">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-11-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="299">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 299.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-12-01">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8233" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-01">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by motion.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8233-8234" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-02">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8250-8266, S8268-8283" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-03">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8326-8357" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="329" datetime="2015-12-03" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 52 - 47. Record Vote Number: 329.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-12-04">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-06T15:58:50-05:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 579, Mr. Price, Tom was recognized for a motion.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H52" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-06T15:58:51-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Price, Tom moved that the House concur in the Senate amendment.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H52-67" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H54" label="text of the motion"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-06T15:59:08-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 579, the House proceeded with one hour of debate on the motion that the House agree to Senate amendment to H.R.3762.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-06T17:24:20-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H66" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="pingpong" roll="6" datetime="2016-01-06T17:54:47-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion that the House agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 240 - 181 (Roll no. 6).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H52-54" label="text as House agreed to the Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-01-06T17:54:48-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2016-01-07">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <vetoed datetime="2016-01-08" state="PROV_KILL:VETO">
      <text>Vetoed by President.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H210-211" label="text of veto message"/>
    </vetoed>
    <action datetime="2016-01-08">
      <text>The Chair laid before the House the veto message from the President.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H210-211" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-08T12:59:57-05:00">
      <text>The Chair announced that the objections of the President to H.R. 3762 would be spread at large upon the Journal and the veto message would be printed as a House document (114-91).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H211" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-08">
      <text>Mr. Scalise moved to postpone consideration of the veto message until Jan. 26.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H211" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-08T13:00:10-05:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Scalise motion to postpone consideration of the veto message.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-08T13:01:18-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to postpone consideration of the veto message was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H211" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-08">
      <text>On motion to postpone consideration of the veto message until Jan. 26. Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-25T14:03:12-05:00">
      <text>Notwithstanding the order of the House on January 8, 2016, the Chair announced that further consideration of the veto message on H.R. 3762 shall be postponed until Tuesday, February 2, 2016. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02">
      <text>Pursuant to the order of the House of January 25, 2016, the Chair announced that the unfinished business was the further consideration of the veto message of the President on H.R. 3762.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02T12:49:51-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the question of passage of H.R. 3762, the objections of the President to the contrary, notwithstanding.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02T14:05:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - Pursuant to rule 8, clause 20, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of passage of H.R. 3762, the objections of the President to the contrary notwithstanding, until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02">
      <text>The Chair announced the unfinished business to be the consideration of the veto.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02T17:53:05-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H482" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="override" roll="53" datetime="2016-02-02" where="h" result="fail" state="VETOED:OVERRIDE_FAIL_ORIGINATING:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage, the objections of the President to the contrary notwithstanding Failed by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 241 - 186 (Roll no. 53).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H482" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02">
      <text>The Chair announced that the bill and accompanying veto message were referred to the Committee on the Budget. The Chair directed the Clerk to notify the Senate of the action to the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="114" relation="procedurally-related" number="483"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="114" relation="unknown" number="579"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h729"/>
    <amendment number="s2919"/>
    <amendment number="s2918"/>
    <amendment number="s2917"/>
    <amendment number="s2916"/>
    <amendment number="s2915"/>
    <amendment number="s2914"/>
    <amendment number="s2913"/>
    <amendment number="s2912"/>
    <amendment number="s2911"/>
    <amendment number="s2910"/>
    <amendment number="s2909"/>
    <amendment number="s2908"/>
    <amendment number="s2907"/>
    <amendment number="s2906"/>
    <amendment number="s2905"/>
    <amendment number="s2904"/>
    <amendment number="s2903"/>
    <amendment number="s2902"/>
    <amendment number="s2901"/>
    <amendment number="s2900"/>
    <amendment number="s2899"/>
    <amendment number="s2898"/>
    <amendment number="s2897"/>
    <amendment number="s2896"/>
    <amendment number="s2895"/>
    <amendment number="s2894"/>
    <amendment number="s2893"/>
    <amendment number="s2892"/>
    <amendment number="s2891"/>
    <amendment number="s2890"/>
    <amendment number="s2889"/>
    <amendment number="s2888"/>
    <amendment number="s2887"/>
    <amendment number="s2886"/>
    <amendment number="s2885"/>
    <amendment number="s2884"/>
    <amendment number="s2883"/>
    <amendment number="s2882"/>
    <amendment number="s2881"/>
    <amendment number="s2880"/>
    <amendment number="s2879"/>
    <amendment number="s2878"/>
    <amendment number="s2877"/>
    <amendment number="s2876"/>
    <amendment number="s2875"/>
    <amendment number="s2874"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2015-12-03T13:02:27Z" status="Passed Senate amended">TITLE I--HEALTH, EDUCATION, LABOR, AND PENSIONS

(Sec. 101) This bill amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) to terminate the Prevention and Public Health Fund, which provides for investment in prevention and public health programs to improve health and restrain the rate of growth in health care costs. Unobligated funds are rescinded.

(Sec. 102) Funding for community health centers is increased.

(Sec. 103) Certain funding for U.S. territories that establish health insurance exchanges is no longer available after 2017.

(Sec. 104) The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) may not collect fees or make payments under the transitional reinsurance program.

(Sec. 105) This bill makes appropriations for FY2016 and FY2017 for HHS to award grants to states to address substance abuse or to respond to urgent mental health needs.

TITLE II--FINANCE

(Sec. 201) This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to require individuals to pay back the full amount of advance payments in excess of their premium assistance tax credit. (Currently, there is a limit on the amount of excess an individual must pay back.)

(Sec. 202) Provisions relating to the premium assistance tax credit, reduced cost-sharing, and eligibility determinations for these subsidies are repealed on December 31, 2017.

(Sec. 203) The small employer health insurance tax credit does not apply after 2017. (This credit is for certain employers who make contributions toward employee health coverage purchased through a health insurance exchange.)

(Sec. 204) The penalty for individuals who do not maintain minimum essential health care coverage is eliminated.

(Sec. 205) Large employers are no longer required to make shared responsibility payments.

(Sec. 206) For one year, this bill restricts the availability of federal funding to a state for payments to an entity (e.g., Planned Parenthood Federation of America) that:

 is a 501(c)(3) tax-exempt organization; is an essential community provider primarily engaged in family planning services and reproductive health; provides for abortions other than abortions in cases of rape or incest, or where a physical condition endangers a woman's life unless an abortion is performed; and received a total of more than $350 million under Medicaid in FY2014, including payments to affiliates, subsidiaries, successors, or clinics. (Sec. 207) This bill amends part A (General Provisions) of title XI of the Social Security Act (SSAct) to require the additional payments to U.S. territories for Medicaid under the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010 to be made by the end of FY2017 instead of the end of FY2019.

This bill amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the SSAct to end the expansion of Medicaid under PPACA on December 31, 2017.

After 2017, hospitals may no longer elect to provide Medicaid services to individuals during a presumptive eligibility period.

States must maintain Medicaid eligibility standards for individuals under 19 years old through FY2017 instead of through FY2019.

The federal medical assistance percentage (FMAP, the federal matching rate for Medicaid expenditures) for U.S. territories is 50% after 2017 (currently, the FMAP is 55%).

The increased FMAP for childless adults and home and community-based attendant services under PPACA ends December 31, 2017.

After 2017, states may no longer elect to provide certain individuals with a presumptive eligibility period for Medicaid.

Medicaid benchmark plans are no longer required to provide minimum essential health benefits after 2017.

After 2017, states are no longer required to operate a website for Medicaid enrollment that is linked to the state's health benefit exchange and Children's Health Insurance program (CHIP).

(Sec. 208) Medicaid allotments for disproportionate share hospitals are increased.

(Sec. 209) The excise tax on high cost employer-sponsored health coverage (popularly known as the "Cadillac tax") does not apply after 2017.

(Sec. 210) Health savings accounts (HSAs), Archer medical savings accounts (MSAs), health flexible spending arrangements (HFSAs), and health reimbursement arrangements may be used to pay for over-the-counter medications.

(Sec. 211) This bill lowers the tax on distributions from HSAs and Archer MSAs that are not used for medical expenses.

(Sec. 212) Salary reduction contributions to an HFSA under a cafeteria plan are no longer limited.

(Sec. 213) The annual fee on manufacturers and importers of brand name prescription drugs is eliminated.

(Sec. 214) The excise tax on medical devices is eliminated.

(Sec. 215) The annual fee on health insurers is eliminated.

(Sec. 216) Medical costs are allowed as a tax deduction regardless of whether the costs are taken into account when determining the amount of the subsidy for an employer-sponsored retiree prescription drug plan under Medicare part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program).

(Sec. 217) A tax deduction is allowed for medical expenses in excess of 7.5% (currently, 10%) of adjusted gross income.

(Sec. 218) The additional Medicare tax on income above a certain threshold is eliminated.

(Sec. 219) The indoor tanning services tax is eliminated.

(Sec. 220) The net investment income tax is eliminated.

(Sec. 221) A health insurer is allowed a tax deduction for the full amount of an employee's compensation. (Currently, there is a limit on the amount of an employee's compensation that a health insurer may deduct.)

(Sec. 222) Provisions relating to the economic substance doctrine are repealed. (The economic substance doctrine treats a transaction as having economic substance if it has a purpose other than reducing income taxes. Currently, there are penalties for claiming tax benefits for transactions without economic substance.)

(Sec. 223) Funds are transferred from the Department of the Treasury to the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-293</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
