<bill session="115" type="h" number="5906" updated="2019-04-18T16:23:58Z">
  <state datetime="2018-06-27T14:59:57-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-06-27T14:59:57-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the America COMPETES Act to establish Department of Energy policy for Advanced Research Projects Agency-Energy, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">ARPA-E Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">ARPA-E Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ARPA-E Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ARPA&#8211;E Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">ARPA-E Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000491"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000374" joined="2018-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2018-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001048" joined="2018-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000628" joined="2018-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001077" joined="2018-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000126" joined="2018-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000387" joined="2018-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000589" joined="2018-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000190" joined="2018-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000583" joined="2018-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2018-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-05-23" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27T14:47:54-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Lucas moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27T14:48:46-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5779-5781" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27T14:48:50-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5906.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2018-06-27T14:59:57-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5779" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27T14:59:58-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-05-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">ARPA-E Act of 2018

This bill amends the America COMPETES Act to require the Advanced Research Projects Agency-Energy (ARPA-E) in the Department of Energy (DOE) to overcome the long-term and high-risk technological barriers in the development of transformative science and technology solutions to address energy, environmental, economic, and national security challenges. (Currently, ARPA-E must overcome barriers in the development of energy technologies.)

The bill expands the goals of ARPA-E to include the development of energy technologies that:

 provide transformative solutions to improve management of radioactive waste, improve the efficiency and reduce the environmental impact of energy production, and address other challenges within the mission of DOE. The bill expands the responsibility of ARPA-E to accelerate novel early-stage research to include nonenergy research.

ARPA-E must:

 include a strategic vision roadmap in each annual report on energy technology projects or advanced technology projects, and ensure that it does not fund an advanced technology project unless the prospective grantee has demonstrated that it has sufficiently attempted to secure private financing or that such project is not independently commercially viable. Specified categories of proprietary information collected by ARPA-E from award recipients shall be considered privileged and confidential and not subject to disclosure under the Freedom of Information Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
