<bill session="114" type="s" number="534" updated="2018-06-02T06:38:43Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-27">PROV_KILL:CLOTUREFAILED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Immigration Rule of Law Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit funds from being used to carry out certain Executive actions related to immigration and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Immigration Rule of Law Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001035"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-23">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-02-24" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="22">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 22.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-02-26">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1152" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-26">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed to the measure presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1152" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1152" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote-aux how="roll" type="cloture" roll="63" datetime="2015-02-27" where="s" result="fail" state="PROV_KILL:CLOTUREFAILED">
      <text>Cloture on the motion to proceed to the measure not invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 57 - 42. Record Vote Number: 63.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1192" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="text CR S1192"/>
    </vote-aux>
    <action datetime="2015-02-27">
      <text>Motion by Senator McConnell to reconsider the vote by which cloture was not invoked on the motion to proceed to S. 534 (Record Vote. No. 63) entered in Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="240"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2801"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health and welfare"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-23T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Immigration Rule of Law Act of 2015

This bill prohibits the use of any funds made available to the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) or to any other federal official, including deposits into the Immigration Examinations Fee Account, to carry out any of the policy changes set forth in the following memoranda dated either November 20 or November 21, 2014 (or any substantially similar policy changes issued or taken on or after January 9, 2015):

 Southern Border and Approaches Campaign; Policies for the Apprehension, Detention and Removal of Undocumented Immigrants; Secure Communities; Exercising Prosecutorial Discretion with Respect to Individuals Who Came to the United States as Children and with Respect to Certain Individuals Who Are the Parents of U.S. Citizens or Permanent Residents; Expansion of the Provisional Waiver Program; Policies Supporting U.S. High-Skilled Businesses and Workers; Families of U.S. Armed Forces Members and Enlistees; Directive to Provide Consistency Regarding Advance Parole; Policies to Promote and Increase Access to U.S. Citizenship; Modernizing and Streamlining the U.S. Immigrant Visa System for the 21st Century; and Creating Welcoming Communities and Fully Integrating Immigrants and Refugees. Such memoranda or substantially similar policy changes are declared to have no statutory or constitutional basis and therefore no legal effect.

No funds or fees made available to the Secretary or to any federal official may be used to grant any federal benefit to any alien pursuant to any of such policy changes.

No funds or fees made available to the Secretary may be used to carry out any policy relating to the apprehension, detention, or removal of aliens that does not treat any alien convicted of any offense involving domestic violence, sexual abuse, child molestation, or child exploitation as within the categories of aliens subject to the highest DHS civil immigration enforcement priorities.

It is the sense of Congress that:

 disparate employer/employee health insurance requirements discourage the hiring of U.S. citizens and those in lawful immigration status; and the Executive Branch should refrain from pursuing policies such as granting to unlawfully present individuals any deferred action under the deferred action for childhood arrivals program and work authorization. It is the sense of Congress that U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Service should:

 stop putting the interests of aliens who are unlawfully present in the United States ahead of the interests of aliens who are following proper immigration laws and procedures by taking specified actions, and use the funds available under existing law to improve services and increase the efficiency of the immigration benefits application process for aliens abroad or who are lawfully present in the United States.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
