<bill session="115" type="h" number="5268" updated="2019-04-18T16:21:09Z">
  <state datetime="2018-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security, through the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, to make grants to eligible local education agencies to provide improved security measures on school grounds, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Schools Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Schools Act</title>
    <title type="display">Safe Schools Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001189"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-03-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Safe Schools Act

This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to make grants to eligible local education agencies to provide improved security measures at schools and on school grounds.

Such grants shall be distributed directly to such agencies and used to improve security through one or more of the following:

 employment of additional school resource officers not already employed by the agency; entering into a contract or a memorandum of understanding with a local law enforcement agency, private entity, or nonprofit corporation for the services of school resource officers; increasing coordination with local law enforcement; and purchasing equipment, technology, or infrastructure improvements to control access to school campus, buildings, and classrooms, expedite notification of first responders, or stop weapons from entering a school building. In awarding grants, FEMA shall give preference to local education agencies that demonstrate that the grants will be used efficiently and effectively to secure school buildings or grounds.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
