<bill session="114" type="h" number="4602" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:54Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Justice for All Reauthorization Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Effective Administration of Criminal Justice Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect crime victims' rights, to eliminate the substantial backlog of DNA and other forensic evidence samples to improve and expand the forensic science testing capacity of Federal, State, and local crime laboratories, to increase research and development of new testing technologies, to develop new training programs regarding the collection and use of forensic evidence, to provide post-conviction testing of DNA evidence to exonerate the innocent, to support accreditation efforts of forensic science laboratories and medical examiner offices, to address training and equipment needs, to improve the performance of counsel in State capital cases, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Justice for All Reauthorization Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000592"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001293" joined="2016-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2016-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2016-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001059" joined="2016-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2016-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000294" joined="2016-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001181" joined="2016-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2016-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2016-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000185" joined="2016-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000244" joined="2016-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001193" joined="2016-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="2577"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-24T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Justice for All Reauthorization Act of 2016

This bill amends the federal criminal code to require a defendant, as a mandatory condition of supervised release, to pay court-ordered restitution.

It amends the Justice for All Act of 2004, the Victims of Crime Act of 1984, the DNA Sexual Assault Justice Act of 2004, and the Innocence Protection Act of 2004, to:

 reauthorize grants for victims assistance programs; reauthorize crime victims notification grants; give preference to Sexual Assault Forensic Exam Program grant applicants that use funds for forensic nurse examiner programs in rural or underserved areas; reauthorize DNA research and development demonstration grants, DNA programs and activities at the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and DNA technology grants to identify missing persons; reauthorize the Capital Litigation Improvement Grant Program; reauthorize the Kirk Bloodsworth Post-Conviction DNA Testing Grant Program; and direct the National Institute of Justice to establish best practices for evidence retention. The Department of Justice must allocate specified funds for testing and auditing backlogged rape kits.

The bill amends the Prison Rape Elimination Act of 2003 to:

 narrow the scope of grant program funds subject to a reduction for a state's failure to comply with national prison rape standards, revise and expand requirements with respect to adopting national prison rape standards, and require background checks for compliance auditors. It amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to revise and reauthorize the Paul Coverdell Forensic Science Improvement Grants Program.

 Effective Administration of Criminal Justice Act of 2015

This bill requires an application for Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program funds to include a statewide strategic plan to improve the administration of criminal justice.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
