<bill session="114" type="h" number="263" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:01Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Adult Day Center Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To expand and enhance existing adult day programs for younger people with neurological diseases or conditions (such as multiple sclerosis, Parkinson's disease, traumatic brain injury, or other similar diseases or conditions) to support and improve access to respite services for family caregivers who are taking care of such people, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Adult Day Center Enhancement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000551"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000911" joined="2015-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2015-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000263" joined="2015-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2015-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2015-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Adult day care"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-09T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Adult Day Center Enhancement Act

Requires the Administration on Aging to initiate a comprehensive survey of current adult day programs that provide care and support to individuals, including young adults, living with neurological diseases or conditions such as multiple sclerosis, Parkinson's disease, or traumatic brain injury. Requires the Administration to identify ongoing successful adult day programs and which of these serve young adults with neurological diseases and conditions and develop best practices to help guide the establishment of additional successful adult day programs.

Directs the Administration to establish a competitive grant program to fund adult day programs serving younger people with neurological diseases or conditions. Defines an "adult day program" as a program that provides comprehensive and effective care and support services to individuals living with neurological diseases or conditions and to their family caregivers and that may assist participants in ways that: (1) maintain or improve their functional abilities or otherwise help them adjust to their changing functional abilities; (2) prevent the onset of complications associated with severe forms of the disease or condition; (3) promote alternatives to placement in nursing homes; (4) reduce the strain on family caregivers taking care of a family member living with neurological diseases or conditions; (5) focus on supporting the emotional, social, and intellectual needs of a younger adult population; or (6) address the needs of veterans living with neurological diseases or conditions.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
