<bill session="114" type="h" number="922" updated="2019-04-11T15:42:40Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 to provide enhanced academic and career training in science, technology, engineering, or mathematics, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics Professional Readiness Education Preparation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STEM PREP Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">STEM PREP Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000370"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000455" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000126" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2015-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-12T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics Professional Readiness Education Preparation Act or the STEM PREP Act of 2015

This bill amends the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 to replace the TECH prep grant program with a STEM prep grant program for career and technical education programs focused on training students to enter the STEM (science, technology, engineering, or mathematics) fields.

A grant-receiving consortium may include a nonprofit institution of higher education offering a one-year certificate program or a one-year apprenticeship program.

The duration of a STEM program, currently 4- to 6-years, may extend from a 3-year to a 6-year length.

Special consideration shall be given to consortium applications showcasing curricula that lead to greater critical thinking and problem solving skills by incorporating fine arts into the STEM prep program.

A matching grant requirement is established for program eligibility.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
