<bill session="114" type="s" number="1984" updated="2019-06-21T11:07:10Z">
  <state datetime="2015-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keeping out Illegal Drugs Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">KIDs Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prevent Indian tribes and tribal organizations that cultivate, manufacture, or distribute marijuana on Indian land from receiving Federal funds.</title>
    <title type="display">KIDs Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000575"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-08-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-08-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-08-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Keeping out Illegal Drugs Act of 2015 or the KIDs Act of 2015

This bill prohibits any Indian tribe or a tribal organization from: (1) cultivating, manufacturing, or distributing marijuana on Indian lands; (2) knowingly or intentionally allowing the cultivation, manufacture, or distribution of marijuana on Indian lands; or (3) failing to prosecute, or to notify the appropriate federal official regarding, an individual or entity who is discovered to be cultivating, manufacturing, or distributing marijuana on Indian lands or failing to destroy the relevant marijuana crop in accordance with federal law.

No funds authorized or appropriated by federal law shall be made available to an Indian tribe or a tribal organization determined to have violated this Act until such tribe or tribal organization has remedied the violation and achieved compliance with this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
