<bill session="115" type="s" number="3518" updated="2019-04-18T16:45:56Z">
  <state datetime="2018-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to exempt from registration brokers performing services in connection with the transfer of ownership of smaller privately held companies.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Mergers, Acquisitions, Sales, and Brokerage Simplification Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Mergers, Acquisitions, Sales, and Brokerage Simplification Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Small Business Mergers, Acquisitions, Sales, and Brokerage Simplification Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000393" joined="2018-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-09-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="477"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="6147"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="6258"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="488"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="10"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-09-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Small Business Mergers, Acquisitions, Sales, and Brokerage Simplification Act of 2018

This bill amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to exempt from&#160;that Act's registration requirements merger-and-acquisition brokers that facilitate transfer of ownership in privately held companies with earnings or revenues under a specified threshold. This exemption shall not apply, however, to brokers that:

 receive, hold, transmit, or have custody of funds or securities to be exchanged by parties to an ownership&#160;transfer; engage on behalf of an issuer in a public offering of registered securities; engage on behalf of any party in a transaction involving specified shell companies; provide financing related to the transfer of ownership; assist any party to obtain financing from a third party in specified circumstances; represent both buyer and seller without disclosure and consent from both parties; facilitate a transaction with a group of buyers formed with the assistance of the broker; engage in transferring ownership to a passive buyer; bind a party to a transfer of ownership; or are subject to suspension or revocation of registration or to other specified disqualifications.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
