<bill session="115" type="h" number="5448" updated="2019-04-18T16:21:43Z">
  <state datetime="2018-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to provide eligibility under the assistive technology program for farmers with disabilities to veterans with disabilities and their families.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to provide eligibility under the assistive technology program for farmers with disabilities to veterans with disabilities and their families.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001200"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001038" joined="2018-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2018-04-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-04-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Biotechnology, Horticulture, and Research.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Biotechnology, Horticulture, and Research" code="HSAG14" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-04-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill amends the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to reauthorize and modify the Department of Agriculture Assistive Technology Program for Farmers with Disabilities. (The program provides grants for programs to provide agricultural education and assistance directed at accommodating disability in farm operations for disabled individuals and family members engaged in farming and farm-related occupations.)

The bill modifies the program to specify that veterans are eligible for assistance under the program, including disabled veterans and family members who: (1) are engaged in farming and farm-related occupations, and (2) are pursuing new farming opportunities.

The bill also permits the grants to be used for programs that provide behavioral therapy programs to assist veterans with mental service-connected disabilities, such as post-traumatic stress disorder.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
