<bill session="114" type="h" number="3754" updated="2019-05-09T23:15:19Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend titles 5 and 28, United States Code, to facilitate recovering the costs of litigation and agency adjudications for prevailing parties in an action against the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Halting Government Overreach Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Halting Government Overreach Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001189"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Antitrust, Commercial, and Administrative Law" code="HSJU05" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-09T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Halting Government Overreach Act of 2015

This bill removes exceptions that prohibit a prevailing party other than the United States from being awarded fees and expenses incurred in a civil action (other than a tort action) brought by or against the United States, or in an agency adjudicatory proceeding, if the position of the United States was substantially justified or special circumstances make an award unjust.

The fees and expenses may be awarded if the prevailing party has a direct and personal interest in the action because of an injury that gave rise to the action.

The bill also removes requirements that make parties ineligible for such an award if their net worth exceeds a specified amount at the time the action was filed or the adjudication was initiated. Under the bill, parties may seek an award of fees and expenses regardless of their net worth.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
