<bill session="115" type="s" number="1651" updated="2019-04-18T16:38:21Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for temporary financing of short-time compensation programs.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Layoff Prevention Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Layoff Prevention Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Layoff Prevention Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2017-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2017-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2017-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2017-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4426-4427" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="4074"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="3468"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Layoff Prevention Act of 2017

This bill requires each state that has already enacted a short-time compensation program to be paid 100% of the amount of short-time compensation paid under such program. Under a short-time compensation program, an employer may avoid a layoff of one or more employees by reducing the hours of all workers in the employer's workforce. Employees affected by a reduction in hours may receive a partial short-time compensation payment to compensate for lost wages. This is a voluntary and temporary program, beginning upon the enactment of this bill and ending five and one-half years later.

The bill imposes certain limitations on payments to states and requires employers to pay their states one-half of the short-time compensation paid under the employer plan.

The Department of Labor must: (1) award grants to states that enact short-time compensation programs to implement or improve the administration of such plans, (2) develop model legislative language for states in developing and enacting short-time compensation plans, and (3) provide technical assistance to states and establish reporting requirements for such programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
