<bill session="115" type="h" number="4567" updated="2019-04-18T16:18:45Z">
  <state datetime="2018-01-10T18:17:40-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-01-10T18:17:40-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-12-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require a Department of Homeland Security overseas personnel enhancement plan, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">DHS Overseas Personnel Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">DHS Overseas Personnel Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">DHS Overseas Personnel Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">DHS Overseas Personnel Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">DHS Overseas Personnel Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">DHS Overseas Personnel Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DHS Overseas Personnel Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DHS Overseas Personnel Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">DHS Overseas Personnel Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2017-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001188" joined="2017-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000132" joined="2017-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2017-12-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-12-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-12-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-01-09">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 115-490.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-01-09" calendar="Union" number="364">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 364.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-01-09T12:39:18-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Katko moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-09T12:39:31-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H34-36" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H34" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-09T12:39:34-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4567.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-09T12:54:18-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-10T18:10:50-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H125"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="12" datetime="2018-01-10T18:17:40-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 415 - 0 (Roll no. 12).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-01-10T18:17:41-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-11">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-06-13">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-07-30">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson without amendment. With written report No. 115-308.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-07-30" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="548">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 548.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Espionage and treason"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-07-30T13:28:34Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">DHS Overseas Personnel Enhancement Act of 2017

(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), by 90 days after the submission of the 3-year strategy for DHS international programs required under the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 and every 180 days thereafter, to brief the congressional homeland security committees on DHS personnel with primary duties that take place outside of the United States.

The briefing shall include:

 a detailed summary of each type of personnel position with such duties and how each such position contributes to DHS's counterterrorism mission, information related to how the geographic and regional placement of such positions contributes to such mission, information related to the position-specific training received by such personnel before and during placement at a foreign location, challenges that may impede the communication of counterterrorism information between DHS personnel at foreign locations and DHS entities in the United States, the status of efforts to implement the three-year strategy for DHS international programs, and the status of efforts to implement a plan to enhance the effectiveness of DHS personnel at foreign locations. (Sec. 3) DHS shall submit to the congressional homeland security committees a plan to enhance the effectiveness of DHS personnel at foreign locations, which shall include proposals to:

 improve efforts of DHS personnel for purposes of providing foreign partner capacity development and furthering DHS's counterterrorism mission; redeploy DHS personnel to respond to changing threats to the United States; enhance collaboration among DHS personnel at foreign locations, other federal personnel at foreign locations, and foreign partners; improve the communication of counterterrorism information between DHS personnel at foreign locations and DHS entities in the United States; and maintain practices to guard against counter-espionage threats associated with DHS personnel. (Sec. 4) The briefing requirement shall terminate four years after the submission of the three-year strategy for DHS international programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-308</report>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-490</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
