<bill session="114" type="h" number="6203" updated="2019-01-09T21:10:25Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">P3 Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Partnerships for Progress and Prosperity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Education to carry out a STEM grant program.</title>
    <title type="display">P3 Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000454"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001066" joined="2016-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000290" joined="2016-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2016-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2016-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2016-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001157" joined="2016-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001193" joined="2016-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Partnerships for Progress and Prosperity Act or the P3 Act

This bill requires the Department of Education (ED) to award grants to local educational agencies&#160;(LEAs) and institutions of higher education for the improvement of students' education in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM).

Each&#160;grantee shall partner with an employer in a STEM field to:

 assist students in obtaining internships or apprenticeships, develop STEM coursework curricula and metrics, carry out dual-credit courses, provide tutoring and mentoring, enable students and teachers to attend STEM events outside of the classroom, provide after-school and summer STEM programs, and purchase educational materials or equipment to facilitate STEM instruction. In awarding grants under the program, ED shall give special consideration to applicants that:

 promote in-classroom engagement between STEM professionals and students; use technology-based materials and content; pair mentors and tutors with students struggling to meet curriculum benchmarks; in the case of LEA applicants, serve schools in which most students are eligible for free or reduced-price lunch; and propose to use grant funds to target interventions for populations that are traditionally underrepresented in STEM fields. Each grantee shall provide matching funds equal to 50% of the grant amount.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
