<bill session="115" type="h" number="2892" updated="2019-04-18T16:11:14Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter 329 of title 49, United States Code, to ensure that new vehicles enable fuel competition so as to reduce the strategic importance of oil to the United States.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Open Fuel Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Open Fuel Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Open Fuel Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000179"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000435" joined="2017-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Digital Commerce and Consumer Protection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Consumer Protection and Commerce" code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Hybrid, electric, and advanced technology vehicles"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Open Fuel Act of 2017 

 This bill requires each fleet of a manufacturer of passenger automobiles (including light-duty motor vehicles) to be comprised of at least:

 50% qualified vehicles in model year 2020, and 80% qualified vehicles in model year 2021 and each subsequent year. A "qualified vehicle" is:

 a vehicle that operates on natural gas, hydrogen, or biodiesel; a flexible fuel vehicle capable of operating on gasoline, E85, and M85; a plug-in electric drive vehicle; or a vehicle propelled solely by fuel cell or by something other than an internal combustion engine. The bill authorizes: (1) a manufacturer to request an exemption from such requirement for specified models, lines, and types of automobiles; and (2) the Department of Transportation to grant such an exemption upon determining that unavoidable events prevent the manufacturer from meeting its required production volume of qualified automobiles.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
