<bill session="114" type="s" number="2225" updated="2018-06-02T07:11:25Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Save Our Small and Seasonal Businesses Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to establish an H-2B temporary non-agricultural work visa program and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Save Our Small and Seasonal Businesses Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000476"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2015-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2015-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2015-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2015-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2015-10-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Temporary and part-time employment"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Save Our Small and Seasonal Businesses Act of 2015

This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to declare that, effective as if enacted on January 1, 2015, a returning H-2B visa alien (temporary nonagricultural worker) who has already been counted toward the applicable numerical limitation shall:

 not again be counted toward that limitation in the current fiscal year, but shall be considered a returning worker; and shall be counted again toward the limitation if the alien departs the United States for a period longer than one year, or was not counted toward the limitation in any of the three most recent fiscal years. "Other temporary service or labor" for H-2B purposes means that an employer's labor need will last: (1) at most 1 year if peak load or intermittent, unless it is a one-time occurrence not to exceed 3 years; or (2) not to exceed 10 months if the employer's need is seasonal.

 An H-2B employer shall file an employee petition with the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), which shall have exclusive authority to issue rules and final determinations for the H-2B visa program.

 H-2B employer requirements are set forth regarding: (1) petitions, (2) admissions and maximum stay in status, (3) housing, (4) enforcement, (5) transportation, (6) recruitment, (7) U.S. worker protections, (8) wages, and (9) absconding workers.

 DHS shall consult with the Department of State to develop an electronic notification system to notify the latter within 48 hours after an H-2B petition's final approval.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
