<bill session="114" type="h" number="1376" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:02Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Patient Choice Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter V of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to permit provisional approval of fast track products.</title>
    <title type="display">Patient Choice Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000568"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2015-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2015-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Patient Choice Act of 2015

Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to authorize provisional approval of fast track products determined by the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to be adequately safe. Treats provisional approval in the same manner as approval of a drug, except that provisional approval is subject to requirements related to informed consent and continued pursuit of safety and efficacy data for purposes of gaining approval for the drug.

Defines the term &#8220;adequately safe&#8221; to mean that: (1) for at least one population, the risk of death or morbidity of the drug is unlikely to be greater than the combined risks of death or morbidity of the disease and existing therapies; or (2) the drug has had a valid marketing authorization for at least four years in one of the countries specified and data adequate for the approval of that marketing authorization has been submitted to HHS.

Prohibits HHS from imposing any requirements for safety studies or data in addition to, or different than, the requirements for studies to establish safety for purposes of Phase 1 (initial introduction of an investigational new drug into humans) or Phase 2 (controlled clinical studies to evaluate the effectiveness of the drug for a particular indication in patients with the disease or condition under study and to determine the common short-term side effects and risks associated with the drug).

Applies the provisional approval only to the indication for which the drug was: (1) designated as a fast track product, and (2) demonstrated to be adequately safe.

Prescribes requirements for termination of provisional approval, withdrawal of provisional approval, and application of market exclusivity to fast-track approval products.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
