<bill session="115" type="s" number="3104" updated="2019-04-18T16:44:12Z">
  <state datetime="2018-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 to expand substantially underserved trust area authority to all rural development programs of the Department of Agriculture.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expanded SUTA Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expanded SUTA Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Expanded SUTA Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001069" joined="2018-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2018-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-06-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-06-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Expanded SUTA Act of 2018 

This bill amends the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 to expand the Department Agriculture (USDA) Substantially Underserved Trust Area (SUTA) authority to: (1) include all programs administered by the USDA rural development mission area, and (2) specify that USDA may use the authority for certain communities within former Indian reservations.

(Under current law, the SUTA authority is limited to certain programs administered by the USDA Rural Utilities Service. The authority permits USDA to modify or waive certain requirements and procedures for loans and grants in order to improve the availability of programs in communities on trust land [e.g., land held in trust by the United States for Native Americans] that have a high need for the benefits of an eligible program.)</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
