<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <amendments />
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <number>371</number>
        <latestAction>
          <actionTime>15:02:59</actionTime>
          <actionDate>2013-10-04</actionDate>
          <text>DEBATE - Mr. Cole asked unanimous consent to modify the text of H.Res. 371 with the amendment at the desk. Agreed to without objection.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <latestTitle>Providing for consideration of the joint resolution (H.J. Res. 75) making continuing appropriations for the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children for fiscal year 2014, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of motions to suspend the rules; waiving a requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII with respect to consideration of certain resolutions reported from the Committee on Rules; and for other purposes.</latestTitle>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>House</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <type>HRES</type>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <billNumber>78</billNumber>
    <title>National Intelligence Program Operations Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
    <notes />
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Appropriations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Central Intelligence Agency (CIA)</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Military operations and strategy</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Public contracts and procurement</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Terrorism</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <subcommittees />
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2013-10-03T14:01:20Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <systemCode>hsap00</systemCode>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <name>Appropriations Committee</name>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <createDate>2013-10-04T09:13:08Z</createDate>
    <cosponsors />
    <laws />
    <version>1.0.0</version>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <updateDate>2013-10-03T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2013-10-04T21:48:55Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>National Intelligence Program Operations Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014 - Makes appropriations, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for national intelligence program operations for FY2014, and for other purposes, such amounts as may be necessary, at a rate for operations provided for in the Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2013 (division C of P.L. 113-6), for payment of personnel compensation and benefits for civilian employees whom the Director of National Intelligence (DNI) determines necessary to continue the following projects or activities conducted in FY2013, for which appropriations, funds, or other authority were made available under such Act, as set forth under the heading &quot;National Intelligence Program&quot; in the classified annex accompanying such Act: </p> <ul> <li>producing finished intelligence for the President or senior military or civilian officials of the federal government; </li> <li>collecting human, signals, or technical intelligence; </li> <li>conducting a covert action under the National Security Act of 1947, as directed by the President;</li> <li>providing analytic support to critical ongoing intelligence operations and military combat operations; and </li> <li>maintaining the capability to provide warnings of counterterrorism and international terrorist threats to protect the life, safety, and security of U.S. interests.</li> </ul> <p>Makes further appropriations for continuing contracts for compensation of contract employees whom the DNI determines necessary to support such projects and activities.</p> <p>Requires the rate of operations for each such project or activity to be calculated to reflect the full amount of any reduction required in FY2013 pursuant to: (1) the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2013 (P.L. 113-6), and (2) the presidential sequestration order dated March 1, 2013, except as attributable to budget authority made available by the Disaster Relief Appropriations Act, 2013 (P.L. 113-2).</p> <p>Makes appropriations and funds made available and authority granted under this joint resolution available until whichever of the following first occurs: (1) enactment into law of an appropriation for any project or activity provided for in this joint resolution, (2) enactment into law of the applicable appropriations Act for FY2014 without any provision for such project or activity, or (3) December 15, 2013. </p> <p>Requires implementation of this joint resolution so that only the most limited funding action be taken in order to provide for continuation of projects and activities.</p> <p>Expresses the sense of Congress that this joint resolution may also be referred to as the Preserving Our Intelligence Capabilities Act.</p>]]></text>
          <actionDate>2013-10-03</actionDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <latestAction>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
      <links />
      <actionDate>2013-10-03</actionDate>
    </latestAction>
    <committeeReports />
    <billType>HJRES</billType>
    <introducedDate>2013-10-03</introducedDate>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>[Congressional Record Volume 159, Number 135 (Thursday, October 3, 2013)]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. YOUNG of Florida:H.J. Res. 78.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:The principal constitutional authority for this legislationis clause 7 of section 9 of article I of the Constitution ofthe United States (the appropriation power), which states:``No Money shall be drawn from the Treasury, but inConsequence of Appropriations made by Law. . . .'' Inaddition, clause 1 of section 8 of article I of theConstitution (the spending power) provides: ``The Congressshall have the Power . . . to pay the Debts and provide forthe common Defence and general Welfare of the United States.. . .'' Together, these specific constitutional provisionsestablish the congressional power of the purse, grantingCongress the authority to appropriate funds, to determinetheir purpose, amount, and period of availability, and to setforth terms and conditions governing their use.[Page H6224]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <recordedVotes />
    <congress>113</congress>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <party>R</party>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>Y000031</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>7882</gpoId>
          <lisID>1255</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <middleName>Bill</middleName>
        <district>13</district>
        <byRequestType />
        <bioguideId>Y000031</bioguideId>
        <state>FL</state>
        <lastName>Young</lastName>
        <firstName>C. W.</firstName>
        <fullName>Rep. Young, C. W. Bill [R-FL-13]</fullName>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <title>Preserving our intelligence capabilities bill</title>
        <parentTitleType>Popular Title</parentTitleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Popular Titles</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <title>National Intelligence Program Operations Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <title>Making continuing appropriations for national intelligence program operations for fiscal year 2014, and for other purposes.</title>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <title>National Intelligence Program Operations Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <policyArea>
      <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
    </policyArea>
    <updateDate>2018-06-05T15:54:31Z</updateDate>
    <actions>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>3</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <item>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsap00</systemCode>
          <name>Appropriations Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionDate>2013-10-03</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2013-10-03</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2013-10-03</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
      </item>
    </actions>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

