<bill session="115" type="h" number="4534" updated="2019-04-18T16:18:38Z">
  <state datetime="2017-12-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-12-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-12-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the interstate Compact governing the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">METRO Accountability and Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">METRO Accountability and Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Metro Efficiency, Transparency, Reliability, Oversight, Accountability and Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Metro Efficiency, Transparency, Reliability, Oversight, Accountability and Reform Act</title>
    <title type="display">METRO Accountability and Reform Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001105"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-12-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Highways and Transit" code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="6852"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-12-04T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Metro Efficiency, Transparency, Reliability, Oversight, Accountability and Reform Act or the METRO Accountability and Reform Act

This bill amends the Passenger Rail Investment and Improvement Act of 2008 to reauthorize through FY2029 the grant program for capital and preventive maintenance projects for the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (WMATA).

The Department of Transportation (DOT) shall issue language to amend the WMATA Compact to establish a Metro Reform Board and transmit such language to the signatories of the compact (i.e., Maryland, Virginia, and the District of Columbia), the funding jurisdictions, and Congress. DOT shall not release any funds until it certifies that the signatories have enacted such language.

DOT may make grants to WMATA to finance the capital and preventive maintenance projects included in the Capital Improvement Program approved by WMATA's Board of Directors.

The bill sets forth protections for WMATA employees, including whistle-blower protections.

The General Services Administration shall initiate a review of the various transit benefit programs administered by each federal department and agency with facilities located in the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Zone for purposes of standardizing the rate of benefit for all federal employees enrolled in such benefit programs.

The Federal Transit Administration shall conduct a review of its competitive grant programs.

The bill establishes a Metro Reform Commission to inform Congress and stakeholders on the progress of signatories in amending the WMATA compact and increasing efficiencies within WMATA. It also modifies standards for arbitrating disputes involving interstate compact agencies.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
