<bill session="115" type="s" number="3024" updated="2019-04-18T16:43:50Z">
  <state datetime="2018-06-07">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill making appropriations for military construction, the Department of Veterans Affairs, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2019, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001236"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-07">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Boozman. With written report No. 115-269.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-06-07" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="446">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 446.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="5786"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="5895"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-06-07T14:44:03Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2019

Provides FY2019 appropriations for Military Construction, the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), and related agencies.

Provides appropriations to the Department of Defense (DOD) for Military Construction for:

 the Army; the Navy and Marine Corps; the Air Force; Defense-wide agencies and activities; the Army and Air National Guard; and the Army, Navy, and Air Force Reserves. Provides appropriations to DOD for the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Security Investment Program.

Provides appropriations for the Department of Defense Base Closure Account.

Provides appropriations to DOD for Construction and Operation and Maintenance of Family Housing for the Army, the Navy and Marine Corps, the Air Force, and Defense-wide agencies and activities.

Provides appropriations to DOD for the Family Housing Improvement Fund and the Military Unaccompanied Housing Improvement Fund.

Provides appropriations to the VA for:

 the Veterans Benefits Administration, the Veterans Health Administration, the National Cemetery Administration, and Departmental Administration. Provides appropriations for related agencies and programs, including:

 the American Battle Monuments Commission, the U.S. Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims, Cemeterial Expenses of the Army, and the Armed Forces Retirement Home. Provide appropriations to DOD for Overseas Contingency Operations Military Construction projects of:

 the Army, the Navy and Marine Corps, the Air Force, and Defense-wide agencies and activities. Sets forth permissible and prohibited uses for funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-269</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
