<bill session="114" type="h" number="673" updated="2018-06-02T02:19:25Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Pay for Performance Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To hold the salaries of Members of a House of Congress in escrow if the House of Congress does not agree to a budget resolution or pass regular appropriation bills on a timely basis during a Congress, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Congressional Pay for Performance Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000598"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001282" joined="2015-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000754" joined="2015-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000621" joined="2015-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000571" joined="2015-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000565" joined="2015-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001191" joined="2015-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000587" joined="2015-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2015-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4814"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4486"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Congressional Pay for Performance Act of 2015 Requires the appropriate payroll administrator of each house of Congress to deposit in an escrow account all mandatory payments for compensation of Members of Congress serving in that house if by April 15 of any calendar year, beginning with 2015, that house has not agreed to a concurrent budget resolution for the fiscal year that begins on October 1 of the calendar year. Requires release to those Members of such payments after April 16 of the calendar year, only upon the earlier of: (1) the day on which that house agrees to a concurrent budget resolution for the fiscal year which begins on October 1 of that calendar year, or (2) the last day of Congress during which that calendar year occurs. Sets forth similar requirements if by July 31 of a calendar year, beginning with 2015, a house of Congress has not passed each of the regular appropriation bills for the fiscal year which begins on October 1 of that calendar year. Requires release to the appropriate Members of salary payments after August 1 of the calendar year, only upon the earlier of: (1) the day on which that house has passed each of the regular appropriation bills for the fiscal year which begins on October 1 of that calendar year, or (2) the last day of Congress during which that calendar year occurs.

Requires the payroll administrator of a house of Congress, in order to ensure that this Act is carried out in a manner consistent with the Constitution, to release for payments to Members of that house any amounts remaining in any escrow account under this Act on the last day of Congress during which the amounts were deposited in such account.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
