<bill session="114" type="h" number="6080" updated="2019-07-20T13:42:02Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the availability of personalized handguns from federally licensed firearms dealers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Modernizing Firearm Technology Act</title>
    <title type="display">Modernizing Firearm Technology Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000623"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Modernizing Firearm Technology Act

This bill amends the federal criminal code to require licensed firearms dealers to prominently display and offer for sale personalized handguns. A personalized handgun gun incorporates a firing restriction into its design so that only an authorized user may fire the gun. An authorized user is the lawful owner of the handgun and any individual authorized by the owner to use the handgun who is allowed to own, carry, or use a firearm in the state where the firearm is being used.

The bill takes effect on the date the National Institute of Justice (NIJ) certifies that at least two different models of personalized handguns are available commercially in sufficient quantities to enable licensed dealers to sell the gun. NIJ may not certify a model of a personalized handgun if it does not fire at least as reliably as the average nonpersonalized handgun.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
