<bill session="114" type="h" number="3857" updated="2018-09-07T15:10:32Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-04">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-11-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Financial Stability Oversight Council to carry out certain requirements under the Financial Stability Act of 2010 before making any new determination under section 113 of such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To require the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Financial Stability Oversight Council to carry out certain requirements under the Financial Stability Act of 2010 before making any new determination under section 113 of such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001189"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-04">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-11-04" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 33 - 24.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-12-16">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 114-878.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-12-16" calendar="Union" number="689">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 689.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-16T13:43:09Z" status="Reported to House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

(Sec. 1) This bill prohibits the Financial Stability Oversight Council (FSOC) from determining under the Financial Stability Act of 2010 that certain nonbank financial companies shall be supervised by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and subject to prudential standards until 90 days after:

 the Federal Reserve Board establishes prudential standards for nonbank financial companies, the Federal Reserve Board promulgates criteria for exempting certain types or classes of U.S. or foreign nonbank financial companies from supervision, FSOC reevaluates within 2016 each such determination and rescinds any of them if the nonbank financial company in question no longer meets specified standards, and FSOC reports to Congress its reasons for not rescinding any determination.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-878</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
