<bill session="115" type="h" number="2266" updated="2019-07-15T21:58:08Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-26">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-10-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="agreed to by house and senate">Making additional supplemental appropriations for disaster relief requirements for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2018, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 28 of the United States Code to authorize the appointment of additional bankruptcy judges; and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Bankruptcy Judgeship Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short">Additional Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Requirements Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short">Additional Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Requirements Act, 2017</title>
    <title type="short">Bankruptcy Judgeship Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Bankruptcy Judgeship Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Bankruptcy Judgeship Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Bankruptcy Judgeship Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bankruptcy Judgeship Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bankruptcy Judgeship Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Additional Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Requirements Act, 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000714"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001066" joined="2017-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2017-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001111" joined="2017-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000621" joined="2017-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000289" joined="2017-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001179" joined="2017-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2017-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2017-05-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-03" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 115-130.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-17" calendar="Union" number="80">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 80.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17T14:01:33-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Goodlatte moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17T14:01:49-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4245-4248" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17T14:01:51-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2266.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2017-05-17T14:18:08-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4245-4246" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17T14:18:10-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-27">
      <text>Senate Committee on the Judiciary discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-27">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6191" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2017-09-27" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-09-28">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by special rule" type="pingpong" datetime="2017-10-12T15:24:28-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:HOUSE">
      <text>House agreed to Senate amendment with amendment pursuant to H.Res. 569.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7989-7992" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7989-7992" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-10-12T15:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Con. Res. 85, enrollment corrections on H.R. 2266 have been made.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-16">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendment to Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-19">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6630" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-19">
      <text>Motion by Senator McConnell to concur in the House amendment to the Senate amendment made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6630"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-19">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to concur in the House amendment to the Senate amendment presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6630"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-19">
      <text>Motion by Senator McConnell to concur in the House amendment to the Senate amendment with an amendment (SA 1568) made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6630"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-19">
      <text>Motion by Senator McConnell to refer to Senate Committee on Appropriations the House message to accompany H.R. 2266 with instructions to report back forthwith with amendment SA 1570 made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6630" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-23">
      <text>Considered by Senate (Message from the House considered).</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6703-6711" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-23">
      <text>Cloture on the motion to concur in the House amendment to the Senate amendment invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 79 - 16. Record Vote Number: 246.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6703, S6709-6710" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-23">
      <text>Motion by Senator McConnell to refer to Senate Committee on Appropriations the House message to accompany H.R. 2266 with instructions to report back forthwith with amendment SA 1570 fell when cloture invoked on the motion to concur in the House amendment to the Senate amendment in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6703" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-24">
      <text>Considered by Senate (Message from the House considered).</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6721-6738" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-24">
      <text>Motion by Senator McConnell to concur in the House amendment to the Senate amendment with an amendment (SA 1568) withdrawn in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6737" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-24">
      <text>Point of order that the motion to concur in the House amendment to the Senate amendment violates section 314(e) of the CBA raised in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-24">
      <text>Motion to waive all applicable budgetary discipline with respect to the measure (the motion to concur in the House amendment to the Senate amendment) agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 80 - 19. Record Vote Number: 247.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="pingpong" roll="248" datetime="2017-10-24" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Senate agreed to the House amendment to the Senate amendment to H.R. 2266 by Yea-Nay Vote. 82 - 17. Record Vote Number: 248.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-10-25">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2017-10-25">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2017-10-26" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="115-72" type="public" datetime="2017-10-26">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 115-72.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Antitrust, Commercial, and Administrative Law" code="HSJU05" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hc" session="115" relation="procedurally-related" number="85"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1237"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="unknown" number="569"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="4008"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="136"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="632"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1107"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Delaware"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1576"/>
    <amendment number="s1575"/>
    <amendment number="s1574"/>
    <amendment number="s1573"/>
    <amendment number="s1572"/>
    <amendment number="s1571"/>
    <amendment number="s1570"/>
    <amendment number="s1569"/>
    <amendment number="s1568"/>
    <amendment number="s1106"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2017-10-27T03:59:59Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the House on October 12, 2017. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Additional Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Requirements Act, 2017 

This bill provides supplemental appropriations for disaster relief, reauthorizes temporary bankruptcy judgeships, and revises requirements regarding the U.S. Trustee System Fund and bankruptcy.

DIVISION A--ADDITIONAL SUPPLEMENTAL APPROPRIATIONS FOR DISASTER RELIEF REQUIREMENTS ACT OF 2017

Additional Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Requirements Act of 2017

This division provides $36.5 billion in FY2018 emergency supplemental appropriations to the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), the Department of Agriculture (USDA), and the Department of the Interior for relief and recovery efforts in response to recent hurricanes and wildfires.

The funds provided by the division are designated as emergency requirements, which exempts the funding from discretionary spending limits and other budget enforcement rules.

TITLE I--DEPARTMENT OF HOMELAND SECURITY

For FEMA, the bill provides $18.67 billion for the Disaster Relief Fund, of which: (1) $10 million must be transferred to the Department of Homeland Security Office of Inspector General for audits and investigations related to disasters, and (2) up to $4.9 billion may be transferred to the Community Disaster Loans Program for direct loans to assist local governments in providing essential services as a result of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, or Maria.

TITLE II--DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR

This title provides $576.5 million for wildfire suppression operations and activities, including: (1) $526.5 million for the Forest Service, and (2) $50 million for the Department of the Interior.

TITLE III--GENERAL PROVISIONS

(Sec. 301) Funds provided by this division are in addition to amounts otherwise appropriated for the fiscal year involved.

(Sec. 302) No part of any appropriation provided by this division is available for obligation beyond the fiscal year, unless this bill expressly provides otherwise.

(Sec. 303) The terms and conditions applicable to the funds provided in this division, including those provided by this title, also apply to the funds provided by the Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Requirements, 2017.

(Sec. 304) Each amount designated in this division by Congress as being for an emergency requirement is only available if the President subsequently designates the amounts and transmits the designations to Congress.

(Sec. 305) Each agency must submit to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), the Government Accountability Office (GAO), the respective Inspector General of each agency, and the congressional appropriations committees internal control plans for funds provided by this division and the Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Requirements, 2017. The GAO must review the design of the plans.

All programs and activities receiving funds under this division shall be deemed to be "susceptible to significant improper payments" for purposes of the Improper Payments Information Act of 2002. (This requires the relevant agency to comply with certain requirements for reports and corrective actions regarding improper payments.)

Funds for grants provided by this division or the Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Requirements, 2017 must be expended by the grantees within 24 months of the agency's obligation of funds for the grant, unless the OMB waives the requirement.

(Sec. 306) This section amends the Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Requirements, 2017 to permit the Department of Housing and Urban Development to award Community Development Block Grant funds provided by the Act directly to Indian tribes, in addition to a state or unit of general local government.

(Sec. 307) This section amends the Continuing Appropriations Act, 2018 to specify that the language included in The Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2017 under the heading "FLAME Wildfire Suppression Reserve Fund' for the Departments of Agriculture and the Interior does not apply for the purpose of the continuing appropriations provided by the Act.

(Sec. 308) This section cancels $16 billion of the debt held by the Department of the Treasury under notes or obligations issued by the National Flood Insurance Program.

(Sec. 309) USDA may use up to $1.27 billion of funds from the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP, formerly known as the food stamp program) contingency reserve to provide a grant to Puerto Rico for disaster nutrition assistance in response to the presidentially declared major disasters and emergencies.

(Sec. 310) This section specifies that the dollar limitation on advance billing of a customer of a Department of Defense working-capital fund does not apply to FEMA during FY2018.

DIVISION B--BANKRUPTCY JUDGESHIP ACT OF 2017

Bankruptcy Judgeship Act of 2017

(Sec. 1002) This bill reauthorizes 14 temporary bankruptcy judgeships in judicial districts in Delaware, Florida, Puerto Rico, Maryland, Michigan, Virginia, Nevada, and North Carolina.

(Sec. 1003) It authorizes the appointment of four additional temporary bankruptcy judges in Delaware, Florida, and Michigan.

(Sec. 1004) The bill amends the federal judicial code to increase the quarterly fee imposed on certain chapter 11 (reorganization) debtors. Specifically, if the balance in the U.S. Trustee System Fund is less than $200 million, then a debtor with total quarterly disbursements of $1 million or more must pay a quarterly fee equal to $250,000 or 1% of disbursements, whichever is less.

It also specifies that for FY2018-FY2022, 98% of the quarterly fees collected must be deposited as offsetting collections to the U.S. Trustee System Fund and 2% must be deposited in the general fund of the Treasury.

(Sec. 1005) This section amends the federal bankruptcy code to include an unsecured claim by a governmental unit (e.g., a tax claim by the Internal Revenue Service) resulting from the sale, transfer, exchange, or disposition of farming property in chapter 12 bankruptcy (family farmer or fisherman reorganization) proceedings. Such a claim that arises before a debtor's discharge, regardless of whether the claim is pre-petition or post-petition, must be treated as a pre-petition claim, is not entitled to priority status, must be provided for under the bankruptcy plan, and is dischargeable.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-130</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
