<bill session="113" type="h" number="3069" updated="2016-10-25T16:07:06Z">
  <state datetime="2013-09-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Shield Our Streets Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve public safety through increased law enforcement presence and enhanced public safety equipment and programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Shield Our Streets Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000714"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2014-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2014-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000185" joined="2013-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1275"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-09-09T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Shield Our Streets Act of 2013 - Authorizes the Attorney General to carry out a program, through the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services, to award grants to assist eligible local law enforcement agencies with hiring and training new law enforcement officers and with rehiring career law enforcement officers who have been laid off as a result of budget reductions.

Defines an "eligible" local law enforcement agency as one that has jurisdiction over all or part of a county or other unit of local government that has a violent crime rate at or above the national average and that has had budget reductions during the most recent five-year period (elevated need locality).

Authorizes the Attorney General to carry out a program to award grants to units of local government that have jurisdiction over all or part of an elevated need locality to enhance public safety in such jurisdictions, including by: (1) purchasing public safety equipment, (2) funding public safety programs, (3) making infrastructure improvements, (4) purchasing and installing lights to deter crime, (5) funding activities related to crime labs, and (6) funding public defender programs. Authorizes such grants to nonprofit organizations that operate in elevated need localities to carry out programs designed to reduce crime in such areas.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
