<bill session="115" type="s" number="1339" updated="2019-04-18T16:37:02Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide authority for access to certain business records collected under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 prior to November 29, 2015, to make the authority for roving surveillance, the authority to treat individual terrorists as agents of foreign powers, and title VII of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 permanent, and to modify the certification requirements for access to telephone toll and transactional records by the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Liberty Through Strength Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Liberty Through Strength Act</title>
    <title type="display">Liberty Through Strength Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001095"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2017-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2017-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2017-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2017-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2017-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2017-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2017-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1297"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Liberty Through Strength Act

This bill gives the National Security Agency (NSA) access to business records, telephone call records, and other tangible items collected prior to November 29, 2015, under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (FISA) in the same manner and for the same purposes for which the NSA had access to such records prior to such date. This access is in effect for five years.

The bill amends the USA PATRIOT Improvement and Reauthorization Act of 2005 to make permanent the expiring&#160;FISA provision that allows wiretap orders that follow the surveillance target rather than the phone (known as "roving wiretaps").

The bill amends the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 to make permanent the expiring FISA provision that revises the definition of "agent of a foreign power" to include any non-U.S. persons who engage in international terrorism or preparatory activities.

The bill amends&#160;the FISA Amendments Act of 2008 to make permanent title VII of FISA,&#160;which allows the Department of Justice&#160;and the Office of the Director of National Intelligence to jointly authorize the&#160;electronic surveillance of non-U.S. persons who are outside the United States.

The federal criminal code is amended to expand the categories of transactional records that the Federal Bureau of Investigation may request from wire or electronic communication service providers about a person or entity for an authorized investigation.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
