<bill session="115" type="hr" number="612" updated="2019-04-18T15:54:39Z">
  <state datetime="2017-11-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-11-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-11-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Recognizing and reaffirming the critical relationship between the United States and the Republic of Korea since the establishment of the Republic of Korea in 1948.</title>
    <title type="display">Recognizing and reaffirming the critical relationship between the United States and the Republic of Korea since the establishment of the Republic of Korea in 1948.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000795"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-11-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Asia and the Pacific.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Asia and the Pacific" code="HSFA05" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-11-09T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Reaffirms: (1) the importance of the U.S.-Republic of Korea (South Korea) alliance as a linchpin for security, stability, and prosperity on the Korean Peninsula, in the Asia-Pacific region, and beyond; (2) U.S. support for South Korean forces and continued combined exercises through the region; and (3) that the U.S. military presence in South Korea should not be included or discussed in any potential negotiation with North Korea.

Reinforces longstanding U.S. commitments to defend South Korea, to include providing a full spectrum of extended deterrence.

Urges the governments of the United States and South Korea to take the opportunity of President Trump's upcoming state visit to South Korea to send a message to North Korea that: (1) destabilizing provocations will be met with a resolute response by the U.S.-South Korea combined forces; and (2) if North Korea instead takes a step in the right direction, the United States, South Korea, and the international community are ready to present a brighter future.

Recognizes that the U.S.-Korea Free Trade Agreement is mutually beneficial and has been contributing to the alliance. Encourages the United States and South Korea to: (1) work together to resolve any outstanding issues through the bilateral consultative process, and (2) continue broadening and deepening the alliance by enhancing cooperation and building new partnerships.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
