<bill session="114" type="s" number="1425" updated="2018-06-02T06:54:19Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting New Manufacturing Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote new manufacturing in the United States by providing for greater transparency and timeliness in obtaining necessary permits, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Promoting New Manufacturing Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001047"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2557"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Promoting New Manufacturing Act

 This bill requires the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to publish on its website, with respect to FY2008 and each fiscal year thereafter, estimates of:

 the total number of preconstruction permits issued by the EPA under the Clean Air Act's New Source Review Program for the construction or modification of a major stationary source (any stationary facility or source of air pollutants which directly emits, or has the potential to emit, 100 tons per year or more of any regulated air pollutant); the percentage of permits issued within one year of the application; and the average length of time for the EPA's Environmental Appeals Board to decide appeals of decisions to grant or deny a permit. A new or revised national ambient air quality standard (NAAQS) may not apply to the review and disposition of a preconstruction permit application until the EPA publishes final implementation regulations and guidance that include information relating to submission and consideration of a preconstruction permit application under the standard.

The EPA must submit annually a report on actions to expedite the process for review of preconstruction permits.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
