<bill session="115" type="h" number="4455" updated="2019-04-18T16:18:21Z">
  <state datetime="2017-11-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-11-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-11-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to improve mitigation assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SMART Rebuilding Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SMART Rebuilding Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Mitigation Activities and Resiliency Targets for Rebuilding Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Mitigation Activities and Resiliency Targets for Rebuilding Act</title>
    <title type="display">SMART Rebuilding Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000612"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001037" joined="2017-11-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-11-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3041"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="4460"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="4"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="4667"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-11-21T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Supporting Mitigation Activities and Resiliency Targets for Rebuilding Act or the SMART Rebuilding Act

This bill amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to authorize the President to provide incentives to invest in measures that increase readiness for, and resilience from, a major disaster.

The Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) must issue comprehensive guidance on measures and investments that will be recognized for the purpose of increasing the federal share of disaster assistance.

The bill authorizes the President to: (1) establish a National Public Infrastructure Predisaster Mitigation Fund which may be used for activities to implement design standards to protect the welfare of buildings' users against disasters, and (2) contribute to state and local governments for their associated expenses which shall include base and overtime wages for extra hires to facilitate the implementation and enforcement of adopted building codes for a period of not more than 180 days after the major disaster is declared.

The President may contribute up to 75% of the cost of hazard mitigation measures determined to be cost-effective and which substantially reduce the risk of, or increase resilience to, future damage, hardship, loss, or suffering in any area affected by a major disaster.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
