<bill session="114" type="s" number="2434" updated="2018-06-02T07:14:10Z">
  <state datetime="2016-01-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-01-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Separation of Powers Restoration and Second Amendment Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide that any executive action that infringes on the powers and duties of Congress under section 8 of article I of the Constitution of the United States or on the Second Amendment to the Constitution of the United States has no force or effect, and to prohibit the use of funds for certain purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Separation of Powers Restoration and Second Amendment Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000603"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2016-01-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2016-01-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-18">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-01-11" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="343">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 343.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="4321"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-12-18T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Separation of Powers Restoration and Second Amendment Protection Act

This bill expresses the sense of Congress that any executive order, memoranda, proclamation, or signing statement issued by the President that infringes on the powers and duties of Congress under article I, section 8 of the Constitution or the Second Amendment, or that would require the expenditure of federal funds not specifically appropriated for such executive action, is advisory only and has no force or effect unless enacted as law.

The bill nullifies any such executive action and prohibits the use of appropriated funds to promulgate or enforce any such action.

The following persons may bring a civil action in an appropriate U.S. district court to challenge the validity of any such executive action: (1) any Member or either or both chambers of Congress, (2) the highest governmental official of any state or political subdivision if the challenged action infringes on a power of such state under any congressional enactment or relevant treaty, and (3) any person aggrieved of the challenged executive action with respect to a liberty or property interest adversely affected directly by the executive action.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
