<bill session="114" type="h" number="852" updated="2018-11-21T21:22:57Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TIPS Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transparency in Phone Solicitation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to provide for additional technical and procedural standards for artificial or prerecorded voice telephone messages and the establishment of such standards for live telephone solicitations.</title>
    <title type="display">TIPS Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001183"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000533" joined="2015-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000567" joined="2015-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Transparency in Phone Solicitation Act of 2015 or the TIPS Act of 2015

Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit businesses, entities, or individuals from making live telephone solicitations unless the solicitor: (1) states the solicitor's identity, telephone number, and address; (2) states the address of a website that the called party may use to indicate that such party does not wish to receive calls from that solicitor; (3) transmits caller identification information, including a telephone number that the called party may use to return the call directly to such solicitor; and (4) releases the called party's line within five seconds after being notified that the called party has hung up to allow the called party to make or receive other calls.

Revises standards applicable to telephone transmissions of artificial or prerecorded voice messages to add comparable procedures requiring any such messages to: (1) state the telephone number and address (currently, telephone number or address) of the calling entity, (2) state the address of a website that the called party may use to indicate that such party does not wish to receive calls from that entity, and (3) transmit caller identification information. Retains the current law requirement that artificial or prerecorded messages must release the line within five seconds after the called party has hung up.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
