<bill session="114" type="s" number="1942" updated="2019-03-03T14:40:58Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require a land conveyance involving the Elkhorn Ranch and the White River National Forest in the State of Colorado, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Elkhorn Ranch and White River National Forest Conveyance Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Elkhorn Ranch and White River National Forest Conveyance Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Elkhorn Ranch and White River National Forest Conveyance Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000562"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2015-11-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-08-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-08-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 114-490.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-11-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-12-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski without amendment. With written report No. 114-189.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-12-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="334">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 334.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="1554"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-12-16T13:30:12Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Elkhorn Ranch and White River National Forest Conveyance Act of 2015

 (Sec. 2) All interest of the United States in 148 acres of identified land shall be conveyed by patent to the Gordman-Leverich Partnership (GLP), a Colorado Limited Liability Partnership.

 The conveyance: (1) shall be subject to the valid existing rights of the lessee of federal oil and gas lease COC-75070 and any other valid existing rights, and (2) shall reserve to the United States the right to collect rent and royalty payments on such lease for its duration.

 The conveyance must: (1) be completed within 180 days after enactment of this Act; and (2) be without consideration, except that all costs incurred by the Department of the Interior relating to any survey, platting, legal description, or other activities carried out to prepare and issue the patent shall be paid to Interior by GLP before conveyance of the land.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-189</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
