<bill session="113" type="h" number="5516" updated="2016-10-25T16:16:35Z">
  <state datetime="2014-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Our Great Lakes Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to prohibit the discharge of dredged material into the Great Lakes, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Protecting Our Great Lakes Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000566"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-09-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Our Great Lakes Act of 2014 - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to prohibit any discharge of dredged material into waters within Lake Erie, Lake Huron, Lake St. Clair, Lake Michigan, Lake Ontario, and Lake Superior lakeward from a line drawn across the mouth of tributaries to the Lakes. Includes within the area protected from discharges all waters enclosed by constructed breakwaters (barriers built in a body of water to break the force of waves and protect surrounding land). Excludes connecting channels from the protected area.

Requires any dredged material resulting from activity in the Great Lakes System to be reused in beneficial ways on land or disposed of in a confined land- or water-based disposal area determined to be economically and environmentally viable by the Army Corps of Engineers in consultation with concerned states.

Treats violators of the prohibition as having violated a condition or limitation set forth in a permit to discharge dredged or fill material into waters of the United States.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
