<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <relatedBills />
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <createDate>2016-11-18T05:08:26Z</createDate>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <subcommittees />
          <type>Standing</type>
          <name>Finance Committee</name>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2016-11-17T20:39:59Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <title>Death Gratuity Equity Act of 2016</title>
    <billNumber>3473</billNumber>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <lastName>MIKULSKI</lastName>
        <bioguideId>M000702</bioguideId>
        <state>MD</state>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>802</lisID>
          <bioguideId>M000702</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8240</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <middleName>ANN</middleName>
        <firstName>BARBARA</firstName>
        <fullName>Sen. Mikulski, Barbara A. [D-MD]</fullName>
        <byRequestType />
        <party>D</party>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <version>1.0.0</version>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <committeeReports />
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-11-17</actionDate>
      <links />
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance. (Sponsor introductory remarks on measure: CR S6486)</text>
    </latestAction>
    <notes />
    <titles>
      <item>
        <title>Death Gratuity Equity Act of 2016</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>A bill to increase outdated death gratuities and funeral allowances for Federal civilian employees killed in the line of duty, to expand the scope of eligible beneficiaries, to codify tax treatment, to change offset requirements, to harmonize death gratuities across Federal agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Death Gratuity Equity Act of 2016</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-11-17</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
          <name>Finance Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links>
          <link>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-162/senate-section/page/S6486</url>
            <name>S6486</name>
          </link>
        </links>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance. (Sponsor introductory remarks on measure: CR S6486)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-11-17</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>2</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <actionDate>2016-11-17</actionDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>Death Gratuity Equity Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill requires federal agencies to pay a death gratuity of $100,000 per employee for the death of civilian employees resulting from injuries sustained in the line of duty that did not result from natural causes or the employee's serious and willful misconduct. The bill also allows an additional payment of up to $8,800 for funeral and burial expenses. (Currently, funeral and burial payments may not exceed $800 per employee and the combination of payments for death gratuity, funeral, burial, and other compensation and reimbursements may not exceed $10,000 per employee.)</p> <p>The amounts must be adjusted annually for inflation. For tax purposes, a death gratuity payment shall not be considered gross income to the person receiving payment.</p> <p>The death gratuity remains at $100,000 for an employee who dies of injuries incurred in connection with service with an Armed Force in a contingency operation, except that employees who are noncitizens and nonresidents of the United States or Canada, and their dependents, are subject to the Department of Labor's authority to modify payments that are substantially disproportionate to compensation for disability or death payable in similar cases under local laws or customs at the place outside the continental United States or Canada where the employee is working at the time of injury. The bill also allows such death gratuities in connection with such Armed Force service to be paid in addition to any other amounts paid under U.S. law based on the same death. </p> <p>The Foreign Service Act of 1980 is amended to make death gratuities payable to the surviving beneficiaries (currently, dependents) of U.S. Foreign Service employees, or individuals in a special category serving in an uncompensated capacity for that agency in support of a diplomatic mission, who die as a result of injuries sustained in the performance of duty abroad. But the Foreign Service death gratuity is reduced by the amount of any federal civilian employee death gratuity paid under this bill for the same death.</p> <p>Additional amounts are authorized to be appropriated for death gratuity payments under this bill if an agency and the Office of Management and Budget determine that a natural disaster, act of terrorism, or other incident results in the inability of the agency to meet these death gratuity payment requirements. An authorized payment that exceeds the amount available to the agency without additional appropriations may be made only if Congress makes the additional appropriations for that purpose.</p>]]></text>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-12-02T20:14:33Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <updateDate>2016-11-17T05:00:00Z</updateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <amendments />
    <introducedDate>2016-11-17</introducedDate>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <fullName>Sen. Cardin, Benjamin L. [D-MD]</fullName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>174</lisID>
          <bioguideId>C000141</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8287</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>C000141</bioguideId>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MD</state>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <lastName>CARDIN</lastName>
        <firstName>BENJAMIN</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-11-17</sponsorshipDate>
        <middleName>L.</middleName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <fullName>Sen. Warner, Mark R. [D-VA]</fullName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>W000805</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8269</gpoId>
          <lisID>1897</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>W000805</bioguideId>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>VA</state>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <lastName>Warner</lastName>
        <firstName>Mark</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-11-17</sponsorshipDate>
        <middleName>R.</middleName>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <updateDate>2019-03-03T14:41:18Z</updateDate>
    <laws />
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <date>2016-11-17T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114s3473is/xml/BILLS-114s3473is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects />
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <billType>S</billType>
    <recordedVotes />
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

