<bill session="113" type="s" number="1475" updated="2016-10-25T16:26:43Z">
  <state datetime="2013-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Nurse Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the position of National Nurse for Public Health, to be filled by the same individual serving as the Chief Nurse Officer of the Public Health Service.</title>
    <title type="display">National Nurse Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001176"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="485"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-08-01T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Nurse Act of 2013 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to designate the Chief Nurse Officer of the Public Health Service as the National Nurse for Public Health within the Office of the Surgeon General.

Includes among the duties of such position providing leadership and coordination of Public Health Service nursing professional affairs for the Office of the Surgeon General and other agencies of the Public Health Service, conducting outreach and education, and providing guidance and leadership for activities that will increase public safety and emergency preparedness.

Requires the National Nurse for Public Health to: (1) participate in identification of national health priorities, (2) encourage volunteerism of nurses and strengthen the relationship between government agencies and health-related national organizations, and (3) promote the dissemination of evidence-based practice in educating the public on health promotion and disease prevention activities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
