<bill session="113" type="s" number="2729" updated="2016-10-25T16:31:57Z">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Private Landowner Protection Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to require the Secretary of the Interior to publish and make available for public comment a draft economic analysis at the time a proposed rule to designate critical habitat is published.</title>
    <title type="display">Private Landowner Protection Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000590"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2014-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="4319"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-07-31T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Private Landowner Protection Act of 2014 - Amends the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to require the Department of the Interior or the Department of Commerce through the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to exclude an area from designation as a critical habitat to conserve an endangered or threatened species if the benefits of exclusion outweigh the benefits of including the area, unless the failure to designate the area as critical habitat will result in the extinction of the species.

Requires the appropriate department to make available for public comment with any proposed rule to designate a critical habitat an analysis that: (1) examines the economic effects of all actions that are related to a critical habitat designation or the protection of the species, (2) is quantitative and qualitative, and (3) examines the incremental effects of the critical habitat designation and the cumulative economic effects of both the critical habitat designation and the listing determination.

Prohibits the analysis from effecting the determination to list a species.

Applies the requirements to any critical habitat designation proposed or promulgated on or after October 30, 2013. Requires any designation finalized on or after that date to be reopened for analysis within 30 days of this Act's enactment.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
