<bill session="113" type="h" number="1188" updated="2018-06-05T16:11:00Z">
  <state datetime="2013-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preserving Our Hometown Independent Pharmacies Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure and foster continued safety and quality of care and a competitive marketplace by exempting independent pharmacies from the antitrust laws in their negotiations with health plans and health insurance insurers.</title>
    <title type="display">Preserving Our Hometown Independent Pharmacies Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001179"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001269" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000556" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001093" joined="2013-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000291" joined="2014-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000449" joined="2013-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000560" joined="2014-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001149" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000591" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001195" joined="2014-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000065" joined="2013-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" code="HSJU05" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-03-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Preserving Our Hometown Independent Pharmacies Act of 2013 - Treats independent pharmacies negotiating contract terms with a health plan for the provision of health care items or services, but only in connection with such negotiations, the same under the antitrust laws as an employee engaged in concerted activities, and not as an employer, independent contractor, managerial employee, or supervisor.

Exempts actions taken in good faith reliance on this Act from being subject to criminal sanctions or civil penalties beyond actual damages incurred.

Declares that this Act does not exempt from application of antitrust laws any agreement or unlawful conspiracy that: (1) would have the effect of boycotting any independent pharmacy; (2) would exclude, limit the participation or reimbursement of, or otherwise limit the scope of services to be provided by any independent pharmacy or group of independent pharmacies with respect to the performance of services within their scope of practice as defined or permitted by relevant law or regulation; (3) allocates a market among competitors; (4) unlawfully ties the sale or purchase of one product or service to the sale or purchase of another product or service; or (5) monopolizes or attempts to monopolize a market.

Makes this Act inapplicable to negotiations between pharmacies and health plans regarding benefits provided under specified federal programs, including Medicaid, veterans' medical care, and the federal employees' health benefits program.

Requires the Comptroller General to study the impact of this Act after five years.

States that this Act does not preclude the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) or the Department of Justice (DOJ) from overseeing the conduct of independent pharmacies covered under this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
