<bill session="114" type="h" number="4719" updated="2019-05-09T23:15:21Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 to require notice and a compliance opportunity to be provided before commencement of a private civil action related to public accommodations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COMPLI Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Correcting Obstructions to Mediate, Prevent, and Limit Inaccessibility Act</title>
    <title type="display">COMPLI Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001166"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Correcting Obstructions to Mediate, Prevent, and Limit Inaccessibility Act or the COMPLI Act

This bill amends the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 to prohibit persons aggrieved by certain public accommodation violations from commencing a civil action for discrimination unless they: (1) provide the owner or operator of the accommodation with a written notice that is specific enough to identify the violation; (2) specify in the notice that the owner or operator has 90 days to remove or correct the violation before an action will be brought; and (3) refrain from sending demand letters, requests for settlement, or other communications to the owner or operator during such 90-day period.

An owner or operator of a public accommodation who is provided such a notice must notify the public of the alleged violation and the steps being taken to remedy it.

Owners or operators are entitled to an additional 30 days to comply if they make a good faith effort but are unable to correct the violation within the original 90-day period.

A civil action for discrimination based on such a violation may not be commenced while a civil action relating to the same violation is pending.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
