<bill session="114" type="h" number="2534" updated="2019-02-14T22:54:54Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SCAN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Scan Containers Absolutely Now Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Security and Accountability For Every Port Act of 2006 (the SAFE PORT Act) to administer a pilot program for 100 percent scanning of cargo containers at domestic ports, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SCAN Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001063"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E776"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Security Technologies.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Innovation" code="HSHM08" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Border Security, Facilitation, and Operations" code="HSHM11" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Scan Containers Absolutely Now Act or the SCAN Act

 Amends the Security and Accountability For Every Port Act of 2006 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to:

 conduct a one-year pilot program at two domestic ports to evaluate the process of 100% scanning of cargo containers and its potential for use at all domestic ports, achieve a full-scale implementation of the program within one year after enactment of this Act, and evaluate and report on such program within one year after program completion. Requires the Secretary to:

 acquire the equipment necessary to conduct the pilot program, make information about the equipment available to domestic ports as part of the application process, and permit such equipment to remain with the selected ports upon completion of the program. Authorizes the Secretary to purchase or lease equipment for, as well as contract for performance of scanning of cargo under, the program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
