<bill session="114" type="s" number="623" updated="2018-06-02T06:40:23Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Human Trafficking Detection Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to train Department of Homeland Security personnel how to effectively deter, detect, disrupt, and prevent human trafficking during the course of their primary roles and responsibilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Human Trafficking Detection Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000293"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="460"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Human Trafficking Detection Act of 2015

 Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to implement a program to: (1) train relevant Transportation Security Administration, U.S. Customs and Border Protection, and other DHS personnel on the best way to effectively deter, detect, and disrupt human trafficking and to interdict suspected perpetrators during the course of their primary roles and responsibilities; and (2) ensure that such personnel regularly receive current information on matters related to the detection of human trafficking.

Permits training to be conducted through in-class or virtual learning capabilities. Requires such training to include:

 methods for identifying suspected victims and perpetrators of human trafficking, methods for approaching a suspected victim in a manner that is sensitive to the victim and not likely to alert a perpetrator, training that is most appropriate for a particular location or environment, and a post-training evaluation of trainees. Directs the Secretary: (1) to reassess the training program annually; (2) within one year after enactment of this Act, to submit a certification to the appropriate congressional committees confirming that all such personnel have successfully completed the required training; and (3) to report annually on the overall effectiveness of the training program and on the number of cases reported by DHS personnel in which human trafficking was suspected and the number that were confirmed cases of human trafficking.

Authorizes the Secretary, upon request, to provide training curricula to assist any state, local, or tribal government or private organization to establish a training program to identify human trafficking.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
