<bill session="115" type="s" number="2496" updated="2019-04-18T16:41:53Z">
  <state datetime="2018-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish Small Business Health Accounts.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Health Account Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Health Account Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Small Business Health Account Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000285"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3562"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="6330"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-03-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Small Business Health Account Act of 2018 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow tax-exempt savings accounts (small business health accounts) for the health expenses of small business employees.

Individuals who are employed by a small business and have not made or received contributions for a health savings account (excluding certain contributions rolled over to a small business health account) during the month are eligible to contribute to an account. Individuals who are eligible for Medicare may not make contributions.

The bill allows a deduction for cash contributions to an account and specifies contribution limits, which must be adjusted for inflation after 2019. Tax-exempt distributions from an account may be used for qualified medical expenses, including: (1) medical care for the individual or a spouse or dependent of the individual, and (2) coverage under a health plan.

The bill sets forth rules and penalties for excess contributions to an account and distributions that are not used for qualified medical expenses.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
