<bill session="114" type="s" number="915" updated="2018-06-02T06:44:54Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Real Estate Investment and Jobs Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Real Estate Investment and Jobs Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to exempt certain stock of real estate investment trusts from the tax on foreign investments in United States real property interests, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Real Estate Investment and Jobs Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Hatch. With written report No. 114-25.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-04-14" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="48">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 48.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2128"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-14T15:13:35Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Real Estate Investment and Jobs Act of 2015 

(Sec. 2) This section increases from 5% to 10% the stock ownership threshold in a real estate investment trust (REIT) for exempting such stock as a U.S. real property interest on disposition.

(Sec. 3) This section provides for an increase from 10% to 15% of the rate of withholding of tax on dispositions of U.S. real property interests.

(Sec. 4) This section requires any corporation that is a U.S. real property holding company during a specified period to disclose such status to the Internal Revenue Service, the corporation's shareholders, and the public. The corporation is subject to penalties for failure to make such a disclosure.

(Sec. 5) This section requires a broker to deduct and withhold a tax equal to 15% of the amount realized on the disposition of stock of a U.S. real property holding company by a foreign person.

(Sec. 6) This provision exempts regulated investment companies (RICs) and REITs from tax rules governing the treatment of stock of a domestic corporation as a U.S. real property holding company.

(Sec. 7) This section provides that neither RICs nor REITs shall not be treated as domestic corporations for purposes of determining whether dividends from a foreign corporation are eligible for the tax deduction for the U.S-sourced portion of such dividends.

(Sec. 8) This section increases from 30% to 35% the rate of the continuous levy on payments made after 180 days after the enactment of this Act to Medicare providers and suppliers for unpaid taxes.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-25</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
