<bill session="115" type="h" number="5575" updated="2019-04-18T16:22:43Z">
  <state datetime="2018-04-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-04-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the treatment of Federal prisoners who are primary caretaker parents, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pathway to Parenting Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pathway to Parenting Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Pathway to Parenting Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000477"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2018-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2018-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000808" joined="2018-04-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-04-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1524"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-04-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Pathway to Parenting Act of 2018

This bill amends the federal criminal code to establish requirements for the treatment of prisoners.

It directs the Bureau of Prisons (BOP) to place prisoners as close to their children as possible, provide videoconferencing free of charge, and provide trauma-informed care to prisoners diagnosed with trauma.

Additionally, with respect to prisoners who are primary caretaker parents, the BOP must provide parenting classes, allow visitation from family members, and establish a pilot program to allow overnight visits from family members.

The bill allows a prisoner who is pregnant or a primary caretaker parent to participate in a residential substance abuse treatment program, even if the individual failed to disclose a substance abuse problem.

Finally, it establishes a pilot program to provide prenatal care to female prisoners.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
