<bill session="114" type="h" number="2396" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:09Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sensible Oversight for Technology which Advances Regulatory Efficiency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SOFTWARE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to the regulation of health software, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SOFTWARE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001243"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000410" joined="2015-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Sensible Oversight for Technology which Advances Regulatory Efficiency Act or the SOFTWARE Act

This bill amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to define health software as software that does not acquire, process, or analyze data from an in vitro diagnostic device or signal acquisition system, is not an accessory or part of a medical device, is not used to prevent disease in the transfusion of blood and blood components, and is for:

 administrative or operational support or the processing and maintenance of financial records; use in clinical, laboratory, or administrative workflow and recordkeeping; managing data but not for active patient monitoring or controlling the functions of a connected medical device; organizing and presenting information for health or wellness education or maintaining a healthy lifestyle; or analyzing information to provide general health information or patient-specific recommendations. The FDA must classify an accessory of a medical device independently from the medical device with which it is used.

Health software is exempted from regulation by the FDA (including as a medical device), except for software that provides patient-specific recommendations and poses a significant risk to patient safety.

The FDA must review existing regulations and guidance regarding the regulation of health software.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
