<bill session="114" type="h" number="1508" updated="2018-08-16T22:57:52Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Space Resource Exploration and Utilization Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Space Resource Exploration and Utilization Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote the development of a United States commercial space resource exploration and utilization industry and to increase the exploration and utilization of resources in outer space.</title>
    <title type="display">Space Resource Exploration and Utilization Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000599"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2015-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001283" joined="2015-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001274" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001289" joined="2015-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001092" joined="2015-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000386" joined="2015-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000689" joined="2015-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-05-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 18 - 15.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-06-15">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology. H. Rept. 114-153.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-06-15" calendar="Union" number="111">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 111.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="976"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Industrial policy and productivity"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Space flight and exploration"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-15T14:21:10Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">Space Resource Exploration and Utilization Act of 2015

(Sec. 2) Directs the President, acting through appropriate federal agencies, to:

 facilitate the commercial exploration and utilization of space resources to meet national needs; discourage government barriers to the development of economically viable, safe, and stable industries for the exploration and utilization of space resources in manners consistent with the existing international obligations of the United States; and promote the right of U.S. commercial entities to explore outer space and utilize space resources, in accordance with such obligations, free from harmful interference, and to transfer or sell such resources. Defines "space resource" as a natural resource of any kind found in place in outer space.

Directs the President to make recommendations to Congress for: (1) the allocation of responsibilities relating to the exploration and utilization of space resources among federal agencies, and (2) any authorities necessary to meet U.S. international obligations with respect to such exploration and resource utilization.

Declares that any asteroid resources obtained in outer space are the property of the entity that obtained them, which shall be entitled to all property rights to them, consistent with applicable federal law and existing international obligations.

States that a U.S. commercial space resource utilization entity:

 shall avoid causing harmful interference in outer space, and may bring a civil action in a U.S. district court for any action by another entity subject to U.S. jurisdiction causing harmful interference to its operations with respect to an asteroid resource utilization activity in outer space.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-153</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
