<bill session="115" type="h" number="4606" updated="2019-06-13T18:31:47Z">
  <state datetime="2018-09-06T16:10:37-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-09-06T16:10:37-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that applications under the Natural Gas Act for the importation or exportation of small volumes of natural gas shall be granted without modification or delay.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Ensuring Small Scale LNG Certainty and Access Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Ensuring Small Scale LNG Certainty and Access Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Ensuring Small Scale LNG Certainty and Access Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Ensuring Small Scale LNG Certainty and Access Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Small Scale LNG Certainty and Access Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Small Scale LNG Certainty and Access Act</title>
    <title type="display">Ensuring Small Scale LNG Certainty and Access Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000292"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2017-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2017-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2018-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000461" joined="2017-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000410" joined="2018-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000566" joined="2017-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-12-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-05-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 35 - 15.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-07-18">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 115-842.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-07-18" calendar="Union" number="651">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 651.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-09-04T19:21:45-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1049 Reported to House. The resolution provides for one hour of general debate on both H.R. 1635 and H.R. 4606. Also, the resolution provides for a motion to recommit with or without instructions for both bills.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-05T13:37:21-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 1049 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-06T13:37:38-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1049.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7887-7894" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7891" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-06T13:37:43-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for one hour of general debate on both H.R. 1635 and H.R. 4606. Also, the resolution provides for a motion to recommit with or without instructions for both bills.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-06T13:38:15-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 1049 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-06T13:38:17-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Liz Cheney to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-06T13:39:32-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 4606.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-06T14:28:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1049, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pallone amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-06T14:39:58-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Pallone amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Pallone demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-06T14:40:40-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1049, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the DeGette amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-06T14:48:41-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the DeGette amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Ms. DeGette demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-06T14:49:01-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Olson moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-06T14:49:27-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-06T14:49:55-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4606 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-06T15:30:08-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7896-7900"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-06T15:30:18-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-06T15:44:05-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 4606.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-06T15:44:20-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-06T15:44:25-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-06T15:46:11-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Watson Coleman moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7898" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-06T15:46:26-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Watson Coleman motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to prevent liquefied natural gas from being transported in pipelines in which the use of eminent domain was utilized for its construction, operation, or maintenance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-06T15:52:07-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-06T16:00:05-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 178 - 231 (Roll no. 391).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="392" datetime="2018-09-06T16:10:37-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 260 - 146 (Roll no. 392).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-09-06T16:10:39-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-06">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="procedurally-related" number="1049"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h963"/>
    <amendment number="h962"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2017-12-11T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Ensuring Small Scale LNG Certainty and Access Act

This bill amends the Natural Gas Act to state that an application under the Natural Gas Act for the importation or exportation of natural gas that does not exceed 0.14 billion cubic feet per day shall be granted without modification or delay.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-842</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
