<bill session="114" type="h" number="1990" updated="2018-06-02T03:22:27Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Our Great Lakes Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to prohibit certain discharges of dredged material into the Great Lakes System, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Protecting Our Great Lakes Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000566"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2015-04-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Our Great Lakes Act 

This bill amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to prohibit discharges of dredged material into the Great Lakes System, except for discharges: (1) into a confined disposal facility; or (2) in connection with a beneficial use or habitat establishment, improvement, and/or restoration. The prohibition becomes effective in five years.

The U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, or a state with an approved permit program, may waive application of the prohibition on a discharge during the first two years of the prohibition if: (1) the Environmental Protection Agency or the state determines that the waiver is necessary and appropriate, and (2) each concerned state approves of the waiver in the case of a waiver issued by the Corps of Engineers.

In determining the least costly manner, and the least costly and most practicable location, for discharges of dredged material resulting from Corps of Engineers operations and maintenance activities in the Great Lakes System, the Corps of Engineers must exclude from consideration the use of open-water placement of dredged material.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
