<bill session="114" type="h" number="3668" updated="2019-02-13T17:31:17Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">California Minerals, Off-Road Recreation, and Conservation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To codify in law and expand certain off-highway vehicle recreation areas in the State of California, to designate as wilderness certain public lands in the State of California administered by the Bureau of Land Management, to expand the Death Valley National Park Wilderness and the San Gorgonio Wilderness in San Bernardino National Forest, to ensure the conservation and necessary management of wildlife in these wilderness areas, to establish the Mojave Trails Special Management Area in the State, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">California Minerals, Off-Road Recreation, and Conservation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001094"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000030" joined="2015-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000387" joined="2015-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000129" joined="2015-10-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="414"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-01T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">California Minerals, Off-Road Recreation, and Conservation Act

Specified off-highway vehicle recreation areas are designated or expanded in San Bernardino County, California.

Certain wilderness areas in California are also designated or expanded, and specified study areas released from further study.

The boundaries of Death Valley National Park and Mojave National Preserve are revised.

 The California Desert Protection Act of 1994 is amended to revise the boundaries of Joshua Tree National Park and authorize a visitor center.

The Wild and Scenic Rivers Act is revised to designate certain wild, scenic, and recreational rivers in California.

There are established the Black Lava Butte and Flat Top Mesa Area of Critical Environmental Concern, the Mojave Trails Special Management Area, and the Sand to Snow National Monument

Federal reversionary interests in certain land in the Metropolitan Water District of Southern California are released.

Certain requirements of the California Desert Protection Act of 1994 for specified California state school land are revised.

Development of renewable energy generation facilities on Juniper Flats is prohibited.

Specified land exchanges are authorized in the San Gorgonio Wilderness and other specified areas.

Requirements are prescribed for conveyance of certain federal lands for the Apple Valley Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area and to the city of Twentynine Palms, California.

The Department of the Interior shall ensure that members of specified Indian tribes have access to designated areas for traditional cultural and religious purposes.

Interior may accept landowner-requested deed restrictions on land donated to or acquired by the United States or, consistent with existing rights, create deed restrictions, easements, or other third-party rights relating to any public land necessary to fulfill certain mitigation requirements or to satisfy the conditions of a habitat conservation plan or general conservation plan.

No extension or establishment of any national monument that would include any designated area may be undertaken by the President except by express authorization of Congress.

A project to install and operate a fiberoptic cable by Inyo County, California, along a certain route shall be eligible for a categorical exclusion from requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
