<bill session="115" type="s" number="2202" updated="2019-04-18T16:40:39Z">
  <state datetime="2017-12-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-12-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-12-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, to authorize appropriations for the National Transportation Safety Board, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">National Transportation Safety Board Reauthorization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">National Transportation Safety Board Reauthorization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Transportation Safety Board Reauthorization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Transportation Safety Board Reauthorization Act</title>
    <title type="display">National Transportation Safety Board Reauthorization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2017-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2017-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2017-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2017-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2017-12-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-12-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-12-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-07-10">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Thune with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 115-293.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-07-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="506">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 506.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-12-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Transportation Safety Board Reauthorization Act

This bill reauthorizes the National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) for FY2019-FY2023.

The NTSB may include any still image obtained from a video recorder for an accident, but must protect from public disclosure any information that readily identifies an individual, including a decedent.

The bill permits the NTSB to release confidential information to the public to protect health and safety and may share information with certain protections.

The NTSB must report to Congress explaining its methodology to prioritize and select recommendations included on the Most Wanted List. The Most Wanted List sets forth NTSB advocacy priorities. It is designed to increase awareness of, and support for, critical changes needed to reduce accidents and save lives.

The bill also requires the NTSB to: (1) expand requirements for providing services to families of accident victims; and (2) review, every five years, its previously issued safety recommendations.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-293</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
