<bill session="114" type="h" number="3829" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:22Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">UNRWA Anti-Incitement and Anti-Terrorism Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote transparency, accountability, and reform within the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">UNRWA Anti-Incitement and Anti-Terrorism Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000435"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001102" joined="2015-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2016-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2015-10-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7264"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli relations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">UNRWA Anti-Incitement and Anti-Terrorism Act 

This bill amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to withhold U.S. contributions to the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East (UNRWA) or to any successor or related entity, or to the regular budget of the United Nations (U.N.) for the support of UNRWA or a successor entity, unless the Department of State certifies to Congress that:

 no UNRWA official, employee, representative, or affiliate is a member of a foreign terrorist organization, has propagated anti-American, anti-Israel, or anti-Semitic rhetoric, or has used UNRWA resources to propagate political materials regarding the Israeli-Palestinian conflict; no UNRWA facility is used by a foreign terrorist organization; no UNRWA school uses educational materials that propagates anti-American, anti-Israel, or anti-Semitic rhetoric; no recipient of UNRWA funds or loans is a member of a foreign terrorist organization; UNRWA is subject to auditing oversight; and UNRWA holds no accounts or other affiliations with financial institutions deemed by the United States to be complicit in money laundering and terror financing. U.S. contributions to UNRWA are limited during the period for which a certification is in effect.

It is the sense of Congress that:

 the President and the Department should lead a diplomatic effort to encourage other nations to withhold contributions to UNRWA, or to the regular budget of the U.N. for the support of UNRWA, until UNRWA has met these conditions; citizens of recognized states should be removed from UNRWA's jurisdiction; UNRWA's definition of a "Palestine refugee" should be changed to that used for a refugee by the Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR); and responsibility for the Palestinian refugees should be fully transferred to UNHCR.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
