<bill session="114" type="h" number="476" updated="2018-06-02T02:08:03Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GI Bill Education Quality Enhancement Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to clarify the process of approving courses of education pursued using educational benefits administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">GI Bill Education Quality Enhancement Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000815"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3016"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-22T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">GI Bill Education Quality Enhancement Act of 2015

Deems specified education programs to be approved for veterans' education benefit purposes if a state approving agency determines that they qualify. Authorizes a state approving agency, or the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) acting in the role of a state approving agency, to approve other accredited programs for such purposes.

Continues to allow state approving agencies to establish additional criteria (other than those set forth in current law) for the approval of nonaccredited courses, but requires VA to determine that such criteria are necessary and treat public, private, and proprietary for-profit educational institutions equitably.

Prohibits VA from including flight training fees in the in-state tuition and fees at public institutions of higher education (IHEs) that are covered by post-9/11 veterans' educational assistance. Requires post-9/11 veterans' educational assistance for flight training programs at public IHEs to be determined in the same manner as such assistance for education programs pursued at non-public or foreign IHEs is determined.

Directs VA to conduct an annual compliance survey of educational institutions and training establishments offering courses approved for veterans' education benefits if at least 20 individuals who are eligible for such benefits are enrolled in any such course. (Currently, an annual compliance survey of each institution offering such courses must be conducted if at least 300 beneficiaries are enrolled or if any such course does not lead to a standard college degree.) Authorizes VA to waive the annual survey for institutions or establishments that have a record of compliance. Requires VA to conduct a biennial survey of each educational institution and training establishment that offers courses approved for veterans' education benefits.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
