<bill session="114" type="sr" number="284" updated="2018-06-02T06:18:17Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution recognizing the importance of mental health globally and highlighting the contributions and value of mental health, psychosocial support, and human capacity, particularly in development contexts and humanitarian settings.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution recognizing the importance of mental health globally and highlighting the contributions and value of mental health, psychosocial support, and human capacity, particularly in development contexts and humanitarian settings.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001169"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2015-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7278" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-08T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Recognizes the importance of World Mental Health Day.

Affirms the continued support of the United States for making resources available to provide mental health services and build capacity, particularly in countries affected by conflict and crisis.

Honors the importance of trained mental health workers as they enhance human well-being and mental health, restore functioning, and save lives through mental health and psychosocial support services.

Calls on relevant agencies to integrate mental health and psychosocial support services into programs, funding opportunities, and budget allocations in order to improve quality of life for individuals living with mental health disorders.

Commends the dedication of those who work to improve the mental health of all individuals, and the important contributions and bravery of individuals who live with or have overcome mental health disorders.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
