<bill session="114" type="h" number="2214" updated="2018-06-02T03:39:00Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disabled Veterans' Access to Medical Exams Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the authority of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to enter into contracts with private physicians to conduct medical disability examinations.</title>
    <title type="display">Disabled Veterans' Access to Medical Exams Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000374"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001245" joined="2015-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001255" joined="2015-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2015-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000581" joined="2015-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000603" joined="2015-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000813" joined="2015-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000799" joined="2015-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-09">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-01T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Disabled Veterans' Access to Medical Exams Improvement Act

Amends the Veterans Benefits Act of 2003 to extend until December 31, 2017, the authority of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to provide for persons other than VA employees (i.e., contract physicians) to conduct medical disability examinations of applicants for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.

Permits licensed, VA-contracted physicians to conduct such examinations at any location in any state, the District of Columbia, or a Commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, so long as the examination is authorized under the contract and the physician is not barred from conducting such an examination in the location in which it occurs.

Amends the Veterans' Benefits Improvement Act of 1996 to provide similar authorities with respect to permissible examination locations to licensed physicians under the pilot program authorizing the VA to use contract physicians to perform medical disability examinations of applicants for benefits under laws carried out through the Under Secretary for Benefits. Expands from 10 to 15 the maximum number of VA regional offices through which the Secretary is authorized to carry out such pilot program.

Directs the Secretary to conduct an annual data analysis (including an analysis of backlogged claims, pending workloads, and the timeliness of completed cases) to determine the regional offices requiring support.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
