<bill session="114" type="s" number="1286" updated="2018-06-02T06:53:11Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Appeals Assistance and Improvement Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to reduce the backlog of appeals of decisions of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs by facilitating pro bono legal assistance for veterans before the United States Court of Veterans Appeals and the Board of Veterans' Appeals, to provide the Secretary with authority to address unreasonably delayed claims, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Veterans Appeals Assistance and Improvement Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2015-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2015-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2016-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2015-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2015-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2015-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2015-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2015-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2015-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2015-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Veterans Appeals Assistance and Improvement Act of 2015

This bill directs the U.S. Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims to establish a financial assistance program to provide legal and other assistance without charge for veterans and other persons seeking Court review who are unable to afford legal representation costs. (Programs include case screening and referral, training for attorney and related personnel, and facilitation of pro bono representation by members of the bar and law school clinical and other programs.)

The Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) shall establish a financial assistance program to provide legal and other assistance without charge to veterans and other persons seeking review by the Board of Veterans' Appeals who are unable to afford legal representation costs.

The Court and the VA shall each carry out such programs through an interagency agreement with the Legal Services Corporation. The Corporation may receive a reimbursable payment from the Court or VA for providing such financial assistance. Funds may not be used for the payment of attorney's fees.

VA shall provide for the expeditious treatment by the Board of any claim that: (1) is remanded to VA by the Court, or (2) has been pending before the Board for eight years or more.

The Government Accountability Office shall review the processing of appeals of VA decisions regarding service-connected disability and dependency and indemnity compensation claims.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
