<bill session="113" type="h" number="611" updated="2016-10-25T15:58:51Z">
  <state datetime="2013-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lyme and Tick-Borne Diseases Prevention, Education, and Research Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the expansion of Federal efforts concerning the prevention, education, treatment, and research activities related to Lyme and other tick-borne diseases, including the establishment of a Tick-Borne Diseases Advisory Committee.</title>
    <title type="display">Lyme and Tick-Borne Diseases Prevention, Education, and Research Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000522"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001269" joined="2014-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001037" joined="2013-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2013-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000564" joined="2013-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001051" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000375" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000379" joined="2013-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000111" joined="2013-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001185" joined="2013-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001149" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000258" joined="2013-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000265" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2014-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000585" joined="2014-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001170" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000467" joined="2013-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000804" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000672" joined="2013-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="610"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="719"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-02-12T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Lyme and Tick-Borne Diseases Prevention, Education, and Research Act of 2013 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish the Tick-Borne Diseases Advisory Committee. Requires the Committee to advise the Secretary and the Assistant Secretary for Health regarding how officials can: (1) ensure interagency coordination and communication and minimize overlap regarding efforts to address tick-borne diseases, (2) identify opportunities to coordinate efforts with other federal agencies and private organizations addressing such diseases, (3) ensure interagency coordination and communication with constituency groups, (4) ensure that a broad spectrum of scientific viewpoints is represented in public health policy decisions and that information disseminated to the public and physicians is balanced, and (5) advise relevant federal agencies on priorities related to Lyme and tick-borne diseases.

Requires the Secretary, acting through the appropriate federal officials, to provide for the coordination of all federal programs and activities related to Lyme and other tick-borne diseases and the conduct or support of specified activities, including: (1) developing sensitive and accurate diagnostic tools and tests, (2) improving the efficient utilization of diagnostic testing currently available, (3) accurately determining the prevalence of such diseases, (4) evaluating the feasibility of creating a national uniform reporting system, (5) providing and promoting access to a clearinghouse of information on such diseases, (6) increasing public education related to such diseases, (7) creating a physician education program, (8) establishing epidemiological research objectives to determine the long term course of illness for Lyme disease, and (9) determining the effectiveness of different treatment modalities by establishing treatment outcome objectives.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
