<bill session="114" type="s" number="1623" updated="2018-08-16T22:54:07Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Maritime Washington National Heritage Area Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Maritime Washington National Heritage Area Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Maritime Washington National Heritage Area in the State of Washington, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Maritime Washington National Heritage Area Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2015-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-08-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski under authority of the order of the Senate of 07/14/2016 with amendments. With written report No. 114-310.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-08-30" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="582">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 582.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks" code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="2833"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-08-30T13:06:58Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Maritime Washington National Heritage Area Act

(Sec. 3) This bill establishes the Maritime Washington National Heritage Area in the state of Washington.

The Washington Trust for Historic Preservation shall be the local coordinating entity for the Heritage Area, and shall prepare and submit a management plan for it.

(Sec. 5) The Washington Trust for Historic Preservation shall not use federal funds made available under this bill for the acquisition of real property or any interests in real property.

(Sec. 7) The bill makes specific disclaimers relating to private property and federal, state, local, and tribal regulatory protections.

Nothing in this bill alters, modifies, diminishes, or extinguishes any Indian tribe's treaty rights within the Heritage Area.

(Sec. 9) The bill authorizes appropriations. The federal cost share of any activity carried out under this bill shall be 50% of its total cost.

The authority of the Department of the Interior to furnish assistance under this bill terminates 15 years after enactment.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-310</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
