<bill session="114" type="s" number="1915" updated="2018-06-05T07:11:15Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-14">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">First Responder Anthrax Preparedness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">First Responder Anthrax Preparedness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">First Responder Anthrax Preparedness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">First Responder Anthrax Preparedness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">First Responder Anthrax Preparedness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to make anthrax vaccines and antimicrobials available to emergency response providers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by senate">A bill to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to make anthrax vaccines available to emergency response providers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">First Responder Anthrax Preparedness Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000368"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2015-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2015-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2015-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2015-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2015-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2015-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2015-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2015-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2016-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000607" joined="2016-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2016-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2015-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2015-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2015-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2016-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2016-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2015-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2015-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2015-10-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-08-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-08-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-12-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-05-09">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 114-251.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-05-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="458">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 458.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-11-16">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6419-6421" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6419" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-16">
      <text>The committee substitute withdrawn by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6419" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2016-11-16" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6420-6421" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-11-17T11:36:01-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-17T14:06:11-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-17">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-29T19:10:44-05:00">
      <text>Mr. King (NY) asked unanimous consent to take from the Speaker's table and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-29T19:11:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6355" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="without objection" type="vote2" datetime="2016-11-29T19:11:03-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6355" label="text of measure as passed"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-11-29T19:11:05-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2016-12-02">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2016-12-14" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="114-268" type="public" datetime="2016-12-14">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 114-268.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1300"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3583"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6381"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s5109"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2016-12-15T04:59:58Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on November 16, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

First Responder Anthrax Preparedness Act

(Sec. 2) This bill requires the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), in coordination with the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), to carry out a pilot program to provide eligible anthrax vaccines nearing the end of their labeled dates of use from the strategic national stockpile to emergency response providers who would be at high risk of exposure to anthrax if an attack should occur and who voluntarily consent.

HHS shall determine whether an anthrax vaccine is eligible to be provided to DHS for the program based on determinations that: (1) the vaccine is not otherwise allotted for other purposes; and (2) the provision of the vaccine will not reduce or otherwise adversely affect the capability to meet projected requirements for such product during a public health emergency.

DHS shall establish a communication platform, develop and deliver education and training, conduct an economic analysis, create a logistical platform, establish goals and desired outcomes for the program, and establish a mechanism to reimburse HHS for the costs of shipment and transportation of such vaccines provided to DHS under such program and the amount by which the warehousing costs of the stockpile are increased in order to operate such program.

DHS must: (1) select between two and five states for voluntary participation in the program; (2) provide guidance to participating states and local governments on identifying providers who are at high risk of exposure; and (3) require each participating state to submit a written certification that each participating emergency response provider is provided with disclosures and educational materials regarding the associated benefits and risks of any vaccine provided and of exposure to anthrax, additional material consistent with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention's clinical guidance, and notice that the federal government is not obligated to continue providing anthrax vaccine after the program ends.

Each state that participates in the program shall ensure that such participation is consistent with the state's All-Hazards Public Health Emergency Preparedness and Response Plan.

DHS shall enter into a memorandum of understanding with HHS to: (1) define each department's roles and responsibilities, and (2) establish appropriate performance metrics and policies for the program.

DHS must submit annual reports on program progress and results, which shall include the costs to administer the program, the number and percentage of eligible providers that volunteer to participate, the degree to which participants complete the vaccine regimen, the total number of doses of vaccine administered, and recommendations to improve participation.

 The final report shall consider whether the program should continue beyond five years after enactment of this bill and shall include: (1) an analysis of the costs and benefits of continuing the program; (2) an explanation of the economic, health, and other risks and benefits of administering vaccines through the program rather than post-event treatment; and (3) a plan under which the program could be continued.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-251</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
