<bill session="114" type="h" number="6118" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:40Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Financial Services Innovation Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote innovation in financial services, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Financial Services Innovation Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001156"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-10-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commodity Exchanges, Energy, and Credit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Commodity Exchanges, Energy, and Credit" code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Financial Services Innovation Act of 2016

This bill requires specified federal departments and agencies (agencies) to periodically publish in the Federal Register a nonexclusive list identifying three or more areas of existing regulation:

 that apply or may apply to a financial innovation offered or intended to be offered by a covered person, and that the agency would consider modifying or waiving if it were to receive a petition from the covered person in accordance with this bill relating to that regulation. The bill defines "a covered person" as a person that offers or intends to offer a financial innovation by submitting a petition to a Financial Services Innovation Office (FSIO) at one or more agencies.

Each agency shall establish its own FSIO to:

 promote financial innovations, and assist covered persons whose petitions have been approved pursuant to this bill. Each agency, through its FSIO, shall:

 support the development of financial innovations; coordinate with FSIOs at other agencies to share information and data; and establish procedures to reduce the time and cost of offering a financial innovation to the public and enable greater access to financial innovations. The agencies shall create a FSIO Liaison Committee which shall consult on the administration, coordination, and oversight of each agency's FSIO.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
