<bill session="114" type="hj" number="80" updated="2019-05-09T23:15:21Z">
  <state datetime="2016-01-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-01-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-01-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to prohibit gerrymandering in the establishment of Congressional districts.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Districts Amendment</title>
    <title type="display">Fair Districts Amendment</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000556"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-01-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts and representation"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-01-11T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Constitutional Amendment

Fair Districts Amendment

This joint resolution proposes a constitutional amendment requiring a state, in establishing districts for the election of Representatives in Congress, to ensure that:

 no plan for the apportionment of Representatives among individual districts, or any individual district established under such plan, is drawn with the intent to favor or disfavor a political party or an incumbent; districts shall not be drawn with the intent or result of denying or abridging the equal opportunity of racial or language minorities to participate in the political process or to diminish their ability to elect Representatives of their choice; and districts shall consist of contiguous territory. Districts shall be as nearly equal in population as is practicable, shall be compact, and shall utilize existing political and geographical boundaries where feasible, unless compliance with such a requirement conflicts with the previous requirements of this joint resolution.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
