<bill session="113" type="h" number="1605" updated="2016-10-25T16:02:19Z">
  <state datetime="2013-04-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Safety and Second Amendment Rights Protection Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">National Commission on Mass Violence Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect Second Amendment rights, ensure that all individuals who should be prohibited from buying a firearm are listed in the National Instant Criminal Background Check System, and provide a responsible and consistent background check process.</title>
    <title type="display">Public Safety and Second Amendment Rights Protection Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000557"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001069" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000216" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000293" joined="2013-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001047" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000062" joined="2013-04-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Veterans' Affairs, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-17">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-17">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1565"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="3335"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-04-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Public Safety and Second Amendment Rights Protection Act of 2013 - Amends the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act to reauthorize for FY2014-FY2017 the grant program for improvements to the criminal history record system.

Amends the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007 (NICS Act) to: (1) establish a four-year implementation plan to ensure maximum coordination and automation of reporting of records or making records available to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System; (2) direct the Attorney General to make grants to states, Indian tribal governments, and state court systems to improve the automation and transmittal of mental health records and criminal history dispositions; (3) provide for reductions in grant funding to states that have not implemented a relief from disabilities programs; (4) make federal court information available for inclusion in the System; and (5) allow the submission to the System of mental health records that would otherwise be protected by the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA).

Provides that nothing in this Act shall be construed to: (1) expand the enforcement authority or jurisdiction of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives (ATF); (2) allow the establishment, directly or indirectly, of a federal firearms registry; or (3) extend background check requirements to transfers of firearms other than those made at gun shows or over the Internet, or to temporary transfers for purposes including lawful hunting or sporting, or to temporary possession of a firearm for purposes of examination or evaluation by a prospective transferee.

National Commission on Mass Violence Act of 2013 - Establishes the National Commission on Mass Violence to study the availability and nature of firearms, including the means of acquiring firearms, issues relating to mental health, and the impacts of the availability and nature of firearms on incidents of mass violence or in preventing mass violence. Requires the Commission to conduct a comprehensive factual study of incidents of mass violence, including incidents not involving firearms, to determine the root causes of such mass violence.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
