<amendment session="115" chamber="s" number="4098" updated="2019-06-13T20:53:23Z">
  <amends type="sj" number="54" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2018-12-13">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001095"/>
  <offered datetime="2018-12-12"/>
  <description>To clarify that the requirement to remove United States Armed Forces does not apply to forces engaged in operations to support efforts to disrupt Houthi attacks against locations outside of Yemen, such as ballistic missile attacks, unmanned aerial vehicle attacks, maritime attacks against United States or international vessels, or terrorist attacks against civilian targets.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2018-12-13" how="roll" result="fail" roll="265">
      <text>Amendment SA 4098 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 45 - 54. Record Vote Number: 265.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-12-13">
      <text>Amendment SA 4098 proposed by Senator Cotton. (consideration: CR S7563-7654 text: CR S7654) To clarify that the requirement to remove United States Armed Forces does not apply to forces engaged in operations to support efforts to disrupt Houthi attacks against locations outside of Yemen, such as ballistic missile attacks, unmanned aerial vehicle attacks, maritime attacks against United States or international vessels, or terrorist attacks against civilian targets.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-12"/>
    <action datetime="2018-12-13">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 4098 proposed by Senator Cotton.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7563-7654" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7654" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-13">
      <text>Senate amendment not agreed to: Amendment SA 4098 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 45 - 54. Record Vote Number: 265.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-13">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 4098 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 45 - 54. Record Vote Number: 265.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-12">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
