<bill session="114" type="h" number="1875" updated="2018-06-02T03:21:15Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Filipino Veterans Recognition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To extend the Filipino Veterans Equity Compensation Fund and to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to accept certain documents as proof of service in determining the eligibility of a person to receive amounts from such Fund.</title>
    <title type="display">Filipino Veterans Recognition Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000369" joined="2015-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001245" joined="2015-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000030" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000571" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000581" joined="2015-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2015-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001193" joined="2015-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000130" joined="2015-04-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Philippines"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Filipino Veterans Recognition Act

This bill amends the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 to authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to make a payment from the Filipino Veterans Equity Compensation Fund to an eligible person who, during the one-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this paragraph, submits to the Secretary:

 a benefits claim; or with respect to a person who filed a benefits claim during such one-year period, a new claim or an appeal to such previously filed claim. In determining an individual's eligibility to receive Compensation Fund benefits the Secretary shall accept as proof of service an affidavit from the government of the Philippines certifying an eligible individual's service (AGO Form 23).

 Such an affidavit shall serve as proof of service regardless of whether the eligible individual:

 submits any other qualifying document, or is included in the Approved Revised Reconstructed Guerilla Roster of 1948, (Missouri List). The Secretary may not accept such an affidavit as proof of service for any VA benefit other than the Compensation Fund.

Nothing in this Act shall be construed as authorizing additional amounts to be appropriated to the Compensation Fund.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
