<bill session="114" type="h" number="6449" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:34Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clean Money Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to provide political advertising vouchers and payments to defray the costs of postage for candidates in general elections to the Senate or House of Representatives who agree to restrictions on the types of contributions such candidates raise and the types of expenditures such candidates make, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Clean Money Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001296"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-12-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="20"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Clean Money Act of 2016

This bill amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) to entitle a candidate in a congressional general election who is certified as a participating candidate under FECA to political advertising vouchers disbursed by the Federal Election Commission (FEC) as well as funds to defray the costs of postage.

Participating candidates shall return to the FEC any political advertising vouchers provided to the authorized committees of the candidate which remain unused.

The Clean Money Fund is established in the Treasury to be available to redeem vouchers that are accepted by broadcasting stations as payment for the purchase of broadcasting time for political advertisements.

The bill imposes civil penalties for violation of contribution and expenditure requirements and requires repayment for improper use of payments made to defray costs of postage.

The bill amends the FECA with respect to: (1) contributions and expenditures by multicandidate and political party political committees on behalf of participating candidates, and (2) restrictions on permitted uses of funds by candidates receiving small dollar financing.

This bill amends the Communications Act of 1934 to set a station's lowest unit price for preemptible use as the charge for a broadcast by the national committee of a political party for an affiliated candidate.

The FEC is authorized to revoke a broadcast station license or construction permit only for at least three willful failures to allow reasonable access to, or to permit purchase of reasonable amounts of time for the use of, a broadcasting station or cable system by a legally qualified candidate for federal office.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
