<bill session="115" type="s" number="2644" updated="2019-04-18T16:42:33Z">
  <state datetime="2018-04-26">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure independent investigations and judicial review of the removal of a special counsel, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Special Counsel Independence and Integrity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Special Counsel Independence and Integrity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Special Counsel Independence and Integrity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Special Counsel Independence and Integrity Act</title>
    <title type="display">Special Counsel Independence and Integrity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000359"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2018-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2018-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2018-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-04-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-04-26" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Grassley with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-04-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="393">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 393.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="5505"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="5476"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-04-26T18:10:49Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Special Counsel Independence and Integrity Act

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the federal judicial code to codify certain Department of Justice (DOJ) regulations that govern the appointment, oversight, and removal of a special counsel, including regulations:

 that authorize the Attorney General to appoint and select a special counsel; that establish the qualifications, scope of jurisdiction, and authority of a special counsel; and that authorize the Attorney General to remove a special counsel for misconduct or other good cause. Additionally, the bill provides new statutory limitations and requirements with respect to the removal from office of a special counsel. Specifically, the bill:

 requires removal to be by the Attorney General or, in certain circumstances, the most senior Senate-confirmed DOJ official; requires a special counsel to be provided written notice that specifies the reason for removal; and allows a special counsel to challenge the removal in federal court. The limitations and requirements with respect to removal apply retroactively in the case of a special counsel who is appointed after January 1, 2017, and removed before the date of enactment.

Finally, the bill requires DOJ to notify Congress when a special counsel is appointed, before a special counsel is removed, and after a special counsel's investigation concludes.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
