<bill session="115" type="s" number="939" updated="2019-04-18T16:35:19Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reserve any amounts forfeited to the United States Government as a result of the criminal prosecution of Joaquin Archivaldo Guzman Loera (commonly known as "El Chapo"), or of other felony convictions involving the transportation of controlled substances into the United States, for security measures along the Southern border, including the completion of a border wall.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">EL CHAPO Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">EL CHAPO Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Lawful Collection of Hidden Assets to Provide Order Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Lawful Collection of Hidden Assets to Provide Order Act</title>
    <title type="display">EL CHAPO Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2017-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="2186"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Ensuring Lawful Collection of Hidden Assets to Provide Order Act or the EL CHAPO Act

This bill requires the forfeited profits of Joaquin Archivaldo Guzman Loera (El Chapo) from his illicit drug trafficking enterprise to be reserved for border security measures between the United States and Mexico, including the completion of a wall.

Additionally, it requires the forfeited funds from the felony conviction of a member of a drug cartel to be reserved for border security measures between the United States and Mexico, including the completion of a wall.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
