<bill session="115" type="s" number="3513" updated="2019-04-18T16:45:54Z">
  <state datetime="2018-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a deadline for the establishment of a process to allow applicants to petition the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to prohibit or restrict the operation of an unmanned aircraft in close proximity to a fixed site facility.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">UAS Critical Infrastructure Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">UAS Critical Infrastructure Protection Act</title>
    <title type="display">UAS Critical Infrastructure Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001113"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2018-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-09-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3511"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-09-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">UAS Critical Infrastructure Protection Act

This bill amends the FAA Extension, Safety, and Security Act of 2016 to include railroad facilities among the critical infrastructure to be considered fixed site facilities for purposes of prohibiting or restricting the operation of an unmanned aircraft (i.e., a drone) in close proximity to such facilities. Other fixed site facilities may include military installations, oil refineries and chemical facilities, or amusement parks.

The Federal Aviation Administration must publish a notice of proposed rulemaking by March 31, 2019, for carrying out the the process for prohibiting or restricting the operation of drones near fixed site facilities, and then issue a final rule within 12 months after publishing the notice of proposed rulemaking.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
