<bill session="114" type="s" number="2707" updated="2018-08-16T23:11:03Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Workplace Advancement and Opportunity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Labor to nullify the proposed rule regarding defining and delimiting the exemptions for executive, administrative, professional, outside sales, and computer employees, to require the Secretary of Labor to conduct a full and complete economic analysis with improved economic data on small businesses, nonprofit employers, Medicare or Medicaid dependent health care providers, and small governmental jurisdictions, and all other employers, and minimize the impact on such employers, before promulgating any substantially similar rule, and to provide a rule of construction regarding the salary threshold exemption under the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Protecting Workplace Advancement and Opportunity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000360" joined="2016-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2016-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2016-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2016-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2016-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2016-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2016-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000542" joined="2016-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2016-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2016-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001071" joined="2016-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2016-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2016-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2016-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2016-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2016-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2016-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2016-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000444" joined="2016-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2016-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2016-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2016-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2016-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2016-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2016-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2016-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2016-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2016-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2016-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2016-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000355" joined="2016-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2016-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2016-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000603" joined="2016-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2016-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2016-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2016-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2016-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2016-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001141" joined="2016-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000320" joined="2016-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2016-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2016-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000127" joined="2016-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2016-04-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 114-676.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Hearings"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="4773"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting Workplace Advancement and Opportunity Act

This bill declares that the proposed or the final rule of the Department of Labor entitled "Defining and Delimiting the Exemptions for Executive, Administrative, Professional, Outside Sales and Computer Employees" shall cease to have any force or effect. The rule revises the "white collar" exemption of executive, administrative, professional, outside sales, and computer employees from minimum wage and maximum hour, or overtime, requirements of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (FLSA).

If the proposed rule is a final rule on the date of enactment of this bill:

 Labor shall not enforce it based on conduct occurring before that enactment date, an employee shall not have any right of action against an employer for the employer's failure to comply with the final rule at any time before that enactment date, any regulations that were amended by the final rule shall be restored and revived as if the final rule had never taken effect, and nothing in this bill shall be construed to create a right of action for an employer against an employee for the recoupment of any payments made to the employee before the enactment of this bill that were in compliance with that final rule. Labor may promulgate any substantially similar rule only if it has completed certain required actions; but the rule shall not contain any automatic updates to the salary threshold for purposes of exemptions to minimum wage and maximum hour requirements under the FLSA.

The requirement that definitions applicable for such exemptions be defined and delimited from time to time by Labor regulations shall be construed to:

 require Labor to issue a new rule through notice and comment rulemaking for each change in any salary threshold it has proposed; and exclude any rule that would result in changes to any salary threshold for multiple time periods, including through any automatic updating procedure. Labor may not promulgate any final rule that includes any revision to duties tests for exemption from minimum wage and maximum hours requirements unless specific regulatory text for the provision was proposed in the proposed rule.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
