<bill session="114" type="sr" number="620" updated="2018-06-02T06:22:20Z">
  <state datetime="2016-11-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-11-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-11-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution reaffirming the United States-Argentina partnership and recognizing Argentina's economic reforms.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution reaffirming the United States-Argentina partnership and recognizing Argentina's economic reforms.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2016-11-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-11-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6552" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-11-29T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Declares that the Senate:

 upholds its commitment to the partnership between the United States and Argentina and reaffirms that Argentina is a major U.S. ally; encourages the Department of State to coordinate an interagency strategy to increase cooperation with the government of Argentina on areas of bilateral, regional, and global concern; commends President Mauricio Macri and his Administration for making far-reaching economic reforms that will benefit the people of Argentina, stimulate economic growth, and deepen Argentina's integration with the global economy; praises such government for resolving its dispute with international creditors; and encourages such government to continue to investigate and prosecute those responsible for the 1994 bombing of the Argentine-Israeli Mutual Association (AMIA) in Buenos Aires and the death of AMIA special prosecutor Alberto Nisman.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
