<bill session="114" type="h" number="3731" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:21Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RaD Fund Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rare Disease Fund Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a Rare Disease Therapeutics Corporation to encourage the development of high-risk, high-return therapies for rare diseases, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">RaD Fund Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000130"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000583" joined="2015-10-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-09T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Rare Disease Fund Act or the RaD Fund Act

This bill requires the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to organize the Rare Disease Therapeutics Corporation to purchase rights to, fund the development of, and sell ownership interests in drugs, biological products, and medical devices for rare diseases.

The NIH must sell stock in the corporation to investors as soon as practicable. The corporation and the NIH may enter into an agreement under which the NIH maintains an ownership interest in the corporation in exchange for providing the corporation with intellectual property or other assistance. The corporation is prohibited from paying dividends on its stock.

The corporation must sell its interest in a rare disease therapy prior to the therapy entering large-scale clinical trials.

The corporation must issue bonds guaranteed by the United States and may issue bonds backed by the corporation. For purposes of securities laws, the securities of the corporation are not issued or guaranteed by the federal government.

The bill establishes within the NIH the Rare Disease Therapeutics Corporation Science Advisory Council to advise the corporation on the purchase, sale, and development of rare disease therapies.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
