<bill session="113" type="h" number="1839" updated="2018-06-05T16:17:10Z">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hermosa Creek Watershed Protection Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Hermosa Creek Watershed Protection Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To designate certain Federal land in the San Juan National Forest in the State of Colorado as wilderness, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Hermosa Creek Watershed Protection Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000470"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001077" joined="2014-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-06">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-09-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 22 - 18.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-22">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-693.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-22" calendar="Union" number="524">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 524.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="841"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-12-22T13:29:12Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">Hermosa Creek Watershed Protection Act of 2014 - (Sec. 4) Permits specified federal lands in San Juan National Forest in Colorado to be called the Hermosa Creek Watershed and Protection Area.

(Sec. 5) Designates certain federal lands in a proposed watershed protection area in San Juan National Forest to be administered by the Department of Agriculture (USDA) as the Hermosa Creek Special Management Area.

Authorizes in the Special Management Area, subject to conditions, specified&#160;activities including: (1) the use of motorized vehicles and snowmobiles, and (2) grazing and other traditional economic activities. Prohibits an area identified as East Hermosa Area from having unauthorized new road construction, renovations of existing nonsystem roads, or commercial timber harvests.

Requires any land interests acquired by the United States within the Special Management Area to occur only through donation or exchange with written consent of the property owner.

Declares that nothing in this Act affects: (1) Colorado's fish and wildlife jurisdiction, or (2) management of water storage reservoirs.

Withdraws federal land within the Special Management Area from: (1) entry, appropriation, or disposal under public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under mining laws; and (3) disposition under mineral leasing, geothermal leasing, or mineral materials laws.

Sets forth authority for the management of ski area permits, vegetation, wildfires, hazardous fuels, insects, and diseases in the Special Management Area.

Requires USDA, within three years after enactment of this Act, to develop a management plan for the long-term protection and management of the Special Management Area.

(Sec. 6) Prohibits designation of the Special Management Area from affecting water rights decreed under existing Colorado laws.

(Sec. 7) Designates certain San Juan National Forest land as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System to be known as Hermosa Creek Wilderness.

(Sec. 8) Withdraws federal land and mineral interests depicted on a map entitled "Perins Peak &amp; Animas City Mountain, Horse Gulch and Lake Nighthorse Mineral Withdrawal" from certain acts under public land, mining, mineral, and geothermal laws. Permits USDA to convey that land to the city of Durango, the county of La Plata, or the state of Colorado pursuant to the Recreation and Public Purposes Act or by a legal exchange.

(Sec. 9) Directs the Department of the Interior, upon the expiration of a specified permit and upon the request and agreement of La Plata, to convey to La Plata identified land managed by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) in the Tres Rios District in Colorado.

Directs Interior to require La Plata&#160;to pay administrative costs associated with such conveyance.

(Sec. 10) Designates certain San Juan County land as the Molas Pass Recreation Area. Authorizes snowmobiles in the area under specified conditions and requires USDA to authorize mountain biking and other recreational uses.

Designates as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System certain San Juan National Forest land depicted as "Weminuche Wilderness Addition" on a map entitled "West Needles Contiguous Wilderness Study Area." Transfers administrative jurisdiction of that land from the BLM to the Forest Service.

(Sec. 11) Declares that nothing in this Act restricts low-level overflights of military aircraft, flight testing and evaluation, special use airspace, or military flight training routes over wilderness areas.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 113-693</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
