<bill session="114" type="s" number="1480" updated="2019-04-11T15:42:24Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide limits on bundling, to reform the lobbying registration process, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lobbying and Campaign Finance Reform Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Lobbying and Campaign Finance Reform Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001267"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-02T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Lobbying and Campaign Finance Reform Act of 2015 

 Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) to declare that, for purposes of dollar limits on contributions, any bundled contribution forwarded by a currently registered lobbyist or a political committee established or controlled by one to an authorized committee of a candidate, a leadership political action committee, or a political party committee shall be treated as both a contribution made by the person forwarding it and as a contribution made by the contributor.

Amends the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 to revise the definition of "lobbyist" with respect to its exemption from coverage of certain individuals whose lobbying activities constitute less than 20% of the time engaged in the services provided to a client over a 3-month period. Extends the 3-month period into a 2-year period.

Amends FECA to prohibit House of Representatives and Senate candidates, Members, Senators, their agents, or any entities directly or indirectly established, financed, maintained, or controlled by or acting on behalf of one or more of them from soliciting funds from any registered lobbyist in connection with an election to the House or Senate during any period in which the chamber is in session (excluding adjournments or recesses for 10 calendar days or longer).</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
