<bill session="114" type="h" number="2203" updated="2019-02-14T23:34:22Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To remove the Kosovo Liberation Army from treatment as a terrorist organization, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To remove the Kosovo Liberation Army from treatment as a terrorist organization, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000179"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000055" joined="2015-05-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Citizenship" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Kosovo"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-01T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Declares that the Kosovo Liberation Army shall not be considered a terrorist organization under the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA), unless the Secretary of State decides otherwise in the Secretary's sole and unreviewable discretion.

 Amends INA to make terrorist activity-related inadmissibility criteria inapplicable to an alien's activities undertaken in association with the Kosovo Liberation Army if the alien:

 is applying for a nonimmigrant visa, unless a consular officer knows or has reasonable grounds to believe that the alien poses a threat to U.S. security, or believes that the visa should not be issued; or presents himself or herself for inspection and admission as a nonimmigrant to an immigration officer at a port of entry or is applying in the United States for nonimmigrant status, unless the Secretary of Homeland Security knows, or has reasonable grounds to believe, that the alien poses a threat to U.S. security, or otherwise believes that the alien should not be admitted to the United States or granted nonimmigrant status. Authorizes the Secretary of State to suspend such prohibition on a case-by-case basis.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
