<bill session="114" type="s" number="2684" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:38Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">UAVs for Energy Infrastructure Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the operation of unmanned aircraft systems by owners and operators of critical infrastructure.</title>
    <title type="display">UAVs for Energy Infrastructure Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000024"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">UAVs for Energy Infrastructure Act

This bill amends the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 to direct the Department of Transportation to establish a process by which a covered person may operate an unmanned aircraft system to conduct the following activities beyond the visual line of sight of the individual operating the system without any restriction on the time of the operation:

 activities for which compliance with current law can be accomplished by the use of manned aircraft, including activities to ensure compliance with federal or state regulatory, permit, or other requirements (including surveys for permits for construction or maintenance of pipelines) and activities relating to ensuring compliance with federal requirements for the transportation of natural gas, other gas, or hazardous substances by pipeline; activities to inspect, repair, or respond to critical infrastructure, including to respond to a pipeline incident, natural or man-made disaster, severe weather event, or other incident beyond the control of such person that may cause material damage to such infrastructure; and other activities if the covered person notifies the local Flight Standards District Office before the operation of the unmanned aircraft system. A "covered person" is a person who owns or operates a pipeline or other critical infrastructure, is an agent of such person, or is the sponsor of a pipeline project.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
