<bill session="114" type="h" number="4546" updated="2018-11-09T00:09:26Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safeguarding Social Security Numbers Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Commissioner of Social Security to issue uniform standards for the method for truncation of Social Security account numbers in order to protect such numbers from being used in the perpetration of fraud or identity theft and to provide for a prohibition on the display to the general public on the Internet of Social Security account numbers by State and local governments and private entities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Safeguarding Social Security Numbers Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000593"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001066" joined="2016-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001175" joined="2016-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Social Security" code="HSWM01" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Social Security Administration"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-11T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Safeguarding Social Security Numbers Act of 2016

 This bill requires the Social Security Administration to issue uniform standards for the method for: (1) truncation of Social Security account numbers in order to facilitate their protection from use in fraud or identity theft, and (2) encryption of (or another method of securing) those numbers transmitted by means of the Internet.

Such standards shall apply to the federal government whenever it: (1) displays a Social Security account number; and (2) transfers, records, or otherwise utilizes such a number.

No state, local government, or any officer, employee, or contractor of one may display to the general public on the Internet all or any portion of any Social Security account number, except in compliance with such truncation and encryption standards or if the number belongs to a deceased individual. The bill prescribes a civil monetary penalty of up to $5,000 per day for violation of this prohibition.

The Department of Justice shall award grants to state and local governments to carry out activities to remove, redact, or truncate, in accordance with the uniform standards, all Social Security account numbers on forms and records of their executive, legislative, and judicial agencies that would be displayed to the general public on the Internet in violation of this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
