<bill session="115" type="s" number="2085" updated="2019-04-18T16:40:09Z">
  <state datetime="2017-11-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-11-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-11-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Agriculture and Consumer Protection Act of 1973 to streamline application processes and reduce the administrative burden for the commodity supplemental food program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nourishing Our Golden Years Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nourishing Our Golden Years Act</title>
    <title type="display">Nourishing Our Golden Years Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2017-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000607" joined="2018-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2018-03-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-11-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-11-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Nourishing Our Golden Years Act 

This bill amends the Agriculture and Consumer Protection Act of 1973 to establish a minimum certification period of one year for the Commodity Supplemental Food Program (CSFP). During the certification period, a participant in the program may continue to receive benefits without a formal review of eligibility.

(The CSFP provides supplemental food to low-income elderly persons who are at least 60 years of age. Certification periods currently vary by state.)

Upon the request of a state, the Department of Agriculture must approve a state certification period of more than year, if, on an annual basis, the local agency administering the program: (1) verifies the address and continued interest of each participant in receiving benefits; and (2) has sufficient reason to determine that the participant still meets the income eligibility standards, which may include a determination that the participant has a fixed income.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
