<bill session="114" type="h" number="4297" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:28Z">
  <state datetime="2015-12-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To impose certain requirements on the Secretary of the Treasury relating to transmittals of country-by-country reports for purposes of the Base Erosion and Profit Shifting Action Plan.</title>
    <title type="display">To impose certain requirements on the Secretary of the Treasury relating to transmittals of country-by-country reports for purposes of the Base Erosion and Profit Shifting Action Plan.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001255"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets and economic espionage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-12-18T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill expressly prohibits the Department of the Treasury from collecting from a U.S. person or transmitting to any foreign jurisdiction any country-by-country report (CbCR) information of any U.S. person for taxable years beginning before January 1, 2017. CbCR information is used by the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development to develop its Base Erosion and Profit Shifting (BEPS) Action Plan to increase the transparency of transfer pricing practices and other tax transactions of multinational business enterprises.

Treasury must: (1) suspend the transmittal of CbCR information of any U.S. person to a foreign jurisdiction if it determines that such jurisdiction is abusing BEPS master file documentation requirements or failing to safeguard the confidentiality of information required in the master file, and (2) report to the congressional tax committees on allegations or reports received concerning the abuse of master file documentation requirements and any actions taken with respect to such allegations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
