<bill session="114" type="s" number="2200" updated="2018-06-02T07:11:14Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-26">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-10-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Workplace Advancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to strengthen equal pay requirements.</title>
    <title type="display">Workplace Advancement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000463"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2015-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2016-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2016-01-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2015-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2016-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2015-12-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2015-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2015-12-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-22">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-10-26" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="278">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 278.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="875"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5237"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Workplace Advancement Act

This bill amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to prohibit discharging or retaliating against any employee because such employee has inquired about, discussed, or disclosed comparative compensation information for the purpose of determining whether the employer is compensating an employee in a manner that provides equal pay for equal work.

The prohibition does not apply to instances in which an employee who has access to the wage information of other employees as a part of the employee's job functions discloses such wages to an individual who has no access to them, except in response to a charge or complaint or in furtherance of an investigation, proceeding, hearing, or action with respect to prohibited sex discrimination, including an investigation conducted by the employer.

It is the sense of Congress that: (1) gender-based discrimination in wages or compensation violates existing law, and (2) Congress recommits itself to the principles of equal pay for equal work.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
