<bill session="114" type="s" number="636" updated="2018-06-02T06:40:28Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Increasing the Safety of Prescription Drug Use Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Recovery Enhancement for Addiction Treatment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">TREAT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reduce prescription drug misuse and abuse.</title>
    <title type="display">Increasing the Safety of Prescription Drug Use Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000039"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2015-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="480"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1455"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Increasing the Safety of Prescription Drug Use Act of 2015

This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to revise, update, and expand state controlled substance monitoring programs, which ensure that prescription history information is accessible for investigations into drug diversion and errant prescribing and dispensing practices.

A state's controlled substance monitoring program database must be interoperable with other states' databases and electronic health records, and must provide up-to-date patient information to practitioners. Practitioners and dispensers are required to use the database.

Database information cannot be used to conduct a criminal investigation against a patient. Certain entities are allowed to make nonidentifiable information from a database available for research.

Federal health care workers must screen patients for abuse of controlled substances, conduct brief interventions, and provide referrals for known or suspected abuse of controlled substances.

Grants are established for: (1) a pilot project to develop a peer review process to evaluate prescribing and pharmacy dispensing patterns, (2) training health care providers to prevent controlled substance abuse, (3) evaluating the prospect of health professions boards reviewing the prescribing authorities of providers, and (4) developing criteria and processes that allow health professions boards or state agencies to certify education and training for informed and safe prescribing of certain controlled substances.

Practitioners who register or renew a registration with the Drug Enforcement Administration to dispense or conduct research with controlled substances must have completed specified continuing medical education. A registered practitioner must screen patients for drug abuse before prescribing certain controlled substances.

The Food and Drug Administration must consider whether naloxone (a drug used to rapidly reverse overdoses of heroin and other opiods) should be a behind-the-counter drug instead of a prescription drug.

This bill amends the Controlled Substances Act to increase the number of patients a practitioner is allowed to treat by dispensing narcotic drugs for maintenance or detoxification.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
