<bill session="114" type="h" number="4022" updated="2019-01-09T21:10:03Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Labor Relations Board Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Labor Relations Act to reform the National Labor Relations Board, the Office of the General Counsel, and the process for appellate review, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">National Labor Relations Board Reform Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000795"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000372" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001048" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000533" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000445" joined="2015-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000448" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000552" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000566" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001071" joined="2015-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001072" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000168" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000587" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000051" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000796" joined="2015-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1629"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" code="HSED02" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="288"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="National Labor Relations Board (NLRB)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-16T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">National Labor Relations Board Reform Act

Amends the National Labor Relations Act to revise requirements with respect to the National Labor Relations Board (NLRB), the Office of the General Counsel (OGC), and the process for appellate review.

Increases NLRB membership from five to six. Requires three members to represent each of the two major political parties and, beginning January 1, 2020, each of the two members whose terms expire on the same date to represent a different major political party.

Requires: (1) four NLRB members to constitute a quorum at all times, and (2) any NLRB determination to be approved by a majority of the members present.

Specifies tenure, including staggered terms, of NLRB members.

Sets forth judicial review procedures for any person subject to a complaint issued or authorized by the OGC.

Sets the compensation rate for each NLRB member, in addition to the OGC, at level IV of the Executive Schedule and the Chairman of the NLRB, as under current law, at level III.

Requires the NLRB to issue a final order reviewing an appeal of a report of an administrative law judge or decision of a regional director within one year after the report or decision; but if the NLRB does not issue a final order within that time, allows any party to the case to move to discharge it. Deems, upon such a motion, the report or the decision to be a final agency action. Prohibits the NLRB from taking further action on the matter.

Reduces authorized appropriations to carry out the Act for each of the succeeding two fiscal years to 80% of the average amount authorized for the prior two fiscal years if, two years after enactment of this Act, the NLRB has failed to issue a final order on more than 90% of the cases pending on (or filed on or after) the date of enactment.

Extends such reduced authorization of appropriations if after four years the NLRB has failed to issue a final order on more than 90% of the cases pending on (or filed on or after) the date that is two years after the date of enactment of this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
