<bill session="113" type="s" number="1148" updated="2016-10-25T16:25:13Z">
  <state datetime="2013-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Benefits Claims Faster Filing Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide notice of average times for processing claims, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Veterans Benefits Claims Faster Filing Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001046"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2013-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000590" joined="2013-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 113-280.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1809"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-06-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Veterans Benefits Claims Faster Filing Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to post in a conspicuous place in each VA regional office and claims intake facility and on the VA website information on: (1) the average processing time for fully developed and not fully developed VA benefits claims submitted in specified forms, and (2) the percentage of such claims filed by specified methods for which benefits are awarded.

Requires the Secretary to notify each person submitting a claim for a VA benefit of such information and of the person's eligibility to receive up to an extra year of benefit payments if the person files a claim that is fully developed.

Requires the notice information to be updated at least quarterly.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
