<bill session="114" type="s" number="3180" updated="2018-06-02T07:47:15Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Flexible HIRE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Flexible Hiring and Improving Recruitment, Retention, and Education Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve hiring and human resources flexibilities for Federal agencies in geographic areas affected by unique situations or circumstances, including remoteness, that cause recruitment and retention challenges, and to provide agencies experiencing such challenges with a toolkit of resources to overcome those challenges.</title>
    <title type="display">Flexible HIRE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001069"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Flexible Hiring and Improving Recruitment, Retention, and Education Act of 2016 or the Flexible HIRE Act

This bill allows the President to authorize agencies to appoint candidates directly to positions that the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) has determined are in geographic areas affected by a unique situation or circumstance that has directly and significantly affected employee recruitment and retention.

In areas within the continental United States in which recruitment and retention have become a severe challenge as the direct result of a dramatic economic development, hardship, or remoteness, the President may permit agencies to appoint candidates without using the statutory preference eligible veteran procedures that would otherwise require such agencies to provide experience credits, award examination points, or restrict competition to certain veterans and families of disabled or deceased veterans. Agencies must still prioritize the hiring of veterans by following regulatory principles regarding the appointment of qualified veterans to competitive service positions.

For positions in such areas, the OPM may establish higher minimum rates of pay and authorize agencies to pay bonuses for recruitment, relocation, or retention.

The OPM must replace the $10 per day cap on the commuting allowance for employees assigned to remote worksites with the mileage reimbursement rate prescribed by the General Services Administration for the use of privately owned automobiles for official government business.

Agencies may pay an allowance to employees assigned to sites remote from: (1) established communities, suitable residences, or affordable housing; (2) medical care, child care, or schools; (3) employment options for spouses; or (4) consumer goods and services.

The OPM must establish a permanent hiring working group to help agencies prepare and deal with such geographic areas.

Agencies must: (1) create pilot programs to increase the number of new employees placed in these unique geographic areas; (2) develop strategies to aide employees' spouses and families; and (3) enhance recruiting methods targeting colleges, veterans transition centers, and job placement programs in such areas.

The OPM must establish a centralized electronic database of individuals completing a federal internship program who are seeking full-time federal employment.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
