<bill session="115" type="s" number="495" updated="2019-04-18T16:33:22Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide incentives for investment in research and development for new medicines, to enhance access to new medicines, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medical Innovation Prize Fund Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medical Innovation Prize Fund Act</title>
    <title type="display">Medical Innovation Prize Fund Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-02T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Medical Innovation Prize Fund Act

This bill denies any person the exclusive right to manufacture, distribute, sell, or use a drug, a biological product, or a medication manufacturing process. The bill establishes the Fund for Medical Innovation Prizes to provide for prize payments in lieu of market exclusivity.

The Board of Trustees of the fund must award prize payments to: (1) the first person to receive approval for a medication; (2) the holder of the patent for a manufacturing process; and (3) persons or communities that contributed to the development of a rewarded medication or process through the open, nondiscriminatory, and royalty-free sharing of knowledge, data, materials, and technology.

The board must establish: (1) criteria for selecting recipients and determining the amount of prizes, and (2) independent expert advisory committees to assist it in carrying out this bill.

The board must establish, and may periodically modify, minimum levels of funding for priority research and development, including research and development regarding global neglected diseases, orphan diseases, global infectious diseases, and other global public health priorities.

The board may authorize nonprofit intermediaries to reward projects for interim research and development of products or for open source dividend prizes.

The Government Accountability Office must determine the board's effectiveness in bringing to market new medications and manufacturing processes in a cost-effective manner and in addressing society's medical needs.

The bill establishes an annual fee on health insurers to fund this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
