<bill session="113" type="s" number="1403" updated="2016-10-25T16:26:27Z">
  <state datetime="2013-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Heroes Fly Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, to direct the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security (Transportation Security Administration) to facilitate the screening of severely injured or disabled members of the Armed Forces and severely injured or disabled veterans at airports, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Helping Heroes Fly Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000590"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2013-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Legislative Interest"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1344"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1367"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-07-31T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Helping Heroes Fly Act - Directs the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security (Transportation Security Administration [TSA]) to develop and implement a process to support and facilitate the movement of severely injured or disabled Armed Forces members and veterans through passenger screening before boarding passenger aircraft.

Requires the Assistant Secretary also to maintain an operations center to provide for the movement of such members and veterans through passenger screening.

Directs the Assistant Secretary to establish and publish certain protocols for severely injured or disabled Armed Forces members and veterans or their family members and others to contact the operations center to request support during and facilitation of passenger screening for the member or veteran.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
