<bill session="114" type="h" number="3234" updated="2018-06-02T04:39:17Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-09T16:31:11-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-02-09T16:31:11-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Failing VA Medical Center Recovery Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">VA Medical Center Recovery Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to establish within the Department of Veterans Affairs an Office of Failing Medical Center Recovery, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to evaluate the ability of each medical center of the Department to provide quality health care to veterans, to ensure that the Secretary improves such medical centers that are underperforming, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">VA Medical Center Recovery Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000591"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5531-5532"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-08-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-09T16:22:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Abraham moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-09T16:22:07-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H628-630" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-09T16:22:11-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3234.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2016-02-09T16:31:11-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H628-629" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-02-09T16:31:16-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-09T16:31:19-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-09T15:02:19Z" status="Passed House amended">VA Medical Center Recovery Act

(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to publish in the Federal Register and on a publicly available VA Internet website a compilation of key health metrics for each VA medical center.

The VA shall: (1) determine on a semiannual basis whether each medical center is satisfactory or underperforming; and (2) upon a determination of underperformance, send a rapid deployment team to the center to ensure that it achieves satisfactory performance as quickly as practicable.

A rapid deployment team shall:

 identify the areas of the medical center that require improvement and whether the center follows directives and best practices; establish a performance remediation plan; review the status of any disciplinary actions taken at the center, any recommendations made by the VA Inspector General, and any Government Accountability Office findings; and provide appropriate training to the director and staff. The Inspector General of the VA shall prioritize investigations regarding underperforming medical centers.

The Office of Accountability Review shall prioritize investigations of whistleblower retaliation regarding underperforming medical centers.

(Sec. 3) The VA shall seek to enter into partnerships with recognized schools of nursing to provide undergraduate nursing students enrolled in such schools with standardized training with respect to:

 the culture of the military and veterans; post-traumatic stress disorder; traumatic brain injury; amputation and assistive devices; environmental, chemical, and toxic exposure; substance use disorders; military sexual trauma; suicide; homelessness; serious illness at the end of life; and federal benefits, services, and resources for veterans.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
