<bill session="114" type="h" number="6133" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:47Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Adam Walsh Reauthorization Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize certain programs established by the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Adam Walsh Reauthorization Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001293" joined="2016-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001295" joined="2016-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000059" joined="2016-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000621" joined="2016-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000600" joined="2016-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000448" joined="2016-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000289" joined="2016-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000556" joined="2016-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000581" joined="2016-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000592" joined="2016-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000480" joined="2016-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000470" joined="2016-11-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-10-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Adam Walsh Reauthorization Act of 2016

This bill amends the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act to:

 reauthorize through FY2021 the Sex Offender Management Assistance program, reauthorize through FY2021 the activities of the U.S. Marshals Service to locate and apprehend sex offenders who violate sex offender registration requirements, reduce from 25 years to 15 years the required registration period for certain juvenile delinquent sex offenders who maintain a clean record, allow a state, Indian tribe, or territory to exempt from disclosure on a public website information about juvenile delinquent sex offenders, specify how to calculate the allocation of Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant (JAG) program funds for local governments after a state's JAG funds are reduced for failure to comply with sex offender registration and notification standards, and establish an alternative method for complying with the in-person verification requirement. It amends the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 to require the Department of Justice to include additional data in its annual report on the enforcement of sex offender registration requirements.

The bill amends the federal criminal code to:

 modify the duties of probation and pretrial services officers to include, when directed by a court, supervision of a sex offender conditionally released from civil commitment subject to court-ordered compliance with a prescribed regimen of medical, psychiatric, or psychological treatment; and extend the statute of limitations for a minor victim of a federal sex offense to file a civil action to 10 years (currently 3 years) from the date such individual reaches age 18.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
