<bill session="113" type="h" number="1724" updated="2016-10-25T16:02:39Z">
  <state datetime="2013-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Kids First Research Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To eliminate taxpayer financing of presidential campaigns and party conventions and reprogram savings to provide for a 10-year pediatric research initiative through the Common Fund administered by the National Institutes of Health, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Kids First Research Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001045"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000013" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001269" joined="2013-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001077" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2013-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001092" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000619" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000451" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001059" joined="2013-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000290" joined="2013-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000363" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001181" joined="2013-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001189" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001150" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000592" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000813" joined="2013-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2013-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on House Administration, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25">
      <text>Referred to House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2019"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-04-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Kids First Research Act of 2013 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to terminate: (1) the taxpayer election to designate $3 of income tax liability for financing of presidential election campaigns, (2) the Presidential Election Campaign Fund, and (3) the Presidential Primary Matching Payment Account.

Redesignates the Presidential Election Campaign Fund as the 10-Year Pediatric Research Initiative Fund. Makes amounts in the Fund available only for allocation to national research institutes and national centers through the Common Fund for making grants for pediatric research under this Act. Requires deposit into the Treasury general fund of any amounts in the Pediatric Research Initiative Fund that remain unobligated on October 1, 2024.

Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH), through the Division of Program Coordination, Planning, and Strategic Initiatives, to allocate funds appropriated under this Act to the national research institutes and national centers for making grants for pediatric research representing important areas of emerging scientific opportunities, rising public health challenges, or knowledge gaps that deserve special emphasis and would benefit from conducting or supporting additional research that involves collaboration between two or more national research institutes or national centers, or would otherwise benefit from strategic coordination and planning.

Authorizes $13 million out of the 10-Year Pediatric Research Initiative Fund for each of FY2014-FY2023 for pediatric research through the Common Fund. Requires such funds to supplement, not supplant, funds otherwise allocated by NIH for pediatric research. Prohibits the use of such amounts for any purpose other than making grants for pediatric research described in this Act.

Requires the Director of NIH, before continuing any health economics research grant, project, or activity, to report to Congress on the justification for such research, including the reason for giving it priority over research on pediatric diseases and disorders. Prohibits the Director from initiating any health economics research grant, project, or activity until the Director has submitted the report outlining the justification and a federal law has been enacted authorizing NIH to use funding specifically for health economics research.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
