<bill session="114" type="h" number="1998" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:40Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HERO Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Human Exploitation Rescue Operations Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To continue operation of the Human Exploitation Rescue Operative (HERO) Child Rescue Corps, a Cyber Crimes Center, a Child Exploitation Investigations Unit, a Computer Forensics Unit, and a Cyber Crimes Unit to support the mission of the Homeland Security Investigations directorate of United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement to combat the exploitation of children.</title>
    <title type="display">HERO Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000797"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001270" joined="2015-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2015-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000266" joined="2015-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001049" joined="2015-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2015-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000462" joined="2015-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2015-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000294" joined="2015-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2015-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000581" joined="2015-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000480" joined="2015-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001188" joined="2015-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001191" joined="2015-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000596" joined="2015-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2015-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000592" joined="2015-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2015-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000185" joined="2015-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2015-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000808" joined="2015-04-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Security Technologies.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Innovation" code="HSHM08" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Border Security, Facilitation, and Operations" code="HSHM11" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="178"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="575"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Human Exploitation Rescue Operations Act of 2015 or the HERO Act of 2015

This&#160;bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to operate, within U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE), a Cyber Crimes Center to provide investigative assistance, training, and equipment to support domestic and international investigations by ICE of cyber-related crimes.

Within the Cyber Crimes Center, DHS shall operate a Child Exploitation Investigations Unit, which shall:

 coordinate all ICE child exploitation initiatives, including investigations into child exploitation, child pornography, child victim identification, traveling child sex offenders, and forced child labor, including the sexual exploitation of minors; focus on child exploitation prevention, investigative capacity building, enforcement operations, and training for law enforcement personnel; provide training and technical expertise to cooperating law enforcement agencies and personnel; provide psychological support and counseling services for ICE personnel engaged in child exploitation prevention initiatives; collaborate with the Department of Defense (DOD) and the National Association to Protect Children to recruit, train, equip, and hire wounded, ill, and injured veterans and transitioning service members through the Human Exploitation Rescue Operative (HERO) Child Rescue Corps program; collaborate with other governmental and nongovernmental entities for the sponsorship of, and participation in, outreach and training activities; and collect and maintain data on the total number of suspects identified by ICE, the number of arrests and cases opened for investigation by ICE, and the number of cases resulting in prosecution and report on such data. DHS shall operate, within the Cyber Crimes Center, a Computer Forensics Unit (CFU). The CFU is directed to: (1) provide training and technical support in digital forensics to ICE personnel and other law enforcement personnel investigating crimes; (2) provide computer hardware, software, and forensic licenses for all computer forensics personnel within ICE; (3) participate in research and development in the area of digital forensics; and (4) collaborate with DOD and the National Association to Protect Children to recruit, train, equip, and hire wounded, ill, and injured veterans and transitioning service members through the Human Exploitation Rescue Operative (HERO) Child Rescue Corps program.

DHS shall also operate, within the Cyber Crimes Center, a Cyber Crimes Unit (CCU). The CCU shall: (1) oversee the cyber security strategy and cyber-related operations and programs for ICE, (2) enhance the ability of ICE to combat criminal enterprises operating on or through the Internet, (3) provide training and technical support in cyber investigations to ICE personnel and other law enforcement personnel, (4) participate in research and development in the area of cyber investigations, and (5) recruit participants in the Human Exploitation Rescue Operative (HERO) Child Rescue Corps program for investigative and forensic positions.

Congress declares that Homeland Security Investigations of ICE should hire, recruit, train, and equipment wounded, ill, or injured military veterans who are affiliated with the HERO Child Rescue Corps program for investigative, intelligence, analyst, and forensic positions.

The bill further amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to expand the purposes of the DHS Acceleration Fund for Research and Development of Homeland Security Technologies to include conducting research and development to advance technology for the investigation of child exploitation crimes, including child victim identification, trafficking in persons, child pornography, and for advanced forensics.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
