<bill session="115" type="h" number="1859" updated="2019-04-18T16:06:07Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 to designate a portion of United States Route 15 in Pennsylvania as part of the Interstate System, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 to designate a portion of United States Route 15 in Pennsylvania as part of the Interstate System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001179"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Highways and Transit" code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-03T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill amends the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 to designate U.S. Route 15 in Pennsylvania from its intersection with Interstate Route 180 to the New York border as part of a high priority corridor on the National Highway System. Pennsylvania shall erect signs identifying such corridor as Interstate Route 99.

The Department of Transportation is authorized to make grants to Pennsylvania for projects to:

 erect signs identifying the segment designated by this bill as part of the Interstate System (IS), and make improvements as necessary for such segment to conform with applicable IS standards. The bill permits vehicles that could operate legally on such segment before its designation as part of the IS to continue to operate on such segment without regard to IS vehicle weight limitations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
