<bill session="114" type="h" number="2550" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:17Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medical Imaging Modernization Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide Medicare payment incentives to transition from traditional x-ray imaging to digital radiography, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Medical Imaging Modernization Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001159"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Radiation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Medical Imaging Modernization Act of 2015

This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to make a special rule reducing by 20% the payment under the physician fee schedule and the hospital outpatient prospective payment system for the technical component of imaging services that are x-rays taken using film.

Imaging services that are x-rays taken using computed radiography technology shall have the technical component payment: (1) for services furnished from 2018 through 2022 reduced by 7%; and (2) for services furnished during 2023 or a subsequent year reduced by 10%.

Reduced expenditures attributable to incentives to transition to digital radiography under the physician fee schedule are exempt from budget-neutrality calculation.

The Department of Health and Human Services may not apply a multiple procedure payment reduction to the professional component of imaging services furnished before it publishes, as part of the Medicare Physician Fee Schedule Proposed Rule for a year, a empirical analysis of the Resource-Based Relative Value Scale (commonly known as the "RBRVS") Data Manager information used to determine what, if any, efficiencies exist within the professional component of imaging services when two or more studies are performed on the same patient on the same day.

These payment reductions under the hospital outpatient prospective payment system for the transition from traditional x-ray imaging to digital radiography shall apply without regard to budget neutrality.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
