<bill session="114" type="s" number="980" updated="2018-06-02T06:45:15Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Defense of Environment and Property Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to clarify the definition of navigable waters, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Defense of Environment and Property Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000603"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2015-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2015-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2015-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2015-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000355" joined="2015-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2015-04-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Army Corps of Engineers"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Defense of Environment and Property Act of 2015

This bill amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to specify the types of water bodies that are "navigable waters" and therefore fall under the scope of the Act. Groundwater is considered to be state water.

Activities carried out by the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) or the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers may not impinge upon states' power over land and water use.

States or individual property owners may obtain judicial review of jurisdictional determinations by the EPA or the Army Corps that would affect their ability to plan the development and use of land and water resources within 30 days after a determination.

The EPA may not use a significant nexus test to determine federal jurisdiction over navigable waters and waters of the United States.

The following rules are nullified: (1) the Army Corps' rule entitled "Final Rule for Regulatory Programs of the Corps of Engineers," (2) the EPA's proposed rule entitled "Advance Notice of Proposed Rulemaking on the Clean Water Act Regulatory Definition of 'Waters of the United States,'" (3) the guidance document entitled "Clean Water Act Jurisdiction Following the U.S. Supreme Court's Decision in Rapanos v. United States &amp; Carabell v. United States" (relating to the definition of waters under the jurisdiction of the Clean Water Act), and (4) any subsequent regulation or guidance issued by federal agencies that defines or interprets the term "navigable waters."

The Army Corps and the EPA may not promulgate rules or issue guidance that expands or interprets the definition of navigable waters unless expressly authorized by Congress.

Federal agencies must obtain the consent of private property owners prior to entering their land to collect information about navigable waters. Federal agencies that issue regulations that relate to the definition of navigable waters or waters of the United States and diminish the fair market value or economic viability of a property must pay the affected property owner an amount equal to twice the value of the loss. Until the landowners have been compensated, such a regulation will have no force or effect.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
