<bill session="114" type="h" number="2750" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:36Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-27T16:35:52-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-07-27T16:35:52-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reform programs of the Transportation Security Administration, streamline transportation security regulations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Improved Security Vetting for Aviation Workers Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Improved Security Vetting for Aviation Workers Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improved Security Vetting for Aviation Workers Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Improved Security Vetting for Aviation Workers Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000375" joined="2015-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2015-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001197" joined="2015-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000604" joined="2015-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000602" joined="2015-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-16">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-06-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-07-27">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 114-227.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-07-27" calendar="Union" number="172">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 172.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-07-27T16:27:09-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Katko moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-27T16:27:31-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5497-5499" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-27T16:27:37-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2750.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2015-07-27T16:35:52-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5497-5498" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-07-27T16:35:53-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Transportation and Maritime Security" code="HSHM07" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3584"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6381"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-27T15:18:00Z" status="Passed House amended">Improved Security Vetting for Aviation Workers Act of 2015

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 todirect the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), by December 31, 2015, in coordination with the DHS Assistant Secretary for Policy, to request from the Director of National Intelligence access to additional data from the Terrorist Identities Datamart Environment data and any or other terrorism-related information to improve the effectiveness of TSA's credential vetting program for individuals with unescorted access to sensitive areas of airports.

The TSA, by the same deadline, shall:

 issue guidance for Transportation Security Inspectors to review annually airport badging office procedures for applicants seeking access to sensitive airport areas, including a comprehensive review of applicants' Criminal History Records Check and work authorization documentation during the course of an inspection; issue guidance to airports requiring that all federalized airport badging authorities place an expiration date on airport credentials commensurate with the period of time during which an individual is lawfully authorized to work in the United States; and review the denial of credentials owing to an applicants's lawful status in order to identify airports with specific weaknesses and coordinate with them to address such weaknesses. The TSA may conduct a Rap Back Service pilot program, in coordination with the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), to determine the feasibility of full implementation of a service through which the TSA would be notified of a change in status of an individual holding a valid credential granting unescorted access to sensitive airport areas across eligible TSA-regulated populations. (The FBI Rap Back Service notifies authorized agencies of criminal, and, in limited cases, civil activity of individuals that occurs after the initial processing and retention of criminal or civil transactions.)

Certain pilot program procedures are prescribed regarding notification only of a change with respect to a disqualifying offense under the credential vetting program.

(Sec. 3) The TSA, within 60 days after enactment of this Act, shall report to Congress on the status of plans to conduct the Rap Back Service pilot program.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-227</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
