<bill session="114" type="h" number="4302" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:31Z">
  <state datetime="2015-12-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">END OF AN ERA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Entering Negotiations to Dissolve Outdated Financial Agencies Nationalizing Export Related Activities</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to pursue with other countries the goal of the mutual elimination of government-backed export credit agencies, and to provide for the abolishment of the Export-Import Bank of the United States if doing so would not put the United States at a competitive disadvantage.</title>
    <title type="display">END OF AN ERA Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000577"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1605"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Export-Import Bank of the United States"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-12-18T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Entering Negotiations to Dissolve Outdated Financial Agencies Nationalizing Export Related Activities or the END OF AN ERA Act

This bill directs the Department of the Treasury to seek to enter into negotiations with other countries for the mutual elimination of government-backed export credit agencies.

Treasury shall submit: (1) annual reports on progress made in arranging such negotiations, on progress made in any such negotiations, and on whether eliminating the Export-Import Bank of the United States at the time of the report would put the United States at a competitive disadvantage; and (2) a certification of any determination that the Bank can be eliminated in a way that would not put the United States at a competitive disadvantage, considering job losses and a decrease in economic activity.

After such a determination is submitted, the Bank may not accept an application for, or enter into a contract that would obligate the Bank to provide, a loan, insurance, or a guarantee or to participate in an extension of credit by another entity.

 The Bank shall be abolished 180 days after Treasury submits such a certification and its functions transferred to Treasury. All such transferred functions shall terminate on the date all obligations of the Bank, and all obligations of others to the Bank, in effect immediately before the abolishment date have been satisfied.

The bill repeals the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 and eliminates related authorizing provisions of various statutes.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
