<bill session="114" type="hr" number="311" updated="2019-05-09T23:15:18Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that Congress should confirm that money is not free speech and that corporations are not people for purposes of the First Amendment right to make campaign contributions by enacting a constitutional amendment overturning the decision of the Supreme Court in the case of Citizens United v. Federal Election Commission, and should restore the right of Congress and the States to impose limits on the amount of expenditures that may be made by candidates and others in support of elections for public office by enacting a constitutional amendment overturning the decision of the Supreme Court in the case of Buckley v. Valeo.</title>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that Congress should confirm that money is not free speech and that corporations are not people for purposes of the First Amendment right to make campaign contributions by enacting a constitutional amendment overturning the decision of the Supreme Court in the case of Citizens United v. Federal Election Commission, and should restore the right of Congress and the States to impose limits on the amount of expenditures that may be made by candidates and others in support of elections for public office by enacting a constitutional amendment overturning the decision of the Supreme Court in the case of Buckley v. Valeo.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000127"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="First Amendment rights"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that, in order to overturn the Supreme Court decision in: (1) Citizens United v. Federal Election Commission, Congress should enact and the states should ratify a constitutional amendment providing that any right of a corporation, other business organization, or other artificial entity to engage in political activity, including making contributions and expenditures to influence an election for public office or a ballot measure, is not derived from the First Amendment but from the laws of the United States and the states and may be exercised only to the extent provided by such laws; and (2) Buckley v. Valeo, Congress should enact and the states should ratify a constitutional amendment providing that Congress and the states have the authority to impose limits on the amount of expenditures that may be made by candidates and others in support of elections for public office.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
