<bill session="114" type="s" number="2458" updated="2018-06-02T07:14:20Z">
  <state datetime="2016-01-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-01-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-01-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend section 217(a)(12) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, relating to the restriction of the use of the Visa Waiver Program for aliens who travel to certain countries.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend section 217(a)(12) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, relating to the restriction of the use of the Visa Waiver Program for aliens who travel to certain countries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-01-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-01-20T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act, as amended by the Visa Waiver Program Improvement and Terrorist Travel Prevention Act of 2015, to include Department of State designation of a country or area as a country or area of concern among the criteria for visa waiver program ineligibility based upon an alien's nationality or presence.

Exceptions to program ineligibility shall include include an alien who was present in a prohibited country to perform official duties as an employee of an international organization for a program country.

 Visa waiver program disqualification under the Visa Waiver Program Improvement and Terrorist Travel Prevention Act of 2015 shall not take effect until 180 days after enactment of such Act for an alien: (1) who, regardless of whether the alien is a national of a program country, is a national of Iraq or Syria, a national of a country designated as supporting terrorism, or a national of any other country or area of concern; or (2) who has been present in such countries or areas on or after March 1, 2011.

The Department of Homeland Security or the State Department may waive such prohibition for a period of up to 90 days if either determines that the waiver is in U.S. national security interests.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
