<bill session="115" type="s" number="886" updated="2019-06-17T18:45:34Z">
  <state datetime="2017-11-09">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-11-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish an Acquisition Review Board in the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">DHS Acquisition Review Board Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">DHS Acquisition Review Board Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">DHS Acquisition Review Board Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">DHS Acquisition Review Board Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DHS Acquisition Review Board Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DHS Acquisition Review Board Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">DHS Acquisition Review Board Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2017-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2427-2428" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-07-26" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-10-16">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson without amendment. With written report No. 115-170.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-10-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="240">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 240.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-11-09">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7164" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2017-11-09" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-11-13">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-13T14:04:13-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-13T18:30:09-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Legislative Interest"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1282"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2825"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1582"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2017-11-09T17:19:55Z" status="Passed Senate amended">DHS Acquisition Review Board Act of 2017

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish an Acquisition Review Board to strengthen accountability and uniformity within the DHS acquisition review process, review major acquisition programs (programs estimated to require a total expenditure of at least $300 million over their life cycle costs), and review the use of best practices.

The board shall convene at DHS's discretion and whenever: (1) a major acquisition program requires authorization to proceed from one acquisition decision event to another, is in breach of its approved requirements, or requires additional review; or (2) a non-major acquisition program requires review.

The board's responsibilities are to:

 determine whether a proposed acquisition program has met the requirements of phases of the acquisition life cycle framework and is able to proceed to the next phase and eventual full production and deployment; oversee whether a proposed acquisition's business strategy, resources, management, and accountability is executable and aligned to strategic initiatives; support the acquisition decision authority in determining the appropriate direction at key acquisition decision events; conduct reviews to ensure that acquisitions are progressing in compliance with the approved documents for their current acquisition phases; review the acquisition documents of each major acquisition program to ensure the reliability of underlying data; and ensure that practices are implemented to require consideration of tradeoffs among cost, schedule, and performance objectives as part of the process for developing requirements for major acquisition programs prior to initiating the second acquisition decision event. If the person exercising acquisition decision authority over a major acquisition program approves such program to proceed into the planning phase before such program has a DHS-approved acquisition program baseline, as required by DHS policy, DHS shall create and approve a baseline report regarding such approval and notify Congress.

DHS, by one year after this bill's enactment and annually through FY2022, shall provide information to Congress on the board's activities.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-170</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
