<bill session="114" type="h" number="4745" updated="2019-02-14T23:30:54Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Interim Consolidated Storage Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to authorize the Secretary of Energy to enter into contracts for the storage of certain high-level radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel and take title to certain high-level radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel.</title>
    <title type="display">Interim Consolidated Storage Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001182"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000566" joined="2016-11-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Environment and Climate Change" code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3643"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Interim Consolidated Storage Act of 2016

This bill amends the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to authorize the Department of Energy (DOE) to enter into new contracts (or modify existing contracts) with the licensee of an interim consolidated storage facility in order to take title to and store in it either high-level radioactive waste or spent nuclear fuel of domestic origin.

The bill defines:

 "interim consolidated storage facility" as a facility licensed by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission for the storage of high-level radioactive waste or spent nuclear fuel received from DOE or from two or more persons that generate or hold title to such fuel generated at a civilian nuclear power reactor, and "high-level radioactive waste" as including Greater than Class C waste. The bill assigns priority to storage of such waste and spent fuel located on sites without an operating nuclear reactor.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
