<bill session="115" type="s" number="1273" updated="2019-04-18T16:36:45Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend chapter 329 of title 49, United States Code, relating to average fuel economy standards for automobiles.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fuel Economy Harmonization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fuel Economy Harmonization Act</title>
    <title type="display">Fuel Economy Harmonization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000575"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2017-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="4011"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fuel Economy Harmonization Act

This bill revises requirements for calculating Corporate Average Fuel Economy (CAFE) credits earned by a passenger automobile manufacturer for exceeding minimal required CAFE standards in a particular model year. Beginning in model year 2016 through model year 2021, a manufacturer may apply any credits earned after model year 2009 to subsequent model years.

The bill revises fuel economy credit transferring program requirements allowing a manufacturer of a fleet that exceeds CAFE standards to transfer the earned credits and to apply them within that fleet to a compliance category of automobiles that fails to achieve prescribed CAFE standards. The maximum increases in any compliance category attributable to transferred credits are:

 1.0 mile per gallon, for model years 2010-2013; 1.5 miles per gallon, for model years 2014-2016; 2.0 miles per gallon, for model years 2017 and 2018; 4.0 miles per gallon, for model years 2019-2021; 6.0 miles per gallon, for model year 2022 and subsequent model years. The bill requires the Environmental Protection Agency to modify its calculation of average fuel economy for model years 2012 through 2025 at the request of a manufacturer for its passenger and nonpassenger automobiles.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
