<bill session="114" type="s" number="1743" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:35Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide greater transparency, accountability, and safety authority to the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Motor Vehicle Safety Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Motor Vehicle Safety Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2015-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2015-07-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4957-4958" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4958-4962" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1467"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2140"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5126"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Lease and rental services"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-09T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Motor Vehicle Safety Act of 2015

This bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to:

 promulgate regulations establishing categories of early warning motor vehicle safety information, especially about fatal incidents, that must be made available to the public; and take specified steps to improve public accessibility to information on vehicle safety databases of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA). The DOT Inspector General shall report biennially on the pre-investigation processes of the NHTSA Office of Defects Investigation to collect and analyze vehicle safety data and determine potential safety issues.

DOT shall report on the operations of the Council for Vehicle Electronics, Vehicle Software, and Emerging Technologies.

The bill increases civil money penalties for motor vehicle safety violations, and establishes both civil and criminal penalties for knowing failure of a business entity or responsible corporate officer to inform an appropriate federal agency of a serious danger associated with covered products, services, or business practices.

In conducting motor vehicle safety research programs, DOT shall, in coordination with Department of State, enter into cooperative and collaborative research and development agreements with foreign governments.

DOT must immediately notify and order motor vehicle or replacement equipment manufacturers of defects or noncompliance presenting an imminent hazard.

No dealer may sell or lease a used passenger motor vehicle until any defect or noncompliance presenting an imminent hazard has been remedied.

DOT shall:

 complete research into development of an unattended children warning system, initiate a rulemaking to require crash avoidance and mitigation systems for certain motor vehicles, and issue a final rule establishing hood and bumper standards for certain other motor vehicles to reduce the pedestrian injuries and fatalities. The bill reauthorizes motor vehicle safety regulation through FY2021.

A manufacturer's recall obligations shall be enforceable against the manufacturer or successors-in-interest whether accomplished by merger, acquisition of the manufacturer's stock, acquisition of its assets, or confirmation of a reorganization plan under federal bankruptcy law.

Dealers must check for and remedy defective or noncomplying motor vehicles.

DOT shall initiate a rulemaking, establish grants to states, and conduct a pilot program relating to safety recalls.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
