<bill session="114" type="hr" number="389" updated="2018-06-02T01:19:13Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Honest Dynamic Scoring Resolution</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to lower the threshold at which the gross budgetary effect of a piece of legislation requires the cost estimates provided for the legislation to incorporate macroeconomic variables resulting from the legislation, and to require the cost estimates provided for appropriation bills and joint resolutions to incorporate such variables.</title>
    <title type="display">Honest Dynamic Scoring Resolution</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000620"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001051" joined="2015-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2015-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Honest Dynamic Scoring Resolution

Amends Rule XIII (Calendars and Committee Reports) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to revise the threshold at which a piece of major legislation's gross budgetary effect requires the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) to provide cost estimates that incorporate macroeconomic variables resulting from the legislation (dynamic scoring).

Changes the threshold from 0.25% of the current projected gross domestic product for that fiscal year to 1% of the total amount of discretionary spending in the most recently ended fiscal year.

Requires a CBO cost estimate for any appropriation bill or joint resolution which funds a project, program, or activity authorized by major legislation to incorporate the budgetary effects of changes in economic output, employment, capital stock, and other macroeconomic variables resulting from the legislation.

Requires the central value within a range to be used for official scoring purposes if CBO provides a range of estimates in addition to a central value for such legislation.

Authorizes CBO to use traditional scoring methods when making such an estimate if the estimate will be the same under both that method and the dynamic scoring method.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
