<bill session="114" type="s" number="268" updated="2018-06-02T06:32:10Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rebuild America Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the infrastructure of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Rebuild America Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2015-01-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak)"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-27T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Rebuild America Act of 2015

Reduces the non-federal share of the cost of any activity funded by this Act by 50% of what it was before enactment of this Act.

Appropriates funds for FY2015-FY2022 to the Highway Trust Fund to improve roads, bridges, and other U.S. transportation infrastructure.

Appropriates funds for FY2015-FY2019: (1) for intercity high-speed rail service, (2) to provide credit assistance for surface transportation projects of national and regional significance, (3) to implement airport improvement and noise compatibility projects at public-use airports, (4) to the Federal Aviation Administration to accelerate deployment of satellite technology to improve airport safety and capacity, and (5) for the TIGER Discretionary Grant Program.

Appropriates funds for FY2015-FY2019 for water infrastructure, including to: (1) the Environmental Protection Agency for capitalization grants to states to establish water pollution control revolving funds and drinking water treatment revolving loan funds and for loans for large water infrastructure projects that are ineligible for funding from a state revolving loan fund; (2) the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to carry out the predisaster hazard mitigation program for minor localized flood reduction projects and major flood risk reduction projects; and (3) the Army Corps of Engineers for inland waterways projects, coastal harbors and channels, inland harbors, and dams and levees.

Appropriates funds for FY2015-FY2019 for the National Park Service.

Appropriates funds for FY2015-FY2019 for the Broadband Initiatives Program, the Broadband Technology Opportunities Program, and the Department of Energy to modernize the electric grid.

Establishes the National Infrastructure Development Bank as a wholly owned government corporation.

Makes the Bank's Board of Directors responsible for monitoring and overseeing energy, environmental, telecommunications, data, or transportation infrastructure projects. Authorizes the Board to:

 make senior and subordinated loans and purchase senior and subordinated debt securities; issue and sell debt securities of the Bank; issue public benefit bonds and provide direct subsidies to infrastructure projects from the proceeds; make loan guarantees; borrow on the global capital market and lend to regional, state, and local entities, and commercial banks, to fund infrastructure projects; and purchase, pool, and sell infrastructure-related loans and securities on the global capital market. Requires the Board to establish: (1) an Executive Committee, a Risk Management Committee, and an Audit Committee; and (2) criteria for determining eligibility for financial assistance from the Bank and disclosure and application procedures for entities to nominate projects for such assistance. Requires the Bank to conduct an analysis that considers the economic, environmental, and social benefits and costs of each project under consideration, prioritizing projects that contribute to economic growth, lead to job creation, and are of regional or national significance. Sets forth criteria to be considered by the Board in determining the eligibility of transportation, environmental, energy, and telecommunications infrastructure projects for assistance.

Exempts all bonds issued by the Bank from state or local government taxation. Deems all debt securities and other obligations issued by the Bank to be exempt securities within the meaning of laws administered by the Securities and Exchange Commission.

Sets forth requirements regarding compliance of financed infrastructure projects with prevailing wage rate, domestic content, and buy American statutes. Authorizes appropriations for the capitalization of the Bank.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
