<bill session="115" type="h" number="2355" updated="2019-04-18T16:08:16Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for integrated plan permits, to establish an Office of the Municipal Ombudsman, to promote green infrastructure, and to require the revision of financial capability guidance.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Water Infrastructure Flexibility Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Water Infrastructure Flexibility Act</title>
    <title type="display">Water Infrastructure Flexibility Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000566"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001286" joined="2017-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2018-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000455" joined="2017-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000295" joined="2017-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2017-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2018-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001199" joined="2017-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000813" joined="2018-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Environment and Climate Change" code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1971"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="7279"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="692"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2800"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-04T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Water Infrastructure Flexibility Act

This bill amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to allow municipalities to develop a plan that integrates wastewater and stormwater management.

A permit for a municipal discharge under the national pollutant discharge elimination system that incorporates an integrated plan may integrate all requirements under the Act addressed in the plan. Those permits may include a schedule of compliance that allows actions for meeting water quality-based effluent limitations to be implemented over more than one permit term if the compliance schedules are authorized by state water quality standards. Those actions may include implementing green infrastructure as part of a water quality-based effluent limitation. (Green infrastructure includes measures that mimic natural processes to store, reuse, or reduce stormwater.)

The bill establishes an Office of the Municipal Ombudsman in the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to provide: (1) technical assistance to municipalities seeking to comply with the Clean Water Act and the Safe Drinking Water Act, and (2) information to the EPA to ensure that agency policies are implemented by all EPA offices.

The EPA must ensure that specified EPA offices promote the integration of green infrastructure into permitting programs, planning efforts, research, technical assistance, and funding guidance.

The bill establishes requirements for revising the EPA's 1997 guidance about combined sewer overflows, including by setting forth criteria for determining the ability of households to pay utility bills. (Combined sewer systems collect rainwater, sewage, and industrial wastewater into one pipe. During storms, the combined wastewater sometimes exceeds the capacity of the treatment plant. When this occurs, combined sewer overflows discharge directly into water bodies.)</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
