<bill session="114" type="h" number="2056" updated="2019-04-11T15:42:41Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a grant program to promote the development of career education programs in computer science in secondary and postsecondary education.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Computer Science Career Education Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Computer Science Career Education Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001097"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000617" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000043" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000581" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001177" joined="2016-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000480" joined="2015-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="1184"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Computer Science Career Education Act of 2015

This bill directs the Department of Education to award competitive grants to consortia composed of at least one local educational agency, at least one institution of higher education (IHE), and community representatives for the development and operation of four- or six-year computer science career education programs.

Each such career education program must include the development of a computer science program for both secondary and postsecondary education that:

 is aligned with rigorous computer science standards for kindergarten through grade 12 computer science education; links secondary schools and IHEs through non-duplicative sequences of courses in computer science career fields; uses, if appropriate and available, experiential or work-based learning in collaboration with local or regional employers; uses educational technology and distance learning to involve all members of the consortium more fully in the development and operation of the programs; aligns with industry needs in the state or region; and creates innovative opportunities for students that lead to attainment of industry-recognized credentials. A program must also provide: (1) professional development for teachers, (2) career and academic counseling for students, and (3) equal access to the full range of career education programs to members of underrepresented groups and special populations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
