<bill session="114" type="h" number="3383" updated="2019-01-09T21:10:01Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Child Performers Protection Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To limit the number of hours that children may be employed as actors, performers, and models, to require blocked trust accounts for the financial protection of such children, to clarify the liability of employers, contractors, and other individuals for sexual harassment of such child performers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Child Performers Protection Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001188"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Workforce Protections" code="HSED10" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Performing arts"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Child Performers Protection Act of 2015

This bill amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to revise the application of child labor requirements and prohibitions with respect to child performers to specify new limitations on the number of hours such children may be employed at the place of employment.

An employer or contractor may not: (1) employ any child performer unless a trust meeting specified requirements has been established on the child performer's behalf and the employer has obtained the account number of the trust account or other proof of its existence; or (2) compensate a child performer in any form besides cash wages, exclusive of board, lodging, or facilities.

Any employment or contracting of a child performer that is not in accordance with such limitations and requirements shall be treated as oppressive labor.

Certain work hour restrictions shall not apply to child performers employed in a live theatrical production.

Any individual in a supervisory role with respect to a child performer shall be liable for unlawful discrimination on the basis of sex against a child performer whether or not the individual is employed by or contracted by a covered employer or contractor.

Any child performer aggrieved by unlawful harassment on the basis of sex, or the performer's parent or guardian, may bring a civil action in any federal court of competent jurisdiction to recover equitable relief and compensatory and punitive damages, costs, and attorneys fees.

The employer of an individual who is alleged to have engaged in unlawful harassment on the basis of sex against a child performer shall conduct an internal review of its policies and procedures for protecting child performers and ensuring appropriate compliance with the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
