<bill session="114" type="h" number="5454" updated="2019-02-14T23:34:29Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Adoptee Citizenship Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for automatic acquisition of United States citizenship for certain internationally adopted individuals, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Adoptee Citizenship Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000510"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001105" joined="2016-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2016-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000448" joined="2016-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2016-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2016-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000522" joined="2016-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000820" joined="2016-12-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Citizenship" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2275"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Adoptee Citizenship Act of 2016

This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to grant automatic citizenship to all qualifying children adopted by a U.S. citizen parent, regardless of the date on which the adoption was finalized.

An individual born outside of the United States who was adopted by a U.S. citizen parent shall automatically become a U.S. citizen when the following conditions have been fulfilled:

 the individual was adopted by a U.S. citizen before the individual reached age 18, the individual was physically present in the United States in the citizen parent's legal custody pursuant to a lawful admission before the individual reached age 18, the individual never acquired U.S. citizenship before the enactment of this Act, and the individual was lawfully residing in the United States on the date of enactment of this Act. An individual who meets such criteria, except for lawfully residing in the United States on the date of enactment of this Act, shall automatically become a U.S. citizen on the date on which the individual is physically present in the United States pursuant to a lawful admission.

 A visa may not be issued to such an individual unless:

 the individual was subjected to a criminal background check; and the Department of Homeland Security and the Department of State coordinated with law enforcement agencies to ensure that appropriate action is taken regarding any unresolved criminal activity.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
