<bill session="114" type="s" number="2760" updated="2018-06-02T07:16:25Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE Lending Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stopping Abuse and Fraud in Electronic Lending Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Truth in Lending Act to address certain issues related to the extension of consumer credit, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SAFE Lending Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001176"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2016-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2016-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2016-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2016-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2016-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2016-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2016-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2016-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2016-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2016-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2016-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2016-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2016-04-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1811-1812" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="5023"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stopping Abuse and Fraud in Electronic Lending Act of 2016 or the SAFE Lending Act of 2016

This bill amends the Electronic Fund Transfer Act (EFTA) to declare that a remotely created check may only be issued by a person specifically designated in writing by the consumer to the insured depository institution at which the consumer maintains the account from which the check is drawn.

 A remotely created check is a paper or electronic check that:

 is not created by the financial institution that holds the customer account from which the check is to be paid; and does not bear a signature applied, or purported to be applied, by the account holder. A consumer may revoke authorization for remotely created checks at any time.

The bill prohibits issuance of any payment order in response to a consumer's exercise of federal consumer financial rights.

Any voluntary electronic fund transfer to repay a small-dollar consumer credit transaction shall be treated as preauthorized under the Truth in Lending Act (TILA).

The TILA is amended to require registration with the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) by any small-dollar lender that facilitates, brokers, arranges, or gathers applications for small-dollar consumer credit (of up to $5,000, adjusted for inflation) extended pursuant to an open-end, non-open-end, or other CFPB-determined credit plan meeting specified criteria.

Small-dollar consumer credit transactions must comply with state law where the consumer resides.

The EFTA is amended to:

 declare unlawful overdraft fees charged on a general-use prepaid card; and authorize the CFPB to prohibit fees for declined transactions involving such a card. The TILA is further amended to prohibit a person from certain activities, including distributing sensitive personal financial information, in connection with a small-dollar consumer credit transaction, if that person ("lead generator") does not itself grant the credit directly to the consumer.

The Government Accountability Office (GAO) shall study: (1) the availability of capital on Indian reservations, and (2) the impact on tribal economic opportunity and wealth of small-dollar consumer credit extensions to tribal members through Internet and non-Internet means.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
