<bill session="114" type="h" number="5831" updated="2018-06-02T05:28:31Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Transportation to establish and implement a fatigue management plan, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To require the Secretary of Transportation to establish and implement a fatigue management plan, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000216"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2016-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Sound recording"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to require all railroad carriers to establish and implement a fatigue management plan that identifies and evaluates any fatigue-related railroad safety hazards on its system and determine the degree of risk associated with each hazard.

DOT shall ensure that railroad carriers provide their employees with predictable work and rest schedules that have either a defined start time or a minimum of 10 hours prior notification before being required to report to duty.

A compromise of a civil penalty for violations of railroad safety regulations or orders may not reduce the minimum federal penalties set for such violations.

DOT shall impose a penalty for a violation at least 30 days after its occurrence without regard to any correction of the violation by the liable party.

The bill revises standards for the installation of inward- and outward-facing imaging recording devices in all controlling locomotive cabs and cab car operating compartments of intercity rail passenger and commuter rail passenger trains.

An in-cab audio or image recording obtained by a railroad carrier may not be used to discipline or be used in an Federal Railroad Administration enforcement proceeding against a railroad employee.

Each freight rail service carrier may voluntarily install DOT-approved inward- or outward-facing image recording devices in their trains.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
