<bill session="114" type="h" number="3798" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:38Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-02">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Due Process Restoration Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Due Process Restoration Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to permit private persons to compel the Securities and Exchange Commission to seek legal or equitable remedies in a civil action, instead of an administrative proceeding, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Due Process Restoration Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000548"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000294" joined="2016-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-02">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises Prior to Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-02">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-03-02" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 32 - 25.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-07-21">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 114-697.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-21" calendar="Union" number="539">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 539.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises" code="HSBA16" name="House Financial Services" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-21T12:57:15Z" status="Reported to House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Due Process Restoration Act of 2015

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to authorize a person who is a party to an administrative proceeding brought by the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) under a securities law, and against whom an order imposing a cease and desist order and a penalty may be issued at the conclusion of the proceeding, to require the SEC to terminate the proceeding. If a person requires the SEC to terminate a proceeding, the SEC may bring a civil action against that person for the same remedy that might have been imposed.

A legal or equitable remedy may be imposed on a person against whom an administrative proceeding was brought only upon a showing by the SEC of clear and convincing evidence that the person has violated the relevant provision of law.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-697</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
