<bill session="115" type="h" number="6351" updated="2019-04-24T20:54:18Z">
  <state datetime="2018-07-18">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to improve the process by which the Secretary of Energy authorizes the transfer of civilian nuclear commerce technology and assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing U.S. Civil Nuclear Competitiveness and Jobs Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing U.S. Civil Nuclear Competitiveness and Jobs Act</title>
    <title type="display">Advancing U.S. Civil Nuclear Competitiveness and Jobs Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000292"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000482" joined="2018-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-07-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-07-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 33 - 16.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-07-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Advancing U.S. Civil Nuclear Competitiveness and Jobs Act

This bill directs the Department of Energy (DOE) to report to Congress on U.S. civil nuclear commerce, including an assessment of how regulations, policies, and legal requirements affect the ability of civilian nuclear facilities to compete internationally.

The bill revises DOE authority to delegate functions concerning transfers of nuclear technology to a covered foreign country.

 DOE shall expedite technology transfers that are not inimical to U.S. interests and that involve low-proliferation-risk reactor activity to a foreign country that is not a nuclear-weapon state, other than the United Kingdom or France.

The Government Accountability Office shall report to Congress regarding DOE actions with respect to the retrospective risk pooling program, in which nuclear suppliers cover the cost of an incident outside the United States that is not covered by funds available for a public liability.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
