<bill session="114" type="s" number="159" updated="2018-06-02T06:29:51Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the operation of the Department of Homeland Security's Unmanned Aircraft System Program.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to improve the operation of the Department of Homeland Security's Unmanned Aircraft System Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000303"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2015-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000444" joined="2015-01-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-13T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Requires the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to fully utilize surveillance and detection capabilities developed or used by federal agencies to enhance the functioning and operational capability to conduct continuous and integrated manned or unmanned monitoring, sensing, or surveillance of 100% of the southern border of the United States.

Prohibits DHS from procuring any additional unmanned aircraft systems (UAS) until it provides written certification that it successfully operated its current UAS fleet at least 23,000 hours during the preceding calendar year. Excepts the procurement of unmanned aircraft that do not weigh more than 150 pounds.

Requires DHS to: (1) use the best available radar and surveillance technology to increase awareness of illegal border activities along the southern border and to identify gaps in surveillance capabilities; and (2) consult with the Department of Defense to identify best practices that could be used by DHS to improve the security of the southern border.

Directs DHS to report biannually on:

 the number of UAS flight hours required, planned, and flown to provide persistent surveillance along the southern border and the number of flight hours cancelled; the number of UAS flight hours planned in support of any federal or state agency; performance measures regarding the number of hours flown, subjects detected, and apprehensions and illicit drug seizures assisted; and the accumulated cost associated with the UAS Program. Terminates this Act five years after its enactment.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
