<bill session="115" type="h" number="5048" updated="2019-04-18T16:20:27Z">
  <state datetime="2018-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food Security Act of 1985 with respect to eligibility to become a third-party provider, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nutrient Management Technical Service Provider Certification Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nutrient Management Technical Service Provider Certification Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Nutrient Management Technical Service Provider Certification Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2018-02-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-02-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-02-15T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Nutrient Management Technical Service Provider Certification Act of 2018 

This bill amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to provide alternative certification methods for third-party technical service providers (TSPs). (TSPs provide technical expertise to agricultural producers on behalf of the Department of Agriculture [USDA] Natural Resource Conservation Service to assist in planning and implementing conservation measures.)

USDA must approve certain professional certifications that meet or exceed national criteria and were established by:

 the USDA, an agriculture-related retailer, a farmer cooperative, the American Society of Agronomy, or the National Alliance of Independent Crop Consultants. A qualified certification includes a certifications as:

 a Certified Crop Advisor by the American Society for Agronomy, a Certified Professional Agronomist by the American Society for Agronomy, and a Comprehensive Nutrient Management Plan Specialist by USDA.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
