<bill session="114" type="s" number="2152" updated="2019-03-03T14:40:34Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-08">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a comprehensive United States Government policy to encourage the efforts of countries in sub-Saharan Africa to develop an appropriate mix of power solutions, including renewable energy, for more broadly distributed electricity access in order to support poverty reduction, promote development outcomes, and drive economic growth, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Electrify Africa Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Electrify Africa Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Electrify Africa Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Electrify Africa Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Electrify Africa Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Electrify Africa Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000360" joined="2015-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2015-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2015-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2015-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2015-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2015-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2015-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2015-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000444" joined="2015-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2015-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2015-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2015-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2015-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2015-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2015-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2015-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2015-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2015-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2015-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2015-12-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2015-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2015-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-10-08" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Corker with amendments. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-11-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="291">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 291.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-12-08">
      <text>By Senator Corker from Committee on Foreign Relations filed written report. Report No. 114-176.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-18">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8861-8865" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-18">
      <text>The committee amendments agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8861-8863" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2015-12-18" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8863-8865" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-12-18">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-18T13:06:27-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01T17:05:05-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Royce moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01T17:05:39-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H396-400" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01T17:05:41-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 2152.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote2" datetime="2016-02-01T17:22:37-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H396-398" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01T17:22:40-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2016-02-03">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2016-02-08" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="114-121" type="public" datetime="2016-02-08">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 114-121.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2847"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1933"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Lighting, heating, cooling"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2939"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2016-02-09T04:59:58Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on December 18, 2015. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Electrify Africa Act of 2015 

(Sec. 3) This bill states that it is U.S. policy to partner with the governments of sub-Saharan African countries, international financial institutions, and African regional economic communities, cooperatives, and private sectors to:

 promote first-time access to power services for at least 50 million people in sub-Saharan Africa by 2020; encourage the installation of at least 20,000 additional megawatts of electrical power in sub-Saharan Africa by 2020; promote reliable and affordable power in urban, rural, and under served areas; encourage necessary reforms to support electricity access projects and market-based power generation and distribution; promote policies to displace kerosene lighting with other technologies; promote an energy development strategy for sub-Saharan Africa that includes the use of oil, natural gas, coal, hydroelectric, wind, solar, and geothermal power; and promote the use of private financing and seek ways to remove barriers to private financing and assistance for projects, including through charitable organizations. (Sec. 4) The President shall: (1) establish a multiyear strategy to assist countries in sub-Saharan Africa implement national power strategies and develop an appropriate mix of power solutions to provide access to reliable, affordable, and sustainable power in order to reduce poverty and drive economic growth and job creation; and (2) ensure that the strategy remains responsive to local community concerns and technological innovation.

 The President may establish an interagency working group to coordinate the activities of U.S. government departments and agencies involved in carrying out the strategy.

(Sec. 5) The U.S. Agency for International Development, the Trade and Development Agency, the Overseas Private Investment Corporation, and the Millennium Challenge Corporation are urged to: (1) prioritize efforts and assistance for power projects and markets in sub-Saharan Africa; and (2) partner with other investors and local institutions, including private sector actors, to increase access to reliable, affordable, and sustainable power.

(Sec. 6) The President should use U.S. influence at international bodies to advocate for:

 increasing investment in power sector and electrification projects in sub-Saharan Africa, addressing energy needs of individuals and communities where electricity grid access is impractical or cost-prohibitive, enhancing private sector coordination, and assisting sub-Saharan African governments to remove unnecessary regulatory barriers to investment. (Sec. 7) Within three years the President shall transmit a strategy progress report to Congress which includes information regarding: (1) U.S. programs supporting policy and legislative changes leading to increased power generation and access in sub-Saharan Africa, and (2) power projects receiving U.S. government support.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-176</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
