<bill session="113" type="s" number="2465" updated="2016-10-25T16:30:52Z">
  <state datetime="2014-07-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Albuquerque Indian School Land Transfer Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Albuquerque Indian School Land Transfer Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Interior to take into trust 4 parcels of Federal land for the benefit of certain Indian Pueblos in the State of New Mexico.</title>
    <title type="display">Albuquerque Indian School Land Transfer Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000039"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2014-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-09">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 113-419.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-08-26">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Tester under authority of the order of the Senate of 08/05/2014 with amendments. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-08-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="543">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 543.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-10-01">
      <text>By Senator Tester from Committee on Indian Affairs filed written report under authority of the order of the Senate of 09/18/2014. Report No. 113-267.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="5625"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-08-26T15:11:25Z" status="Reported to Senate amended">Albuquerque Indian School Land Transfer Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to take into trust 4 tracts of federal land in New Mexico, the combined acreage of which is approximately 11.11 acres, that were historically part of the Albuquerque Indian School for the benefit of 19 specified pueblos immediately after the requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA) have been satisfied regarding the trust acquisition of such federal land.

 Requires the federal lands taken into trust to be used for the educational, health, cultural, business, and economic development of the 19 pueblos.

Requires the federal lands taken into trust to remain subject to any private or municipal encumbrance, right-of-way, restriction, easement of record, or utility service agreement in effect on this Act's enactment date.

Requires the 19 pueblos to allow the Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA) to continue to use the federal lands taken into trust for the facilities and purposes as in existence on this Act's enactment date.

Prohibits gaming from being carried out on the federal lands taken into trust under this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 113-267</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
