<bill session="114" type="h" number="6458" updated="2018-11-09T00:09:21Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Help our Neediest Families Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title IV of the Social Security Act to prohibit a State from requiring individuals to submit to drug testing as a condition of assistance under the program of block grants to States for temporary assistance to needy families, to amend the United States Housing Act of 1937 to prohibit a public housing agency from requiring individuals to submit to drug testing as a condition of assistance under the Housing Choice Voucher Program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Help our Neediest Families Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000131"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-12-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Help Our Neediest Families Act of 2016

This bill amends part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF) of title IV of the Social Security Act to prohibit a state to which a TANF grant is made from using any part of such grant for drug testing of TANF applicants or recipients.

If the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) determines that a state has violated such prohibition, it shall reduce the family assistance grant amount payable to the state for the immediately succeeding fiscal year by not more than 1%.

This bill amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to prohibit drug testing of aid recipients under the housing choice voucher program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
