<bill session="114" type="s" number="1292" updated="2018-08-16T23:11:09Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-03">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HUBZone Revitalization Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">HUBZone Revitalization Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Small Business Act to treat certain qualified disaster areas as HUBZones and to extend the period for HUBZone treatment for certain base closure areas, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">HUBZone Revitalization Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2015-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-06-03" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-06-10">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Reported by Senator Vitter without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-06-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="112">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 112.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26">
      <text>By Senator Vitter from Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship filed written report. Report No. 114-269.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1376"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1266"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1735"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-10T14:49:45Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

HUBZone Revitalization Act of 2015

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Small Business Act to redefine HUBZones (historically underutilized business Zones) eligible for certain assistance to include a qualified disaster area (a specified census tract or nonmetropolitan county located in a major declared disaster area or in an area where a catastrophic incident has occurred).

A qualified disaster area shall be treated as a HUBZone for 5 years after it has been declared a major disaster area or for 10 years after a catastrophic incident has occurred within it.

The Federal Emergency Management Agency shall provide the Small Business Administration with any data it needs to verify a small business's eligibility for the HUBZone small business loan program.

(Sec. 3) HUBZones shall now also include areas that can be used by small businesses whose principal offices are located in base closure HUBZones, with at least 35% of their employees residing in:

 a HUBZone, a census tract in which the base closure HUBZone is wholly contained, a census tract that intersects the boundaries of the base closure HUBZone, or census tract contiguous with these census tracts. This bill also amends the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2005 to extend HUBZone eligibility assistance for base closure areas from five years to eight years after their closure.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-269</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
