<bill session="114" type="h" number="2298" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:16Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Patient Safety and Drug Abuse Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for programs to prevent prescription drug abuse under parts C and D of the Medicare program.</title>
    <title type="display">Medicare Patient Safety and Drug Abuse Prevention Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001257"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000576" joined="2015-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2015-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000395" joined="2015-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1021"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1913"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5189"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Medicare Patient Safety and Drug Abuse Prevention Act 

Amends part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to authorize a prescription drug plan (PDP) sponsor to establish a drug management program for at-risk beneficiaries.

Requires a PDP sponsor, with respect to covered part D drugs, to have in place, directly or through appropriate arrangements, a utilization management tool designed to prevent: (1) the abuse of frequently abused drugs by individuals, and (2) the diversion of such drugs at pharmacies.

Directs the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to authorize Medicare drug integrity contractors (MEDICs) to accept directly an individual's prescription and necessary medical records from pharmacies, PDPs, and physicians in order for MEDICs to provide information relevant to determining whether the individual is an at-risk beneficiary.

Requires the Inspector General of HHS to study the effectiveness of MEDICs in identifying, combating, and preventing fraud under the Medicare program.

Expresses the sense of Congress that Medicare Advantage organizations and PDP sponsors should consider using e-prescribing and other health information technology tools to support combating fraud under MA-PD plans and prescription drug plans under parts C (Medicare+Choice) and D.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
