<bill session="114" type="s" number="570" updated="2018-06-02T06:39:34Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Comprehensive Dental Reform Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve access to oral health care for vulnerable and underserved populations.</title>
    <title type="display">Comprehensive Dental Reform Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2015-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2015-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2015-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2015-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="1055"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-25T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Comprehensive Dental Reform Act of 2015

Amends titles XVIII (Medicare) and XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to cover oral health services.

Increases the federal medical assistance percentage for oral health services, thereby increasing payments to states under Medicaid.

Directs the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services to maintain a database of dental benefits available to adult Medicaid enrollees in each state.

Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish, revise, and extend funding for grant programs for:

 educating nondental professionals about oral health care; providing dental services in hospital emergency rooms or in community settings; providing scholarships and education loans for oral health professional students; providing oral health services to low-income and underserved individuals; building, operating, or expanding dental clinics in schools; and providing mobile, comprehensive dental services at locations that serve individuals who qualify for benefits under specified programs. Authorizes community based dental residencies.

Authorizes specified agencies to conduct research on oral health issues through FY2019.

Amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to make oral health services an essential health benefit.

Removes restrictions on the authority of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to provide dental care to veterans (thereby requiring dental care on the same basis as other VA-provided medical care and services).

Authorizes the VA, Department of Defense, Bureau of Prisons, and Indian Health Service to carry out demonstration programs to train and employ alternative dental health care providers in order to increase access to dental services.

 Directs the Department of Health and Human Services to conduct a cost-benefit analysis of the expansion of dental service coverage pursuant to this Act.

Directs the Government Accountability Office to evaluate the implementation and utilization of expanded dental service coverage under this Act and the demonstration programs authorized by this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
