<bill session="115" type="s" number="2619" updated="2019-04-18T16:42:27Z">
  <state datetime="2018-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to reauthorize energy programs through fiscal year 2023, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Agricultural Energy Programs Reauthorization Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Agricultural Energy Programs Reauthorization Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Agricultural Energy Programs Reauthorization Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001203"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2018-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-03-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1776"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-03-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Agricultural Energy Programs Reauthorization Act of 2018 

This bill amends the Farm Security Rural Investment Act of 2002 to reauthorize through FY2023 several Department of Agriculture (USDA) energy programs, including:

 the Biobased Markets Program; the Biorefinery, Renewable Chemical, and Biobased Product Manufacturing Assistance Program; the Bioenergy Program for Advanced Biofuels; the Rural Energy For America Program (REAP); the Biomass Research and Development Initiative; the Feedstock Flexibility Program; and the Community Wood Energy Program. The bill modifies and reauthorizes the Biomass Crop Assistance Program to:

 rename it the Biofuels and Biobased Product Feedstock and Wildland Fire Protection Program; require USDA to provide assistance under the program for hazardous woody fuel reduction projects; and expand the definition of eligible materials to include algae and animal waste byproducts, including fat, oil, grease, and manure. The bill provides mandatory funding through FY2023 for several of the reauthorized programs.

The bill modifies the Biobased Markets Program to: (1) include producers of renewable chemicals in the voluntary labeling program, and (2) require USDA and the Department of Commerce to jointly develop North American Industry Classification system codes for renewable chemical manufacturers and biobased products manufacturers.

The bill modifies REAP to prohibit more than 30% of the funds from being used each year for: (1) any one form of renewable energy, or (2) technologies to improve the efficiency of energy usage.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
