<bill session="114" type="h" number="367" updated="2018-06-02T02:06:38Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Campaign Sunlight Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to require the Federal Election Commission to establish and operate a website through which members of the public may view the contents of certain political advertisements, to require the sponsors of such advertisements to furnish the contents of the advertisements to the Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Campaign Sunlight Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000610"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001037" joined="2015-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2015-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2015-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2015-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000170" joined="2015-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2015-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000130" joined="2015-01-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-14T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Campaign Sunlight Act of 2015

 Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to direct the Federal Election Commission (FEC) to establish and operate a website (Campaign Accountability Site) through which members of the public may view the contents of political advertisements.

Requires the sponsor of a political advertisement to submit its contents to the FEC in a format the FEC may require. Requires the format to make the sources of such contents available on the website directly or through hyperlinks to the sources.

Requires the sponsor to submit an advertisement to the FEC within: (1) 24 hours after its dissemination, if it is disseminated during the 7 days before the election involved; or (2) 72 hours after dissemination during any other period.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
