<bill session="113" type="h" number="1165" updated="2018-06-05T16:10:48Z">
  <state datetime="2013-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Maximize Offshore Resource Exploration Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MORE Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To greatly enhance the Nation's environmental, energy, economic, and national security by terminating long-standing Federal prohibitions on the domestic production of abundant offshore supplies of oil and natural gas, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">MORE Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000059"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001051" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000566" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000508" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001139" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000181" joined="2013-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on the Budget, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on the Budget, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on the Budget, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="4956"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-03-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Maximize Offshore Resource Exploration Act of 2013 or MORE Act of 2013 - Declares without force or effect all federal prohibitions against the expenditure of appropriated funds to conduct natural gas leasing and preleasing activities for any area of the Outer Continental Shelf (OCS).

Revokes all withdrawals of federal submerged lands from leasing for oil and natural gas exploration and production.

Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to prohibit the Secretary of the Interior from granting an oil or natural gas lease for any OCS located within 25 miles of a state coastline unless the state has enacted a law approving the issuance of such leases by the Secretary.

Sets forth an allocation schedule for a: (1) 75% state share of revenues derived from U.S. royalties under qualified oil and gas leases on submerged lands located within the seaward boundaries of a state, and (2) 90% state share of revenues derived from royalties under leases that are located within 25 miles of the coastline of a state and within the seaward boundaries.

Extends the jurisdiction of state civil and criminal law, as appropriate, to the Alaska, Pacific, Gulf of Mexico, and Atlantic OCS Region State Adjacent Zones and OCS Planning Areas.

Establishes a separate account in the Treasury to be known as the Renewable Energy Reserve, consisting of 12.5% of revenues derived from U.S. royalties under such oil and gas leases located within the seaward boundaries and 5% of revenues derived from leases located within 25 miles of the coastline of a state and within the seaward boundaries.

Makes the Reserve available to offset the cost of subsequently enacted legislation to: (1) accelerate the use of cleaner domestic energy resources and alternative fuels; (2) promote the utilization of energy-efficient products and practices; and (3) increase research, development, and deployment of clean renewable energy and efficiency technologies and job training programs for those purposes.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
