<bill session="114" type="h" number="4876" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:34Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Prescription Drug Abuse Prevention Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the establishment of programs to prevent prescription drug abuse under the Medicare program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Medicare Prescription Drug Abuse Prevention Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000015" joined="2016-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000585" joined="2016-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000462" joined="2016-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="524"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1913"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Medicare Prescription Drug Abuse Prevention Act of 2016

This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to: (1) authorize a Medicare prescription drug plan (PDP) sponsor to establish a drug management program under which the PDP sponsor may limit an at-risk beneficiary's access to coverage for frequently abused drugs to include only those drugs that are prescribed by selected prescribers and dispensed by selected pharmacies; and (2) require a PDP sponsor to have in place a utilization management tool to prevent drug abuse.

With respect to a drug management program, a PDP sponsor must: (1) provide specified notice to a beneficiary who has been identified by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid (CMS) as "at-risk" and consequently enrolled in the program; and (2) in selecting prescribers and dispensers, ensure that the beneficiary continues to have reasonable access to drugs. These determinations shall be subject to expedited reconsideration and appeal. A PDP sponsor must review and consider an at-risk beneficiary's preferences regarding prescriber and pharmacy selection.

Certain individuals, including those receiving hospice care or residing in a long-term care facility, are exempted from enrollment in a drug management program.

CMS must, for purposes of quality or performance assessments, review and consider complaints received from at-risk beneficiaries regarding lack of access due to their enrollment in a drug management program. In addition, CMS must establish rules and procedures requiring a PDP sponsor to provide specified program data.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
