<bill session="114" type="s" number="2078" updated="2018-06-02T07:10:09Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-16">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-10-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Commission on International Religious Freedom Reauthorization Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">United States Commission on International Religious Freedom Reauthorization Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">United States Commission on International Religious Freedom Reauthorization Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">United States Commission on International Religious Freedom Reauthorization Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">United States Commission on International Religious Freedom Reauthorization Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to reauthorize the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">United States Commission on International Religious Freedom Reauthorization Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001071"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-24">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Corker. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-09-24" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="238">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 238.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2015-09-30" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7051-7052" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7051-7052" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-10-01T09:23:19-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-01">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-01T09:51:58-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-06T16:52:52-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Royce moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-06T16:52:54-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6808-6811" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-06T16:52:59-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 2078.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote2" datetime="2015-10-06T17:13:47-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6808" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-10-06T17:13:49-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2015-10-08">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2015-10-16" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="114-71" type="public" datetime="2015-10-16">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 114-71.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="2079"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-17T03:59:58Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the Senate reported version is repeated here.)

United States Commission on International Religious Freedom Reauthorization Act of 2015

This bill reauthorizes the U.S.&#160;Commission on International Religious Freedom (USCIRF) through FY2019.

(Sec. 2) It expresses the sense of Congress that USCIRF: (1) was created to independently assess and accurately describe threats to religious freedom around the world; and (2) should ensure that U.S. efforts to advance religious freedom abroad are timely, appropriate to the circumstances, prudent, and effective.

(Sec. 3) The termination date of USCIRF is extended to September 30, 2019.

(Sec. 4) The Chair and Vice Chair of USCIRF must at least biennially carry out a strategic policy and organizational review and submit a strategic plan to Congress concerning: (1) prioritized actions for USCIRF, (2) any changes it considers necessary with regard to the scope, content, and timing of USCIRF's annual report; (3) any changes USCIRF considers necessary with regard to personnel matters; and (4) USCIRF's funding requirements.

If unanimous agreement is not possible, items for inclusion in the strategic plan may, at the joint discretion of the Chair and Vice Chair, be approved by: (1) a majority of Commissioners appointed by an elected official from the political party of the President, and (2) a majority of Commissioners appointed by an elected official from the political party that is not the party of the President.

The Vice Chair for such purposes must be appointed by an elected official from the political party that is different from the political party of the elected official who appointed the Chair.

USCIRF is authorized to implement provisions related to personnel and the annual report that are included in the strategic plan, notwithstanding USCIRF's annual recommendations on U.S. policy options and a current requirement that a decision to employ or terminate an Executive Director be made by an affirmative vote of at least six of USCIRF's nine members.

USCIRF, upon request, must provide testimony and make information available to Congress.

(Sec. 5) USCIRF is authorized to expend appropriated amounts only if it complies with this Act and submits its annual financial report identifying expenditures for the preceding fiscal year.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
