<bill session="114" type="s" number="461" updated="2018-06-05T07:11:27Z">
  <state datetime="2016-11-29">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-11-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cross-Border Trade Enhancement Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Cross-Border Trade Enhancement Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Cross-Border Trade Enhancement Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for alternative financing arrangements for the provision of certain services and the construction and maintenance of infrastructure at land border ports of entry, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Cross-Border Trade Enhancement Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000444" joined="2016-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2016-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2016-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2015-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2016-12-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S931-932" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-05-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-07-12">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="559">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 559.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-08-30">
      <text>By Senator Johnson from Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs filed written report under authority of the order of the Senate of 07/14/2016. Report No. 114-303.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-29">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6573-6575" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6573-6575" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-29">
      <text>The committee substitute withdrawn by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6575" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2016-11-29" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-11-30">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-30T12:02:19-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-30T15:15:50-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="208"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="875"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6381"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural trade"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s5115"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2016-11-29T14:57:18Z" status="Passed Senate amended">Cross-Border Trade Enhancement Act of 2016

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize the U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) to enter into agreements with certain entities for the CBP to provide customs, agricultural processing, border security, or inspection-related immigration services at federal-owned land, or sea or air ports of entry, subject to payment of a fee to reimburse the CBP for providing such services. The bill prescribes requirements for the termination of CBP services and the imposition of a penalty after notice and demand for payment of fees not timely paid by an entity.

The CBP and the General Services Administration may enter into an agreement with an entity to accept donations of:

 personal property, money, or nonpersonal services for use in the purchase and installation of furniture and other equipment at new or existing sea or air ports of entry or new or existing federal-owned land ports of entry; or real property or money for use in the construction or maintenance of such facilities. The CBP shall establish, and make available to the public, criteria for evaluating a proposal to enter into agreements to accept donations.

CBP and the Government Accountability Office shall report annually to specified congressional committees on CBP fee agreements and donations.

(Sec. 3) Modifies CBP reporting requirements under the Trade Facilitation and Trade Enforcement Act of 2015 to include reporting on reimbursable fee agreements with CBP.

(Sec. 4) The bill amends the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2013, and the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2014, to repeal:

 CBP authority to enter into reimbursable fee agreements for a period of up to five years, and the partnership pilot program allowing CBP to enter into partnerships with the private sector and government entities at ports of entry for certain CBP services and to accept certain donations. (Sec. 5) The bill amends the Anti-Border Corruption Act of 2010 to permit the CBP to waive certain polygraph examination requirements for certain qualifying applicants for law enforcement positions with CBP.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-303</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
