<bill session="115" type="h" number="7342" updated="2019-04-18T16:29:00Z">
  <state datetime="2018-12-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to protect children's health by denying any deduction for advertising and marketing directed at children to promote the consumption of food of poor nutritional quality.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Subsidizing Childhood Obesity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Subsidizing Childhood Obesity Act</title>
    <title type="display">Stop Subsidizing Childhood Obesity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000216"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-12-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business expenses"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Fruit and vegetables"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-12-19T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop Subsidizing Childhood Obesity Act

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to deny a tax deduction for advertising or marketing&#160;directed at children (age 14 or under) for food of poor nutritional quality or a brand primarily associated&#160;with food of poor nutritional quality. The bill also denies a deduction for related expenses, including:

 travel; goods or services constituting entertainment, amusement, or recreation; gifts; or other promotion expenses. The Department of the Treasury must enter into a contract with the National Academy of Medicine to develop procedures to evaluate and identify food of poor nutritional quality and brands that are primarily associated with such food.

The bill authorizes additional funding to carry out the Fresh Fruit and Vegetable Program under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
