<bill session="114" type="s" number="2899" updated="2018-06-02T07:18:34Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Zika Response and Regulatory Relief Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to remove Federal barriers to combating mosquito-borne transmission of the Zika virus and promote public health, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Zika Response and Regulatory Relief Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Insects"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Zika Response and Regulatory Relief Act 

This bill amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) by revising requirements for state permit programs under the national pollutant discharge elimination system (NPDES).

The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) must waive for 180 days after this bill's enactment: (1) state NPDES permit requirements for public health pesticide applications of a mosquito control program, and (2) certain reporting requirements for such pesticide applications in permits issued by the EPA before this bill's enactment. The EPA may extend the period during which permit and reporting requirements may be waived for up to an additional 180 days beyond the original period to protect the public health.

States administering NPDES programs must also waive reporting requirements with respect to the pesticide applications during those periods.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
