<bill session="113" type="h" number="1909" updated="2016-10-25T16:03:14Z">
  <state datetime="2013-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Export Coordination Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Export Enhancement Act of 1988 to make improvements to the trade promotion policies and programs of the United States Government.</title>
    <title type="display">Export Coordination Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000546"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2013-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000266" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001092" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001051" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001053" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000362" joined="2013-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000569" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001149" joined="2013-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001182" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000470" joined="2013-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Terrorism, Nonproliferation, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Terrorism,  Nonproliferation, and Trade" code="HSFA18" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1179"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-05-09T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Export Coordination Act of 2013 - Amends the Export Enhancement Act of 1988 to revise the duties of the Trade Promotion Coordinating Committee (TPCC).

Requires the TPCC to: (1) identify opportunities to consolidate or co-locate offices of federal agencies involved in export promotion and export financing activities; (2) assess the use and coordination of electronic databases among federal agencies in support of such activities; and (3) provide a detailed listing of current and future federal and state-led trade missions, trade fairs, and related activities to ensure better delivery of services to U.S. businesses.

Requires the Secretary of Commerce to make available information on federal and state-led trade missions, trade fairs, and related activities on the Export.gov website.

Requires the governmentwide strategic plan for federal trade promotion efforts to: (1) clearly identify and explain the role, goals, and objectives of each TPCC member agency with respect its export promotion and export financing activities; (2) include the recommendations of the Comptroller General relating to coordination of the TPCC and member agencies; and (3) reflect the recommendations of the U.S. Travel Association (currently, U.S. National Tourism Organization) to the degree considered appropriate by the TPCC.

Revises membership of the TPCC to include representatives from the Millennium Challenge Corporation, as well as one or more presidential appointees representing state trade promotion agencies.

Requires the Inspector General of the Department of Commerce to report annually to Congress on the extent to which the TPCC is successfully carrying out its duties.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
