<bill session="114" type="h" number="6063" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:39Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">911 Emergency Service Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 to require investment advisers who advise a private fund that owns an emergency services company to disclose to the Securities and Exchange Commission the average response times of emergency vehicles deployed by such company in response to 9-1-1 calls, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">911 Emergency Service Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000474"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">911 Emergency Service Protection Act

This bill amends the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 to require each investment adviser who is required to file annual or other reports under such Act and who advises a private fund that owns a controlling interest in an emergency services company to disclose to the Securities and Exchange Commission, at least annually:

 the change in the average response time of emergency vehicles since the private fund acquired a controlling interest in the company, the percentage of response times of emergency vehicles deployed by the company to a unit of local government that do not meet a required response time established by a contract for emergency services between the company and such local government, and a description of the impact of any such response time failure on the value of the company to the private fund.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
