<bill session="114" type="h" number="720" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:35Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-24">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Gerardo Hernandez Airport Security Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Gerardo Hernandez Airport Security Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Gerardo Hernandez Airport Security Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gerardo Hernandez Airport Security Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Gerardo Hernandez Airport Security Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve intergovernmental planning for and communication during security incidents at domestic airports, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Gerardo Hernandez Airport Security Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2015-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001067" joined="2015-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2015-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000602" joined="2015-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2015-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000474" joined="2015-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000187" joined="2015-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-10T17:18:23-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Katko moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-10T17:18:45-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H894-897" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-10T17:18:46-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 720.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-10T17:32:54-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-10T19:00:07-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H898-899" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="70" datetime="2015-02-10T19:08:09-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 411 - 1 (Roll no. 70).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H894-895" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-02-10T19:08:10-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-11">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-02-26">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-07-23">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Thune with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 114-92.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-07-23" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="163">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 163.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2015-08-05" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6422-6423" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6422-6423" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-08-06">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-16T15:12:25-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Katko moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5990-5993" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-16T15:12:35-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the Senate amendment to H.R. 720.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="pingpong" datetime="2015-09-16T15:26:13-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5990-5991" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-09-16T15:26:14-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2015-09-17">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2015-09-24" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="114-50" type="public" datetime="2015-09-24">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 114-50.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Transportation and Maritime Security" code="HSHM07" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-25T03:59:58Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on August 5, 2015. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Gerardo Hernandez Airport Security Act of 2015 

 (Sec. 3) Directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) of the Department of Homeland Security to: (1) conduct outreach to all U.S. airports at which the TSA performs, or oversees the implementation and performance of, security measures; and (2) give necessary technical assistance to verify that such airports have in place individualized working plans for responding to security incidents inside the airport perimeter, including active shooters, acts of terrorism, and incidents that target passenger-screening checkpoints.

Requires the TSA to report to Congress on the outreach findings, including an analysis of the level of preparedness such airports have to respond to such incidents.

 (Sec. 4) Requires the TSA to: (1) identify best practices that exist across airports for security incident planning, management, and training; and (2) establish a mechanism through which to share those best practices with other airport operators nationwide.

(Sec. 5) Requires the TSA also to: (1) certify annually to specified congressional committees that all screening personnel have participated in practical training exercises for active shooter scenarios, and (2) analyze for those same committees how TSA can use cost savings achieved through efficiencies to increase over the next five fiscal years the funding available for checkpoint screening law enforcement support reimbursable agreements.

(Sec. 7) Directs the TSA to: (1) conduct outreach to all passenger transportation agencies and providers with high-risk facilities to verify that they have in place plans for responding to active shooters, acts of terrorism, or other security-related incidents that target passengers; and (2) identify best practices for security incident planning, management, and training and establish a mechanism through which to share such practices with passenger transportation agencies nationwide.

(Sec. 8) Declares that no additional appropriations are authorized to carry out this Act. Requires this Act to be carried out using amounts otherwise available.

(Sec. 9) Requires the TSA to review the interoperable communications capabilities of law enforcement, fire, and medical personnel responsible for responding to security incidents at all U.S. airports at which the TSA performs, or oversees the implementation and performance of, security measures.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-92</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
