<bill session="114" type="s" number="3344" updated="2018-06-02T07:48:11Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Innovation for Tomorrow's Workforce Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 to encourage innovation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Innovation for Tomorrow's Workforce Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2016-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5587"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Innovation for Tomorrow's Workforce Act

This bill amends the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 to authorize the Department of Education to award early-phase, mid-phase, or expansion grants to eligible entities, including local educational agencies and area career and technical education (CTE) schools, to:

 create, develop, implement, or take to scale evidence-based, field initiated innovations, including through a pay for success initiative to improve CTE student outcomes; and evaluate such innovations rigorously. Funding under the Act may be used by eligible agencies for state leadership activities and by eligible recipients for local uses to support CTE programs to:

 make all forms of instructional content widely available, which may include the use of open educational resources; and support pay for success initiatives. Funding under the Act may also be used by eligible agencies for state leadership activities to provide or support work-based learning opportunities for students, which may include employer-led training resulting in recognized credential and apprenticeship programs for such students. Funds received for local use shall be used for such activities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
