<bill session="114" type="s" number="385" updated="2018-06-02T06:33:03Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Biennial Appropriations Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for a biennial appropriations process with the exception of defense spending and to enhance oversight and the performance of the Federal Government.</title>
    <title type="display">Biennial Appropriations Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000285"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2015-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000174" joined="2015-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2015-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2015-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="150"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Biennial Appropriations Act 

This bill amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to change the annual appropriations process to a biennial process for nondefense spending. Congress must consider the defense appropriations bill annually and the remaining appropriations bills in either odd-numbered or even-numbered years. In each year that the appropriations bill for an agency is not considered, Congress must conduct oversight hearings.

The bill requires the congressional budget resolution to be accompanied by committee allocations for biennial appropriations and the President's budget to include details that reflect the biennial process.

It also creates a point of order against considering: (1) legislation authorizing appropriations for less than two years unless the program requires no further appropriations and will be completed after appropriations are expended, and (2) authorization or revenue legislation until Congress completes action on the budget resolution, appropriations bills, and reconciliation bills.

The Office of Management and Budget must report to Congress on the impact and feasibility of a biennial budget process.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
