<bill session="113" type="h" number="398" updated="2016-10-25T15:58:11Z">
  <state datetime="2013-01-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Halt in Pay Increases and Cut Congressional Pay Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reduce the rate of pay for Members of Congress by 10 percent and to eliminate automatic pay adjustments for Members.</title>
    <title type="display">Congressional Halt in Pay Increases and Cut Congressional Pay Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000565"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001286" joined="2013-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000368" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001171" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001191" joined="2013-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-23">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-01-23T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Congressional Halt in Pay Increases and Cut Congressional Pay Act - Amends the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 to provide that, as of the beginning of the first applicable pay period commencing after the next regularly scheduled general election for federal office following the enactment of this Act, the annual rate of pay for Members of Congress shall be equal to the annual rate of pay for that position as of the date on which that general election is held, reduced by 10%. (Thus eliminates the automatic pay adjustments for Members of Congress, and reduces their compensation by 10%.)</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
