<bill session="114" type="s" number="1977" updated="2018-06-02T06:59:11Z">
  <state datetime="2015-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gun Violence Intervention Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide family members and close associates of an individual who they fear is a danger to himself, herself, or others new tools to prevent gun violence.</title>
    <title type="display">Gun Violence Intervention Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000711"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2015-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2015-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2015-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2015-09-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-08-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-08-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="410"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-08-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Gun Violence Intervention Act of 2015

This bill amends the federal criminal code to prohibit an individual who has been issued a gun violence prevention order from owning, purchasing, possessing, or receiving any firearms. In addition, no person may sell ammunition to any individual subject to a prevention order.

The bill is designed to allow family members and associates to petition a court to issue a gun violence prevention order to any individual who may pose a danger to themselves or others. States are allowed to temporarily seize firearms from individuals who have been issued a prevention order. Individuals who have their firearms seized are given an opportunity to petition the court for an order allowing them to regain possession of their firearms.

The Department of Justice's Office of Community Oriented Policing Services is authorized to issue grant funds to assist states in implementing this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
