<bill session="114" type="h" number="6076" updated="2018-08-16T22:57:55Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-07T17:13:40-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-12-07T17:13:40-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">To Research, Evaluate, Assess, and Treat Astronauts Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TREAT Astronauts Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">To Research, Evaluate, Assess, and Treat Astronauts Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">TREAT Astronauts Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration to establish a program for the medical monitoring, diagnosis, and treatment of astronauts, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">TREAT Astronauts Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001291"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000374" joined="2016-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001283" joined="2016-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000290" joined="2016-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000126" joined="2016-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000387" joined="2016-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000593" joined="2016-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2016-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000583" joined="2016-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2016-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-09-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-12-07T14:44:33-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Babin moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-07T14:44:46-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7306-7310" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-07T14:44:47-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6076.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-07T15:07:18-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-07T17:07:01-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7324-7325" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="614" datetime="2016-12-07T17:13:40-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 413 - 0 (Roll no. 614).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7306-7307" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-12-07T17:13:41-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3346"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6531"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-07T16:50:18Z" status="Passed House amended">To Research, Evaluate, Assess, and Treat Astronauts Act or the TREAT Astronauts Act

(Sec. 3) This bill authorizes the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) to provide for:

 the medical monitoring and diagnosis of a former U.S. government astronaut or former payload specialist for conditions that NASA considers potentially associated with human space flight; and the treatment of such an astronaut or payload specialist for conditions that NASA considers associated with human space flight, including scientific and medical tests for psychological and medical conditions. The bill requires that such medical monitoring, diagnosis, or treatment shall be provided without any deductible, copayment, or other cost sharing obligation.

NASA may not require such an astronaut or payload specialist to participate in the medical monitoring, diagnosis, or treatment authorized by this bill.

NASA shall protect the privacy of all medical records generated with respect to such medical monitoring, diagnosis, and treatment and accessible to NASA.

The term "government astronaut" does not include individuals who are international partner astronauts.

NASA shall arrange with an independent external organization to undertake an independent cost estimate of the cost to NASA and the federal government for the implementation and administration of the activities of NASA under this bill.

NASA shall study any potential privacy or legal issues related to the possible sharing beyond the federal government of data acquired under the activities of NASA.

The NASA Inspector General shall periodically audit or review NASA's activities to prevent waste, fraud, and abuse.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
