<bill session="114" type="h" number="2451" updated="2018-06-02T03:42:30Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Buy America Update Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 23 and title 49, United States Code, to strengthen domestic content standards, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Buy America Update Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001286" joined="2015-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000624" joined="2015-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001038" joined="2015-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000295" joined="2015-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000368" joined="2015-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000581" joined="2015-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2015-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2015-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Highways and Transit" code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Aviation" code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-19T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Buy America Update Act

This bill exempts from Buy America requirements the procurement of railroad rolling stock when:

 the cost of components and subcomponents produced in the United States is more than 60% of the cost of all components of the rolling stock; and final assembly of such rolling stock has occurred in the United States. The Department of Transportation (DOT) shall initiate a rulemaking to develop audit procedures for an agency to review rolling stock offeror and recipient compliance with domestic content requirements, and issue guidance on best practices for pre-award and post-delivery audits by recipients.

Before seeking a Buy America waiver request, Amtrak shall contract with the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) to conduct a supplier scouting process for domestic suppliers that can provide the compliant products for which a waiver will be sought. DOT must consider Amtrak's scouting report before deciding on the request.

Before issuing the Federal Aviation Administration a waiver of Buy America requirements, DOT shall consult with the NIST and begin a supplier scouting process for domestic suppliers that can provide for compliant aviation products for which a waiver will be sought.

DOT may approve an airport improvement project financed with passenger facility charges only if steel and manufactured goods used in the project are produced in the United States.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
