<bill session="114" type="h" number="1206" updated="2018-11-09T00:09:26Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-20T16:00:34-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-04-20T16:00:34-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Hires for the Delinquent IRS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">No Hires for the Delinquent IRS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">No Hires for the Delinquent IRS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the hiring of additional Internal Revenue Service employees until the Secretary of the Treasury certifies that no employee of the Internal Revenue Service has a seriously delinquent tax debt.</title>
    <title type="display">No Hires for the Delinquent IRS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000603"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000372" joined="2016-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2015-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001293" joined="2016-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001103" joined="2015-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001076" joined="2016-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000291" joined="2015-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000461" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2015-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001067" joined="2015-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2015-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001156" joined="2015-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001187" joined="2015-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000189" joined="2015-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000168" joined="2015-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000592" joined="2015-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000611" joined="2015-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2015-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000587" joined="2015-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000582" joined="2015-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001189" joined="2015-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2016-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000819" joined="2015-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2015-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000065" joined="2015-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000018" joined="2015-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-04-18">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 114-499.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-18" calendar="Union" number="381">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 381.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-04-18T18:58:31-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 687 Reported to House. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Resolution provides for the consideration of H.R. 1206 and H.R. 4885.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-20T13:15:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Smith (MO) asked unanimous consent that the question of adopting a motion to recommit on H.R. 1206 may be subject to postponement as though under clause 8 of rule 20.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1868" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-20T13:16:06-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 687.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1868-1874, H1874-1876" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-20T13:16:11-04:00">
      <text>Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Resolution provides for the consideration of H.R. 1206 and H.R. 4885.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-20T13:17:24-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 1206.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-20T14:10:02-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1873" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-20T14:10:10-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Kildee moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1873-1874, H1874-1875" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1873" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-20T14:10:28-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kildee motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to insert a special rule of applicability which shall not apply for any year if the Federal tax delinquecny rate for either chamber of Congress is greater than the Federal delinquency tax rate for the Dept. of Treasury, as published by the IRS in its Federal Employee/Retireee Delinquency Initiative (FERDI) for the prior year.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-20T14:17:50-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1874, H1875" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-20T14:17:58-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.R. 1206, the Chair put the question on adoption of the motion to recommit and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Kildee demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceeding on the motion to recommit until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-20T15:31:50-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1874-1876" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-20T15:53:14-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 177 - 245 (Roll no. 159).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="160" datetime="2016-04-20T16:00:34-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 254 - 170 (Roll no. 160).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1868" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-04-20T16:00:35-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-21">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="434">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 434.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="303"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1563"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5005"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="114" relation="unknown" number="687"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h978"/>
    <amendment number="h977"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2016-04-20T21:00:20Z" status="Passed House amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on April 18, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

No Hires for the Delinquent IRS Act 

(Sec. 2) This bill prohibits any federal officer or employee from hiring any Internal Revenue Service (IRS) employees until the IRS submits to Congress either: (1) a written certification that the IRS does not employ any individual who has a seriously delinquent tax debt, or (2) a report detailing why the certification cannot be made and necessary remedial actions.

A seriously delinquent tax debt is an outstanding tax debt for which the IRS has filed a notice of lien in public records, excluding a tax debt: (1) that is being paid in a timely manner under an approved installment payment agreement or an offer-in-compromise, (2) for which a collection due process hearing has been requested or is pending, (3) for which a tax levy has been issued, or (4) with respect to which relief has been granted due to economic hardship.

If the IRS is unable to provide the required certification, it may submit to Congress a report that:

 states that the certification cannot be made, explains why the certification is not possible, outlines remedial actions required to provide a certification, and indicates the time required for the actions to be completed. (Sec. 3) No additional funds are authorized to carry out the requirements of this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-499</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
