<bill session="113" type="h" number="2571" updated="2016-10-25T16:05:21Z">
  <state datetime="2013-11-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-11-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consumer Right to Financial Privacy Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Consumer Right to Financial Privacy Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act to require the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection to notify and obtain permission from consumers before collecting nonpublic personal information about such consumers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Consumer Right to Financial Privacy Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000614"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2013-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001058" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000111" joined="2013-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001182" joined="2013-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000586" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001188" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000796" joined="2013-07-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-29">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit Prior to Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-11-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 32 - 25.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-02-06">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 113-344.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-02-06" calendar="Union" number="254">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 254.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" code="HSBA15" name="House Financial Services" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-02-06T15:10:13Z" status="Reported to House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Consumer Right to Financial Privacy Act of 2013 - (Sec. 1) Amends the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act to revise the prohibition against the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB)'s obtaining, from a covered person or service provider, any personally identifiable financial information about a consumer.

(Sec. 2) Prohibits the CFPB, in addition, from requesting, accessing, collecting, using, retaining, or disclosing nonpublic personal information about a consumer unless: (1) the CFPB clearly and conspicuously discloses to the consumer, in writing or in an electronic form, what information will be requested, obtained, accessed, collected, used, retained, or disclosed; and (2) the consumer informs the CFPB, before such information is requested, obtained, accessed, collected, used, retained, or disclosed, that such information may be requested, obtained, accessed, collected, used, retained, or disclosed.

 Subjects to the same restrictions and conditions any person directed or engaged by the CFPB to collect such information on its behalf.

(Sec. 3) Amends the Right to Financial Privacy Act of 1978 to repeal the exemption from its application for CFPB examination or disclosure of financial records or information in the exercise of CFPB authority with respect to a financial institution (thus applying the Act to CFPB examinations and disclosures).</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 113-344</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
