<bill session="115" type="h" number="4642" updated="2019-04-18T16:18:59Z">
  <state datetime="2017-12-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Veterans Access, Choice, and Accountability Act of 2014 to include in the Veterans Choice Program all veterans enrolled in the patient enrollment system of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Improved Access and Care Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Improved Access and Care Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Veterans Improved Access and Care Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000470"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-12-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="2168"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-12-14T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans Improved Access and Care Act of 2017

This bill amends the Veterans Access, Choice, and Accountability Act of 2014 to provide access to hospital care and medical services in non-Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) facilities for all veterans who are enrolled in the VA health care system. (Currently, such access is based upon appointment wait times and distance from, or existence of, VA facilities.)

The VA shall: (1) establish a pilot program to expedite the Veterans Health Administration (VHA) process for bringing on a medical provider after such person is offered a tentative VHA position (onboarding), (2) give priority to medical facilities facing hiring shortages of licensed independent medical providers, and (3) submit to Congress a strategy for reducing the length of the medical provider hiring process by half.

The bill requires that certain personal information be transmitted to the National Practitioner Data Bank and the applicable state licensing board whenever a major adverse action based upon performance or conduct is taken against certain VHA health care employees.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
