<bill session="113" type="h" number="1663" updated="2018-06-05T16:15:45Z">
  <state datetime="2013-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PARTS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Automotive Repair, Trade, and Sales Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 35, United States Code, to provide for an exception from infringement for certain component parts of motor vehicles.</title>
    <title type="display">PARTS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2013-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000258" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000593" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000244" joined="2014-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="identical" number="780"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-04-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Promoting Automotive Repair, Trade, and Sales Act of 2013 or PARTS Act - Makes it not an act of infringement, with respect to a design patent that claims a component part of a motor vehicle as originally manufactured, to: (1) make, test, or offer to sell within the United States, or import into the United States, any article of manufacture that is similar or the same in appearance to the component part claimed in such design patent if the purpose of such article is for the repair of a motor vehicle to restore its appearance to as originally manufactured; and (2) use or sell within the United States any such same or similar articles for such restorations more than 30 months after the claimed component part is first offered for public sale as part of a motor vehicle in any country.

Defines "component part" as a component part of the exterior of a motor vehicle only (such as a hood, fender, tail light, side mirror, or quarter panel), excluding an inflatable restraint system or other component part located in the interior of a motor vehicle.

Specifies that an offer to sell includes any marketing of an article of manufacture to prospective purchasers or users and any pre-sale distribution.

Applies this Act to any patent issued, or application filed, before, on, or after the effective date of this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
