<bill session="115" type="s" number="2201" updated="2019-04-18T16:40:39Z">
  <state datetime="2017-12-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-12-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-12-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to improve college access and college completion for all students.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Access, Success, and Persistence in Reshaping Education Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Access, Success, and Persistence in Reshaping Education Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ASPIRE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ASPIRE Act</title>
    <title type="display">ASPIRE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2017-12-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-12-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-12-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Access, Success, and Persistence in Reshaping Education Act of 2017 or the ASPIRE Act

This bill amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 by requiring the Department of Education (ED) to rank institutions of higher education (IHEs) based on the percentage of first-time, full-time students who receive Pell Grants and are enrolled at the IHEs. The IHEs in the bottom 5% must improve the enrollment of those students by specific deadlines or pay a fee-per-student penalty.

Additionally, ED must rank IHEs based on the percentage of first-time, full-time students who enroll at the school and graduate within 6 years. The bill gives IHEs in the bottom 5% the option of receiving funding to improve student graduation rates. Those IHEs must improve those rates by specific deadlines or pay a penalty.

The bill establishes consumer warning requirements for IHEs with low enrollment or graduation rates.

ED must establish: (1) grant programs for improving graduation rates, and (2) a bonus program for providing nonfinancial rewards to IHEs that make college more affordable and increase college access and success for low-income or working class students and moderate-income students.

ED must collect the penalty fees and use them to fund the grant and award program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
