<bill session="114" type="s" number="3228" updated="2018-06-02T07:47:33Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Assessing Coastal Areas to Assist States Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Army to conduct a study of coastal areas in the South Atlantic Division of the Corps of Engineers to identify risks and vulnerabilities of those areas as a result of sea level rise, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Assessing Coastal Areas to Assist States Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2016-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2848"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Assessing Coastal Areas to Assist States Act

This bill directs the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers to conduct a study to identify the risks and vulnerabilities of the coastal areas located within the geographic boundaries of the South Atlantic Division of the Corps of Engineers to increased hurricane and storm damage as a result of sea level rise.

In carrying out the study, the Corps of Engineers shall: (1) conduct necessary analyses, with special emphasis on regional sediment management as a method to sustainably maintain or enhance current levels of storm protection to produce a comprehensive understanding of coastal vulnerabilities in the affected areas and to identify initial measures to address such vulnerabilities; and (2) develop a long-term strategy for addressing such increased damage and for identifying opportunities to enhance resiliency, increase sustainability, and lower risks in population centers, areas of concentrated economic development, and areas with vulnerable environmental resources.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
