<bill session="114" type="h" number="1186" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:37Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SALTS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Synthetic Abuse and Labeling of Toxic Substances Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Controlled Substances Act relating to controlled substance analogues.</title>
    <title type="display">SALTS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000238"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2015-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2015-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1327"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-27T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Synthetic Abuse and Labeling of Toxic Substances Act of 2015 or the SALTS Act

Amends the Controlled Substances Act to authorize the following factors to be considered in determining whether a controlled substance analogue was intended for human consumption:

 the marketing, advertising, and labeling of the substance; the known efficacy or usefulness of the substance for the marketed, advertised, or labeled purpose; the difference between the price at which the substance is sold and the price at which the substance it is purported to be or advertised as is normally sold; the diversion of the substance from legitimate channels and the clandestine importation, manufacture, or distribution of the substance; whether the defendant knew or should have known that the substance was intended to be consumed by injection, inhalation, ingestion, or any other immediate means; and whether the substance is manufactured, formulated, sold, distributed, or marketed with the intent to avoid the provisions of existing drug laws. Declares that evidence that a substance was not marketed, advertised, or labeled for human consumption shall not by itself be sufficient to establish that the substance was not intended for human consumption.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
