<bill session="114" type="s" number="2278" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:36Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote the availability of additional unlicensed spectrum for innovation and investment, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Unlicensed Spectrum Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Promoting Unlicensed Spectrum Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Promoting Unlicensed Spectrum Act of 2015 

This bill requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to ensure that spectrum allocation and assignment produces a balance between radio frequency bands available for: (1) exclusive licensing through an auction, and (2) unlicensed operations on a nonexclusive basis without the expectation of protection from interference.

The FCC must consider whether to adopt rules that permit unlicensed operations in spectrum assigned by auction until the licensee brings the spectrum into use by initiating commercial service.

The bill declares that it is the policy of the United States to:

 maximize the utility of the spectrum resources of the United States, advance innovation and investment in wireless broadband services, and promote a balanced spectrum policy that makes adequate spectrum resources available for both licensed and unlicensed technologies. The FCC must consult with the National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA) to develop a national strategy for making additional radio frequency bands available for unlicensed operations. The strategy must: (1) identify proposed radio frequency bands to be cleared of incumbent users; (2) ensure that consumers have access to additional low-, mid-, and high-band frequencies for unlicensed operations; and (3) consider rules and other ways to promote spectrum sharing and improve spectrum utilization.

The NTIA, in conjunction with the FCC and the Office of Management and Budget, must submit to Congress a report on the steps necessary to designate additional radio frequency bands used by federal entities for unlicensed operations without causing harmful interference to government operations. The report must consider the impact on homeland security or national security communications and include recommendations to ensure the solvency of the Spectrum Relocation Fund.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
