<bill session="114" type="s" number="2718" updated="2018-06-02T07:16:05Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Perkins Fund for Equity and Excellence</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 to support innovative approaches to career and technical education and redesign the high school experience for students by providing students with equitable access to rigorous, engaging, and relevant real world education through partnerships with business and industry and higher education that prepare students to graduate from high school and enroll into postsecondary education without the need for remediation and with the ability to use knowledge to solve complex problems, think critically, communicate effectively, collaborate with others, and develop academic mindsets.</title>
    <title type="display">Perkins Fund for Equity and Excellence</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000384"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2016-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2016-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2016-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2016-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1598" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Perkins Fund for Equity and Excellence

This bill amends the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 to&#160;replace the existing Tech Prep program with a new competitive grant program to support career and technical education.&#160;Under the program,&#160;local educational agencies&#160;and their&#160;partners may apply for grant funding to support:

 career and technical education programs that are aligned with postsecondary education programs, dual or concurrent enrollment programs and early college programs, certain evidence-based strategies and delivery models related to career and technical education, teacher and leader experiential and informational-gathering site visits, professional development of educators and business partners, structured interdisciplinary collaboration and common planning time, teacher and leader externship programs, cross-credentialing for teachers, paid student internships or other paid work-based learning experiences, and guidance counseling. Unless granted a waiver, a grant recipient must provide specified matching funds in the fourth and fifth years of the five-year grant.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
