<bill session="115" type="h" number="6773" updated="2019-04-18T16:27:18Z">
  <state datetime="2018-09-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-09-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-09-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to issue rules requiring the inclusion of new safety equipment in school buses, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">School Bus Safety Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">School Bus Safety Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">School Bus Safety Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001068"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-09-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1236"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Highways and Transit" code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="3432"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-09-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">School Bus Safety Act of 2018

This bill requires the Department of Transportation (DOT) to issue rules prescribing or amending motor vehicle safety standards to require school buses with a gross vehicle weight rating of greater than 10,000 pounds to be equipped with a three-point safety belt at each designated seating position. DOT shall also issue rules to require (1) school buses to be equipped with an automatic emergency braking system, an event data recorder, and an electronic stability control system; and (2) at least 30 hours of behind-the-wheel instruction for school bus operators.

The Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration and the Federal Railroad Administration shall publish a final rule entitled "Evaluation of Safety Sensitive Personnel for Moderate-to-Severe Obstructive Sleep Apnea."

The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) shall complete a study of the benefits of requiring school buses to be equipped with a motion-activated detection system that can detect pedestrians located near the exterior of the school bus and alert the bus operator of the pedestrians. The NHTSA must also study the benefits of requiring school buses to have a system that alerts the operator if a passenger is not wearing a three-point safety belt.

The bill requires DOT to establish a grant program to assist local educational agencies to purchase school buses equipped with three-point safety belts at each designated seating position and assist them in modifying existing school buses to be equipped with such belts.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
