<bill session="114" type="h" number="6057" updated="2019-05-09T23:15:21Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit contributions and expenditures by multicandidate political committees controlled by foreign-owned corporations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ethics in Foreign Lobbying Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="display">Ethics in Foreign Lobbying Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000009"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Ethics in Foreign Lobbying Act of 2016

 This bill amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit contributions and expenditures in federal elections by multicandidate political committees or separate segregated funds sponsored by foreign-controlled corporations and associations (at least 50% owned by a non-U.S. citizen or foreign national). Ownership and operating fund reporting requirements are set forth.

 A foreign national Floor Agenda Team may not participate in the decision-making process of any person's election-related activities (such as those of a corporation, labor organization, or political committee).

The bill establishes within the Federal Election Commission (FEC) a clearinghouse of existing public information regarding the political activities of foreign principals and agents of foreign principals.

 The Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938 is amended to: (1) revise foreign agents' supplemental reporting requirements, and (2) provide civil penalties for specified reporting violations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
