<bill session="113" type="s" number="2031" updated="2016-10-25T16:28:53Z">
  <state datetime="2014-11-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-11-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ashland Breakwater Light Transfer Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Ashland Breakwater Light Transfer Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Act to provide for the establishment of the Apostle Islands National Lakeshore in the State of Wisconsin, and for other purposes, to adjust the boundary of that National Lakeshore to include the lighthouse known as Ashland Harbor Breakwater Light, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Ashland Breakwater Light Transfer Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2014-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-23">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-493.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-11-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-10">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Landrieu with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 113-297.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="637">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 637.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks" code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="4049"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Seashores and lakeshores"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-12-10T17:29:15Z" status="Reported to Senate amended">Ashland Breakwater Light Transfer Act - Adjusts the boundary of the Apostle Islands National Lakeshore in Wisconsin to include the Ashland Harbor Breakwater Light Addition at the end of the breakwater on Chequamegon Bay, Wisconsin.

Declares that Congress does not intend for the designation of that property to create a protective perimeter or buffer zone around its boundary.

Authorizes the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating to operate, maintain, keep, locate, inspect, repair, and replace any federal aid to navigation located at the Ashland Harbor Breakwater Light for as long as it is needed for navigational purposes.

Permits the Secretary to enter, at any time, the Ashland Harbor Breakwater Light or any federal aid to navigation at the Breakwater Light, for as long as such aid is needed for navigational purposes, without notice to the extent that it is not possible to provide advance notice.

Authorizes the Secretary to enter into agreements with the city of Ashland and the County of Bayfield, Wisconsin, for the purpose of cooperative law enforcement and emergency services within the boundaries of the Lakeshore.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 113-297</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
