<bill session="114" type="h" number="1456" updated="2019-01-09T21:25:56Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Biennial Budgeting and Appropriations Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide a biennial budget for the United States Government.</title>
    <title type="display">Biennial Budgeting and Appropriations Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000413"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2015-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001187" joined="2015-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="150"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1610"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="House Committee on the Budget"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Senate Committee on the Budget"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Biennial Budgeting and Appropriations Act of 2015

This bill amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974, the Congressional Budget Impoundment and Control Act of 1974, and the Rules of the House of Representatives to change the process for the President's budget submission, congressional budget resolutions, appropriations bills, and government strategic and performance plans from the current annual process to a biennial process, in which a biennium is the two consecutive fiscal years beginning on October 1 of any odd-numbered year.

The Congressional Budget Office must submit to Congress a quarterly analysis comparing revenues, spending, and the deficit or surplus for the current fiscal year to assumptions included in the congressional budget resolution.

The House Budget Committee must use the second session of each Congress to study issues with long-term budgetary and economic implications.

The bill creates a point of order in the House and Senate against authorizations of appropriations that do not include specific authorizations covering at least each fiscal year in one or more bienniums.

The Office of Management and Budget must report to Congress on the impact and feasibility of changing the definition of a fiscal year and the budget process based on that definition to a two-year fiscal period.

The bill requires the biennial process to take effect beginning with the FY2020 budget process and sets forth procedures and requirements for a transition period during the 115th Congress.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
