<bill session="115" type="s" number="1476" updated="2019-04-18T16:37:36Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to safeguard the United States and our allies from Russian ballistic and cruise missile threats, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Countering Russian Missiles Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Countering Russian Missiles Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Countering Russian Missiles Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Countering Russian Missiles Act of 2017

This bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to submit annual reports on:

 the status of the Russian Federation's new SSC-8 ground-launched cruise missile, its capabilities, and the threat it poses to the European and Asian allies of the United States and U.S. assets in the region; whether the United States faces significant military disadvantages with the introduction of the SSC-8 to the European continent; gaps in the current U.S. missile defense infrastructure in Europe; gaps in capability that a new U.S. intermediate range missile, that is not compliant with the Treaty between the United States and the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics on the Elimination of Their Intermediate-Range and Shorter-Range Missiles (INF Treaty), would address in Europe and Asia; and the time line for fielding, and the cost for deployment of, an INF range missile. The Department of State must submit an annual report that includes a plan: (1) describing how the United States will coordinate with its European allies to enhance missile detection and defense; and (2) recommending additional foreign military sales, financing, or international military education and training for such allies for strengthening missile defense capabilities.

The bill requires specified consultation by the President and Congress regarding Russian Federation compliance with the treaty.

The bill prohibits any funds from being made available or expended for any action that effects U.S. withdrawal from the treaty unless the President certifies that withdrawal is in U.S. vital national security interests.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
