<bill session="115" type="h" number="4466" updated="2019-04-18T16:18:24Z">
  <state datetime="2017-11-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-11-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-11-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide funding flexibility to the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority, to grant authority to amend the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Compact, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">WMATA Flexible Funding and Safety Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">WMATA Flexible Funding and Safety Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="display">WMATA Flexible Funding and Safety Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001304"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2017-11-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-11-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Antitrust, Commercial, and Administrative Law" code="HSJU05" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Highways and Transit" code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-11-28T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">WMATA Flexible Funding and Safety Improvement Act

This bill amends federal transportation law to authorize the Department of Transportation to make grants to finance the operating cost of equipment and facilities for use in an urbanized area with a population of at least 200,000 for a public transportation system that: (1) operates as an interstate compact agency; and (2) is an agency and instrumentality of three signatories that have enacted legislation to provide a dedicated source of revenue to finance the operating costs of equipment and facilities for use in public transportation and that results in the collection of local and state funds covering at least 50% of such costs.

The consent of Congress is granted for Maryland, Virginia, and the District of Columbia to amend the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Regulation Compact to authorize the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (WMATA) to establish and maintain the Jeanice McMillan WMATA Track Safety Task Force and the Thomasine Maria Smith WMATA Bus Safety Task Force.

The compact may be amended to: (1) direct the Inspector General for the transit authority, prior to the renewal of any private MetroAccess contract by such authority for the provision of demand response services, to conduct a review of the MetroAccess program; and (2) prohibit the authority from renewing the MetroAccess contract unless specified conditions are met. "MetroAcess" is the paratransit service of WMATA for individuals whose disability prevents them from using a bus or rail facility.

The compact may be amended to provide for a flat fare, free transfer pilot program, and an ability-based fares program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
