<bill session="114" type="s" number="1050" updated="2018-06-02T06:45:46Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">INSPIRES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Inspiring New STEM Professionals by Investing in Renovation of Education Spaces Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 by establishing a program to support the modernization, renovation, or repair of career and technical education facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">INSPIRES Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2015-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Inspiring New STEM Professionals by Investing in Renovation of Education Spaces Act or the INSPIRES Act

 Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to direct the Department of Education (ED) to support local educational agencies (LEAs), community colleges, and other appropriate entities in modernizing, renovating, or repairing facilities used to provide science, technology, engineering, mathematics, or career and technical education to public elementary, secondary school, or community college students.

Requires ED to furnish such support by providing eligible entities with grants or loan guarantees or by making payments of interest on the financial instruments they use to fund the modernization, renovation, or repair of those facilities.

Prohibits the use of that support for new construction or the payment of routine maintenance costs.

Requires ED to direct at least 25% of the funds made available under this Act to: (1) public schools or secondary schools served by high-need LEAs, or (2) community colleges that serve a substantial number of rural students.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
