<amendment session="114" chamber="s" number="2910" updated="2018-06-04T17:54:24Z">
  <amends type="h" number="3762" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2015-12-03">offered</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000062"/>
  <offered datetime="2015-12-03"/>
  <description>To increase public safety by permitting the Attorney General to deny the transfer of firearms or the issuance of firearms and explosives licenses to known or suspected dangerous terrorists.</description>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-03">
      <text>Amendment SA 2910 ruled out of order by the chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-03">
      <text>Motion to waive all applicable budgetary discipline with respect to amendment SA 2910 rejected in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 45 - 54. Record Vote Number: 319.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8347" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-03">
      <text>Point of order that the amendment violates section 313(b)(1)(c) of the CBA raised in Senate with respect to amendment SA 2910.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-03">
      <text>Amendment SA 2910 proposed by Senator Feinstein to Amendment SA 2874. (consideration: CR S8346-8347) To increase public safety by permitting the Attorney General to deny the transfer of firearms or the issuance of firearms and explosives licenses to known or suspected dangerous terrorists.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-03"/>
    <action datetime="2015-12-03">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Motion to waive all applicable budgetary discipline with respect to amendment SA 2910 rejected in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 45 - 54. Record Vote Number: 319.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8347" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-03">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 2910 proposed by Senator Feinstein to Amendment SA 2874.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8346-8347" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-03">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
