<bill session="114" type="s" number="1920" updated="2018-06-02T06:58:53Z">
  <state datetime="2015-08-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-08-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-08-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Biennial Report on the Skills Gap Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Comptroller General of the United States to develop and submit to Congress a biennial report on the current state of the skills gap in the United States, as of the date of the report, that includes an analysis of the effectiveness of efforts to close the skills gap and policy recommendations to improve such efforts, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Biennial Report on the Skills Gap Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000607"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2015-08-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-08-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-08-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-08-04T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Biennial Report on the Skills Gap Act of 2015

This bill directs the Government Accountability Office to submit a biennial report on the current state of the skills gap in the United States, including: (1) an analysis of the effectiveness of efforts to close such gap, and (2) policy recommendations to improve such efforts.

The bill defines "skills gap" as the difference between the specific skills set of employees and the skills desired by employers.

Each report may include:

 an analysis of employer participation in apprenticeships and on-the-job training in the United States; an assessment of the Department of Labor's Registered Apprenticeship program to determine if it can be better utilized; an analysis of the prevalence and portability of recognized postsecondary credentials that align with occupations that are in demand; a comparison of policies and strategies addressing the current skills gap in the United States with those employed by other large countries; and an analysis of the specific barriers preventing the U.S. workforce from acquiring the skills desired by U.S. employers, including an assessment of opportunities to reduce those barriers.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
