<bill session="114" type="s" number="2629" updated="2018-06-02T07:15:30Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Global Development Lab Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish in the United States Agency for International Development an entity to be known as the United States Global Development Lab, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Global Development Lab Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2016-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2016-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2016-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2016-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Global Development Lab Act of 2016

This bill establishes in the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) the United States Global Development Lab, whose duties shall include:

 increasing the application of science, technology, innovation and partnerships to develop new solutions to end extreme poverty; discovering and testing development innovations to increase cost effectiveness and support U.S. foreign policy and development goals; leveraging the expertise, resources, and investment of businesses, nongovernmental organizations, science and research organizations, and universities to increase program impact and sustainability; utilizing innovation-driven competitions to expand the number and diversity of solutions to development challenges; and supporting USAID missions and bureaus in applying science, technology, innovation, and partnership approaches to decision making, procurement, and program design.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
