<bill session="114" type="s" number="1000" updated="2018-08-16T23:11:09Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-23">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SCORE for Small Business Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">SCORE for Small Business Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to strengthen resources for entrepreneurs by improving the SCORE program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SCORE for Small Business Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000584"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2015-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2015-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2015-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2015-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2015-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-04-23" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-06-10">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Reported by Senator Vitter with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-06-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="110">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 110.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-04-21">
      <text>By Senator Vitter from Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship filed written report. Report No. 114-242.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4909"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4788"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-10T14:44:04Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">SCORE for Small Business Act of 2015

 (Sec. 2) Amends the Small Business Act to reauthorize the SCORE (Service Corps of Retired Executives) program for FY2015-FY2018 for Small Business Administration (SBA) grants or cooperative agreements that do not exceed a total of $10.5 million in each such fiscal year.

Requires a SCORE program volunteer, based on business experience and knowledge, to:

 provide at no cost to individuals who own, or aspire to own, small businesses personal counseling, mentoring, and coaching relating to the process of starting, expanding, managing, buying, and selling a business; facilitate low-cost education workshops for these individuals; and use appropriate tools, resources, and expertise of other organizations to carry out the SCORE program. Directs the SBA to ensure that the SCORE program and each of its chapters develop and implement plans and goals to more effectively and efficiently provide services to individuals in rural areas, economically disadvantaged communities, and other traditionally underserved communities, including plans for electronic initiatives, web-based initiatives, chapter expansion, partnerships, and development of new skills by SCORE program volunteers.

Bars the SBA and the SCORE Association from disclosing certain personal identifying information on any individual or small business receiving SCORE Association's assistance without the individual's or small business's consent, unless the SBA:

 is ordered to make such a disclosure by a court in any civil or criminal enforcement action initiated by a federal or state agency; or determines such a disclosure to be necessary to conduct a financial audit of the SCORE program, in which case the disclosure shall be limited to the information necessary for the audit. Exempts from these privacy requirements SBA access to program activity data or SBA use of client information to conduct client surveys.

Prohibits the SBA, in carrying out the Entrepreneurship Education Program during each of FY2016-FY2018, from obligating: (1) more than $5 million, and (2) less than $2.5 million to carry out the Emerging Leaders Initiatives.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-242</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
