<bill session="114" type="s" number="869" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:53Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">All-of-the-Above Federal Building Energy Conservation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve energy performance in Federal buildings, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">All-of-the-Above Federal Building Energy Conservation Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000607" joined="2015-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2015-03-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2177"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="720"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">All-Of-The-Above Federal Building Energy Conservation Act of 2015 

 Amends the National Energy Conservation Policy Act to extend energy performance requirements for federal buildings in FY2016-FY2017 (from a 33% reduction from 2003 energy consumption level for FY2016 to a 36% reduction for FY2017).

Requires the Department of Energy (DOE) to review the results of the implementation of such requirements by December 31, 2017 (currently, December 31, 2014) and, based on such review, report to Congress on the feasibility of requiring each agency to apply energy conservation measures to, and improve the design for the construction of, agency buildings to achieve a reduction in energy consumption.

Requires designated facility energy managers to consider using a system to manage energy use at their facilities in accordance with the International Organization for Standardization standard numbered 50001 and entitled "Energy Management Systems."

Establishes exemptions from energy and water evaluation requirements.

 Amends the Energy Conservation and Production Act to revise the definition of "federal building" to include buildings altered by federal agencies, and to define "major renovation," for purposes of such Act. Requires DOE to establish revised federal building energy efficiency performance standards after the approval of revisions of ASHRAE Standard 90.1 or the International Energy Conservation Code (IECC) to meet or exceed such revisions, including requiring, unless new or renovated federal buildings are demonstrated not to be life-cycle cost effective: (1) such buildings to be designed to achieve energy consumption levels that are at least 30% below the levels established in the ASHRAE Standard or the IECC, and (2) no less than 30% of the hot water demand for each new building or building undergoing a major renovation to be met through the installation and use of solar hot water heaters.

Requires DOE to review federal building energy standards once every five years and upgrade to the standards to include all new energy efficiency and renewable energy measures that are technologically feasible and economically justified if DOE determines that significant energy savings would result.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
