<bill session="114" type="hr" number="195" updated="2019-01-29T22:16:12Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives about a national strategy for the Internet of Things to promote economic growth and consumer empowerment.</title>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives about a national strategy for the Internet of Things to promote economic growth and consumer empowerment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000567"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Consumer Protection and Commerce" code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="sr" session="114" relation="unknown" number="110"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="114" relation="unknown" number="847"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that United States should: (1) develop a national strategy to encourage development of the Internet of Things for connected technologies to empower consumers, foster future economic growth, and improve the nation's collective social well-being; (2) recognize the importance of consensus-based best practices and communication among businesses and stakeholders; (3) commit to using the Internet of Things to improve its efficiency and effectiveness and to cut waste, fraud, and abuse; and (4) only address discrete harms in the Internet of Things marketplace when identified pursuant to a cost-benefit analysis revealing that governmental action is necessary.

Calls on U.S. innovators to commit to improving the quality of life for future generations by developing safe, new technologies aimed at tackling the most challenging societal issues facing the world.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
