<bill session="113" type="h" number="5546" updated="2016-10-25T16:16:44Z">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Marine Disease Emergency Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Commerce to identify, declare, and respond to marine disease emergencies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Marine Disease Emergency Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000560" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000510" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-10-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Conservation and Forestry" code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" code="HSII22" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-09-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Marine Disease Emergency Act of 2014 - Authorizes the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to declare and respond to a marine disease emergency (an event that affects the marine environment, is caused by a marine disease or environmental stressor, is likely to threaten the sustainability of a marine species or the health of a marine ecosystem, and is likely to expand in geographic scope).

Requires NOAA to designate an individual to coordinate the response to each emergency and develop and publish a response plan for each emergency within 21 days of the declaration.

Terminates the emergency when NOAA declares that the emergency no longer exists or 120 days after the declaration was made, whichever occurs first. Authorizes NOAA to renew a declaration.

Establishes the Marine Disease Emergency Working Group in NOAA to provide advice on assessing, declaring, and responding to those emergencies.

Establishes the Marine Disease Emergency Fund for responding to those emergencies.

Requires NOAA to establish a National Data Repository for Marine Diseases Research and Services to collect, store, and disseminate information on marine diseases and related data and facilitate the development and rapid dissemination of research on marine diseases.

Deems sea star wasting syndrome, a marine mortality event affecting species of sea stars, to be a marine disease emergency.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
