<bill session="114" type="h" number="4392" updated="2019-01-09T21:26:29Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-04-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to require that the Office of Personnel Management submit an annual report to Congress relating to the use of official time by Federal employees.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend title 5, United States Code, to require that the Office of Personnel Management submit an annual report to Congress relating to the use of official time by Federal employees.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000593"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001071" joined="2016-01-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-12">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 114-484.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-12" state="REPORTED" calendar="Union" number="368">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 368.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Reporting, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4361"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-12T14:00:20Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">(Sec. 1) This bill requires the Office of Personnel Management to submit an annual report to Congress on the use of official time by federal employees. The bill defines "official time" as any period of time granted to a federal employee to perform representational or consultative functions and during which the employee would otherwise be in a duty status.

Each such report shall include, for each agency and for all agencies:

 the total amount of official time granted to employees; the average amount of official time expended per bargaining unit employee; the specific types of activities or purposes for which official time was granted and the impact which the granting of such official time had on agency operations; the total number of employees to whom official time was granted and, of that total, the number who were not engaged in any activities or purposes except those involving the use of official time; the total amount of compensation (including fringe benefits) afforded to employees in connection with activities or purposes for which they were granted official time; and a description of any room or space designated at the agency where official time activities will be conducted.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-484</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
