<bill session="115" type="s" number="1275" updated="2019-06-21T11:07:16Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the housing conditions and promote useful land uses within tribal communities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bringing Useful Initiatives for Indian Land Development Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bringing Useful Initiatives for Indian Land Development Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BUIILD Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BUIILD Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">BUIILD Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001061"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-13">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 115-89.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Bringing Useful Initiatives for Indian Land Development Act of 2017 or BUIILD Act of 2017

This bill amends the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 to modify the environmental review process used for certain affordable housing activities on Indian reservations. Specifically, the bill allows an Indian tribe that receives federal funds in addition to block grant amounts under the Act to assume all of the responsibilities for environmental review that would apply to the federal agencies providing funds for the project if the grant amount constitutes the largest single source of federal funds that the tribe reasonably expects to commit to the project at the time of environmental review.

The bill reauthorizes through FY2025 the block grant program for affordable housing activities on Indian reservations, training and technical assistance for Indian tribes and tribally designated housing entities, and the Indian Housing Loan Guarantee Fund.

In addition, the bill increases from 50 years to 99 years the term that tribal trusts or restricted lands may be leased for housing development and residential purposes.

Funds provided under a grant under the Act may be used to meet matching or cost participation requirements under other federal or nonfederal programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
