<bill session="114" type="h" number="3767" updated="2018-06-02T04:46:13Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Government Publishing Overreach Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 44, United States Code, to prohibit the assembly or manufacture of secure credentials or their component parts by the Government Publishing Office.</title>
    <title type="display">Preventing Government Publishing Overreach Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001243"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000461" joined="2016-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000819" joined="2015-10-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government Publishing Office (GPO)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Preventing Government Publishing Overreach Act of 2015

 This bill prohibits the Government Publishing Office from assembling or manufacturing any secure credentials or the component parts of any such credential.

Such prohibition is inapplicable to the following activities:

 stitching security paper into an already assembled eCover for the Department of State; manufacturing NEXUS and SENTRI cards pursuant to any existing contract or purchase order until the earlier of the date on which such contract expires or such purchase order is filled, or December 31, 2016; assembling or manufacturing any secure credentials specifically at the request of the Central Intelligence Agency or the National Security Agency for use in classified programs or activities; and manufacturing identification badges for the presidential inauguration. The term "secure credential" is defined as an identification document that includes component security parts designed to authenticate the document or reduce the risk of the unauthorized replication or alteration of the document.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
