<amendment session="114" chamber="s" number="812" updated="2018-06-04T02:15:44Z">
  <amends type="sc" number="11" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2015-03-27">withdrawn</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001111"/>
  <offered datetime="2015-03-25"/>
  <description>To establish a deficit-neutral reserve fund to provide women with affordable access to comprehensive health care, including preventive services (such as contraception and breast cancer screenings), improve maternal health, and ensure that a woman has the same benefits and services no matter what part of the United States she lives in, all of which is critical to improving the health and well-being of women, children, their families, and society as a whole, and is an essential part of a woman's economic security and opportunity.</description>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-27">
      <text>Proposed amendment SA 812 withdrawn in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 3/26/2015 S2022" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1960-1961" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Amendment SA 812 proposed by Senator Sanders for Senator Murray. (consideration: CR S1873-1874; text: CR S1873) To establish a deficit-neutral reserve fund to provide women with affordable access to comprehensive health care, including preventive services (such as contraception and breast cancer screenings), improve maternal health, and ensure that a woman has the same benefits and services no matter what part of the United States she lives in, all of which is critical to improving the health and well-being of women, children, their families, and society as a whole, and is an essential part of a woman's economic security and opportunity.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25"/>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 812 proposed by Senator Sanders for Senator Murray.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1873-1874" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1873" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
