<bill session="115" type="h" number="938" updated="2019-04-18T16:02:00Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to provide clarification with respect to the liability of third party payers for medical assistance paid under the Medicaid program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicaid Third Party Liability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicaid Third Party Liability Act</title>
    <title type="display">Medicaid Third Party Liability Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001248"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000461" joined="2017-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000558" joined="2017-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2027"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3921"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Medicaid Third Party Liability Act

This bill alters provisions related to third-party liability for medical assistance paid under the Medicaid program. Specifically, with respect to such liability, the bill:

 expands the&#160;definition of "responsible third party"&#160;to include, among other health insurers,&#160;the TRICARE program; eliminates special rules with respect to certain services provided to children; requires the inclusion, in a contract between a state Medicaid program and a health insurer, of&#160;certain information regarding whether the state is delegating or transferring to the&#160;insurer a right of&#160;third-party recovery;&#160; provides for the treatment as overpayment of reimbursements made by a responsible third party to a health insurer; disallows a responsible third party from denying a state's claim solely on the basis of a failure to obtain a prior authorization;&#160; imposes a timeline for a responsible third party to respond to a state's inquiry regarding a claim for payment; provides for reductions to a state Medicaid program's federal matching rate&#160;if the state&#160;fails to comply with third-party insurance requirements; and modifies other provisions related to third-party liability under the Medicaid program. Third-party liability requirements applicable&#160;under Medicaid&#160;shall also apply&#160;under the Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP).

The Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services&#160;must:

 publish on its website, and annually update, best practices for assessing third-party liability; monitor and analyze efforts to assess that liability; in consultation with states, develop and make available a model uniform reporting field for identifying information related to responsible third parties; and provide other specified information and guidance to states.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
