<bill session="114" type="h" number="1291" updated="2018-06-02T02:28:33Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Highway-Rail Grade Crossing Safety Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve highway-rail grade crossing safety, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Highway-Rail Grade Crossing Safety Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000293"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2015-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001047" joined="2015-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001185" joined="2015-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000096" joined="2015-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Highways and Transit" code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="532"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-04T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Highway-Rail Grade Crossing Safety Act of 2015 

This bill authorizes appropriations for FY2016-FY2019 for the highway safety improvement program, with $50 million set aside for each fiscal year for the Railway-Highway Crossings Program.

The limitation to three states per year is eliminated, so all states now become eligible for the award of Highway-Rail Grade Crossing Safety improvement grants to develop or continue enhanced public education and awareness activities, in combination with targeted law enforcement, to reduce traffic law violations at highway-rail grade crossings, as well as to prevent and reduce injuries and fatalities along railroad rights-of-way. The limitation on grant amounts awarded to a state is increased from $250,000 to $2.5 million.

Eligibility requirements are revised for the award of capital grants to states under the rail line relocation and improvement program.

Increased appropriations under the Rail Safety Improvement Act of 2008 are authorized for FY2016-FY2019 for the Federal Railroad Administration (FRA) to make grants to the Operation Lifesaver program.

The FRA shall hire:

 16 full-time grade crossing safety managers to work with state and local officials to identify safety improvements to highway-rail grade crossings; and 8 trespass prevention managers to work with local governments, schools, businesses, and railroads to develop site-specific mitigation plans. The Secretary of Transportation shall study the feasibility of requiring railroad carriers to provide additional means for the public to report problems at highway-rail grade crossings, including via the Internet and text messaging.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
