<bill session="114" type="s" number="642" updated="2018-06-02T06:40:29Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Human Trafficking Survivors Relief and Empowerment Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to aid human trafficking victims' recovery and rehabilitation.</title>
    <title type="display">Human Trafficking Survivors Relief and Empowerment Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hc" session="114" relation="unknown" number="47"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Human Trafficking Survivors Relief and Empowerment Act of 2015

Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to direct the Attorney General to give preferential consideration for a public safety and community policing grant to an applicant in a state that has in effect a law that:

 provides a process by which an individual who is a human trafficking survivor can move to vacate any arrest or conviction records for prostitution or any other non-violent offense committed as a direct result of human trafficking; establishes a rebuttable presumption that any arrest or conviction of an individual for an offense associated with human trafficking is a result of being trafficked, if the individual has been granted nonimmigrant status as a victim of severe form of human trafficking, is the subject of a certification by the Secretary of Health and Human Services as willing to assist in an investigation and prosecution of severe forms of trafficking in persons, or has other similar documentation of trafficking issued by a federal agency; protects the identity of individuals who are human trafficking survivors in public and court records; and does not require an individual who is a human trafficking survivor to provide official documentation as described in this Act in order to receive protection under the law. Authorizes the Legal Services Corporation and the recipients of its funding to provide legal services on behalf a human trafficking survivor applying for a motion to vacate under such a state law.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
