<amendment session="114" chamber="h" number="522" updated="2018-11-08T23:28:54Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2596" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2015-06-16T15:52:13-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000592"/>
  <offered datetime="2015-06-16"/>
  <description>Amendment requires the Director of National Intelligence to submit a report that represents the coordinated assessment of the intelligence community on how terrorists and terrorist organizations are using social media, the intelligence value of social media posts by terrorists and terrorist organizations, and the impact on the national security of the United States of the public availability of terrorist content on social media.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment No. 15 printed in House Report 114-155 to require the Director of National Intelligence to submit a report that represents the coordinated assessment of the intelligence community on how terrorists and terrorist organizations are using social media, the intelligence value of social media posts by terrorists and terrorist organizations, and the impact on the national security of the United States of the public availability of terrorist content on social media.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2015-06-16T15:52:13-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Poe (TX) amendment (A015) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-06-16T15:48:29-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A015) offered by Mr. Poe (TX).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4416-4417" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4416" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-16"/>
    <action datetime="2015-06-16T15:52:13-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-16T15:48:29-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A015) offered by Mr. Poe (TX).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4416-4417" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4416" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-16T15:52:13-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Poe (TX) amendment (A015) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-16">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
