<bill session="113" type="h" number="3049" updated="2016-10-25T16:07:02Z">
  <state datetime="2013-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Justice for Fort Hood and Little Rock Heroes Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To treat members of the Armed Forces who were killed or wounded in the November 5, 2009, attack at Fort Hood, Texas, or the June 1, 2009, attack at Little Rock, Arkansas, as if the members were awarded the Purple Heart, to clarify the eligibility of such members for combat-related special compensation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Justice for Fort Hood and Little Rock Heroes Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000583"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001051" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000567" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000816" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000672" joined="2013-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1433"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-08-02T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Justice for Fort Hood and Little Rock Heroes Act - Requires an individual who, while a member of the Armed Forces, was killed or wounded in the attack at Fort Hood, Texas, on November 5, 2009, or in the attack at the recruiting station in Little Rock, Arkansas, on June 1, 2009, to be treated as if the individual has been awarded a Purple Heart as of the date of this Act's enactment for purposes of all applicable federal laws, regulations, and policies.

Requires such an individual who was wounded in either such attack to be treated as an "eligible combat-related disabled uniformed services retiree" for purposes of determining that individual's eligibility for combat-related special compensation.

Disqualifies an individual whose death or wound was the result of the individual's willful misconduct.

Encourages each state and local government to treat such an individual as eligible for any benefits provided to individuals by reason of being killed or wounded while serving in the line of duty as a member of the Armed Forces.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
