<bill session="114" type="h" number="6006" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:33Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lost Boys and Girls Rebuilding Infrastructure to Sustain Enduring Peace in South Sudan Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lost Boys and Girls RISE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a pilot program to provide fellowships to certain former Sudanese refugees, known as the "Lost Boys and Lost Girls of Sudan", to assist in reconstruction efforts in South Sudan.</title>
    <title type="display">Lost Boys and Girls RISE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001270"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001037" joined="2016-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2016-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2016-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2016-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2016-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000385" joined="2016-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2016-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2016-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000610" joined="2016-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2016-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000808" joined="2016-11-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Lost Boys and Girls Rebuilding Infrastructure to Sustain Enduring Peace in South Sudan Act or the Lost Boys and Girls RISE Act

This bill directs the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) to establish a three-year pilot program to provide fellowships to up to 500 eligible individuals to assist in developing agricultural, business development, educational, medical, technological, or transportation infrastructure in South Sudan. (The program may begin after the Department of State determines that it is safe for U.S. citizens, especially citizens of Sudanese or South Sudanese descent, to travel to South Sudan and lifts the general travel warning for South Sudan.)

It is the sense of Congress that USAID should: (1) consult with members of the Lost Boys and Lost Girls of Sudan community in the United States for purposes of identifying potential participants, and (2) consider individuals who are recommended to USAID by a member of Congress.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
