<bill session="115" type="h" number="4524" updated="2019-04-18T16:18:35Z">
  <state datetime="2017-12-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-12-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-12-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To expand retirement coverage, preserve retirement income, simplify rules related to retirement plans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Retirement Plan Simplification and Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Retirement Plan Simplification and Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Retirement Plan Simplification and Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000015"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-12-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3910"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Temporary and part-time employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-12-01T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Retirement Plan Simplification and Enhancement Act of 2017 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to modify requirements and tax provisions regarding retirement plans.

With respect to employer-provided retirement plans, the bill modifies requirements regarding:

 automatic enrollment; coverage rules for long-term, part-time workers; employer contributions; the timing for adopting a qualified retirement plan; correcting errors; financial incentives for contributing to a plan; the portability of lifetime income and managed account investment options; distribution options; notices and disclosures to participants; interest rates for defined benefit plans; and due dates for employer pension contributions. The bill also:

 repeals the maximum age for traditional Individual Retirement Account (IRA) contributions, modifies the rollover options that are available to nonspouse beneficiaries, increases the age at which participants are required to begin taking distributions, exempts participants with retirement plan balances that do not exceed $250,000 from the required minimum distribution rules, expands tax credits for small employers that adopt certain retirement plans, makes the saver's tax credit available on Form 1040-EZ, modifies the required minimum distribution requirements for life annuities, modifies the requirements for qualifying longevity annuity contracts, modifies the rules for fiduciaries who make economically targeted investments, and establishes an Office of the Participant and Plan Sponsor Advocate within the Internal Revenue Service.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
