<bill session="114" type="h" number="710" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:39Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-16">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="agreed to by house and senate">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to prepare a comprehensive security assessment of the transportation security card program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to prepare a comprehensive security assessment of the transportation security card program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Essential Transportation Worker Identification Credential Assessment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Essential Transportation Worker Identification Credential Assessment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Essential Transportation Worker Identification Credential Assessment Act</title>
    <title type="display">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to prepare a comprehensive security assessment of the transportation security card program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001150" joined="2015-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2015-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-10T19:11:10-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Carter (GA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-10T19:11:16-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H899-903" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-10T19:11:17-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 710.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2015-02-10T19:25:49-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H899-900" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-02-10T19:25:53-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-11">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22">
      <text>Senate Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2319" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-05-20">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-04-25">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Thune with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 114-244.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="436">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 436.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-12-10">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7145-7147" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-10">
      <text>The committee substitute withdrawn by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7146" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2016-12-10" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-12-12">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-13T14:39:30-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (NJ) asked unanimous consent to take from the Speaker's table and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="without objection" type="pingpong" datetime="2016-12-13T14:40:03-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion that the House agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7585-7586" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7585-7586" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-12-13T14:40:30-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2016-12-15">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2016-12-16" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="114-278" type="public" datetime="2016-12-16">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 114-278.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Border Security, Facilitation, and Operations" code="HSHM11" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s5183"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2016-12-17T04:59:58Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on December 10, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

(Sec. 1) This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to commence actions to improve its process for vetting individuals with access to secure areas of vessels and maritime facilities.

These actions shall include:

 conducting a comprehensive risk analysis of security threat assessment procedures, including identifying procedures that need additional internal controls as well as best practices for quality assurance at every stage of the assessment; implementing such internal controls and best practices; improving fraud detection techniques; updating the guidance provided to Trusted Agents (Credentialing Office) regarding the vetting process and related regulations; finalizing a manual for such agents and adjudicators on the vetting process; and establishing quality controls to ensure consistent procedures to review adjudication decisions and terrorism vetting decisions. The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) shall commission a national laboratory, a university-based center within the Science and Technology Directorate's centers of excellence network, or a qualified federally-funded research and development center to conduct an assessment of the effectiveness of the Transportation Worker Identification Credential (TWIC) Program at enhancing security and reducing security risks for maritime facilities and vessels that pose a high risk of being involved in a transportation security incident.

The assessment shall review:

 the credentialing process, the process for renewing TWIC applications, and the security value of the TWIC program. If the assessment identifies a deficiency in effectiveness of the TWIC Program, DHS shall submit to Congress a corrective action plan that:

 responds to assessment findings and includes an implementation plan with benchmarks, and shall be considered in any DHS rulemaking with respect to the TWIC Program. The DHS Inspector General must review and report on the corrective action plan.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-244</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
