<bill session="115" type="sc" number="30" updated="2019-04-18T16:29:14Z">
  <state datetime="2017-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A concurrent resolution expressing the sense of Congress with respect to United States policy toward Tibet and that the treatment of the Tibetan people should be an important factor in the conduct of United States relations with the People's Republic of China.</title>
    <title type="display">A concurrent resolution expressing the sense of Congress with respect to United States policy toward Tibet and that the treatment of the Tibetan people should be an important factor in the conduct of United States relations with the People's Republic of China.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2017-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2017-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2017-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2017-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2017-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2017-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2017-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2017-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-11-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7306-7308" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hc" session="115" relation="unknown" number="89"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Tibet"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-11-16T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Expresses the sense of Congress that it should be U.S. policy to:

 make the treatment of the Tibetan people an important factor in the conduct of U.S. relations with the People's Republic of China; consistent with the Tibetan Policy Act of 2002, encourage the Chinese government to enter into a dialogue with the Dalai Lama leading to a negotiated agreement on Tibet, publicly call for the release of those held prisoner for expressing their political or religious views in Tibetan areas, and establish an office in Lhasa, Tibet, to assist visiting U.S. citizens and monitor political, economic, and cultural developments in Tibet; appoint the Special Coordinator for Tibetan Issues at the rank of Under Secretary of State; revoke appropriate privileges of any Chinese official found responsible for impeding access of U.S. citizens to Tibet and ensure that reciprocal visa processing measures are occurring; continue to designate China as a country of particular concern pursuant to the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998; and engage with appropriate Chinese officials to stop the demolition of Tibetan Buddhist religious institutions, revise religious and travel regulations to conform with international human rights standards, and ensure that Tibetan nomads are allowed to continue their way of life on the Tibetan Plateau and are not forcibly relocated into "socialist villages."</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
