<bill session="115" type="h" number="4475" updated="2019-06-17T18:22:32Z">
  <state datetime="2017-12-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-12-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-11-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the establishment of the National Volcano Early Warning and Monitoring System.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">National Volcano Early Warning and Monitoring System Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">National Volcano Early Warning and Monitoring System Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Volcano Early Warning and Monitoring System Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Volcano Early Warning and Monitoring System Act</title>
    <title type="display">National Volcano Early Warning and Monitoring System Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-11-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-12-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-01-09">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 115-501.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-01-09" calendar="Union" number="374">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 374.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="346"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Earth sciences"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-01-09T16:50:31Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">National Volcano Early Warning and Monitoring System Act

(Sec. 3) This bill directs the United States Geological Survey (USGS) to establish the National Volcano Early Warning and Monitoring System to monitor, issue warnings of, and protect U.S. citizens from undue and avoidable harm from, volcanic activity.

The purposes of the system are to: (1) organize, modernize, standardize, and stabilize the monitoring systems of U.S. volcano observatories; and (2) unify such systems into a single interoperative system. The objective of the system is to monitor all U.S. volcanoes at a level commensurate with the threat posed by the volcanoes by: (1) upgrading existing networks on monitored volcanoes, (2) installing new networks on unmonitored volcanoes, and (3) employing geodetic and other components when applicable.

The system shall include: (1) a national volcano watch office that is operational 24 hours a day and 7 days a week, (2) a national volcano data center, (3) an external grants program to support research in volcano monitoring science and technology, and (4) modernization activities including the comprehensive application of emerging technologies.

The USGS must: (1) submit to Congress a five-year management plan for establishing and operating the system, and (2) establish an advisory committee to assist in implementing the system.

 The USGS may enter into cooperative agreements designating institutions of higher education and state or territorial agencies as volcano observatory partners for the system.

The USGS must conduct a study to assess the feasibility of establishing volcano observatories in Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, and American Samoa to monitor volcanic activity across the western and southern Pacific Ocean along the Ring of Fire. If determined to be feasible, the USGS may enter into cooperative agreements with institutions of higher education or territorial agencies to establish such observatories as part of the National Volcano Early Warning and Monitoring System.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-501</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
