<bill session="113" type="h" number="4866" updated="2016-10-25T16:14:04Z">
  <state datetime="2014-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lesser Prairie Chicken Voluntary Recovery Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reverse the Department of the Interior's listing of the lesser prairie chicken as a threatened species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973, to prevent further consideration of listing of such species as a threatened species or endangered species under that Act pending implementation of the Western Association of Fish and Wildlife Agencies' Lesser Prairie-Chicken Range-Wide Conservation Plan and other conservation measures, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Lesser Prairie Chicken Voluntary Recovery Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001190"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001283" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000461" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001057" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000491" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000182" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000588" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000238" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000470" joined="2014-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-09">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2677"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-06-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Lesser Prairie Chicken Voluntary Recovery Act of 2014 - Removes the Department of the Interior's listing of the lesser prairie chicken as threatened under the Endangered Species Act of 1973. Prohibits further treatment of the species as threatened or endangered before January 31, 2020.

Requires Interior to monitor and submit an annual report on progress in the conservation of the lesser prairie chicken under:

 the Lesser Prairie-Chicken Range-Wide Conservation Plan of the Western Association of Fish and Wildlife Agencies, all related Candidate Conservation Agreements (agreements to voluntarily undertake measures to conserve a covered species), Candidate Conservation Agreements With Assurances (agreements to voluntarily undertake measures to conserve a covered species with assurances that additional measures will not be imposed if the species becomes listed in the future), conservation programs administered by the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (USFWS), the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), and the Department of Agriculture (USDA), state conservation programs, and private conservation efforts. Prohibits the lesser prairie chicken from being treated as threatened or endangered beginning on January 31, 2020, unless Interior publishes a determination that conservation efforts under the Range-Wide Plan, agreements, programs, and efforts have not achieved the Plan's conservation goals.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
