<amendment session="115" chamber="h" number="620" updated="2019-06-30T15:28:07Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2018-05-18T11:19:50-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000604"/>
  <offered datetime="2018-05-17"/>
  <description>Amendment sought to amend the Agricultural Risk Protection Act of 2000 to prohibit USDA from awarding value-added agricultural product market development grants to support the marketing of beer, wine, distilled spirits, hard cider, or other alcohol products. Also, the amendment sought to rescind $8 million of the unobligated funds that were previously provided to USDA for grants.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 17 printed in House Report 115-679 to amend the Agricultural Risk Protection act of 2000 to prohibit the Depa rtment of Agriculture (USDA) from awarding value-added agricultural product market development grants to support the marketing of beer, wine, distilled spirits, hard cider, or other alcohol products. The amendment also rescinds $8 million of the unobligated funds that were previously provided to USDA for grants.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2018-05-18T11:19:50-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="200">
      <text>On agreeing to the Russell amendment (A035) Failed by recorded vote: 54 - 356 (Roll no. 200).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4227-4228" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-05-17T18:34:38-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A035) offered by Mr. Russell.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4201-4203" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4201" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-17"/>
    <action datetime="2018-05-17T18:34:38-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A035) offered by Mr. Russell.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4201-4203" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4201" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-18T11:19:50-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Russell amendment (A035) Failed by recorded vote: 54 - 356 (Roll no. 200).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4227-4228" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-18T11:19:50-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-18T11:19:50-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-17">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
