<bill session="114" type="s" number="3046" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:37Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Tip-overs of Unstable, Risky Dressers on Youth Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STURDY Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Consumer Product Safety Commission to promulgate a consumer product safety rule for free-standing clothing storage units to protect children from tip-over-related death or injury, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">STURDY Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2016-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2016-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="5442"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-09T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stop Tip-overs of Unstable, Risky Dressers on Youth Act or the STURDY Act

 This bill requires the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to promulgate a final consumer product safety standard for free-standing clothing storage units (furniture items referred to as, or that may contain, a chest, door chest, chest of drawers, dresser, or bureau) to protect children from tip-over-related death or injury, unless the CPSC determines that a voluntary ASTM (American Society for Testing and Materials) International standard adequately protects children and is likely to be complied with by furniture manufacturers.

If an ASTM standard meets the CPSC's requirements, the standard shall be treated as a consumer product safety rule.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
