<bill session="114" type="h" number="538" updated="2019-06-21T11:07:10Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-08T16:31:05-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-10-08T16:31:05-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To facilitate the development of energy on Indian lands by reducing Federal regulations that impede tribal development of Indian lands, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Native American Energy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Native American Energy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native American Energy Act</title>
    <title type="display">Native American Energy Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2015-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-09-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 23 - 12.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-09-10">
      <text>Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-10">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-01">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 114-276.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-10-01" calendar="Union" number="208">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 208.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-10-07T18:38:48-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 466 Reported to House. For H.R. 538, resolution provides for one hour of debate, makes specified amendments in order and allows one motion to recommit, with or without instructions. For H.R. 702, resolution provides for one hour of debate, makes specified amendments in order and allows one motion to recommit, with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08T14:57:43-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 466.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6911-6920" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08T14:57:48-04:00">
      <text>For H.R. 538, resolution provides for one hour of debate, makes specified amendments in order and allows one motion to recommit, with or without instructions. For H.R. 702, resolution provides for one hour of debate, makes specified amendments in order and allows one motion to recommit, with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08T14:58:12-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 466 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08T14:58:30-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable David Rouzer to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08T14:59:05-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 538.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08T15:38:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 466, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Young (AK) Part A amendment no. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08T15:41:17-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 466, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lujan Grisham (NM) Part A amendment no. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08T15:46:15-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 538.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08T15:46:53-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6916-6917" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08T15:47:39-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Lujan, Ben Ray (NM) moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6918-6919" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6918" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08T15:48:16-04:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ben Ray Lujan (NM) motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions in the motion seek to report the same back to the House forthwith with an amendment to ensure that nothing in the underlying legislation will infringe on the authority of the President to protect any sacred or ceremonial Native American tribal site.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08T15:52:15-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6919" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08T16:22:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 184 - 239 (Roll no. 543).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6919" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="544" datetime="2015-10-08T16:31:05-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 254 - 173 (Roll no. 544).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08T16:31:06-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-19">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indigenous Peoples of the United States" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1487"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="791"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3682"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="114" relation="unknown" number="466"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2012"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h712"/>
    <amendment number="h711"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2015-10-08T11:12:35Z" status="Passed House amended">Native American Energy Act

 (Sec. 2) This bill amends the Energy Policy Act of 1992 to allow the Department of the Interior, an affected Indian tribe, or a certified third-party appraiser under contract with the Indian tribe to appraise Indian land or trust assets involved in a transaction requiring Interior approval. (Currently, Interior sets appraisal requirements.)

Interior must approve or disapprove an appraisal within 60 days or the appraisal is deemed approved.

A tribe may waive the requirement for an appraisal if it also waives any claims for damages it might have against the United States as a result of the lack of an appraisal. (Sec. 3) Each agency within Interior involved in the review of oil and gas activities on Indian lands must use a uniform system of reference numbers and tracking systems for oil and gas wells.

(Sec. 4) This bill amends the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 to make the environmental impact statement for a major federal action (excluding an action related to gaming) on Indian lands available for review and comment only to the affected tribe, individuals residing within the affected area, and state, tribal, and local governments within the affected area.

(Sec. 5) This bill sets forth provisions for the judicial review of a cause of action related to energy development on Indian land.

(Sec. 6) This bill amends the Tribal Forest Protection Act of 2004 to direct Interior, for land under Bureau of Land Management jurisdiction, and the Department of Agriculture (USDA), for land under Forest Service jurisdiction, to enter into agreements with Indian tribes to carry out demonstration projects that promote biomass energy production on Indian forest land and in nearby communities by providing tribes with reliable supplies of woody biomass from federal lands. Interior and USDA may carry out demonstration projects by which tribes may perform the functions of programs under the Tribal Forest Protection Act of 2004.

(Sec. 7) Activity pursuant to a tribal resource management plan or an integrated resource management plan approved by Interior under the National Indian Forest Resources Management Act or the American Indian Agricultural Resource Management Act is considered to be a sustainable management practice.

(Sec. 8) This bill amends the Long-Term Leasing Act to allow the Navajo Nation to enter into mineral resource leases on their restricted lands without Interior's approval. The maximum term of a Navajo Nation lease that does not require Interior's approval is extended for commercial and agricultural leases and established for mineral resource leases.

(Sec. 9) Interior rules regarding hydraulic fracturing do not apply on land held in trust for Indians or on restricted Indian land, except with the express consent of the Indian beneficiaries. Hydraulic fracturing or fracking is a process to extract underground resources such as oil or gas from a geologic formation by injecting water, a propping agent (e.g., sand), and chemical additives into a well under enough pressure to fracture the geological formation.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-276</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
