<bill session="114" type="h" number="5890" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:41Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Asia-Pacific Maritime Security Initiative Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote stability and security in the Asia-Pacific maritime domains, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Asia-Pacific Maritime Security Initiative Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001287" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001245" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000616" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000179" joined="2016-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Indonesia"/>
    <term name="Malaysia"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Philippines"/>
    <term name="Taiwan"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Asia-Pacific Maritime Security Initiative Act of 2016

This bill expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the United States should support the efforts of the Southeast Asian nations to strengthen their maritime security capacity, and (2) the maritime security of U.S. allies and partners bordering the South China Sea would be enhanced by the transfer of an Oliver Hazard Perry class frigate to an appropriate regional country.

In selecting Asia-Pacific region countries to receive maritime capacity building assistance, the Department of State may prioritize those countries that will contribute to achieving the following regional objectives:

 retaining access to waterways that are critical to the security and free flow of commerce and U.S. security objectives, improving maritime domain awareness, countering piracy, disrupting maritime trafficking that benefits organizations that are threats to U.S. security, and enhancing country or regional organization capabilities to respond to emerging maritime security threats. The bill urges the State Department to seek a bilateral memorandum of understanding with each of the governments of the Philippines, Malaysia, Vietnam, and Indonesia to outline the delivery of planned maritime security capabilities through FY2020.

The bill authorizes: (1) international military education/training and foreign military financing for the Asia-Pacific region, and (2) the Southeast Asia Maritime Law Enforcement Initiative.

The Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 is amended to provide priority delivery of excess defense articles to Malaysia, Vietnam, and Indonesia for articles that are used for maritime security-related missions.

The President shall ensure that the U.S. government treats proposed arms sales for Taiwan with the same procedures that are accorded to all other countries.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
