<bill session="114" type="h" number="3842" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:45Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-16">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers Reform and Improvement Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers Reform and Improvement Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers Reform and Improvement Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers Reform and Improvement Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers Reform and Improvement Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve homeland security, including domestic preparedness and response to terrorism, by reforming Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers to provide training to first responders, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers Reform and Improvement Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001103"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001051" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000583" joined="2015-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2015-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000601" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000474" joined="2015-10-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-04">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-11-04" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-11-19">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 114-343, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-19">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-11-19" calendar="Union" number="262">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 262.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-12-08T13:12:01-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Carter (GA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-08T13:12:14-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9037-9040, H9041" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-08T13:12:16-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3842.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-08T13:53:42-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate on the motion to suspend the rules and pass H.R. 3842.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-08T13:56:29-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-08T17:20:25-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9062" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="680" datetime="2015-12-08T17:29:36-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 420 - 2 (Roll no. 680).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9037-9038" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-12-08T17:29:37-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-10">
      <text>Senate Committee on the Judiciary discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-10">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7104-7106" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="2016-12-10" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-12-12">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-13T14:40:31-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (NJ) asked unanimous consent to take from the Speaker's table and agree to the Senate amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="without objection" type="pingpong" datetime="2016-12-13T14:40:35-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion that the House agree to the Senate amendments Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7586" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7586" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-12-13T14:40:39-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2016-12-15">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2016-12-16" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="114-285" type="public" datetime="2016-12-16">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 114-285.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2781"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6381"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s5171"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2016-12-17T04:59:58Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on December 10, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers Reform and Improvement Act of 2015

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to codify the establishment of the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center (FLETC) within the Department of Homeland Security (DHS).

The FLETC must be headed by a director who reports to the DHS Secretary.

The bill sets forth functions of the director, including to: establish and execute organizational plans and priorities; direct and manage training facilities, programs, and activities; develop training goals and curricula; disseminate homeland security information to law enforcement and security agencies and private sector stakeholders; conduct acquisition in compliance with federal law and regulations; coordinate and share digital resources with federal agencies; and collaborate to improve international instructional development, training, and technical assistance to foreign law enforcement.

Additionally, the bill sets forth training responsibilities of the FLETC and partner organizations (i.e., federal agencies that participate in FLETC training programs under a formal memorandum of understanding).

It authorizes the FLETC to: (1) train federal employees engaged in homeland security operations or law enforcement activities, and (2) execute strategic partnerships with state and local law enforcement agencies and coordinate with private sector stakeholders to provide training. The FLETC must consult with relevant law enforcement and security agencies to develop and deliver training programs.

A partner organization must pay for and assign non-reimbursable detailed instructors to support training programs.

The FLETC may conduct federal employee trainings at FLETC facilities, at off-site locations, or by distributed learning (e.g., online); detail its employees throughout DHS; charge fees for non-federal trainings; provide certain student support services; hire retired federal employees with training experience; and reimburse travel expenses of non-federal and intermittent federal employees. Individuals who attend FLETC training must reside in FLETC housing, to the extent practicable.

Finally, the bill codifies existing authorities of the FLETC to spend funds to promote awareness of and support for law enforcement training, accept and use gifts for authorized purposes, accept reimbursement for the construction or renovation of training facilities, obligate funds in anticipation of reimbursements, purchase uniforms and passenger vehicles, and provide room and board for student interns. It also authorizes the FLETC to spend funds to honor and memorialize FLETC graduates who have died in the line of duty.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-343</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
