<bill session="113" type="h" number="1683" updated="2018-06-05T16:15:56Z">
  <state datetime="2013-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Columbine-Hondo Wilderness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Columbine-Hondo Wilderness in the State of New Mexico, to provide for the conveyance of certain parcels of National Forest System land in the State, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Columbine-Hondo Wilderness Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000570"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000580" joined="2013-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="identical" number="776"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="3979"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation facilities"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-04-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Columbine-Hondo Wilderness Act - Designates specified land in Carson National Forest in New Mexico, which shall be known as the Columbine-Hondo Wilderness, as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System.

Releases any federal land within the Columbine-Hondo Wilderness Study Area administered by the Forest Service that is not designated as wilderness by this Act from further review for designation as wilderness.

Modifies the boundary of the Wheeler Peak Wilderness in New Mexico as specified on the map entitled "Columbine-Hondo, Wheeler Peak Wilderness."

Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to convey to the town of Red River in New Mexico, one or more parcels of federal land in Taos County, New Mexico, identified as Parcels, 1, 2, 3, and 4 on the map entitled "Town of Red River Town Site Act Proposal" (the Red River Conveyance Map).

Directs the Secretary to convey to the village of Taos Ski Valley in New Mexico the National Forest System land identified as parcel 1 on the map entitled "Village of Taos Ski Valley Town Site Act Proposal."

Authorizes the conveyance of certain National Forest System land in New Mexico involving Parcels 5 and 6 as identified on the Red River Conveyance Map.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
