<bill session="114" type="sr" number="524" updated="2018-06-02T06:21:20Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate on the conflict in Yemen.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate on the conflict in Yemen.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001169"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2016-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2016-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4946" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Corker without amendment and with a preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="575">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 575.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Persian Gulf States"/>
    <term name="Reconstruction and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Saudi Arabia"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Yemen"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T18:58:29Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Expresses the sense of the Senate that:

 all sides to the current conflict in Yemen should abide by international obligations to protect civilians, facilitate the delivery of humanitarian relief throughout the country, and respect negotiated cease-fires and work toward a lasting political settlement; U.S.-supported Saudi military operations in Yemen should take all feasible precautions to reduce the risk of harm to civilians and civilian objects, and should increase prioritization of targeting of designated foreign terrorist organizations, including al Qaeda in the Arabian Peninsula and affiliates of the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant; the Houthi-Saleh forces engaged in the conflict in Yemen should cease indiscriminate shelling of areas inhabited by civilians and should allow free access by humanitarian relief organizations seeking to deliver aid to civilian populations under siege; and a reconstruction and stabilization plan should be developed alongside a negotiated political framework, in consultation with local stakeholders and with robust financing from the international community, including Gulf Cooperation Council countries that have previously made pledges to fund Yemen's post-conflict reconstruction.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
