<bill session="115" type="s" number="3143" updated="2019-04-18T16:44:23Z">
  <state datetime="2018-08-01">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for a coordinated Federal program to accelerate quantum research and development for the economic and national security of the United States.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">National Quantum Initiative Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">National Quantum Initiative Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Quantum Initiative Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Quantum Initiative Act</title>
    <title type="display">National Quantum Initiative Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2018-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2018-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001075" joined="2018-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2018-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2018-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-06-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-08-01" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-11-27">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Thune with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 115-389.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-11-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="676">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 676.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="6227"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-11-27T15:41:10Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">National Quantum Initiative Act

This bill directs the President to implement a National Quantum Initiative Program to, among other things, establish the goals and priorities for a 10-year plan to accelerate the development of quantum information science and technology applications.

The bill defines "quantum information science" as the use of quantum mechanics for the storage, transmission, manipulation, or measurement of information in ways that offer advantages to classical capabilities.

The National Science and Technology Council shall establish a Subcommittee on Quantum Information Science, including membership from the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) and the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) to guide program activities.

The President must establish a National Quantum Initiative Advisory Committee to advise the President and subcommittee on the program and quantum information science trends and developments.

NIST shall carry out specified quantum science activities and convene a consortium to discuss the development of a quantum information science and technology industry.

The National Science Foundation shall:

 carry out a basic research and education program on quantum information science and engineering, and award grants for the establishment of Multidisciplinary Centers for Quantum Research and Education.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-389</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
