<bill session="113" type="h" number="1229" updated="2016-10-25T16:01:06Z">
  <state datetime="2013-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Security and Financial Empowerment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Victims of Abuse Insurance Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Victims' Employment Sustainability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote the economic security and safety of victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Security and Financial Empowerment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000486"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001245" joined="2014-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2014-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2014-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001101" joined="2014-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000216" joined="2013-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2014-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000455" joined="2013-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001063" joined="2014-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2014-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2013-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000562" joined="2014-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001188" joined="2014-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2014-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000588" joined="2014-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2014-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000030" joined="2014-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001170" joined="2014-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000808" joined="2013-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, Ways and Means, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-15">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-15">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-15">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, And Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" code="HSED02" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Workforce Protections" code="HSED10" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Human Resources" code="HSWM03" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-03-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Security and Financial Empowerment Act - Authorizes appropriations for grants for the national resource center on workplace responses to assist victims of domestic and sexual violence for FY2014-FY2018. Establishes limits on the use of funds for administrative costs. Requires the center to provide information and assistance to enable victim service organizations to provide resource materials or other assistance to employers, labor organizations, or employees.

Amends the Violence Against Women Act (VAWA) to set forth entitlement standards and implementation guidelines for employee use of emergency leave to address domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking (domestic or sexual violence). Prohibits: (1) any employer from interfering with the exercise of any right provided under this Act; or (2) discrimination against any individual for exercising any such right, opposing any practice made unlawful by this Act, or instituting any proceeding under this Act. Establishes a private right of action to enforce this Act. Directs the Secretary of Labor to receive, investigate, and attempt to resolve complaints of violations of this Act. Permits victims of domestic or sexual violence to substitute existing leave in lieu of emergency leave.

Authorizes state use of funds under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF) to provide nonrecurrent short-term emergency benefits for victims of domestic or sexual violence on emergency leave. Adds provisions to VAWA, entitled the Victims' Employment Sustainability Act, to prohibit certain discriminatory practices against victims of domestic or sexual violence by: (1) employers with respect to the terms, conditions, or privileges of employment; or (2) public agencies with respect to the terms or conditions of public assistance. Authorizes civil actions by individuals or the Attorney General to enforce such provisions. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to prohibit denial of unemployment compensation to individuals separated from employment due to their experience of domestic or sexual violence. Amends the Social Security Act to require training of unemployment compensation and TANF personnel to provide necessary services to victims of domestic or sexual violence. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award a grant to a national victim services organization to develop and disseminate a model training program. Victims of Abuse Insurance Protection Act - Prohibits denial or restriction of insurance coverage (including termination of health insurance coverage) or addition of a premium differential based on the status of the applicant or insured as a victim of abuse by a household or family member, intimate partner, or caretaker. Provides for enforcement of such prohibitions by the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) and by a private cause of action.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
