<bill session="113" type="s" number="2838" updated="2016-10-25T16:32:21Z">
  <state datetime="2014-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">U.S. OUTDOOR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Optimal Use of Trade to Develop Outerwear and Outdoor Recreation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for duty-free treatment of certain recreational performance outerwear, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">U.S. OUTDOOR Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2014-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="5646"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-09-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">United States Optimal Use of Trade to Develop Outerwear and Outdoor Recreation Act or the U.S. OUTDOOR Act - Amends the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to provide for the duty-free treatment of certain recreational performance outerwear.

Establishes the Sustainable Textile and Apparel Research Fund (STAR Fund).

Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to impose and collect, with specified exceptions, a fee of 1.5% of the appraised value of imported recreational performance outerwear and to deposit amounts collected into the STAR Fund.

Requires the Secretary of Commerce to make quarterly distributions from the STAR Fund to one or more appropriate organizations to conduct applied research, development, and education activities to enhance the competitiveness of U.S. businesses in clean, eco-friendly apparel, other textile and apparel products, and sewn-product design and manufacturing.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
