<bill session="115" type="hr" number="552" updated="2019-04-18T15:54:29Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-10-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Reaffirming the United States-Liberia partnership, and calling for free, fair, and peaceful elections in Liberia in October 2017.</title>
    <title type="display">Reaffirming the United States-Liberia partnership, and calling for free, fair, and peaceful elections in Liberia in October 2017.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000604"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-10-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="sr" session="115" relation="identical" number="266"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Liberia"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-10-02T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Welcomes the visit of President Ellen Johnson Sirleaf to the U.S. Congress for her final address as President of Liberia.

Commends Sirleaf's efforts to consolidate post-conflict peacebuilding and democratic gains, promote social and economic development, and foster ties with the international community and her work to advance international gender equality.

Urges the government, people, and political parties of Liberia to:

 hold free, fair, credible, and peaceful elections in October 2017 and in the future; adhere to the objectives set out in the Ganta and Farmington River Declarations and promote and ensure peaceful conduct among candidates, their supporters, and Liberian citizens; ensure that there is robust civic education and electoral campaign outreach to politically marginalized groups; and raise awareness of, and express zero tolerance for, violence against women, gender discrimination, or social bias in the electoral process. Supports efforts by the Department of State and the U.S. Agency for International Development to assist in election preparations.

Calls on Liberian citizens to fully participate in the general elections and to pursue legal avenues to resolve any disputes over the results. Encourages Liberian civil society organizations to intensify civic and voter education. Condemns any external interference in the election.

Encourages President Trump to appoint an Assistant Secretary of State for African Affairs.

 Calls upon the U.S. government and international partners to support successful elections and Liberia's anticipated historic democratic post-electoral transition of executive power.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
