<bill session="115" type="s" number="3092" updated="2019-04-18T16:44:09Z">
  <state datetime="2018-06-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to provide certain requirements relating to commitments by State agencies to provide the State share of the administrative costs of administering the supplemental nutrition assistance program.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency SNAP Lapse Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency SNAP Lapse Act</title>
    <title type="display">Emergency SNAP Lapse Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000393"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-06-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-06-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Emergency SNAP Lapse Act

 This bill amends the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to require the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to withhold Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP, formerly known as the food stamp program) funds from state agencies that do not provide sufficient funds to pay the state share of the administrative costs of the program.

To participate in SNAP, state agencies must submit annually to USDA a statement certifying the amount of funds committed by the state agency to pay the state share of the administrative costs for the year. If the state agency has not committed sufficient funds, USDA must notify the agency, provide a specified period of time to correct the failure, and withhold SNAP funds if the failure is not corrected.

USDA must use any funds that are withheld from a state to provide grants to private nonprofit entities within the state for the costs of: (1) providing food to individuals in need; and (2) administering the grants, including hiring additional personnel.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
