<bill session="114" type="h" number="3561" updated="2019-02-01T21:05:41Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Access to Education Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the section 484(r) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to exclude certain marijuana-related offenses from the drug-related offenses that result in students being barred from receiving Federal educational loans, grants, and work assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Fair Access to Education Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000574"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1322"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Investment" code="HSED13" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Fair Access to Education Act of 2015

This bill amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to modify federal student aid eligibility criteria. Specifically, it limits drug offense convictions that bar a student from participating in federal student aid programs.

Under current law, any drug offense conviction involving sale or possession of a controlled substance triggers suspension of federal student aid eligibility for a student who commits the drug offense while enrolled in postsecondary education and receiving federal student aid. This bill excludes from triggering drug offense convictions any misdemeanor offense for marijuana possession that occurred before, on, or after enactment of this bill.

This bill reestablishes federal student aid eligibility for certain students who are ineligible&#160;due to a prior conviction for misdemeanor marijuana possession.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
