<amendment session="114" chamber="h" number="336" updated="2019-02-17T14:41:26Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2578" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2015-06-03T01:40:14-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000605"/>
  <offered datetime="2015-06-03"/>
  <description>At the end of the bill (before the short title), add the following:    SEC.___. None of the funds made available in this Act may be used to implement the United States Global Climate Research Program's National Climate Assessment, the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change's Fifth Assessment Report, the United Nation's Agenda 21 sustainable development plan, or the May 2013 Technical Update of the Social Cost of Carbon for Regulatory Impact Analysis under Executive Order 12866.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment to prohibit the use of funds to implement the United States Global Climate Research Program's National Climate Assessment, the Intergovernmental Report, the United Nation's Agenda 21 sustainable development plan, or the May 2013 Technical Update of the Social Cost of Carbon for Regulatory Impact Analysis under Executive Order 12866.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2015-06-03T01:40:14-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Perry amendment (A068) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-06-03T01:34:36-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A068) offered by Mr. Perry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3752" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3752" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-03"/>
    <action datetime="2015-06-03T01:40:14-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Perry amendment (A068) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-03T01:40:14-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-03T01:34:36-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A068) offered by Mr. Perry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3752" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3752" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-03">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
