<bill session="114" type="s" number="1599" updated="2018-06-02T06:56:06Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-22">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Criminal Antitrust Anti-Retaliation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Criminal Antitrust Anti-Retaliation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Criminal Antitrust Anti-Retaliation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide anti-retaliation protections for antitrust whistleblowers.</title>
    <title type="display">Criminal Antitrust Anti-Retaliation Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2015-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4252" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-07-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-07-16">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Grassley with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-07-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="151">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 151.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2015-07-22" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5474-5475" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5474" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-07-23">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-23T10:19:32-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-23T16:43:28-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-22T11:49:05Z" status="Passed Senate amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the Senate on July 16, 2015. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Criminal Antitrust Anti-Retaliation Act of 2015

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Antitrust Criminal Penalty Enhancement and Reform Act of 2004 to prohibit an employer from discharging, demoting, suspending, harassing, or in any other manner discriminating against an employee, contractor, subcontractor, or agent of such employer (covered individual) who by a lawful act: (1) provided information to the employer or a federal regulatory or law enforcement agency, or any Member of Congress or congressional committee concerning a violation of antitrust law or of another criminal law committed in conjunction with a potential violation of antitrust law or in conjunction with an antitrust investigation by the Department of Justice; or (2) filed or caused to be filed, testified, participated, or otherwise assisted in a federal investigation or proceeding relating to such a violation. This protection does not extend, however, to any covered individual who planned and initiated such a violation or an obstruction to its investigation.

A violation with respect to the antitrust laws shall not be construed to include a civil violation of any law that is not also a criminal violation.

A covered individual who alleges discharge or other discrimination by an employer in violation of such prohibition is authorized to seek relief: (1) by filing a complaint with the Department of Labor; or (2) if Labor has not issued a final decision within 180 days of such filing, by bringing an action at law or equity in the appropriate U.S. district court. A covered individual who prevails in any such action is entitled to all relief necessary to make the individual whole, including reinstatement with the same status, back pay plus interest, and compensation for special damages sustained.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
