<bill session="114" type="h" number="4641" updated="2018-11-21T21:40:15Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-11T16:17:03-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-05-11T16:17:03-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the establishment of an inter-agency task force to review, modify, and update best practices for pain management and prescribing pain medication, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To provide for the establishment of an inter-agency task force to review, modify, and update best practices for pain management and prescribing pain medication, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001284"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000379" joined="2016-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000168" joined="2016-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-20">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-20">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-05-03">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 114-536.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-05-03" calendar="Union" number="412">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 412.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-05-10T20:12:17-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 720 Reported to House. Resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 4641 and H.R. 5046 and makes specified amendments in order on each measure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11T13:38:28-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 720.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2234-2247" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11T13:38:33-04:00">
      <text>Resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 4641 and H.R. 5046 and makes specified amendments in order on each measure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11T13:40:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 720 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11T13:40:01-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Ted Poe to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11T13:40:33-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 4641.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11T14:13:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 720, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brownley (CA) Part A amendment no. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11T14:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 720, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brooks (IN) Part A amendment no. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11T14:22:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 720, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Grayson Part A amendment no. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11T14:25:26-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 720, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Clark (MA) Part A amendment no. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11T14:29:43-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 720, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pallone Part A amendment no. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11T14:33:56-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 720, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Nolan Part A amendment no. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11T14:38:34-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 720, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Watson Coleman Part A amendment no. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11T14:43:26-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 720, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kuster Part A amendment no. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11T14:48:34-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 720, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Schiff Part A amendment no. 9.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11T14:53:39-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 720, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Clark (MA) Part A amendment no. 10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11T14:56:28-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 720, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rothfus Part A amendment no. 11.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11T15:02:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 720, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Clark (MA) Part A amendment no. 12.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11T15:08:13-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 720, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Esty Part A amendment no. 13.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11T15:16:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 720, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Welch Part A amendment no. 14.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11T15:21:33-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 720, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Sessions Part A amendment no. 15.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11T15:27:51-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 4641.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11T15:28:50-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2247" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11T15:29:06-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2238" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11T15:30:04-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate H.R. 4641, the Chair put the question on passage of the bill, and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mrs. Brooks (IN) demanded the yea and nays, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of passage until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11T15:53:10-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2253" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="184" datetime="2016-05-11T16:17:03-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 412 - 4 (Roll no. 184).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11T16:17:05-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="524"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="114" relation="unknown" number="720"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h997"/>
    <amendment number="h996"/>
    <amendment number="h995"/>
    <amendment number="h994"/>
    <amendment number="h993"/>
    <amendment number="h992"/>
    <amendment number="h991"/>
    <amendment number="h990"/>
    <amendment number="h989"/>
    <amendment number="h988"/>
    <amendment number="h987"/>
    <amendment number="h986"/>
    <amendment number="h985"/>
    <amendment number="h984"/>
    <amendment number="h983"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2016-05-11T20:55:35Z" status="Passed House amended">(Sec. 1) This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services to convene a Pain Management Best Practices Inter-Agency Task Force to: (1) review, modify, and update best practices for pain management and prescribing pain medication; and (2) examine and identify the need for, development of, and availability of medical alternatives to opioids (drugs with effects similar to opium, such as certain pain medications).

The task force must submit a report that includes: (1) the modified and updated best practices; (2) a strategy for disseminating the best practices; (3) the feasibility of linking the best practices to Drug Enforcement Administration registration of manufacturers, distributors, and dispensers of controlled substances; (4) recommendations for effectively applying the best practices at medical facilities; and (5) recommendations regarding medical alternatives to opioids.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-536</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
