<bill session="114" type="s" number="1226" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:53Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Helium Production Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Mineral Leasing Act and the Mineral Leasing Act for Acquired Lands to promote a greater domestic helium supply, to establish a Federal helium leasing program for public land, and to secure a helium supply for national defense and Federal researchers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">American Helium Production Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-19">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">American Helium Production Act of 2015 

This bill amends the Mineral Leasing Act to permit the Department of the Interior to lease federal land for helium exploration, development, and production under substantially the same terms and conditions as federal land is leased for oil and gas exploration, development, and production.

Any lease issued for gas exploration or development in effect grants the lessee a right of first refusal to engage in helium exploration and production on land subject to the lease under the Mineral Leasing Act as well as under the Mineral Leasing Act for Acquired Lands.

The Department shall collect a $5,000 permit processing fee per application at the time the final decision is made whether to issue a permit to drill under a helium lease.

The Bureau of Land Management must prepare a programmatic environmental impact statement for an agencywide helium exploration and development program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
