<bill session="115" type="s" number="3309" updated="2019-04-18T16:45:01Z">
  <state datetime="2018-09-26">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize cyber incident response teams at the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">DHS Cyber Incident Response Teams Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DHS Cyber Incident Response Teams Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DHS Cyber Incident Response Teams Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">DHS Cyber Incident Response Teams Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2018-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-09-26" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-12-04">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 115-412.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-12-04" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="716">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 716.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="5074"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-07-31T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">DHS Cyber Incident Response Teams Act of 2018

This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Department of Homeland Security's (DHS's) national cybersecurity and communications integration center to maintain cyber hunt and incident response teams to provide, upon request, assistance including: (1) assisting asset owners and operators in restoring services following a cyber incident; (2) identifying cybersecurity risk and unauthorized cyber activity; and (3) mitigation strategies to prevent, deter, and protect against cybersecurity risks.

DHS may include private sector cybersecurity specialists on such teams, and must continually assess and evaluate the teams and their operations and report specified metrics to Congress.

No additional funds are authorized to carry out this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-412</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
