<bill session="114" type="hr" number="104" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:14Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the President should provide Congress with a detailed deployment and troop commitment plan prior to approval for authorization to commit United States Armed Forces to fight the Islamic State of Iraq and Syria.</title>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the President should provide Congress with a detailed deployment and troop commitment plan prior to approval for authorization to commit United States Armed Forces to fight the Islamic State of Iraq and Syria.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000588"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-11T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that:

 only Congress has the constitutional authority to declare war according to article 1, section 8, clause 11 of the Constitution; the President should set clear objectives for the U.S. Armed Forces before committing them to battle; and the President should provide Congress with a clear and definitive deployment and troop commitment plan before engaging in hostilities against the Islamic State of Iraq and Syria (ISIS). States that the House should not approve a request for the Use of Military Force against ISIS:

 unless the President provides Congress with requested information, and if the President commits to defeating ISIS using temporary duty assignment as a main means of troop deployment.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
