<bill session="115" type="s" number="1565" updated="2019-04-18T16:37:58Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to support the preparation and retention of outstanding educators in all fields to ensure a bright future for children in under-resourced, under-served communities in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Future Educators Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Future Educators Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Supporting Future Educators Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000457"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Supporting Future Educators Act of 2017

This bill requires the Department of Education (ED) to establish the Strengthen-Our-Schools Grant Program, which shall award competitive, renewable five-year grants to local education agencies to fund:

 teaching residency programs, including distance-learning facilities or infrastructure, mentor teacher incentives, resident salaries, and resident tuition; additional credit requirements for a teacher to become licensed in a second subject area or earn an additional qualification that meets a specific need of the school; additional credit requirements needed to qualify teachers to teach dual or concurrent enrollment programs; and housing supplements or special housing programs to support prospective teachers in high-need districts. Not less than 10% of&#160;available&#160;grant funds shall be directed to programs that address teacher shortages in rural school districts.

ED must&#160;create&#160;a national database of qualified mentor teachers who can provide student-teacher supervision to participants in teacher preparation programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
