<amendment session="114" chamber="s" number="968" updated="2018-06-04T02:15:48Z">
  <amends type="sc" number="11" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2015-03-26">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <offered datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  <description>To establish a deficit-neutral reserve fund relating to enacting middle class tax relief, including extending and expanding refundable tax credits, such as tax provisions and policies included in legislation like the Working Families Tax Relief Act, American Opportunity Tax Credit Permanence and Consolidation Act, Helping Working Families Afford Child Care Act, or the 21st Century Worker Tax Cut Act, among other legislation.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2015-03-26" how="roll" result="pass" roll="125">
      <text>Amendment SA 968 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 73 - 27. Record Vote Number: 125.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Amendment SA 968 proposed by Senator Enzi for Senator Wyden. (consideration: CR S1995-1997, S2007-2008; text: CR S1996) To establish a deficit-neutral reserve fund relating to enacting middle class tax relief, including extending and expanding refundable tax credits, such as tax provisions and policies included in legislation like the Working Families Tax Relief Act, American Opportunity Tax Credit Permanence and Consolidation Act, Helping Working Families Afford Child Care Act, or the 21st Century Worker Tax Cut Act, among other legislation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26"/>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 968 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 73 - 27. Record Vote Number: 125.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 968 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 73 - 27. Record Vote Number: 125.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 968 proposed by Senator Enzi for Senator Wyden.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1995-1997, S2007-2008" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1996" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
