<bill session="114" type="s" number="829" updated="2018-06-02T06:44:10Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Orthotics and Prosthetics Improvement Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to refine how Medicare pays for orthotics and prosthetics and to improve beneficiary experience and outcomes with orthotic and prosthetic care, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Medicare Orthotics and Prosthetics Improvement Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2015-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1530"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Medicare Orthotics and Prosthetics Improvement Act of 2015

This bill directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall designate and approve independent accreditation organizations that apply quality standards for suppliers only if they are Boards for Orthotist/Prosthetist Certification or essentially equivalent programs.

Special payment rules for certain prosthetics and custom-fabricated orthotics are extended to custom-fitted orthotics. Such rules do not apply, however, to off-the-shelf orthotics furnished on or after January 1, 2016, which are included in a competitive acquisition program.

Decisions about Medicare coverage of orthotics and prosthetics on or after January 1, 2016, must take into account the complexity of the item as well as supplier qualifications (which do not apply, however, to physicians, occupational therapists, or physical therapists state-licensed to provide such items).

Documentation created by an orthotist or prosthetist is considered part of the patient's medical record.

Requirements for suppliers of orthotics and prosthetics are separated from those for suppliers of durable medical equipment.

Orthotists and prosthetists must have a supplier number for Medicare payment to be made.

Patients are not liable for payment of furnished orthotics or prosthetics where payment may not be made or where payment is denied. Only the orthotists or prosthetists are liable in such circumstances.

Only the patient may make the minimal self-adjustment required to qualify off-the-shelf orthotics for Medicare coverage in a competitive acquisition program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
