<bill session="114" type="s" number="2214" updated="2018-06-02T07:11:21Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cody Miller Patient Medication Information Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require patient medication information to be provided with certain prescription drugs.</title>
    <title type="display">Cody Miller Patient Medication Information Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000555"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2015-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2015-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2015-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2015-10-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Cody Miller Patient Medication Information Act

This bill amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to direct the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) to regulate the authorship, content, format, and dissemination of patient medication information for prescription drugs. (Patient medication information includes the instructional brochures provided to patients when a prescription is filled.)

FDA regulations must require drug patient medication information to be scientifically accurate, to be based on the approved professional labeling, and to include plain language that is not promotional in tone or content and that provides specified information including drug uses and side effects.

The regulations must include standards for: (1) timely reviews and updates of patient medication information, (2) updates to help communicate information that is shared by similar drugs, and (3) assessing the effectiveness of patient medication information in promoting patient understanding and safe and effective use of medications. The FDA must develop a public electronic repository for all patient medication information.

When a prescription drug is sold or dispensed, patient medication information must be provided.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
