<bill session="114" type="s" number="1036" updated="2018-06-02T06:45:42Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sage-Grouse Protection and Conservation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to provide certain Western States assistance in the development of statewide conservation and management plans for the protection and recovery of sage-grouse species, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Sage-Grouse Protection and Conservation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000562"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2015-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2015-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2015-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2015-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2015-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2015-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2015-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2015-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-06">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="1997"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Sage-Grouse Protection and Conservation Act

This bill addresses the management of the greater sage-grouse (Centrocercus urophasianus) and the Gunnison sage-grouse (Centrocercus minimus) in California, Colorado, Idaho, Montana, Nevada, North Dakota, Oregon, South Dakota, Utah, Washington, and Wyoming.

If the Department of Agriculture (USDA) or the Department of the Interior receives, or has already received, from one of those states a statewide conservation and management plan for the protection and recovery of those sage-grouse species, the appropriate department must take steps during the next six years to: (1) allow for appropriate monitoring and collection of data, and (2) assess the state plan's success.

The appropriate department must: (1) share data with states and assist them in developing and implementing plans; (2) require states that opt to have plans in lieu of federal endangered species plans to monitor and report on relevant data, including population trends; (3) use statewide plans as the basis for all relevant determinations under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969; and (4) stay any land use planning activities relating to federal management of sage-grouse species on public land or National Forest System land within those states that have plans.

The appropriate department may extend the provisions of the bill for six more years with the consent of the relevant state.

Interior must fully implement for at least six years Secretarial Order 3336 to prevent and suppress rangeland fire and restore sagebrush landscapes impacted by fire across the Western United States.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
