<bill session="114" type="s" number="55" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:49Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Offshore Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend the seaward boundaries of certain States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Offshore Fairness Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2015-01-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="South Carolina"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Offshore Fairness Act 

This bill amends the Submerged Lands Act to change the seaward boundaries of Alabama, Florida, Georgia, Louisiana, Mississippi, North Carolina, South Carolina, and Virginia from a distance of three geographic miles from the coast line to a distance of three marine leagues. This change expands the offshore jurisdictions of those states.

The Department of the Interior must convey the submerged land in the Outer Continental Shelf that is within this expanded area to a state upon request. After a conveyance, states are prohibited from imposing on that land: (1) burdens or requirements on an interest owner that would be stricter than federal burdens or requirements, or (2) administrative or judicial penalties or sanctions on an interest owner that are more severe than the federal penalties or sanctions.

The submerged land within the seaward boundaries of those states are subject to federal oil and gas mineral rights and are considered to be part of the federal Outer Continental Shelf for purposes of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act, the Gulf of Mexico Energy Security Act of 2006, and other laws applicable to the leasing of the oil and gas resources.

Alabama, Florida, Louisiana, Mississippi, and Texas are given exclusive fishery management authority to manage and conserve the Gulf of Mexico red snapper in adjacent coastal waters of the applicable state and through the exclusive economic zone. The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration must provide financial assistance to those states for stock assessments and data collection relating to the Gulf of Mexico red snapper.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
