<bill session="114" type="s" number="2756" updated="2018-06-02T07:16:24Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Iran Cyber Sanctions Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to impose sanctions with respect to Iranian persons responsible for knowingly engaging in significant activities undermining cybersecurity, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Iran Cyber Sanctions Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000605"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2016-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2016-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2016-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2016-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5222"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Iran Cyber Sanctions Act of 2016

This bill requires the President to report to Congress at least every 180 days regarding significant activities undermining cybersecurity conducted by Iranian persons against the United States or U.S. persons. The reports must: (1) identify Iranians involved in such activities; (2) describe their conduct; (3) assess the Iranian government's or other foreign governments' material support for such activities; and (4) provide a strategy to counter efforts by Iranian persons to conduct such activities, which shall include engaging foreign governments to halt the capabilities of such Iranian persons.

The President must include on the Office of Foreign Assets Control's specially designated nationals and blocked persons list (which identifies individuals and entities whose assets within the United States are blocked from being accessed and with whom U.S. persons are prohibited from engaging in transactions) Iranian persons who are: (1) identified in such reports; or (2) indicted by the Department of Justice in connection with such activities undermining U.S. cybersecurity, unless the President submits an explanation for excluding such a person from that list.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
