<bill session="115" type="s" number="1442" updated="2019-04-18T16:37:29Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish United States policy for the Arctic region for the next 10 years, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing Our Arctic Interests Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing Our Arctic Interests Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Securing Our Arctic Interests Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001198"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Military command and structure"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Securing Our Arctic Interests Act of 2017

This bill authorizes the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, to enter into a contract or contracts to procure up to six polar-class icebreakers.

The Government Accountability Office (GAO) must report to Congress on the cost and procurement schedule for new icebreakers.

The Department of the Navy must report to the congressional defense committees on the Navy's capabilities in the Arctic region. The GAO shall transmit a review of such report to such committees.

The bill establishes a Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for the Arctic Region, who shall oversee:

 advocacy for U.S. national security interests in the region, mitigation of operational seams to improve unity of effort among the combatant commands with responsibility for the region, identification of any capability and resource gaps in the region and the formulation of plans to mitigate such gaps, identification of actions by foreign nations that increase the threat to U.S. interests in the region and the formulation of mitigation plans, and planning of military-to-military cooperation with partner nations that have mutual security interests in the region. The Department of Defense must report to the congressional defense committees on: (1) the requirements and investment plans for military infrastructure required to protect national security interests in the region; and (2) strategies to improve U.S. communications, domain awareness, and navigational capabilities in the region.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
