<bill session="114" type="h" number="4119" updated="2019-03-03T14:40:52Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-22T13:56:47-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-03-22T13:56:47-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the exchange of certain land located in Gulf Islands National Seashore, Jackson County, Mississippi, between the National Park Service and the Veterans of Foreign Wars, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Gulf Islands National Seashore Land Exchange Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Gulf Islands National Seashore Land Exchange Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Gulf Islands National Seashore Land Exchange Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gulf Islands National Seashore Land Exchange Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Gulf Islands National Seashore Land Exchange Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000601"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02">
      <text>Subcommittee on Federal Lands Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-02-03" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-03-02">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 114-441.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-03-02" calendar="Union" number="337">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 337.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-03-22T13:51:20-04:00">
      <text>Mr. McClintock moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-22T13:51:38-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1523-1524" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-22T13:51:48-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4119.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2016-03-22T13:56:47-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1523" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-03-22T13:56:48-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-04">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-13">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-09-06">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski with amendments. With written report No. 114-340.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-09-06" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="611">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 611.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks" code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2012"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Seashores and lakeshores"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-06T16:01:45Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Gulf Islands National Seashore Land Exchange Act of 2016

(Sec. 2) This bill authorizes the Department of the Interior, through the National Park Service, to convey to the Veterans of Foreign Wars Post 5699 approximately 1.542 acres of real property located within the Gulf Islands National Seashore in Jackson County, Mississippi, in exchange for a parcel of 2.161 acres.

The values of the parcels of real property to be exchanged shall be equal, as determined by an appraisal conducted:

 by a qualified and independent appraiser, and in accordance with nationally recognized appraisal standards. If the values of such parcels of real property are not equal, their values shall be equalized through:

 a cash payment, or adjustments to their acreage. Interior shall require the Post to cover Interior's costs to carry out the land exchange or to reimburse Interior for them. If Interior collects amounts from the Post in advance of incurring the actual costs, it shall refund to the Post any amount in excess of those costs.

The bill subjects the exchange to valid existing rights.

Land and interests acquired by the United States by this bill shall be administered as part of the Gulf Islands National Seashore.

Interior shall modify the boundaries of the Gulf Islands National Seashore to reflect such land exchange upon its completion.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-441</report>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-340</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
