<bill session="113" type="h" number="5845" updated="2016-10-25T16:17:46Z">
  <state datetime="2014-12-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-12-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Comprehensive Addiction and Recovery Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Attorney General to award grants to address the national epidemics of prescription opioid abuse and heroin use.</title>
    <title type="display">Comprehensive Addiction and Recovery Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001270" joined="2014-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000266" joined="2014-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000295" joined="2014-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001179" joined="2014-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2014-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000185" joined="2014-12-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-10">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-10">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-12-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Comprehensive Addiction and Recovery Act of 2014 - Directs the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to convene a Pain Management Best Practices Interagency Task Force.

Authorizes the Attorney General to make grants to address drug abuse, including for educational efforts, communitywide strategies that address local drug crises, alternative to incarceration programs, disposal sites for unwanted prescription medications, educational programs for offenders, programs to address the use of opioids among pregnant and parenting female offenders, and veterans treatment court programs.

Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Center for Substance Abuse Treatment to award grants to state substance abuse agencies, units of local government, nonprofit organizations, and Indian tribes or tribal organizations that have a high rate, or have had a rapid increase, in the use of opioids.

Directs the Attorney General to make grants for medication assisted treatment programs through criminal justice agencies, initiatives involving young people, and recovery services.

 Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to prohibit the Department of Education (ED) from including any question about the conviction of an applicant for the possession or sale of illegal drugs on the Free Application for Federal Student Aid (FAFSA) form.

Directs HHS to establish a bipartisan Task Force on Recovery and Collateral Consequences (collateral consequences are penalties imposed on an individual as a result of a criminal conviction but not as part of the court judgment, or optionally imposed by an administrative agency, official, or civil court).

 Requires grants under this Act to give priority to states that provide civil liability protection for individuals administering naloxone (a prescription drug used to rapidly reverse an opioid overdose) to counteract opioid overdoses.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
