<bill session="114" type="s" number="2681" updated="2019-03-03T14:41:06Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">San Juan County Settlement Implementation Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to retire coal preference right lease applications for which the Secretary has made an affirmative commercial quantities determination, to substitute certain land selections of the Navajo Nation, to designate certain wilderness areas, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">San Juan County Settlement Implementation Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001046"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2016-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 114-509.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">San Juan County Settlement Implementation Act of 2016

This bill authorizes the Department of the Interior to retire any coal preference right lease application for which it has made an affirmative commercial quantities determination by:

 issuing bidding rights in exchange for relinquishment of the application, and making a payment to the relevant state of 50% of the dollar amount of any bidding right subsequently used in lieu of any monetary bonus in a coal lease sale or of rental or royalty under a federal coal lease. Interior shall make such payments from amounts that would otherwise be deposited in the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts under the Mineral Leasing Act.

The bill declares such bidding rights fully transferable to any other person.

The bill cancels specified land selections made by the Navajo Nation pursuant to the Navajo-Hopi Land Settlement Act of 1974. Subject to specified exclusions, the Navajo Nation may make new land selections to replace those canceled.

The bill designates approximately 7,242 acres of land as the Ah-shi-sle-pah Wilderness and incorporates approximately 2,250 acres of specified federal land into the Bisti/De-Na-Zin Wilderness.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
