<bill session="114" type="s" number="3349" updated="2018-06-02T07:48:14Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Career and Technical Education for Adult Learners Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 to improve career and technical education opportunities for adult learners, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Career and Technical Education for Adult Learners Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2016-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5847" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Career and Technical Education for Adult Learners Act of 2016 

This bill amends the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 to modify the requirements for career and technical education programs to align the programs with adult education programs.

The bill revises the purposes of the Act to include promoting adult education and supporting partnerships among adult education programs.

States may develop core indicators of performance for career and technical education students at the adult education level. At a minimum, the indicators must measure: (1) student attainment of challenging career and technical skill proficiency, including student achievement on technical assessments that are aligned with industry-recognized standards; and (2) the eligibly entity's performance on the indicators of performance described in the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act.

The bill also: (1) includes the state director of adult education in the development of the state plan for career and technical education, and (2) specifies that adult education providers that also offer certain career and technical education courses leading to technical skill proficiency and an industry-recognized credential or certificate are eligible to receive funds under the Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
