<bill session="115" type="s" number="982" updated="2019-04-18T16:35:30Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act to require mandatory reporting of incidents of child abuse or neglect, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Speak Up to Protect Every Abused Kid Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Speak Up to Protect Every Abused Kid Act</title>
    <title type="display">Speak Up to Protect Every Abused Kid Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2018-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2018-01-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Speak Up to Protect Every Abused Kid Act 

This bill amends the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act to direct the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to make grants to eligible entities to carry out educational campaigns and provide evidence-based or evidence-informed training regarding state laws for mandatory reporting of incidents of child abuse or neglect.

A state plan under a grant program for child abuse or neglect prevention and treatment shall contain specified assurances about: mandatory reporting of suspected or known incidents of child abuse or neglect to state child protective services agencies or law enforcement agencies; procedures to ensure coordination with law enforcement and state or community-based victims' services agencies to ensure that child abuse victims are referred for appropriate follow-up services; primary state responsibility to accept and investigate reports of known and suspected child abuse or neglect for an incident that occurred in the state, even if the child or alleged perpetrator resides in a different state; and established state procedures to screen for domestic violence in the course of investigating child abuse. The bill specifies those individuals and professionals who are required to report suspected or known incidents of child abuse or neglect. HHS shall collect information on state laws for mandatory reporting of incidents of child abuse or neglect in order to assess the implementation of the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
