<bill session="114" type="h" number="5656" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:40Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TRASH Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Trash Reduction and Sensible Handling Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to authorize States to restrict interstate waste imports and impose a higher fee on out-of-State waste.</title>
    <title type="display">TRASH Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001227" joined="2016-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2016-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2016-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001166" joined="2016-07-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1953"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Trash Reduction and Sensible Handling Act of 2016 or the TRASH Act

This bill amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to authorize state solid waste management plans to restrict the importation of out-of-state waste at the state and local level by requiring out-of-state waste to be from states with waste handling and reduction standards that are equivalent or higher than the standards of the state receiving the waste.

Those plans may impose a community benefit fee on out-of-state waste, which may be higher than the fees for in-state waste. States may provide those fees to affected communities and may differentiate community benefit fees based on whether the imported waste was disposed of at a landfill, an incinerator, a resource recovery facility, a waste-to-energy facility, or other waste handling facility.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
