<bill session="114" type="h" number="1316" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:38Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans' Heritage Firearms Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide an amnesty period during which veterans and their family members can register certain firearms in the National Firearms Registration and Transfer Record, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Veterans' Heritage Firearms Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001144"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001250" joined="2015-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001184" joined="2015-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000611" joined="2016-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001172" joined="2015-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="670"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-04T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans' Heritage Firearms Act of 2015

Provides a 90-day amnesty period during which veterans and their family members can register in the National Firearms Registration and Transfer Record any firearm acquired before October 31, 1968, by a veteran while a member of the Armed Forces stationed outside the continental United States. Grants such an individual limited immunity under the federal criminal code and the Internal Revenue Code with respect to the acquisition, possession, transportation, or alteration of such firearm before or concurrent with such registration. Extends such immunity to a veteran who attempts to register a qualifying firearm outside of the amnesty period if the veteran surrenders the firearm within 30 days after being notified of potential criminal liability for continued possession.

Requires the Attorney General to provide clear notice of, and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out an outreach program and develop a communications strategy to provide veterans information regarding, the amnesty and registration period.

Requires the Attorney General to: (1) transfer each firearm qualifying as a curio or relic that has been forfeited to the United States to the first qualified museum that requests it, and (2) publish information identifying each such firearm that is available to be transferred to a museum. Prohibits the Attorney General from destroying any such firearm that has been forfeited until five years after the forfeiture. Requires that any firearm transferred to a qualified museum be registered to the transferee.

Makes a prohibition against transfer or possession of a machine-gun inapplicable to a transfer to or by, or possession by, a museum that is open to the public and incorporated as a not-for-profit corporation under applicable state law.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
