<bill session="114" type="s" number="868" updated="2018-06-02T06:44:39Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Justice for Former American Hostages in Iran Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a fund to make payment to the Americans held hostage in Iran, and to members of their families, who are identified as members of the proposed class in case number 1:00-CV-03110 (ESG) of the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Justice for Former American Hostages in Iran Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2015-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2015-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2015-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1635"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3338"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Justice for Former American Hostages in Iran Act of 2015

Establishes in the Treasury the American Hostages in Iran Compensation Fund to: (1) make payments to the Americans held hostage in Iran, and to their families, who are identified as members of the proposed class in case number 1:00-CV-03110 (ESG) of the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia; and (2) satisfy their claims against Iran relating to the taking of hostages and treatment of personnel of the U.S. embassy in Tehran between November 3, 1979, and January 20, 1981.

Imposes a surcharge, to be deposited into the Fund, of 30% on the amount of: (1) any fine or penalty imposed for a violation (committed on or after enactment of this Act) of a law or regulation penalizing any economic activity relating to Iran that is administered by the Departments of State, Treasury, Justice, Commerce, or Energy; or (2) the monetary amount of a settlement entered into by a person regarding a suspected violation of such a law or regulation.

 Requires Fund payments to members of the proposed class in the following order of priority:

 $10,000 for each day of captivity first to each living former hostage and then to the estate of each deceased former hostage, and $5,000 to each spouse and child of a former hostage for each day of captivity of the former hostage. Prohibits a payment recipient from maintaining an action against Iran in any federal or state court for any claims relating to the hostage events. Waives and forever releases all existing claims against Iran for those events upon payment from the Fund to all designated recipients.

Requires the State Department to submit recommendations to Congress if Fund amounts will be insufficient to pay all recipients within 444 days after enactment of this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
