<bill session="114" type="s" number="2938" updated="2018-08-16T22:54:05Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Certainty for States and Tribes Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to reestablish the Royalty Policy Committee in order to further a more consultative process with key Federal, State, tribal, environmental, and energy stakeholders, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Certainty for States and Tribes Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2016-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2016-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2016-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2879-2880" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5259"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Certainty for States and Tribes Act

This bill directs the Department of the Interior to reestablish the Royalty Policy Committee, which should include members representing states and Indian tribes who produce minerals on federal or tribal land. In addition, Interior must establish a State and Tribal Resources Board, a subcommittee to the Royalty Policy Committee. The board and committee must advise Interior as it formulates policies and regulations regarding mineral production on federal and tribal lands. The board can delay the issuance of a final regulation by Interior if the board determines that such regulation will have a negative state or Tribal budgetary or economic impact.

The Bureau of Land Management (BLM) must complete by January 15, 2019, its programmatic review of the federal coal leasing program as described in Secretarial Order 3338. Secretarial Order 3338 directed the BLM to prepare a discretionary review of the federal coal program. (Interior issued Secretarial Order 3338 on January 15, 2016.)

The moratorium on the issuance of new federal coal leasesby the BLMshall terminate on January 16, 2019.Additionally, the bill allows leases and modifications to be issued by the BLM for any coalleasing application currently under review. Secretarial Order 3338 prohibited approval of such leases and modifications.

The bill also directs the BLM toconduct federal coal lease sales and modifications within one year after it completes an analysis of anapplication.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
