<bill session="113" type="h" number="5744" updated="2016-10-25T16:17:24Z">
  <state datetime="2014-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">State Wide Interoperable Communications Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SWIC Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require recipients of State Homeland Security Grant Program funding to preserve and strengthen interoperable emergency communications capabilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SWIC Enhancement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000604"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2014-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Preparedness, Response and Communications.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Emergency Preparedness, Response, and Communications" code="HSHM12" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-11-19T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">State Wide Interoperable Communications Enhancement Act or the SWIC Enhancement Act - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require a state to include in its application for State Homeland Security Grant Program funding a certification: (1) that the governor of the state has designated a Statewide Interoperability Coordinator, or (2) indicating that the state is performing the functions of such a Coordinator in another manner and identifying the primary point of contact for performance of such functions.

Sets forth as such Coordinator's functions:

 overseeing the daily operations of the state's interoperability efforts; coordinating state interoperability and communications projects and grant applications for such projects; establishing and maintaining working groups to develop and implement key interoperability initiatives; and implementing and updating a Statewide Communications Interoperability Plan that specifies the current status of state efforts to enhance communications interoperability within the state, including future goals for communications interoperability among emergency response agencies in the state.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
