<bill session="114" type="h" number="1015" updated="2018-06-02T02:24:03Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Business Opportunities for Veterans Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the oversight of contracts awarded by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans.</title>
    <title type="display">Protecting Business Opportunities for Veterans Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001057"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-13">
      <text>Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" code="HSVR08" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-20T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Business Opportunities for Veterans Act of 2015

Extends subcontracting limitations that apply to certain small businesses awarded contracts under various Small Business Administration (SBA) programs to small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans with or without service-connected disabilities who are awarded Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) contracts.

Requires, for purposes of applying such subcontracting limitations to veterans with small businesses awarded such VA contracts, that: (1) small businesses owned and controlled by veterans be treated in the same manner as small businesses owned and controlled by veterans with service-connected disabilities, and (2) "similarly situated entities" include subcontractors for small businesses owned and controlled by a veteran with or without a service-connected disability (contract amounts expended by small businesses on subcontractors that are similarly situated entities are not considered toward subcontracting limits).

Directs the VA Secretary, before awarding such a contract, to obtain from the offeror a certification: (1) specifying and promising to comply with the subcontracting performance requirements applicable to such offeror, and (2) acknowledging that the certification is subject to criminal laws concerning false or fraudulent statements or representations. Subjects small businesses to fines, imprisonment, or both for not acting in good faith.

Requires the VA's Chief Acquisition Officer and the Director of the Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization to: (1) establish a process to monitor the subcontracting requirement compliance of veterans' small businesses that are awarded VA contracts, and (2) refer violations to the VA's Inspector General. Directs the Inspector General to submit annual reports to Congress regarding such violations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
