<bill session="114" type="s" number="2935" updated="2018-06-02T07:18:46Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">End Housing Subsidies for the Rich Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to limit the availability of public housing for over-income families.</title>
    <title type="display">End Housing Subsidies for the Rich Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000444"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000542" joined="2016-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3083"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">End Housing Subsidies for the Rich Act of 2016

This bill amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to revise eligibility requirements for assisted housing.

If a public housing agency (PHA) determines that a tenant's income is greater than 120% of the area median income for two consecutive years, the PHA must terminate the family's tenancy within six months.

Such a family may, however, continue to occupy the dwelling unit month-to-month if:

 the PHA charges the family the fair market rent, and there are no eligible families applying for housing assistance from the PHA for that month and the agency provides at least a 30-day public notice of the availability of such assistance. A PHA may not rent a dwelling unit to or assist families with net family assets exceeding $100,000 annually (adjusted for inflation) or an ownership interest in property that is suitable for occupancy. This restriction does not apply to victims of domestic violence, individuals using housing assistance for homeownership opportunities, or a family that is offering a property for sale.

PHAs must require applicants to authorize financial institutions to disclose records necessary to determine eligibility for benefits.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
