<bill session="115" type="h" number="3909" updated="2019-04-18T16:15:50Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-10-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Gandhi-King Scholarly Exchange Initiative focusing on peace and nonviolence in global conflict resolution, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gandhi-King Scholarly Exchange Initiative Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gandhi-King Scholarly Exchange Initiative Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Gandhi-King Scholarly Exchange Initiative Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000287"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2018-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2018-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-10-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Area studies and international education"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="India"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-10-02T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Gandhi-King Scholarly Exchange Initiative Act of 2017 

This bill authorizes the Department of State to carry out, in cooperation with the government of India, the Gandhi-King Scholarly Exchange Initiative comprised of educational, scholarly, and professional exchange programs, including:

 an annual public diplomacy forum for scholars from the United States and India that focuses on the legacies of Mahatma Gandhi and Martin Luther King, Jr.; a professional development training initiative for government employees to develop international conflict solutions based on the principles of nonviolence developed in consultation with the president and chief executive officer of the United States Institute of Peace, the Under Secretary for Public Diplomacy and Public Affairs of the Department of State, and U.S. cooperating partners; and an undergraduate, graduate, and post-graduate student exchange for students to study the history and legacies of Martin Luther King, Jr., and Mahatma Gandhi, visit historic sites in India and the United States that were integral to the American civil rights movement and the Indian independence movement, and research and develop papers on the importance of peace, nonviolence, and reconciliation in current conflict regions.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
