<bill session="114" type="s" number="1541" updated="2018-06-02T06:55:10Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transportation Empowerment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to empower States with authority for most taxing and spending for highway programs and mass transit programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Transportation Empowerment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000577"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2015-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2015-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000444" joined="2015-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2015-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000127" joined="2015-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2716"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hybrid, electric, and advanced technology vehicles"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Regional and metropolitan planning"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Transportation Empowerment Act

This bill prescribes a limitation on funding of transportation programs and projects for FY2016-FY2020.

Appropriations out of the Highway Trust Fund (HTF) (other than the Mass Transit Account) are authorized for FY2016-FY2020, subject to a certain limitation, for specified core programs under the federal-aid highway program, including:

 emergency relief for highways and roads, the federal lands transportation program, and Federal Highway Administration administrative expenses. A state may transfer and use excess federal-aid highway funds for any surface transportation project (including mass transit and rail).

Certain limits are placed on federal assistance to states for highway bridge replacement and rehabilitation to bridges on the federal-aid highway system.

Beginning with FY2015, a highway construction or improvement project shall not be considered a federal project:

 unless and until a state expends federal funds for the construction portion of the project, solely by reason of the state expenditure of federal funds before the construction phase of the project (including for any environmental document or design work), or upon state reimbursement to the federal government of the federal costs of such projects. The Internal Revenue Code is amended to make amounts in the HTF available for expenditure for core highway programs through FY2022.

The Department of the Treasury shall pay from the HTF into the Treasury general fund amounts equivalent to the floor stocks refunds made before July 1, 2022, as well as into the Airport and Airway Trust Fund amounts equivalent to certain aviation fuel taxes received before October 1, 2022.

A motor fuel tax rate schedule is prescribed for the financing of core highway programs.

Treasury authority to make certain transfers to the Mass Transit Account shall be terminated at the end of FY2016, at which time Treasury shall transfer all amounts from the Mass Transit Account to the Highway Account.

The national highway performance program is revised to repeal program requirements for specified National Highway System transportation improvement projects, including environmental mitigation projects.

The surface transportation program is revised to eliminate from eligibility for program assistance:

 carpool projects, fringe and corridor parking facilities and programs, including electric vehicle and natural gas vehicle infrastructure, and bicycle transportation and pedestrian walkways projects; transportation alternatives; and environmental mitigation projects, including environmental restoration and pollution abatement projects. Also repealed are:

 the obligation of a state to use a portion of program funds for replacement or rehabilitation of off-system bridges, metropolitan transportation planning requirements for federal-aid highways, and the authorization of federal assistance to states for historic bridges. Certain requirements of the highway safety improvement program are revised or repealed, eliminating eligibility for projects for pedestrian or bicyclist safety or safety of persons with disabilities.

The congestion mitigation and air quality improvement program and the transportation alternatives program are repealed.

Appropriations out of the HTF (other than the Mass Transit Account) are authorized for FY2016-FY2020 for the highway research and development program.

Treasury shall allocate to the states for surface transportation projects (including mass transit and rail) any excess highway tax receipts appropriated to the HTF in FY2016-FY2019.

Excise taxes on gasoline, diesel fuel or kerosene, and diesel-water fuel emulsion are reduced.

Credits or refunds are required for certain floor stocks taxes on liquids imposed before October 1, 2020.

This Act shall become effective only if the Office of Management and Budget certifies that it is deficit neutral.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
