<bill session="114" type="s" number="1089" updated="2018-06-02T06:45:57Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Social Impact Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to encourage and support partnerships between the public and private sectors to improve our Nation's social programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Social Impact Partnership Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2015-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2015-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2015-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001071" joined="2016-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2016-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1336"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5170"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3458"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Teenage pregnancy"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Social Impact Partnership Act

Amends title XX (Block Grants to States for Social Services and Elder Justice) of the Social Security Act to add a new part C (Social Impact Partnerships).

Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to publish in the Federal Register a request for proposals from states or local governments for social impact partnership projects which produce a measurable, clearly defined outcome that results in social benefit, such as employment for the unemployed, high school graduation, and reduction of teen and unplanned pregnancies as well as incidences and adverse consequences of child abuse and neglect. Requires applications to include a feasibility study, funded under this Act, which contains specified information.

Requires the Secretary to decide whether to enter into such a contract within six months after receiving an application.

Requires independent evaluation to determine whether the state or local government project has met an outcome specified in the contract in order for such governments to receive outcome payments.

Establishes the Federal Interagency Council on Social Impact Partnerships.

Makes appropriations for 10 years to carry out this Act.

Authorizes the Government Accountability Office to audit the social impact partnership project activities of any state, local, government, or nongovernment entity that receives funds under this Act.

Amends the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 to require the appropriate federal financial supervisory agency to consider, in assessing and taking into account the record of a financial institution in meeting the credit needs of its entire community, its investments in social impact partnership projects.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
