<bill session="114" type="h" number="3227" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:43Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting America's Warriors Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect the Second Amendment rights of members of the Armed Forces and civilian employees of the Department of Defense trained in the use of firearms to carry officially-issued or personally-owned firearms on military installations in the United States.</title>
    <title type="display">Protecting America's Warriors Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000604"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001092" joined="2016-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2016-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001144" joined="2015-10-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting America's Warriors Act

This bill states that any provision in any law, rule, regulation, or executive order that prohibits trained military personnel or trained civilian personnel from carrying officially-issued or personally-owned firearms (defined as handguns only) on a military installation in the United States shall have no force or effect with regard to such military personnel.

The Department of Defense and the Secretaries of the military departments shall not reinstate the firearm bans or enact similar restrictions prohibiting or restricting trained military personnel or trained civilian personnel from carrying officially-issued or personally-owned firearms on a military installation in the United States.

The President shall not take any executive action or promulgate any rule or issue any executive order or regulation to prohibit or restrict trained military personnel or trained civilian personnel from carrying officially-issued or personally-owned firearms on a military installation in the United States.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
