<bill session="115" type="h" number="3233" updated="2019-04-18T16:12:41Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote fair trade, allow for greater participation in trade enforcement, and improve accountability and transparency in trade matters.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Trade Accessibility and Accountability Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Trade Accessibility and Accountability Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Fair Trade Accessibility and Accountability Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001180"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2017-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Trade" code="HSWM04" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="U.S. International Trade Commission"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Fair Trade Accessibility and Accountability Act of 2017

This bill directs the Department of Commerce to provide financial assistance to small firms to assist them in preparing and filing petitions to obtain the remedies and benefits available under the Tariff Act of 1930 relating to the imposition of countervailing and antidumping duties investigations. Commerce shall review an application for assistance submitted by a small firm based on the firm's ability-to-pay and its economic impact in its local community. The amount of such assistance is capped.

The bill amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to modify criteria for determining industry support for petitions in countervailing and antidumping duties investigations.

A U.S. business enterprise may file a petition with the Senate Committee on Finance or the House Committee on Ways and Means to determine whether or not a foreign country has violated its obligations under any trade agreement to which the United States is a party.

 Any good listed on a General Services Administration federal supply schedule described as made in America must have all or virtually all of the good and component parts made in the United States. Suppliers of any good not in compliance with Made in America requirements are subject to civil penalties.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
