<bill session="114" type="s" number="2528" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:38Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote the safe manufacture, use, and transportation of lithium batteries and cells, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lithium Battery Safety Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="display">Lithium Battery Safety Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000032"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Lithium Battery Safety Act of 2016

This bill amends the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 to repeal the prohibition against new Department of Transportation (DOT) regulations for the transportation by aircraft of lithium metal cells or batteries or lithium ion cells or batteries that are more stringent than the requirements of the International Civil Aviation Organization Technical Instructions for the Safe Transport of Dangerous Goods by Air, as amended.

DOT shall:

 initiate a comprehensive review of existing and any other applicable regulations regarding the air transportation, including passenger-carrying and cargo aircraft, of lithium batteries and cells; and take any additional action appropriate to mitigate sufficiently the risks posed by lithium batteries and cells to safe air transport. The President shall establish a lithium battery safety working group to promote and coordinate efforts related to the promotion of the safe manufacture, use, and transportation of lithium batteries and cells.

The working group shall research:

 additional ways to decrease the risk of fires and explosions from lithium batteries and cells, additional ways to ensure uniform transportation requirements for both bulk and individual batteries, and new or existing technologies that could reduce the fire and explosion risk of lithium batteries and cells.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
