<bill session="114" type="s" number="1222" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:53Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Continuity of Electric Capacity Resources Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Power Act to provide for reports relating to electric capacity resources of transmission organizations and the amendment of certain tariffs to address the procurement of electric capacity resources, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Continuity of Electric Capacity Resources Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-19">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Continuity of Electric Capacity Resources Act 

This bill amends the Federal Power Act to require the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to notify transmission organizations that they must file an electric capacity resources report if they have a tariff on file that addresses the procurement of electric capacity resources.

Report contents must:

 identify electric capacity resources available to the transmission organization; describe the fuel sources and operational characteristics of each electric capacity resource; evaluate the financial health, viability, and projected remaining years of service of these available electric capacity resources; and assess the current and projected reliability of the elements of the bulk-power system under the transmission organization's control. Subsequent to this report, transmission organizations must also submit tariff amendments that would achieve specified objectives, including a diverse generation portfolio and the availability of transmission facilities and transmission support services that would provide a continuous supply of electricity for customers.

The bill shields any person from liability for actions taken to comply with a FERC order for temporary connections and exchanges of facilities during war or an energy emergency.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
