<amendment session="114" chamber="h" number="956" updated="2019-02-14T23:30:52Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2406" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2016-02-26T10:30:30-05:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000456"/>
  <offered datetime="2016-02-26"/>
  <description>Amendment requires the Forest Administrator to amend the travel plan for the Kisatchie National Forest in Louisiana to allow Utility Terrain Vehicle (UTV) access on roads designated by the Secretary of Louisiana Wildlife and Fisheries, except when such designation would pose an unacceptable safety risk. If a road is denied, the amendment requires the Forest Administrator to publish a notice in the Federal Register with a justification for the closure.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment No. 11 printed in House Report 114-429 to require the Forest Administrator to amend the travel plan for the Kisatchie National Forest in Louisiana to allow Utility Terrain Vehicle (UTV) access on roads nominated by the Secretary of Louisiana Wildlife and Fisheries, except when such designation would pose an unacceptable safety risk. If a road is denied, the amendment would require the Forest Administrator to publish a notice in the Federal Register with a justification for the closure.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2016-02-26T10:30:30-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Fleming amendment (A011) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-02-26T10:22:30-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A011) offered by Mr. Fleming.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H973-974" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H973" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-26"/>
    <action datetime="2016-02-26T10:30:30-05:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-26T10:22:30-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A011) offered by Mr. Fleming.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H973-974" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H973" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-26T10:30:30-05:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Fleming amendment (A011) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-26">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
