<bill session="114" type="s" number="2128" updated="2018-06-02T07:10:33Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-07">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Inspector General Mandates Reporting Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Inspector General Mandates Reporting Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Council of Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency to submit to Congress a report on Inspector General mandates.</title>
    <title type="display">Inspector General Mandates Reporting Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001197"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2015-10-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-10-07" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-11-30">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson with an amendment. With written report No. 114-171.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-11-30" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="305">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 305.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3011"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-30T22:07:09Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Inspector General Mandates Reporting Act of 2015

(Sec. 2) This bill requires each Office of Inspector General to submit to the Council of Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency a report which: (1) shall include a list of each reporting requirement for such Office, and (2) may include a list of reporting requirements that such Office recommends should be modified or repealed.

Within 60 days after receiving such report, the Council shall submit to Congress a report which: (1) shall include a list of reporting requirements that are common to more than one Office of Inspector General and a list of reporting requirements that are unique to each Office, and (2) may include recommendations for reporting requirements that should be modified or repealed.

These reports shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified index.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-171</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
