<bill session="114" type="h" number="6187" updated="2018-10-30T18:54:39Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VET MD Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans-Specific Education for Tomorrow's Medical Doctors Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish in the Department of Veterans Affairs a pilot program instituting a clinical observation program for pre-med students preparing to attend medical school.</title>
    <title type="display">VET MD Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000490" joined="2016-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2016-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2016-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001151" joined="2016-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000170" joined="2016-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000576" joined="2016-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2016-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2016-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000131" joined="2016-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1380"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans-Specific Education for Tomorrow's Medical Doctors Act or the VET MD Act

This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to carry out a three-year pilot program at at least five VA medical centers to provide undergraduate students a clinical observation experience.

The VA shall ensure that such program:

 increases the awareness, knowledge, and empathy of future medical professionals toward the medical conditions common to veterans; increases the diversity of the recruitment pool of future VA physicians; provides a diverse clinical observation experience commensurate with the standard expectations for medical school applications; and expands clinical observation opportunities for all students by encouraging students of all backgrounds to consider a career in medicine. The VA shall select undergraduate students who are U.S. citizens enrolled in an accredited science or medical program of study to participate in the program, with priority to students who resided in a health professional shortage area and who are the first in their immediate family to attend an undergraduate institution.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
