<bill session="114" type="h" number="4607" updated="2019-02-13T17:31:25Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Estuary Restoration Act of 2000 to modify requirements that apply to projects carried out under the estuary habitat restoration program established by the Secretary of the Army, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Estuary Restoration Act of 2000 to modify requirements that apply to projects carried out under the estuary habitat restoration program established by the Secretary of the Army, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2016-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2016-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000612" joined="2016-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2016-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2016-04-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water, Oceans, and Wildlife" code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-24T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill amends the Estuary Restoration Act of 2000 to authorize a nongovernmental organization, that is allowed to serve as a non-federal interest for an estuary habitat restoration project, to provide lands owned and managed by a legally constituted public body (including a federally recognized Indian tribe) for habitat or fish and wildlife conservation. Such body must agree to: (1) operate and maintain, or allow the nongovernmental organization to operate and maintain, the project; and (2) retain the land in public ownership for uses compatible with the project.

The Secretary of the Army may not carry out such a project unless a non-federal interest has agreed to provide for operation, maintenance, and monitoring of the project (current law requires that such interest has agreed to provide for long-term maintenance and monitoring of the project).

The bill authorizes a nongovernmental organization serving as the non-federal interest for a project to pay the operation, maintenance, and replacement and rehabilitation costs of the project and the non-federal share of the costs of construction of the project.

The Secretary shall: (1) issue guidelines for implementing such projects, making every effort to streamline implementation requirements and reduce overhead costs, including by maximizing consistency with the requirements of restoration programs administered by other federal agencies; and (2) develop and revise the guidelines through a public process.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
