<bill session="114" type="s" number="769" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:33Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to streamline the permit process for rail and transit infrastructure.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Track, Railroad, and Infrastructure Network Act</title>
    <title type="display">Track, Railroad, and Infrastructure Network Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000575"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2015-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2015-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2015-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Track, Railroad, and Infrastructure Network Act

This bill exempts improvements to, maintenance, rehabilitation, or operation of railroad or rail transit lines (but not stations) that are in use or were historically used for the transportation of goods or passengers from federal policies and requirements for the preservation of public park and recreation lands, wildlife and waterfowl refuges, and historic sites. This permits such activities without the necessity to: (1) demonstrate there is no feasible and prudent alternative to the use of such land, and (2) plan to minimize harm to a historic site.

The Secretary of Transportation (DOT) may make a finding of de minimis impact on such preservation as a result of mitigation undertaken pursuant to a review of a transportation program or project pursuant to the National Historic Preservation Act.

Any rail project that requires DOT approval shall be subject to specified environmental project development procedures.

Any environmental impact statement, categorical exclusion, or other decision relating to a transportation project that is issued by a DOT agency under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 shall be available to any rail project to which that statement, exclusion, or decision reasonably applies.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
