<bill session="114" type="hr" number="830" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:38Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Calling for all parties to respect the arbitral tribunal ruling with regard to the South China Sea and to express United States policy on freedom of navigation and overflight in the East and South China Seas.</title>
    <title type="display">Calling for all parties to respect the arbitral tribunal ruling with regard to the South China Sea and to express United States policy on freedom of navigation and overflight in the East and South China Seas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000602"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Asia and the Pacific.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Asia and the Pacific" code="HSFA05" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="sr" session="114" relation="identical" number="526"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Philippines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Expresses support for the July 12, 2016, ruling issued by the International Tribunal of the Law of the Sea as binding on all parties in the case brought at the request of the Republic of Philippines against the People's Republic of China concerning a dispute over the maritime jurisdiction in the South China Sea. Calls on all claimants to pursue peaceful resolution of outstanding maritime claims in the South China Sea consistent with international law.

 Urges all parties to implement the Declaration on the Conduct of Parties in the South China Sea and to take steps toward early conclusion of a meaningful Code of Conduct.

Opposes actions in the South China Sea to change the status quo by coercion or force.

Calls on China to cease all reclamation and militarization activities in the South China Sea and end provocative actions in the East China Sea.

Reaffirms: (1) Article V of the Mutual Defense Treaty Between the United States and the Philippines, and (2) Article V of the Treaty of Mutual Cooperation and Security between the United States and Japan.

Urges: (1) the Department of State to utilize all diplomatic channels to communicate U.S. support for freedom of navigation and overflight in the South China Sea, and (2) the Department of Defense to enforce freedom of navigation and overflight in the East and South China Seas.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
