<bill session="114" type="h" number="4106" updated="2018-08-16T22:57:53Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Vehicle Innovation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application in vehicle technologies at the Department of Energy.</title>
    <title type="display">Vehicle Innovation Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000624"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2015-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2015-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Research and Technology" code="HSSY15" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1408"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2012"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2089"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Hybrid, electric, and advanced technology vehicles"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Materials"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-19T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Vehicle Innovation Act of 2015

This bill authorizes appropriations to the Department of Energy (DOE) for research, development, engineering, demonstration, and commercial application of vehicles and related technologies for FY2016-FY2020.

The bill requires DOE to:

 conduct a program of research, development, engineering, demonstration, and commercial application activities (R&amp;D activities) on materials, technologies, and processes with the potential to substantially reduce or eliminate petroleum use and the emissions of the nation's passenger and commercial vehicles; ensure that it continues to support R&amp;D activities and maintains competency in mid- to long-term transformational vehicle technologies with potential to achieve deep reductions in petroleum use and emissions; conduct research, development, engineering, demonstration, and deployment activities on connectivity of vehicle roadway, vulnerable road users, traffic control systems, and transportation data systems, including technologies that allow for improved safety, reduced energy and fuel use, optimized traffic flow, and vehicle electrification; carry out a program of R&amp;D activities on advanced vehicle manufacturing technologies and practices; carry out a program of cooperative research, development, demonstration, and commercial application activities on advanced technologies for medium- to heavy-duty commercial, vocational, recreational, and transit vehicles; conduct a competitive grant program to demonstrate the integration of multiple advanced technologies on Class 8 (heavy duty) truck and trailer platforms; develop standard testing procedures and technologies for evaluating the performance of advanced heavy vehicle technologies under a range of representative duty cycles and operating conditions and evaluate heavy vehicle performance using work performance-based metrics other than those based on miles per gallon and appropriate metrics based on the work performed by nonroad systems; and undertake a pilot program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial applications of technologies to improve total machine or system efficiency for nonroad mobile equipment and to seek opportunities to transfer relevant research findings and technologies between the nonroad and on-highway equipment and vehicle sectors. DOE may construct heavy duty truck and bus testing facilities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
