<bill session="114" type="h" number="6501" updated="2019-02-14T23:04:52Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prescription Drug and Medical Device Price Review Board Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish within the Food and Drug Administration the Prescription Drug and Medical Device Price Review Board to regulate the prices of certain prescription drugs and medical devices, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Prescription Drug and Medical Device Price Review Board Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000216"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000984" joined="2016-12-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000399" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2016-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-08T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Prescription Drug and Medical Device Price Review Board Act of 2016

This bill establishes the Prescription Drug and Medical Device Price Review Board within the Food and Drug Administration. Each manufacturer of a prescription drug or medical device that is sold in the United States must submit to the board:

 each type of prescription drug and medical device that it sells in the United States, or in a country that is a member of the Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development; the price charged by the manufacturer for the drug or device; and the costs of the manufacturer to produce them. The board must establish a formula for determining whether the average manufacturer price of a prescription drug or medical device over an annual quarter is an excessive price. Manufacturers may not charge excessive prices. Individuals may petition the board to determine whether the price for a prescription drug or medical device is excessive.

The board may subject violators to reduced patent terms, civil penalties, and increased Medicaid rebates. The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose a tax on the sale of prescription drugs or medical devices that have excessive prices.

The board must allow individuals to import from approved counties prescription drugs and devices that are comparable to prescription drugs and devices with excessive prices.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
