<bill session="114" type="s" number="2669" updated="2018-06-02T07:15:44Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Removal of Terminated Providers from Medicaidand CHIP Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend titles XIX and XXI of the Social Security Act to require States to provide to the Secretary of Health and Human Services certain information with respect to provider terminations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Ensuring Removal of Terminated Providers from Medicaidand CHIP Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000174" joined="2016-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1441-1442" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3716"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5210"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="34"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Ensuring Removal of Terminated Providers from Medicaid and CHIP Act

This bill amends titles XIX (Medicaid) and XXI (Children's Health Insurance Program [CHIP]) of the Social Security Act to prohibit federal payment under Medicaid for nonemergency services furnished by providers whose participation in Medicaid, Medicare, or CHIP has been terminated.

Under current law, a state must exclude from Medicaid participation any provider that has been terminated under any state's Medicaid program or under Medicare. The bill maintains those requirements and further requires a state to exclude from Medicaid participation any provider that has been terminated under CHIP. Furthermore, a state must exclude from CHIP participation any provider that has been terminated under Medicaid or Medicare.

The bill also revises a state's reporting requirements with respect to terminating a provider under a state plan. A state shall require each Medicaid or CHIP provider, whether the provider participates on a fee-for-service (FFS) basis or within the network of a managed care organization (MCO), to enroll with the state by providing specified identifying information. When notifying the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) that a provider has been terminated under a state plan, the state must submit this information as well as information regarding the termination date and reason. HHS shall review such termination notifications and, if appropriate, include them in a database or similar system, as specified by the bill.

The bill prohibits federal payment under a state's Medicaid or CHIP program for services provided by an MCO unless: (1) the&#160;state has a system for notifying MCOs when a provider is terminated under Medicaid, Medicare, or CHIP; and (2) any contract between the state plan and an MCO provides that such providers be excluded from participation in the MCO provider network.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
