<bill session="115" type="s" number="3681" updated="2019-04-18T16:46:34Z">
  <state datetime="2018-11-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-11-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-11-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Animal Health Protection Act to establish an Animal Disease and Disaster Prevention, Surveillance, and Rapid Response Program and a National Livestock Vaccine Bank, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Animal Disease and Disaster Prevention, Surveillance, and Rapid Response Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Animal Disease and Disaster Prevention, Surveillance, and Rapid Response Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Animal Disease and Disaster Prevention, Surveillance, and Rapid Response Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2018-11-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-11-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-11-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3042"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-11-29T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Animal Disease and Disaster Prevention, Surveillance, and Rapid Response Act of 2018 

This bill establishes the Animal Disease and Disaster Prevention, Surveillance, and Rapid Response Program within the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to support activities to prevent, detect, and rapidly respond to animal pests and diseases affecting the economic interests of the livestock industry and related U.S. industries.

The bill also establishes a National Livestock Vaccine Bank within USDA to leverage, as appropriate, the mechanisms and infrastructure that have been developed for the management, storage, and distribution of the National Veterinary Stockpile. The vaccine bank must maintain a sufficient quantity of animal vaccine, antiviral, or therapeutic products: (1) to appropriately respond to the most damaging animal diseases affecting human health and the economy, and (2) be capable of deployment within 24 hours of an outbreak of the animal disease.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
