<bill session="115" type="s" number="1884" updated="2019-06-17T18:48:47Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-04">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-10-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for joint reports by relevant Federal agencies to Congress regarding incidents of terrorism, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">REPORT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">REPORT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Reporting Efficiently to Proper Officials in Response to Terrorism Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Reporting Efficiently to Proper Officials in Response to Terrorism Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REPORT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REPORT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reporting Efficiently to Proper Officials in Response to Terrorism Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reporting Efficiently to Proper Officials in Response to Terrorism Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Reporting Efficiently to Proper Officials in Response to Terrorism Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2017-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-09-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-10-04" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-02-26">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 115-210.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-02-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="336">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 336.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Legislative Interest"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="625"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-02-26T14:32:16Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Reporting Efficiently to Proper Officials in Response to Terrorism Act of 2017 or the REPORT Act

This bill requires the primary government agency investigating an act of terrorism that occurs in the United States, in collaboration with the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), the Department of Justice (DOJ), the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), and, as appropriate, the National Counterterrorism Center (NCC), to submit to Congress an unclassified report on such act not later than one year after the completion of the investigation. Such required reports may be combined into a quarterly report to Congress. This reporting requirement shall not apply in instances in which DHS, DOJ, the FBI, or the NCC determines that the information required to be reported could jeopardize an ongoing investigation or prosecution, in which case Congress shall be notified of such determination before the first anniversary of the completion of the investigation.

Each such report shall include: (1) a statement of the facts of the act of terrorism, (2) an explanation of any gaps in national security that could be addressed to prevent future acts of terrorism, (3) recommendations for additional measures that could be taken to improve homeland security, and (4) a summary of the report for public distribution.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-210</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
