<bill session="114" type="h" number="734" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:34Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-24T19:07:39-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-02-24T19:07:39-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Federal Communications Commission Consolidated Reporting Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Communications Commission Consolidated Reporting Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Federal Communications Commission Consolidated Reporting Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to consolidate the reporting obligations of the Federal Communications Commission in order to improve congressional oversight and reduce reporting burdens.</title>
    <title type="display">Federal Communications Commission Consolidated Reporting Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001176"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2015-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2015-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000791" joined="2015-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-24">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 114-27.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-02-24" state="REPORTED" calendar="Union" number="19">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 19.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-02-24T16:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Walden moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-24T16:15:17-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1095-1098" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-24T16:15:18-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 734.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-24T16:23:23-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-24T18:58:48-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1101-1102" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="85" datetime="2015-02-24T19:07:39-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed/agreed to in House: On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 411 - 0 (Roll no. 85).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1095-1096" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-02-24T19:07:39-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="85" datetime="2015-02-24T19:07:39-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 411 - 0 (Roll no. 85).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1095-1096" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-02-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Communications and Technology" code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="253"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-24T12:38:33Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Federal Communications Commission Consolidated Reporting Act of 2015

(Sec. 2) Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to replace various reporting requirements with a communications marketplace report that the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) is required to publish on its website and submit to Congress every two years assessing: (1) competition in the communications marketplace; (2) deployment of communications capabilities, including whether advanced telecommunications capability is being deployed to all Americans in a reasonable and timely fashion; and (3) whether laws, regulations, or regulatory practices pose a barrier to competitive entry or expansion of existing providers of communications services.

Requires the report to describe the FCC's actions in the marketplace and its agenda for the next two years.

Directs the FCC to: (1) compile a list of geographic areas that are not served by any provider of advanced telecommunications capability; and (2) consider market entry barriers for entrepreneurs and small businesses in accordance with national policy favoring diversity of media voices, competition, technological advancement, and promotion of the public interest, convenience, and necessity.

Requires the FCC's competition assessments to include the aggregate average total amount paid by cable systems for retransmission consent.

(Sec. 3) Repeals or consolidates various reports of the FCC and the Corporation for Public Broadcasting, including reports on satellite competition, international broadband, video programming, cable industry prices, small business entry barriers, commercial mobile radio, services to minority and diverse audiences, waivers from requirements prohibiting FCC employees from being financially interested in companies subject to FCC regulation, and several other existing reports under such Act.

Amends the Telecommunications Act of 1996 to require the FCC to determine from the communications marketplace report every two years (currently, in an inquiry initiated each year) whether it must act immediately to accelerate deployment of advanced telecommunications capabilities, particularly in elementary and secondary schools, by removing barriers to infrastructure investment and promoting competition.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-27</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
