<bill session="114" type="s" number="514" updated="2018-06-02T06:33:43Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promise Neighborhoods Authorization Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish the Promise Neighborhoods program.</title>
    <title type="display">Promise Neighborhoods Authorization Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001169"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2015-06-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-12T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Promise Neighborhoods Authorization Act of 2015

Amends title IV (21st Century Schools) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish a new part D, entitled "the Promise Neighborhoods Act of 2015."

Directs the Secretary, under subpart 1 (Promise Neighborhood Partnership Grants), to award renewable, competitive, matching grants to institutions of higher education (IHEs), Indian tribes or tribal organizations, or nonprofit organizations to implement a comprehensive continuum of coordinated services and supports that engage community partners in improving the academic achievement, health and social development, and college and career readiness of children who live in distressed neighborhoods with persistently low-achieving schools or schools with an achievement gap.

Directs the Secretary, under subpart 2 (Promise School Grants), to award renewable, competitive, matching grants to high-need local educational agencies (LEAs) that partner with nonprofit organizations or IHEs, and to Indian schools that partner with nonprofit organizations or IHEs, to implement school-centered strategies and integrated student supports that leverage community partnerships to improve student achievement and development in schools with high concentrations of low-income children. Gives priority to applicants that propose to: (1) include significant investments in high-quality early learning programs, and (2) give schools the operational flexibility to carry out grant activities.

Requires part D grantees to evaluate their programs continuously and improve them based on data and outcomes. Directs the Secretary to use certain performance metrics to determine the eligibility of part D grantees for continued funding and renewal of their grant. Directs the Secretary to evaluate this part's grant programs and disseminate research on best practices for improving the academic and developmental outcomes of children living in our most distressed communities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
