<bill session="114" type="s" number="2894" updated="2018-06-02T07:18:33Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pension Fund Integrity Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to provide for salary reductions for certain employees of a pension plan in critical or declining status that reduces participant benefits, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Pension Fund Integrity Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000770"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2016-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2016-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2016-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2016-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2016-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Pension Fund Integrity Act of 2016 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to require salary reductions for certain employees of systemically important multiemployer pension plans that are in critical or declining status and that reduce participant benefits.

When a benefit suspension is in effect, any compensation paid to employees of a plan that exceeds the amounts specified in this bill is a prohibited transaction that is subject to a tax to be paid by the plan sponsor.

If a plan is in endangered, critical, or critical and declining status, payments for lobbying and political expenses for any person other than an employee of the plan are prohibited transactions and subject to a tax to be paid by the plan sponsor.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
