<bill session="114" type="s" number="2610" updated="2018-08-16T22:54:04Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to approve an agreement between the United States and the Republic of Palau.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to approve an agreement between the United States and the Republic of Palau.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2016-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2016-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1136-1137" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-05">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 114-426.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Marshall Islands"/>
    <term name="Micronesia"/>
    <term name="Palau"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-01T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill approves, with specified exceptions, the agreement and appendices signed by the United States and the Republic of Palau on September 3, 2010, in connection with the Compact of Free Association between the United States and Palau.

If Palau withdraws more than $5 million from the trust fund set up by the Compact in FY2016, or more than $8 million in FY2017, certain amounts will be withheld from Palau until it reimburses the fund for the total amounts withdrawn that exceeded $5 million in FY2016 or $8 million in FY2017.

 The bill authorizes appropriations to: (1) subsidize postal services to Palau, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, and the Federated States of Micronesia for FY2017-FY2024; and (2) carry out specified federal responsibilities under the Compact through FY2023.

The bill repeals specified offset requirements.

Funding is provided through:

 FY2018 to reduce government arrears of Palau, FY2023 for additional economic assistance, and FY2024 for infrastructure projects. Funding is provided through FY2024 to create an Infrastructure Maintenance Fund for routine and periodic maintenance of major capital improvement projects. (Palau is required to provide specified quarterly amounts for the Fund.)

The bill revises specified passport requirements.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
