<bill session="114" type="s" number="535" updated="2019-03-03T14:40:24Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-30">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Energy Efficiency Improvement Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate" partial="1">Better Buildings Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Energy Efficiency Improvement Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Better Buildings Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Efficiency Improvement Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Better Buildings Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Energy Efficiency Improvement Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted" partial="1">Better Buildings Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote energy efficiency.</title>
    <title type="display">Energy Efficiency Improvement Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000449"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2015-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2015-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2015-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2015-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2015-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2015-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2015-02-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-23">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-02-24" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="23">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 23.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="2015-03-27" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 3/26/2015 S2082-2085" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 3/26/2015 S2082-2085" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-03-27">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-13T14:05:09-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21T15:32:09-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Whitfield moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21T15:32:29-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2324-2329" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21T15:32:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 535.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote2" datetime="2015-04-21T15:55:39-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2324-2326" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21T15:55:41-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2015-04-23">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2015-04-30" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="114-11" type="public" datetime="2015-04-30">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 114-11.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="873"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="128"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="259"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="906"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="720"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1052"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2177"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1867"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="1802"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Lighting, heating, cooling"/>
    <term name="Materials"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-01T03:59:59Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the Senate passed version is repeated here.)

Energy Efficiency Improvement Act of 2015

TITLE I--BETTER BUILDINGS

Better Buildings Act of 2015

 (Sec. 102) This bill requires the General Services Administration (GSA) to: (1) develop and publish model leasing provisions to encourage building owners and tenants to use greater cost-effective energy efficiency and water efficiency measures in commercial buildings, (2) develop policies and practices to implement the measures for the realty services provided by the GSA to agencies, and (3) make available the model provisions and best practices to state and local governments for use in managing owned and leased building spaces.

The GSA may use the model leasing provisions in any standard leasing document that designates a federal agency as a landlord or tenant.

(Sec. 103) The bill amends the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to require the Department of Energy (DOE)'s Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy to study the feasibility of: (1) significantly improving energy efficiency in commercial buildings through the design and construction of spaces within the buildings with high-performance energy efficiency measures; and (2) encouraging owners and tenants to implement those measures. A high-performance energy efficiency measure is a technology, product, or practice that will result in substantial operational cost savings by reducing energy consumption and utility costs.

(Sec. 104) The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) must develop a voluntary Tenant Star program within the Energy Star program to recognize tenants in commercial buildings that voluntarily achieve high levels of energy efficiency. The EPA may develop a voluntary program to recognize commercial building owners and tenants that use high-performance energy efficiency measures in the design and construction of leased spaces.

DOE's Energy Information Administration must collect in each of its Commercial Buildings Energy Consumption Surveys data on: (1) categories of building occupancy that are known to consume significant quantities of energy; and (2) other aspects of the property, building operation, or building occupancy relevant to lowering energy consumption.

TITLE II--GRID-ENABLED WATER HEATERS

(Sec. 201) The bill amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to provide energy conservation standards for grid-enabled water heaters for use as part of an electric thermal storage or demand response program, which is a program that enables customers to reduce or shift their power use during peak demand periods. Labeling and reporting requirements concerning the heaters are also established.

The manufacturer or private labeler of these heaters must provide the activation keys for the heaters only to a utility or other program operator that uses those heaters.

DOE must publish an analysis that assesses the extent to which the heaters are put into use in the program. If sales of the heaters exceed by at least 15% the quantity of the heaters activated for use in the program, DOE must establish procedures to prevent the diversion of heaters for non-program purposes.

The requirements for grid-enabled water heaters must remain in effect until DOE determines: (1) grid-enabled water heaters do not require a separate efficiency requirement; or (2) sales of grid-enabled water heaters exceed by at least 15% the quantity of the heaters activated for use in demand response and thermal storage programs annually and procedures to prevent product diversion for non-program purposes would not be adequate to prevent the product diversion.

It shall be unlawful for any person to: (1) enable a grid-enabled water heater to operate at its designed specification and capabilities with knowledge that it is not used as part of an electric thermal storage or demand response program, or (2) knowingly remove or render illegible the label of a grid-enabled water heater. TITLE III--ENERGY INFORMATION FOR COMMERCIAL BUILDINGS

(Sec. 301) A federal agency leasing space in a building without an Energy Star label must include in its lease provisions requirements that the space's energy efficiency be measured against a nationally-recognized benchmark. The agency must also meet certain energy consumption information disclosure requirements.

DOE must study and report on the impact of: (1) state and local performance benchmarking and disclosure policies, and any associated building efficiency policies, for commercial and multifamily buildings; and (2) programs and systems in which utilities provide aggregated information regarding whole building energy consumption and usage information to owners of multitenant buildings. The study must identify best practice policy approaches that have resulted in the greatest improvements in building energy efficiency.

DOE must maintain a database for storing and making available public energy-related information on commercial and multifamily buildings.

DOE must report on the progress made in complying with these information requirements within two years and biennially thereafter.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
