<bill session="115" type="s" number="2239" updated="2019-04-18T16:40:48Z">
  <state datetime="2017-12-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Veterans Access, Choice, and Accountability Act of 2014 to improve the scheduling of appointments, the accountability of third party administrators, and payment to providers under such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Deserve Better Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Deserve Better Act</title>
    <title type="display">Veterans Deserve Better Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000770"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-12-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8164-8165" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="4783"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-12-14T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Veterans Deserve Better Act

This bill amends the Veterans Access, Choice, and Accountability Act of 2014 to require: (1) the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to pay for hospital care or medical services furnished by a non-VA health care entity or provider under the Veterans Choice Program within 45 days of receipt of a paper claim or within 30 days of receipt of an electronic claim, and (2) the entity or provider to file a claim with the VA within 180 days of providing the service.

The VA shall bar providers or entities that file fraudulent health claims from program participation.

The VA shall: (1) ensure that contracts with third party administrators require that veterans' health care appointments be scheduled within five days, and (2) track all appointments and follow up on delayed appointments.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
