<bill session="114" type="h" number="6264" updated="2019-01-09T21:10:27Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prepare All Kids Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To assist States in providing voluntary high-quality universal prekindergarten programs and programs to support infants and toddlers.</title>
    <title type="display">Prepare All Kids Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="645"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Prepare All Kids Act of 2016

This bill amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require the Department of Education to establish a Prekindergarten Incentive Fund from which matching grants shall be awarded to states and, through them, subgrants to qualified prekindergarten providers for the&#160;establishment, expansion, or enhancement of&#160;voluntary, high-quality, full-day prekindergarten programs serving children ages three through five.

State grantees shall set aside specified portions of grant funds: (1)&#160;for quality early childhood development programs for children from birth through age three, and (2) to extend the hours of early childhood development programs to create extended day and year programs.

Prekindergarten subgrantees must: (1) maintain a maximum class size of 20 children, with at least 1 prekindergarten teacher per classroom; and (2) ensure that the ratio of children to prekindergarten teachers and teacher aides does not exceed 10 to 1.

Program funds may not be used for assessments of children in prekindergarten or early childhood development programs if: (1) the assessments are used to reward or sanction individual children, teachers, programs, or schools; or (2) a single assessment is used as the primary or sole method for assessing program effectiveness.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
