<bill session="114" type="h" number="4340" updated="2019-04-11T15:40:29Z">
  <state datetime="2016-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a review of the Office of Government Contracting and Business Development of the Small Business Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SB CAPE Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Contracting and Acquisition Programs Efficiency Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="display">SB CAPE Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000600"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2016-01-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-01-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4341"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-01-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Small Business Contracting and Acquisition Programs Efficiency Act of 2016 or the SB CAPE Act of 2016

This bill directs the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to initiate a review of the Office of Government Contracting and Business Development (OGCBD) of the Small Business Administration (SBA).

This review shall examine:

 the extent to which SBA personnel who carry out certain procurement and business development programs report to the OGCBD, whether greater efficiency and consistency in the certification process of the procurement and business development programs could be achieved by creating a single organizational unit of employees to process all certifications required by such programs, whether greater efficiency and efficacy in the performance of such programs could be achieved by improving the alignment of the field personnel assigned to them, how the OGCBD could improve its staffing of regulatory drafting functions and its coordination with the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council to ensure timely rulemaking by the SBA, and any other areas in which the GAO determines that the SBA could improve its performance with respect to procurement and business development programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
