<bill session="115" type="h" number="6444" updated="2019-04-18T16:26:18Z">
  <state datetime="2018-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the indexing of certain assets for purposes of determining gain or loss.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Capital Gains Inflation Relief Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Capital Gains Inflation Relief Act</title>
    <title type="display">Capital Gains Inflation Relief Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000578" joined="2018-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001187" joined="2018-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000190" joined="2018-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001183" joined="2018-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001172" joined="2018-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-07-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2017"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2688"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-07-19T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Capital Gains Inflation Relief Act 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow the adjusted basis of certain assets (including common stock in a C corporation and tangible property used in a trade or business) to be indexed for inflation for the purpose of determining the gain or loss of a taxpayer (other than a corporation) who has held the asset for more than three years.

The bill sets forth rules for applying the inflation adjustment to:

 short sales; regulated investment companies; real estate investment trusts; other pass-through entities, including partnerships, S corporations, and common trust funds; dispositions between related persons; and improvements to property or contributions of capital. The Internal Revenue Service may disallow an adjustment if any person transfers cash, debt, or any other property to another person for the principal purpose of securing or increasing the adjustment allowed by this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
