<bill session="113" type="h" number="2955" updated="2016-10-25T16:06:44Z">
  <state datetime="2013-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Runaway and Homeless Youth Inclusion Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act to ensure that recipients of assistance under that Act provide services to sexual and gender minority youth in a manner that is culturally competent, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Runaway and Homeless Youth Inclusion Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001160"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2014-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001101" joined="2014-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001038" joined="2014-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000620" joined="2014-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000216" joined="2014-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2014-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2014-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2013-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2014-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000380" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000562" joined="2013-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001185" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2013-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2014-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000604" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2014-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001165" joined="2014-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001175" joined="2014-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001193" joined="2014-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000266" joined="2014-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2013-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000808" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000062" joined="2014-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-08-01T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Runaway and Homeless Youth Inclusion Act of 2013 - Amends the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act to revise requirements for services provided under grants from the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) for centers for runaway and homeless youth and their families.

Requires the plan proposed by grant applicants for a runaway and homeless youth center to:

 provide services to persons in a minority category related to sexual orientation or gender identity or expression, include demographics on the sexual orientation and gender identity or expression of the youth it serves within its statistical records, and serve youth in a manner that is culturally competent. Revises requirements for:

 transitional living programs for homeless youth to require such programs to serve them in a manner that is culturally competent, and sexual abuse prevention programs to require certification to HHS that these programs have systems in place to ensure services to all youth in such a manner. Requires the HHS report on periodic estimates of incidence and prevalence of youth homelessness to include data on the demographics of such individuals (except identity), including whether they are sexual and gender minority youth.

Prohibits any person in the United States, on the basis of actual or perceived race, color, religion, national origin, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity or expression, or disability, from being excluded from participation in, denied the benefits of, or subjected to discrimination under: (1) any program or activity funded in whole or in part with funds made available under the Act; or (2) any program or activity funded in whole or in part with funds appropriated for grants, agreements, and other assistance administered with such funds.

Grants the Attorney General and the Office of Justice Programs the same authority to enforce this Act as granted under the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
