<bill session="115" type="h" number="6674" updated="2019-04-18T16:26:59Z">
  <state datetime="2018-08-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-08-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-08-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to permit kindergarten through grade 12 educational expenses to be paid from a 529 account.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student Empowerment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student Empowerment Act</title>
    <title type="display">Student Empowerment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001195"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-08-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-08-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="3102"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-08-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Student Empowerment Act 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow tax-exempt distributions from qualified tuition programs (known as 529 plans) to be used for additional educational expenses in connection with enrollment or attendance at an elementary or secondary school.

(Under current law, distributions in connection with an elementary or secondary school are limited to tuition for a public, private, or religious school.) The bill allows the distributions to be used for additional educational expenses, including:

 curriculum and curricular materials, books or other instructional materials, online educational materials, tutoring or educational classes outside the home, testing fees, fees for dual enrollment in an institution of higher education, and educational therapies for students with disabilities. Distributions may also be used for the purposes above in connection with a homeschool (whether treated as a homeschool or a private school under state law).</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
