<bill session="114" type="h" number="4133" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:26Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Housing Accountability Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the United States Housing Act of 1937 to ensure accountability in the provision of public housing, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Public Housing Accountability Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001289"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001274" joined="2016-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001103" joined="2016-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000591" joined="2016-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-30T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Public Housing Accountability Act of 2015

This bill amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to add a requirement for periodic review of family income with respect to rental assistance for low-income families.

Reviews of family income shall be made at any time the family income changes by an amount estimated to result in an increase of 10% or more in annual adjusted income (or such other amount as the Department of Housing and Urban Development may establish). A public housing agency (PHA) or owner may elect not to conduct such a review in the last three months of a period during which the family is certified eligible for rental assistance.

The bill also revises the authorization for a PHA that owns or operates fewer than 250 units to lease a dwelling unit in a public housing project, on a month-to-month basis, to an over-income family if there are no eligible families applying to the PHA for housing assistance for that month. The PHA must give a 30-day notice-to-vacate, subject to a specified appeal procedure, to any family determined over-income because of an income review.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
