<bill session="114" type="h" number="2641" updated="2019-01-29T22:16:12Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Horseracing Integrity and Safety Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the integrity and safety of interstate horseracing, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Horseracing Integrity and Safety Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000373"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2016-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001101" joined="2015-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000216" joined="2015-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2015-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000556" joined="2016-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000386" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2016-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2015-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000523" joined="2016-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000030" joined="2016-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2015-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Consumer Protection and Commerce" code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine and animal diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-03T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Horseracing Integrity and Safety Act of 2015

Requires that: (1) there be an independent anti-doping organization with responsibility for ensuring the integrity and safety of horse races that are the subject of interstate off-track wagers, and (2) the independent anti-doping organization designated pursuant to the Office of National Drug Control Policy Reauthorization Act of 2006 serve as such organization.

Sets forth as the duties of such organization: (1) developing, publishing, and maintaining rules regarding substances, methods, and treatments that may and may not be administered to a horse participating in such a race; (2) implementing programing relating to anti-doping education, research, testing, and adjudication to prevent any horse participating in such a race from racing under the effect of any prohibited substance, method, or treatment; and (3) excluding from participation in any such race any person who is determined to have violated such a rule or who is subject to a suspension from horse racing activities by any state racing commission.

Prescribes conditions under which such organization may: (1) suspend the period a person is excluded from participation, and (2) permit the use of furosemide by a horse participating in such a race during the two-year period following enactment of this bill.

Permits a host racing association to conduct a horse race that is the subject of an interstate off-track wager, and permits an interstate off-track wager to be accepted by an off-track betting system, only if consent is obtained from such organization. Requires such organization to ensure that all costs incurred in carrying out its duties are defrayed pursuant to agreements for such consent.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
