<bill session="114" type="h" number="5721" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:42Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Local Coverage Determination Clarification Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act in order to improve the process whereby medicare administrative contractors issue local coverage determinations under the Medicare program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Local Coverage Determination Clarification Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000290"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001257" joined="2016-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2016-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001294" joined="2016-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001038" joined="2016-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001045" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000188" joined="2016-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000382" joined="2016-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001158" joined="2016-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000258" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000591" joined="2016-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000586" joined="2016-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2016-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001187" joined="2016-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2016-12-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="3392"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Local Coverage Determination Clarification Act of 2016

This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to revise the process by which Medicare administrative contractors (MACs) issue and reconsider local coverage determinations (LCDs) that: (1) are new,&#160;(2) restrict or substantively revise existing LCDs, or (3) are otherwise specified in regulation. (MACs are private insurers that process Medicare claims within specified geographic areas.)

Before&#160;such an LCD&#160;may take effect, the MAC issuing the determination must, with respect to each geographic area to which the determination applies:

 publish online a&#160;proposed version of the determination and other specified, related information; convene one or more public meetings to review the draft determination, receive comments, and secure the advice of an expert panel; post online a record of the minutes from each such meeting; provide a period for submission of written public comments; and post online specified information related to the rationale for the final determination. Upon the filing of an applicable&#160;request by an interested party with regard to the reconsideration of a specified LCD, the MAC that issued the determination shall:

 provide specified information related to whether the determination failed to correctly apply qualifying relevant evidence, exceeds the scope of its intended purpose, fails to apply as intended, or is otherwise erroneous; preserve the determination, modify the determination, or rescind the determination in part; and make publicly available a written description of such action. An interested party may appeal&#160;a reconsideration decision to the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS).

CMS shall appoint a Medicare Reviews and Appeals Ombudsman to carry out specified duties with regard to LCDs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
