<bill session="115" type="h" number="5973" updated="2019-04-18T16:24:13Z">
  <state datetime="2018-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to require a report on risk transfer, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disaster Assistance Risk Transfer Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disaster Assistance Risk Transfer Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Disaster Assistance Risk Transfer Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000593"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-05-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Disaster Assistance Risk Transfer Act of 2018

This bill amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to direct the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to solicit proposals and authorize it to secure contracts from private entities providing insurance, reinsurance, or capital market investments to transfer a portion of the risk of disaster assistance.

FEMA shall deposit any funds collected as the result of transfer of risk arrangements into the Disaster Relief Fund and such funds shall be available for any purpose for which such fund may be used.

FEMA may annually transfer a portion of the risk of the payments that may be made to private insurance, reinsurance, or the capital markets if it determines that transferring such a portion is in the public interest.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
