<bill session="113" type="h" number="3526" updated="2016-10-25T16:08:49Z">
  <state datetime="2013-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Humanitarian Assistance Facilitation Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To permit persons subject to the jurisdiction of the United States to enter into transactions with certain sanctioned foreign persons that are customary, necessary, and incidental to the donation or provision of goods or services to prevent or alleviate the suffering of civilian populations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Humanitarian Assistance Facilitation Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000522"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000449" joined="2013-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2013-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2013-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-18">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Somalia"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-11-18T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Humanitarian Assistance Facilitation Act of 2013 - Expresses the sense of Congress that humanitarian organizations acting in good faith and with the appropriate restrictions and controls in place should not be prevented from providing aid to civilian populations before or early on in humanitarian crises, such as in the famine in al-Shabaab-controlled areas of Somalia.

Amends the International Emergency Economic Powers Act to permit under specified conditions persons subject to U.S. jurisdiction to enter into transactions with certain sanctioned foreign persons that are customary, necessary, and incidental to the donation or provision of goods or services to prevent or alleviate the suffering of civilian populations.

Directs the Secretary of State to establish an Advisory Council on United States Policy Related to Non-Governmental Activities to Prevent and Respond to Human Suffering in Areas Affected By Certain Sanctioned Foreign Persons.

Amends the federal criminal code to exclude from the definition of "material support or resources" (regarding foreign terrorist organizations) engaging in speech or communication with a terrorist organization to prevent or alleviate the suffering of a civilian population, including speech or communication to reduce or eliminate the frequency and severity of violent conflict and reducing its impact on the civilian population.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
