<bill session="114" type="h" number="3106" updated="2018-06-02T04:37:57Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-09T15:18:11-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-02-09T15:18:11-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Construction Reform Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Construction Reform Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Construction Reform Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize Department major medical facility construction projects for fiscal year 2015, to amend title 38, United States Code, to make certain improvements in the administration of Department medical facility construction projects, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To amend title 38, United States Code, to make certain improvements in the administration of Department medical facility construction projects.</title>
    <title type="display">Construction Reform Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001144"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001257" joined="2015-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001077" joined="2015-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-14">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Health Prior to Introduction and Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-22">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-22">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-09-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-12-03">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 114-364.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-12-03" calendar="Union" number="277">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 277.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-02-09T15:09:11-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Miller (FL) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-09T15:09:32-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H601-603" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-09T15:09:34-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3106.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2016-02-09T15:18:11-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H601-602" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-02-09T15:18:14-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-09T15:18:22-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral, Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2365"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-09T14:48:01Z" status="Passed House amended">Construction Reform Act of 2016

(Sec. 2) This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to use industry standards, standard designs, and best practices in carrying out medical facility construction.

A super construction project is one for the construction, alteration, or acquisition of a medical facility involving a total expenditure of more than $100 million (but does not include an acquisition by exchange).

 The VA shall provide, on a non-reimbursable basis, a non-VA federal entity with: (1) design, planning, and construction assistance; (2) project documents; and (3) other assistance upon request.

With respect to a proposed change to a contract entered into by a non-VA federal entity with which the VA has entered into an agreement that is estimated at a value of less than $250,000, the entity shall issue a final decision regarding such change within 30 days.

 With respect to a proposed contract change estimated at a value of $250,000 or more:

 the VA may make recommendations to the entity; the VA may issue the final decision regarding the change within 30 days after the entity proposes it; and if the VA does not issue a final decision within 60 days after the entity proposes the contract change, the entity shall issue a final decision regarding the change no later than 90 days after it proposes the change. The VA shall ensure that each VA employee with responsibilities relating to the construction or alteration of medical facilities undergoes ongoing professional training and development.

 The VA is prohibited from:

 obligating or expending funds for advance planning or design for any super construction project until 60 days after congressional notification, obligating funds for a major medical facility project or a super construction project by more than 10% of the amount approved by law unless certain congressional committees approve the obligation, or using bid savings amounts or funds for other than their original purpose before 30 days after notifying those committees unless each committee approves the obligation. The VA shall enter into a contract with an appropriate non-department federal entity to conduct an external forensic audit of: (1) the medical center construction project in Aurora, Colorado; and (2) the expenditures relating to any major medical facility or super construction project when such expenditures exceed the amount approved by law by more than 25%.

The VA must complete a 10-year master plan for: (1) each existing VA medical facility by December 31, 2016, and (2) each new VA medical facility by not later than the earlier of the date on which activation is completed or the date of the facility's formal dedication.

(Sec. 3) There is established in the Office of Inspector General an Assistant Inspector General for Construction who shall be responsible for conducting, supervising, and coordinating audits, evaluations, and investigations of the planning, design, contracting, and construction of VA facilities and infrastructure, including major and minor construction projects and leases.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-364</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
