<bill session="114" type="s" number="3031" updated="2018-06-02T07:46:16Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Child Abuse in Residential Programs for Teens Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require certain standards and enforcement provisions to prevent child abuse and neglect in residential programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Stop Child Abuse in Residential Programs for Teens Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001169"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2016-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2016-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3060"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-08T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stop Child Abuse in Residential Programs for Teens Act of 2016 

This bill directs the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to require each covered program in a state, in order for the state to remain eligible for grants to prevent child abuse and neglect at residential programs, to prohibit child abuse and neglect and meet specified minimum standards.

A "covered program" is one operated by a public or private entity that, with respect to one or more children who are unrelated to the program owner or operator, purports to provide treatment or modify behaviors in a residential environment.

HHS shall: (1) implement a review process for overseeing, investigating, and evaluating reports of child abuse and neglect; and (2) establish a process to assist states in the oversight and enforcement of this bill.

HHS must refer any violation of such standards to the Attorney General, who may bring an action on his or her own initiative regardless of whether such a referral has been made.

The bill amends the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act to establish additional eligibility requirements for grants to states to prevent child abuse and neglect at residential programs. States receiving grants must develop policies and procedures to prevent child abuse and neglect at covered programs, including standards that meet or exceed the standards required under this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
