<bill session="114" type="h" number="2552" updated="2019-04-11T15:39:45Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the Department of Homeland Security from procuring certain items directly related to the national security unless the items are grown, reprocessed, reused, or produced in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Berry Amendment Extension Act</title>
    <title type="display">Berry Amendment Extension Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000291" joined="2015-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001165" joined="2015-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight and Management Efficiency.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Oversight, Management, and Accountability" code="HSHM09" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Berry Amendment Extension Act

 Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to prohibit the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) from procuring specified covered items directly related to national security interests (including clothing, tents, or natural fiber products) that are not grown, reprocessed, reused, or produced in the United States, except to the extent satisfactory quality and sufficient quantity of any such product cannot be procured as and when needed.

Makes additional exceptions for: (1) procurements by vessels in foreign waters, (2) emergency procurements, and (3) purchases for amounts not greater than the simplified acquisition threshold described in military procurement provisions. Requires DHS to post a notification that an exception has been applied not later than seven days after the award of the contract. Directs DHS to ensure that: (1) each member of DHS's acquisition workforce who regularly participates in textile acquisition receives training on this Act's requirements, and (2) any such training includes comprehensive information on such requirements. Requires this Act to be applied in a manner consistent with U.S. obligations under international agreements.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
