<bill session="114" type="s" number="1903" updated="2018-06-02T06:58:45Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reducing Disparities Using Care Models and Education Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for a study by the National Academy of Medicine on health disparities, to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop guidelines on reducing health disparities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Reducing Disparities Using Care Models and Education Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2015-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3285"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reducing Disparities Using Care Models and Education Act of 2015

This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to contract with the National Academy of Medicine (formerly known as the Institute of Medicine) to study health disparities, existing programs and policies intended to reduce disparities, and priorities for, and expansion of, programs targeting disparities.

HHS must develop guidelines for entities to develop and implement programs to reduce health disparities. HHS must incorporate these guidelines into its activities.

HHS may award grants for programs to reduce health disparities.

The Innovation Center of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services must test a payment and service delivery model that includes incentives for reducing health disparities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
