<bill session="114" type="sr" number="330" updated="2018-06-02T06:18:47Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-10">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution congratulating the Tunisian National Dialogue Quartet for winning the 2015 Nobel Peace Prize.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution congratulating the Tunisian National Dialogue Quartet for winning the 2015 Nobel Peace Prize.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2015-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2015-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2015-12-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8440-8441" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-02-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-02-10">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Corker without amendment and with a preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-02-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="366">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 366.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Tunisia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-10T14:34:35Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Congratulates the Tunisian National Dialogue Quartet on winning the 2015 Nobel Peace Prize.

Commends the leaders of the Tunisian General Labor Union, the Tunisian Confederation of Industry, Trade, and Handicrafts, the Tunisian Human Rights League, and the Tunisian Order of Lawyers for negotiating solutions to political crises.

Commends Tunisian political leaders for their willingness to compromise and work together in the interest of the Tunisian people.

Encourages the government of Tunisia to move swiftly to implement necessary political and economic reforms that will benefit the Tunisian people and consolidate Tunisia's democratic transition.

Reaffirms the commitment of the United States to support the government of Tunisia and its people as they continue on the path to democracy, stability, and prosperity.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
