<bill session="115" type="h" number="4947" updated="2019-04-18T16:20:08Z">
  <state datetime="2018-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve infrastructure in small towns and rural areas.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Infrastructure Development and Partnerships Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Infrastructure Development and Partnerships Act</title>
    <title type="display">Rural Infrastructure Development and Partnerships Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000293"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000464" joined="2018-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000386" joined="2018-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2018-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-02-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commodity Exchanges, Energy, and Credit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Commodity Exchanges, Energy, and Credit" code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-02-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Rural Infrastructure Development and Partnerships Act 

This bill establishes within the Department of Agriculture a Rural Partnerships Office to be headed by a director appointed by the President.

The duties of the office include:

 establishing and running a program to provide technical assistance to improve delivery, financing, operations, and maintenance of rural infrastructure; establishing an online clearinghouse of best practices; providing grants to assist rural communities in developing cost-effective infrastructure projects; and coordinating activities of rural liaisons to develop guidelines for rural funding or financing programs at federal agencies and identify opportunities to work across agencies. The bill also requires each federal agency that provides financial assistance to a rural community for an activity related to rural infrastructure to designate a rural liaison to:

 review and make recommendations regarding regulations, guidance, and procedures that present hardships to rural communities; participate in reviewing applications for technical assistance; serve as an ombudsperson for rural communities; and meet regularly with other rural liaisons to coordinate efforts and identify ways to work together to support rural infrastructure needs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
