<bill session="114" type="sr" number="515" updated="2018-06-02T06:21:12Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution welcoming Prime Minister Lee Hsien-Loong to the United States and reaffirming Singapore's strategic partnership with the United States, encompassing broad and robust economic, military-to-military, law enforcement, and counterterrorism cooperation.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution welcoming Prime Minister Lee Hsien-Loong to the United States and reaffirming Singapore's strategic partnership with the United States, encompassing broad and robust economic, military-to-military, law enforcement, and counterterrorism cooperation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2016-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2016-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4729-4730" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Corker without amendment and with a preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="565">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 565.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2016-07-14" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5186" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="114" relation="unknown" number="374"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Singapore"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T14:24:49Z" status="Passed Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Welcomes Prime Minister Lee Hsien-Loong of Singapore for his official visit to the United States and for the State Dinner on August 2, 2016, as the United States and Singapore commemorate the 50th anniversary of their bilateral diplomatic relationship.

Affirms the importance of the U.S.-Singapore strategic partnership in securing regional peace and stability.

Applauds Singapore's leadership in counterterrorism, including the deployment of military assets as part of the anti-ISIL (Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant) coalition and innovative counterterrorism efforts within the Asia-Pacific region.

Anticipates the deepening of the security relationship following the signing of an enhanced Defense Cooperation Agreement on December 7, 2015, and welcomes further cooperation in areas such as cybersecurity, humanitarian assistance and disaster relief, and defense technology.

Recognizes the vitality of the bilateral trade and investment relationship between the United States and Singapore.

Expresses support for continued close cooperation between the United States and Singapore to build capacity for commercial engagement, energy development, innovation, trade facilitation, and to achieve development goals in the Asia-Pacific region.

Urges the President to continue U.S. support of multilateral institutions and fora, working in close cooperation with partners, such as Singapore, who share a commitment to an inclusive, rules-based regional architecture.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
