<bill session="114" type="s" number="2867" updated="2018-06-02T07:18:19Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SEC Small Business Advocate Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to establish an Office of the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation and a Small Business Capital Formation Advisory Committee, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SEC Small Business Advocate Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001069"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2016-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2016-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2016-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-14">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3784"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4168"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5485"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5983"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6427"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">SEC Small Business Advocate Act of 2015

This bill amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to establish within the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) an Office of the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation.

The Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation shall:

 assist small businesses and small business investors in resolving significant problems they may have with the SEC or with self-regulatory organizations; identify areas in which such businesses and investors would benefit from changes in SEC regulations or the rules of such organizations; identify problems that small businesses have with securing access to capital, including any unique challenges faced by minority-owned and women-owned small businesses; analyze the potential impact on such businesses and investors of proposed SEC regulations and proposed rules that are likely to have a significant economic impact on small businesses and small business capital formation; conduct outreach to such businesses and investors to solicit views on relevant capital formation issues; propose to the SEC changes in its regulations or orders, and propose to Congress legislative, administrative, or personnel changes, to mitigate problems identified and to promote the interests of such businesses and investors; consult with the Investor Advocate on such proposals and advise the Investor Advocate on small business-related issues; and be responsible for planning, organizing, and executing the annual Government-Business Forum on Small Business Capital Formation. The bill also establishes the Small Business Capital Formation Advisory Committee, which shall provide the SEC with advice on SEC rules, regulations, and policies regarding its mission of protecting investors, maintaining fair, orderly, and efficient markets, and facilitating capital formation, as they relate to:

 capital raising by emerging, privately held small businesses and publicly traded companies with less than $250 million in public market capitalization through securities offerings; trading in the securities of such businesses and companies; and public reporting and corporate governance requirements of such businesses and companies. The SEC shall assess the Committee's recommendations and disclose any action it intends to take with respect to such recommendations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
