<amendment session="114" chamber="h" number="812" updated="2018-11-09T00:02:53Z">
  <amends type="h" number="22" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2015-11-04T23:08:19-05:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000598"/>
  <offered datetime="2015-11-04"/>
  <description>Amendment sought to prohibit the Export-Import Bank from providing a guarantee or extending credit to a foreign borrower in connection with the export of goods or services by a U.S. company unless the U.S. company guarantees repayment of, and pledges collateral in an amount sufficient to cover, a percentage of the amount provided by the Bank and makes that guarantee senior to any other obligation. Amendment also sought to provide an exception to this requirement for small businesses.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment printed in Part B of House Report 114-326 to prohibit the Export Import Bank from providing a guarantee or extending credit to a foreign borrower in connection with the export of goods or services by a U.S. company unless the U.S. company guarantees repayment of, and pledges collateral in an amount sufficient to cover, a percentage of the amount provided by the Bank and makes that guarantee senior to any other obligation. Amendment also provides an exception to this requirement for small businesses.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2015-11-04T23:08:19-05:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="613">
      <text>On agreeing to the Rothfus amendment (A079) Failed by recorded vote: 115 - 313 (Roll no. 613).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-11-04T21:10:00-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A079) offered by Mr. Rothfus.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7703-7705, H7716" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7703" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-04"/>
    <action datetime="2015-11-04T23:08:19-05:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-04T23:08:19-05:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-04T23:08:19-05:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Rothfus amendment (A079) Failed by recorded vote: 115 - 313 (Roll no. 613).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-04T21:10:00-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A079) offered by Mr. Rothfus.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7703-7705, H7716" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7703" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-04">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
