<bill session="114" type="h" number="3408" updated="2019-02-01T21:05:41Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Campus Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to protect victims of sexual violence, to improve the adjudication by institutions of higher education of allegations related to sexual violence, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Fair Campus Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001284" joined="2015-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Investment" code="HSED13" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3403"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC)"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Fair Campus Act of 2015

This bill amends title I (General Provisions) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA) to establish requirements with respect to sexual violence allegations at institutions of higher education (IHEs).

An IHE that receives HEA funds, except a foreign institution, must provide support services to affected students and annual training to relevant personnel.

This bill prohibits an IHE from imposing sanctions on a person, including a student organization (e.g., a fraternity or sorority), with respect to alleged sexual violence, except pursuant to a formal hearing in accordance with institutional disciplinary proceedings. It specifies due process requirements for such proceedings, permits an IHE to select the applicable standard of proof, and directs an IHE to publish applicable procedures in its student handbook.

 An IHE may initiate an institutional disciplinary proceeding to impose certain interim sanctions (e.g., a class schedule adjustment).

It also prohibits an IHE from requiring a sorority or fraternity to: (1) admit members who do not meet membership requirements, or (2) waive its coverage exemption under title IX of the Education Amendments Act of 1972 (title IX prohibits sex&#160;discrimination in federally funded education programs and activities) as a disciplinary or punitive measure.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
