<bill session="115" type="s" number="2133" updated="2019-04-18T16:40:21Z">
  <state datetime="2017-11-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Food Security Act of 1985 to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to enter into alternative funding arrangements with certain community irrigation associations and community land grants.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PLACES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PLACES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Land Grants and Acequias Conservation and Environmental Services Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Land Grants and Acequias Conservation and Environmental Services Act</title>
    <title type="display">PLACES Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000039"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2017-11-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-11-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-11-15T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Providing Land Grants and Acequias Conservation and Environmental Services Act or the PLACES Act 

This bill amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to authorize the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to enter into an alternative funding arrangement under any USDA conservation program with an entity that: (1) is comprised of members who are producers that are eligible for payments under the Environmental Quality Incentives Program, and (2) is a local governmental entity that does not have the authority to impose taxes or levies.

(An alternative funding arrangement would allow certain community irrigation associations and community land grants to receive assistance directly from the conservation programs.) USDA may also provide technical and administrative assistance under the alternative funding arrangement.

USDA may enter into an arrangement if: (1) the goals and objectives of the applicable conservation program will be met by the arrangement, and (2) statutory limitations regarding contracts with individual producers will not be exceeded by any member of the entity.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
