<bill session="114" type="s" number="1388" updated="2018-06-02T06:54:07Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cuba Normalization Accountability Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the President to submit a plan for resolving all outstanding claims relating to property confiscated by the Government of Cuba before taking action to ease restrictions on travel to or trade with Cuba, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Cuba Normalization Accountability Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2015-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="2466"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-19T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Cuba Normalization Accountability Act of 2015

This bill expresses the sense of Congress that the United States should not pursue efforts to ease restrictions on travel to or trade with Cuba, or otherwise normalize relations with Cuba further, until: (1) the President submits to Congress the plan for resolving confiscated property claims, (2) all property taken by the Cuban government from U.S. nationals on or after January 1, 1959, has been returned or full compensation for that property has been provided to them, and (3) the government of Cuba provides secure protection for the internationally recognized human rights of the people of Cuba.

The President may not take any action to ease restrictions on travel to or trade with Cuba under the Cuban Assets Control Regulations, the Export Administration Regulations, or any other regulations relating to the economic embargo of Cuba before submitting to Congress the plan for resolving outstanding claims for confiscated property to ensure that:

 all property taken by the government of Cuba from U.S. nationals on or after January 1, 1959, has been returned to them; or full compensation for such property has been provided to them. The President shall include in the plan an assessment of the effect of planned actions to ease the restrictions on claims relating to confiscated property considered by the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission of the United States before the date of the enactment of this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
