<bill session="114" type="h" number="5112" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:33Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Unfair or Deceptive Acts or Practices Uniformity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Consumer Protection Act of 2010 to grant the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection the authority to regulate certain acts and practices using processes and procedures consistent with and similar to those in place at the Federal Trade Commission, to encourage greater communication amongst regulators, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Unfair or Deceptive Acts or Practices Uniformity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000569"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000369" joined="2016-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001282" joined="2016-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001182" joined="2016-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000593" joined="2016-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2016-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Unfair or Deceptive Acts or Practices Uniformity Act 

This bill amends the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 to repeal the authority of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) to take action to prevent a covered person or service provider from committing or engaging in an abusive act or practice under federal law in connection with any transaction with a consumer for a consumer financial product or service, or the offering of one.

Regarding CFPB authority over deceptive acts, the bill prohibits the CFPB from taking any action against a covered person or service provider without first consulting with such person's primary financial regulatory agency.

The CFPB must comply with the same rules as govern the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices in or affecting commerce. (The FTC may prescribe interpretive rules, general policy statements, and definitions regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices, but has no authority to prescribe any other kind of rule with respect to such acts or practices.)</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
