<bill session="113" type="h" number="5205" updated="2016-10-25T16:15:29Z">
  <state datetime="2014-09-15T19:12:31-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-09-15T19:12:31-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Northern Nevada Land Conservation and Economic Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Elko Motocross and Tribal Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Lyon County Economic Development and Conservation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Naval Air Station Fallon Housing and Safety Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Pine Forest Range Recreation Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Restoring Storey County Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Northern Nevada Land Conservation and Economic Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Elko Motocross and Tribal Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Lyon County Economic Development and Conservation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Naval Air Station Fallon Housing and Safety Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Pine Forest Range Recreation Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Restoring Storey County Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Northern Nevada Land Conservation and Economic Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Elko Motocross and Tribal Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Lyon County Economic Development and Conservation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Naval Air Station Fallon Housing and Safety Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Pine Forest Range Recreation Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Restoring Storey County Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize certain land conveyances involving public lands in northern Nevada to promote economic development and conservation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Northern Nevada Land Conservation and Economic Development Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000369"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001055" joined="2014-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001066" joined="2014-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2014-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-09-15">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-593.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-09-15" calendar="Union" number="440">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 440.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-09-15T19:00:25-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hastings (WA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-15T19:00:58-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7486-7492" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-15T19:01:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5205.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2014-09-15T19:12:31-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7486-7491" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-09-15T19:12:33-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="433"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="696"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1167"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1168"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1169"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1170"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="159"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="342"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1157"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1983"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-09-15T14:58:56Z" status="Passed House amended">Northern Nevada Land Conservation and Economic Development Act - Title I: Pine Forest Range Recreation Enhancement Act - Pine Forest Range Recreation Enhancement Act - (Sec. 103) Designates approximately 26,000 acres of land managed by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) in Humboldt County, Nevada, as the Pine Forest Range Wilderness.

Removes the Little Onion Basin from the boundaries of the Wilderness and from designation as wilderness.

Withdraws the Wilderness from: (1) entry, appropriation, and disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) disposition under laws relating to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials.

(Sec. 104) Allows livestock grazing already established in the Wilderness to continue.

Authorizes the Department of the Interior to take measures in the Wilderness determined necessary to control fire, insects, and diseases.

Requires the Secretary, with respect to the Wilderness, to follow the procedural and substantive requirements of state law in order to obtain and hold any water rights not already in existence.

Prohibits the President, or any U.S. officer, employee, or agent, from funding, assisting, authorizing, or issuing a license or permit for the development of any new water resource facility within any portion of the Wilderness in Humboldt County.

(Sec. 105) Releases certain other land in the county from study as a wilderness area.

(Sec. 106) Authorizes Interior to conduct any management activities in the Wilderness necessary for the maintenance or restoration of fish and wildlife populations and the habitats to support them.

Permits the state to continue using aircraft, including helicopters, to provide water for wildlife in the Wilderness.

Permits the state (including a designee) to conduct wildlife management activities in the Wilderness: (1) in accordance with the terms and conditions in a specified cooperative management agreement between the Secretary of the Interior and the state, and (2) subject to all applicable laws (including regulations).

(Sec. 107) Authorizes land exchanges involving federal and non-federal lands in the county.

Expresses the intent of Congress that such land exchanges be completed within five years of enactment of this Act.

(Sec. 108) Declares that nothing in this title alters or diminishes the treaty rights of any Indian tribe.

Title II: Lyon County Economic Development and Conservation Act - Lyon County Economic Development and Conservation Act - (Sec. 202) Directs Interior to convey to Yerington, Nevada, land in Lyon and Mineral Counties, Nevada.

(Sec. 203) Designates approximately 47,449 acres of land managed by the Forest Service as the Wovoka Wilderness.

Withdraws the Wilderness from: (1) entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) disposition under laws relating to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials.

Allows livestock grazing already established in the Wilderness to continue.

Authorizes the Department of the Interior to take measures in the Wilderness determined to be necessary to control fire, insects, and diseases.

Requires the Secretary, with respect to the Wilderness, to follow the procedural and substantive requirements of state law in order to obtain and hold any water rights not already in existence.

Prohibits either the President or any U.S. officer, employee, or agent from funding, assisting, authorizing, or issuing a license or permit for the development of any new water resource facility within any portion of the Wilderness in Lyon County.

Directs the Secretary to issue a water development permit within the non-wilderness boundaries of the Bald Mountain grazing allotment for livestock grazing activities if a permittee within the allotment applies within ten years after enactment of this Act for development of water resources to water livestock.

Authorizes the Interior to conduct any management activities in the Wilderness necessary for the maintenance or restoration of fish and wildlife populations and the habitats to support them.

Allows the state to continue using aircraft, including helicopters, to provide water for wildlife populations in the Wilderness.

Permits the state (including a designee) to conduct wildlife management activities in the Wilderness: (1) in accordance with the terms and conditions in a specified cooperative management agreement between the Secretary and the state, and (2) subject to all applicable laws (including regulations).

Requires the Secretary to authorize structures and facilities, including existing ones, for wildlife water development projects (including guzzlers) in the Wilderness, if they meet certain criteria.

(Sec. 204) Withdraws all specified federal land administered by the Forest Service from: (1) entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) operation of the mineral laws, geothermal leasing laws, and mineral materials laws.

Permits the use of motorized and mechanical vehicles (except aircraft, including helicopters) in the Withdrawal Area only on roads and trails designated for their use, unless the use of such vehicles is needed for administrative purposes or to respond to an emergency.

(Sec. 205) Declares that nothing in this title alters or diminishes the treaty rights of any Indian tribe.

Title III: Carlin Economic Self-Determination Act - (Sec. 301) Directs Interior to convey approximately 1,329 acres of land to Carlin, Nevada.

Releases the United States from all liabilities or claims of any kind or nature arising from the presence, release, or threat of release of any hazardous substance, pollutant, contaminant, petroleum product (or derivative), solid waste, mine materials, or mining related features existing on the land.

Withdraws the land identified for conveyance from: (1) entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) disposition under the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.

Title IV: Fernley Economic Self-Determination Act - (Sec. 402) Directs Interior to convey specified land to Fernley, Nevada.

Permits Fernley and the Bureau of Reclamation to retain easements or rights-of-way on the land to be conveyed, including easements or rights-of-way necessary to carry out the operation and maintenance of the Truckee Canal Irrigation District Canal or the Newlands Project.

(Sec. 403) Releases the United States from all liabilities or claims of any kind or nature arising from the presence, release, or threat of release of any hazardous substance, pollutant, contaminant, petroleum product (or derivative), solid waste, mine materials, or mining related features existing on the land.

Title V: Restoring Storey County Act - Restoring Storey County Act - (Sec. 503) Directs the BLM to convey approximately 1,745 acres of land to Storey County, Nevada.

Title VI: Elko Motocross and Tribal Conveyance Act -Elko Motocross and Tribal Conveyance Act - Subtitle A: Elko Motocross Land Conveyance - (Sec. 612) Directs the BLM to convey approximately 275 acres of BLM land to Elko County, Nevada, for: (1) a motocross, bicycle, off-highway vehicle, or stock car racing area; or (2) other public purpose consistent with the Recreation and Public Purposes Act.

Subtitle B: Trust Land for Te-moak Tribe of Western Shoshone Indians of Nevada (Elko Band) - (Sec. 621) Holds approximately 373 acres of BLM land in trust for the Te-moak Tribe of Western Shoshone Indians of Nevada. Makes such land part of the Tribe's reservation.

Prohibits certain gaming on such land. Limits use of such land to: (1) traditional and customary uses, (2) stewardship conservation for the benefit of the Tribe, and (3) residential or recreational development. Requires the Tribe to pay the Secretary the fair market value of any portion of such land used for another purpose.

Permits Interior to carry out any fuels reduction and other landscape restoration activities on the land that is beneficial to the Tribe and the BLM.

Title VII: Naval Air Station Fallon Housing and Safety Development Act - Naval Air Station Fallon Housing and Safety Development Act - (Sec. 702) Directs Interior to transfer to the Navy approximately 400 acres of land adjacent to Naval Air Station Fallon in Churchill County, Nevada.

(Sec. 704) Withdraws the land to be transferred under this Act from all forms of appropriation under the public land laws, including the mining laws and geothermal leasing laws, so long as such land remains under the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Navy.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 113-593</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
