<bill session="114" type="h" number="2756" updated="2019-01-09T21:09:57Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Patient Freedom Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reform the provision of health insurance coverage by promoting health savings accounts, State-based alternatives to coverage under the Affordable Care Act, and price transparency, in order to promote a more market-based health care system, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Patient Freedom Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000374"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="1531"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Patient Freedom Act of 2015

This bill provides states with three options regarding title I (provisions on health insurance reform, exchanges, and subsidies) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA): (1) continue implementing PPACA, (2) do not apply title I of PPACA except to prohibit lifetime or annual limits on health insurance benefits and require coverage of dependents up to 26 years old, or (3) the second option plus implementation of a health savings account (HSA) deposit system.

In states implementing an HSA deposit system, residents who are enrolled in health insurance coverage that meets state standards receive monthly deposits in their HSAs either from states administering federal funds or as a tax credit paid in advance. States that administer deposits are entitled to payments from the Department of Health and Human Services for population health initiatives.

States with an HSA deposit system must offer a health insurance plan that is continually available for enrollment and penalize residents who have a break in coverage.

This bill amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSAct) to disregard assets in an HSA for purposes of determining Medicaid eligibility and benefits except for long-term care services.

This bill amends SSAct title XVIII (Medicare) to require participating hospitals to limit costs to individuals for uncovered emergency medical care.

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to eliminate the requirement that an individual have a high deductible health plan to be eligible for the tax benefits of an HSA.

HSAs can be used to pay premiums for health insurance that meets specified requirements.

HSA tax benefits only apply to payments for health care for which the provider publishes the price.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
