<bill session="114" type="s" number="2969" updated="2018-06-02T07:45:33Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disaster Management Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to conduct a comprehensive study relating to disaster costs and losses, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Disaster Management Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000293"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Disaster Management Act of 2016

This bill requires the National Advisory Council of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to commence a comprehensive study relating to disaster losses and federal disaster assistance. The council shall consider: (1) an assessment of trends in disaster costs and losses and federal disaster assistance and factors contributing to such trends; and (2) fundamental principles that drive national disaster assistance decision-making.

The council shall: (1) develop recommendations to reduce disaster costs and losses in the United States and to more efficiently and effectively deliver federal disaster assistance; and (2) report to FEMA and Congress on its data, analysis, and recommendations.

FEMA shall submit a report that includes an action plan to improve field operations after a major disaster or emergency declaration by the President.

FEMA shall establish: (1) a pilot program that increases the amount threshold for use of the simplified procedure for providing assistance under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act for the purpose of determining whether such increase can facilitate a more efficient and effective delivery of assistance, without sacrificing oversight capabilities, for a major disaster or emergency declaration by the President; and (2) a pilot program that modifies the management cost rates used to determine contributions under such Act for management costs for the purpose of determining whether such modifications can facilitate a more efficient and effective administration of disaster assistance grants for a major disaster or emergency.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
