<bill session="115" type="h" number="2365" updated="2019-04-18T16:08:19Z">
  <state datetime="2018-06-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To convey certain Federal land in California to Apple Valley, California, Twentynine Palms, California, Barstow, California, and Victorville, California.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Desert Community Lands Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Desert Community Lands Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Desert Community Lands Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Desert Community Lands Act</title>
    <title type="display">Desert Community Lands Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001094"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-13">
      <text>Subcommittee on Federal Lands Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-06-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 20 - 15.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-11-09">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 115-1013.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-11-09" calendar="Union" number="792">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 792.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-04T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Desert Community Lands Act

This bill directs the Department of the Interior to convey, without consideration, to the town of Apple Valley in California the surface estate of specified land, to be known and designated as the Apple Valley Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area.

The conveyed land may be used by the town to provide: (1) a suitable location for the establishment of a centralized, off-road vehicle recreation park; (2) the public with opportunities for off-road vehicle recreation; and (3) a designated area and facilities that would discourage unauthorized use of off-highway vehicles in areas that have been identified by the federal government, the state of California, or San Bernardino County, California, to contain environmentally sensitive land.

Such land may not be disposed of by the town without Interior's approval.

Interior may develop a special management plan for the recreation area to enhance the safe use of off-highway vehicles for recreational purposes.

Interior shall convey, without consideration, the surface estate of specified lands to the cities of Twentynine Palms, Barstow, and Victorville in California.

All land conveyances under this bill are subject to valid existing rights and do not include the mineral estate in the lands conveyed.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-1013</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
