<bill session="115" type="s" number="1571" updated="2019-04-18T16:37:59Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize the National Flood Insurance Program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Flood Insurance Program Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Flood Insurance Program Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">National Flood Insurance Program Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000880"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2017-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="7187"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3628"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3703"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3670"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Flood Insurance Program Reauthorization Act of 2017

This bill amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to reauthorize through FY2023 and revise the National Flood Insurance Program (NFIP).

A community that participates in NFIP and has been repeatedly flooded must: (1) assess the continuing risks to community areas repeatedly damaged by floods; and (2) develop and implement&#160;a publicly available, community-specific plan for mitigating continuing flood risks to such areas. A community that does not comply with these requirements shall be subject to sanctions.

The amount of coverage available under the Increased Cost of Compliance (ICC) program is increased. This bill makes available ICC coverage in communities outside special flood hazard areas that have adopted specified land use and control measures.

After FY2021, as a condition of qualifying for NFIP, local or state governments are required to impose upon a seller or lessor a duty to disclose specified flood information.

The Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) must incorporate the replacement value of structures in setting flood premium rates.

This bill amends the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012 to reauthorize through FY2023 and revise the mapping program.

 In addition to reinsurance, alternatives may be used by FEMA in its risk transfer activities.

This bill amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to provide procedures for the declaration of a major disaster for wildfire on federal land.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
