<bill session="114" type="h" number="3984" updated="2018-06-02T04:48:34Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fairness for Crime Victims Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prevent diversion of funds from the Crime Victims Fund.</title>
    <title type="display">Fairness for Crime Victims Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000373"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001296" joined="2015-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001181" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000605" joined="2015-11-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="1495"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Fairness for Crime Victims Act of 2015

This bill amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to establish a point of order in the Senate and House of Representatives against any provision in an appropriation measure, amendment, motion, or conference report that: (1) contains a change in mandatory program spending, (2) reduces budget authority in the current year but does not reduce outlays over time, and (3) limits obligations from the Crime Victims Fund during a fiscal year to less than the average amount deposited into the Fund during the previous three fiscal years.

The bill permits a Senator to raise a point of order to strike such provision or to prevent its incorporation through amendment or motion. If the point of order is sustained by the Chair, the provision is stricken and may not be offered as an amendment from the floor. A motion to waive or suspend the point of order, or a motion to sustain an appeal of the ruling the Chair on such point of order, requires the affirmative vote of three-fifths of Members.

It also prohibits consideration of such provision in the House of Representatives.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
