<bill session="113" type="h" number="914" updated="2018-06-05T16:06:32Z">
  <state datetime="2013-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Religious Freedom Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to require that implementation of the repeal of the former Department of Defense policy concerning homosexual behavior in the Armed Forces not infringe upon the free exercise of religion by and the rights of conscience of members of the Armed Forces, including chaplains, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Military Religious Freedom Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001057"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001280" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001283" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000552" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001052" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001053" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000289" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000362" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001158" joined="2013-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000182" joined="2013-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000588" joined="2013-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000798" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2013-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000815" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000796" joined="2013-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-02-28T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Military Religious Freedom Protection Act - Requires the sincerely held religious or moral beliefs of a member of the Armed Forces concerning the appropriate and inappropriate expression of human sexuality to be accommodated and not the basis of any adverse personnel action, discrimination, or denial of promotion, schooling, training, or assignment (adverse actions).

Prohibits a military chaplain from being directed, ordered, or required to perform any duty, rite, ritual, ceremony, service, or function (ceremony) that is contrary to the conscience, moral principles, or religious beliefs (beliefs) of the chaplain or the chaplain's faith group. Prohibits the refusal of a chaplain to perform a ceremony that is contrary to such beliefs from being the basis of any adverse actions.

Requires the Secretary of Defense to issue regulations setting forth guidance to implement such requirements and prohibitions.

Prohibits a military installation or other property owned, rented, or otherwise under the jurisdiction or control of the Department of Defense (DOD) from being used to officiate, solemnize, or perform a marriage or marriage-like ceremony involving anything other than the union of one man with one woman.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
