<bill session="115" type="s" number="1670" updated="2019-04-18T16:38:25Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Energy to establish a program to increase participation in community solar and the receipt of associated benefits, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Solar Consumer Choice Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Solar Consumer Choice Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Community Solar Consumer Choice Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001267"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2017-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor and aged"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Community Solar Consumer Choice Act of 2017

This bill requires the Department of Energy (DOE) to establish a program to expand community solar options to: (1) individuals, particularly individuals that do not have regular access to onsite solar, including low- and moderate-income individuals; (2) businesses; (3) nonprofit organizations; and (4) states and local and tribal governments.

Community solar is a solar power plant, through which the benefits of the electricity produced is shared by electricity customers.

In carrying out the program, DOE must: (1) provide technical assistance to states and local and tribal governments for projects to increase community solar; (2) assist such governments in the development of new and innovative financial and business models that leverage competition in the marketplace in order to serve community solar subscribers; and (3) use national laboratories to collect and disseminate data that assists private entities in the financing of, subscription to, and operation of community solar projects.

The bill encourages the federal government to participate in community solar projects, including by subscribing to community solar facilities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
