<bill session="114" type="s" number="355" updated="2018-06-02T06:32:55Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Teach Safe Relationships Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to support the provision of safe relationship behavior education and training.</title>
    <title type="display">Teach Safe Relationships Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000384"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2015-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2015-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2015-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2015-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S738" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="3141"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="HIV/AIDS"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Teach Safe Relationships Act of 2015

This bill amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to authorize the Department of Education (ED) to award competitive four-year grants to local educational agencies (LEAs) to provide: (1) professional development to school administrators, teachers, and staff in safe relationship behavior education; and (2) educational programming and curricula for students regarding safe relationship behavior.

"Safe relationship behavior education" is&#160;education that:

 is medically accurate and appropriate for an individual's age, developmental stage, and culture; promotes safe relationships and teaches students to recognize and prevent coercion, violence, or abuse, including physical and emotional relationship abuse; includes education regarding communication skills, emotional health, accountability, and well-being in relationships; and includes education regarding healthy relationships and consent. ED must provide LEAs with policy guidance regarding safe relationship behavior training and the promotion of safe and healthy relationships.

ESEA funds may not be used for sex or HIV-prevention education in schools if that instruction does not include safe relationship behavior education. (Under current law, sex or HIV-prevention education in schools must be age appropriate and include the health benefits of abstinence.)</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
