<bill session="114" type="h" number="1083" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:02Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicaid Physician Self-Referral Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act to apply the Medicare restriction on self-referral to State plan requirements under Medicaid, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Medicaid Physician Self-Referral Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000404"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E251"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-25T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Medicaid Physician Self-Referral Act of 2015

 Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSAct) with respect to physician self-referral limitations to repeal the prohibition against payment of federal funds to a state for medical assistance expenditures for a designated health service furnished to an individual on the basis of a referral (self-referral) that would result in denial of payment under SSAct title XVIII (Medicare).

Requires a state plan for medical assistance to prohibit payment for a Medicaid designated health service furnished to an individual on the basis of a physician's referral if the physician (or an immediate family member) has an ownership or investment interest or a compensation arrangement with the entity furnishing the service that would not comply with Medicare requirements.

Requires application of certain reporting requirements and sanctions to a provider of a Medicaid designated health service the same way they apply under Medicare.

Amends SSAct title XVIII to: (1) apply the False Claims Act to violations of the self-referral prohibition, and (2) declare the authority of the Secretary of Health and Human Services to issue regulations under Medicaid limited to the application of self-referral limitations to state plan requirements.

Directs the Secretary to establish a protocol consistent with the Medicare self-referral disclosure protocol required under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act that enables health care providers to disclose an actual or potential violation of Medicare self-referral limitations as applied to Medicaid.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
