<bill session="114" type="h" number="2472" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:09Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Everson Walls and Ron Springs Gift for Life Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a National Organ and Tissue Donor Registry Resource Center, to authorize grants for State organ and tissue donor registries, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Everson Walls and Ron Springs Gift for Life Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001049"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000546" joined="2015-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Organ and tissue donation and transplantation"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Everson Walls and Ron Springs Gift for Life Act of 2015

This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Health Resources and Services Administration to establish a National Organ and Tissue Donor Registry Resource Center.

The Center must: (1) advance the development, expansion, and evaluation of state organ donor registries; (2) facilitate timely exchange of donor information between state registries; and (3) maintain a clearinghouse for information on registry best practices.

The Department of Health and Human Services must award grants to states in order to develop, expand, or maintain state organ donor registries and establish benchmarks for improvement in organ donation. A state registry that receives a grant must be accessible to individual donors and the Center.

A person taking an individual's organs is not civilly liable as long as the person verified the individual's consent with a state organ donor registry.

The Government Accountability Office must study the feasibility of establishing a database to track the health effects of living organ donation.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
