<bill session="115" type="s" number="3764" updated="2019-05-01T14:27:32Z">
  <state datetime="2018-12-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-12-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 and the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act to require the pre- and post-application reporting of, and to establish buffer zones for, restricted use pesticides, to prohibit the use of pesticides containing chlorpyrifos, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prohibit Chlorpyrifos Poisoning Students Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prohibit Chlorpyrifos Poisoning Students Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Prohibit Chlorpyrifos Poisoning Students Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-12-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-12-18T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Prohibit Chlorpyrifos Poisoning Students Act of 2018

This bill regulates restricted use pesticides. Specifically, the bill requires certified applicators of restricted use pesticides to submit a quarterly report to the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) documenting all use of those pesticides. The EPA shall make publicly available a summary of those reports.

The bill also requires certified applicators of restricted use pesticides to post signage in the area in which an application is to occur not later than seven days before the application.

The bill prohibits: (1) any pesticide containing chlorpyrifos (unless a temporary permit is granted to a certified applicator), and (2) application of a pesticide classified for restricted use, or an organophosphate pesticide, on or within a buffer zone of a school property.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
