<bill session="115" type="s" number="2232" updated="2019-07-16T21:20:10Z">
  <state datetime="2017-12-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to provide for the integration of distributed energy resources, to modernize electricity grid infrastructure, to provide for the consideration of non-wires alternatives, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Next Generation GRID Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Next Generation GRID Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Next Generation Grid Resources and Infrastructure Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Next Generation Grid Resources and Infrastructure Development Act</title>
    <title type="display">Next Generation GRID Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000383"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-12-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-12-14T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Next Generation Grid Resources and Infrastructure Development Act or the Next Generation GRID Act 

This bill amends the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to (1)establish a right of interconnection for distributed energy resources, (2)require each electric utility to develop an electricity distribution resource plan, (3)require each state to consider non-wire alternatives for allowing an electric utility to recover costs associated with an electricity transmission and distribution project, (4)require the Department of Energy to establish a pilot program for a distribution system operator, and (5)require each state to consider the use of performance-based incentive mechanisms to achieve its public interest goals.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
