<bill session="114" type="h" number="4705" updated="2018-11-09T00:09:16Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Austin and Perry Safe Boating Incentive Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a nonrefundable credit for the purchase of emergency position-indicating radio beacons and personal locator beacons.</title>
    <title type="display">Austin and Perry Safe Boating Incentive Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000583" joined="2016-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Austin and Perry Safe Boating Incentive Act

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow individual taxpayers a new tax credit for 50% of the amount paid or accrued, up to $200 in a taxable year ($500 for all taxable years), for a qualified emergency position-indicating radio beacon and a qualified personal locator beacon.

A "qualified emergency position-indicating radio beacon" is a device installed on an eligible boat that: (1) transmits distress signals at a frequency between 406.0 and 406.1 MHz, (2) is manufactured by a company approved to manufacture beacons by the International Cospas-Sarsat Programme, and (3) is registered with the United States National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration. A "qualified personal locator beacon" is a similarly-defined device designed to be carried by an individual and acquired for use in boating activities. An "eligible boat" is any recreational vessel, any small passenger vessel carrying not more than 250 passengers, and any uninspected passenger vessel as those terms are defined in provisions of the U.S. Code.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
