<bill session="115" type="h" number="3551" updated="2019-04-18T16:14:13Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-23T18:54:42-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-10-23T18:54:42-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Security and Accountability for Every Port Act of 2006 to reauthorize the Customs-Trade Partnership Against Terrorism Program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">C-TPAT Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">C-TPAT Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">C-TPAT Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">C-TPAT Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">C-TPAT Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001197"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000580" joined="2017-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001073" joined="2017-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2017-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2017-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000578" joined="2017-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000609" joined="2017-09-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-08-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-07">
      <text>Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-09-07" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-09-25">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 115-323.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-09-25" calendar="Union" number="233">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 233.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-10-23T16:52:28-04:00">
      <text>Ms. McSally moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-23T16:52:42-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8052-8056" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-23T16:52:43-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3551.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-23T17:00:12-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-23T18:30:46-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8062" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="569" datetime="2017-10-23T18:54:42-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 402 - 1 (Roll no. 569).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8052-8055" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-10-23T18:54:43-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Border Security, Facilitation, and Operations" code="HSHM11" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-09-25T14:18:04Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">C-TPAT Reauthorization Act of 2017

This bill amends the Security and Accountability for Every Port Act of 2006 to reauthorize within U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) the Customs-Trade Partnership Against Terrorism (C-TPAT) program. The CBP shall publish on its website or other online publication: (1) information about benefits to program participants, and (2) notice of any changes to benefits to participants by 30 days before any such changes take effect.

The bill specifies that: (1) applicants may be eligible to participate as Tier 1 or Tier 2 participants, (2) importers may be eligible to participate as Tier 3 participants, and (3) the Executive Assistant Commissioner may extend Tier 3 participation to other entity types if appropriate. To be eligible, an entity shall: (1) have a designated company employee authorized to bind such entity that is a direct company employee and will serve as the primary point of contact responsible for participation; and (2) at the time of initial application and annually thereafter, submit an international supply chain security profile.

The CBP must establish minimum security criteria for participants in the program, review such minimum security criteria at least once every two years, and update such minimum security criteria as necessary.

The CBP may recognize regulatory inspections conducted by other components of the Department of Homeland Security of entities as sufficient to constitute validation for C-TPAT program participation. It shall: (1) implement a recertification process for all C-TPAT program participants, (2) consider the potential for participation in the C-TPAT program by importers of non-containerized cargoes and non-asset-based third party logistics providers, and (3) establish sufficient internal quality controls and record management to support the management systems of the C-TPAT program.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-323</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
