<bill session="114" type="h" number="3784" updated="2018-09-07T15:11:25Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-16">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SEC Small Business Advocate Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">SEC Small Business Advocate Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">SEC Small Business Advocate Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">SEC Small Business Advocate Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">SEC Small Business Advocate Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to establish an Office of the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation and a Small Business Capital Formation Advisory Committee, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SEC Small Business Advocate Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001083"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001045" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000614" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000458" joined="2015-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000380" joined="2015-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2015-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000602" joined="2015-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2015-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000081" joined="2015-12-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-02">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises Prior to Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-12-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 56 - 0.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 114-408.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-02-01" calendar="Union" number="311">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 311.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01T15:29:04-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Garrett moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01T15:29:14-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H379-382" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01T15:29:15-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3784.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2016-02-01T15:40:47-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H379-381" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01T15:40:49-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-10">
      <text>Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7108" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2016-12-10" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-12-12">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2016-12-15">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2016-12-16" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="114-284" type="public" datetime="2016-12-16">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 114-284.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises" code="HSBA16" name="House Financial Services" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4168"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2867"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5485"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6427"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5983"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-17T04:59:58Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the House on February 1, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

SEC Small Business Advocate Act of 2016

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to establish within the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) an Office of the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation.

The Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation shall:

 assist small businesses and small business investors in resolving significant problems they may have with the SEC or with self-regulatory organizations; identify areas in which such businesses and investors would benefit from changes in SEC regulations or the rules of such organizations; identify problems that small businesses have with securing access to capital, including any unique challenges to minority-owned and women-owned small businesses; analyze the potential impact on such businesses and investors of proposed SEC regulations and proposed rules that are likely to have a significant economic impact on small businesses and small business capital formation; conduct outreach to such businesses and investors to solicit views on relevant capital formation issues; propose to the SEC changes in its regulations or orders, and propose to Congress legislative, administrative, or personnel changes, to mitigate problems identified and to promote the interests of such businesses and investors; consult with the Investor Advocate on such proposals and advise the Investor Advocate on small business-related issues; submit annual reports on its activities to specified congressional committees; and be responsible for planning, organizing, and executing the annual Government-Business Forum on Small Business Capital Formation. The bill also establishes the Small Business Capital Formation Advisory Committee, which shall provide the SEC with advice on SEC rules, regulations, and policies regarding its mission of protecting investors, maintaining fair, orderly, and efficient markets, and facilitating capital formation, as they relate to:

 capital raising by emerging, privately held small businesses and publicly traded companies with less than $250 million in public market capitalization through securities offerings; trading in the securities of such businesses and companies; and public reporting and corporate governance requirements of such businesses and companies. The SEC shall assess the committee's recommendations and disclose any action it intends to take with respect to such recommendations.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-408</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
