<bill session="114" type="h" number="6476" updated="2019-05-09T23:15:21Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Deter Revolving-door Appointments in our Nation; Stop Washington Appointees from becoming Manipulative Petitioners Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DRAIN the SWAMP Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 and the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938 to restrict the lobbying activities of former political appointees, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">DRAIN the SWAMP Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000571" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000480" joined="2016-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7401-7402"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-08T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Deter Revolving-door Appointments in our Nation; Stop Washington Appointees from becoming Manipulative Petitioners Act or the DRAIN the SWAMP Act

This bill amends the federal criminal code to revise post-employment lobbying restrictions on senior executive branch officials and employees.

Specifically, it imposes a five-year ban on communications by a former political appointee with the intent to influence officers or employees at their former executive branch agency or department.

The term political appointee includes certain senior political officials compensated on the Executive Schedule; limited term, limited emergency, and noncareer appointees in the Senior Executive Service; and employees in confidential or policy-determining positions in the excepted service.

Additionally, the bill amends the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938 to impose a lifetime ban on lobbying by a former political appointee on behalf of a foreign government or foreign political party.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
