<bill session="113" type="h" number="2484" updated="2016-10-25T16:05:04Z">
  <state datetime="2013-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Conrad State 30 and Physician Access Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide incentives to physicians to practice in rural and medically underserved communities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Conrad State 30 and Physician Access Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001287"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2013-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2013-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000620" joined="2013-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000057" joined="2014-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2014-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001187" joined="2013-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2013-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000011" joined="2013-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000131" joined="2014-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000065" joined="2013-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="identical" number="616"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="4951"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-06-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Conrad State 30 and Physician Access Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Technical Corrections Act of 1994 to make the J-1 visa waiver (Conrad state 30/medical services in underserved areas) program permanent.

Excludes from numerical immigration limitations alien physicians who have completed national interest waiver requirements by working in a health care shortage area (including alien physicians who completed such service before the date of enactment of this Act and any spouses or children of such alien physicians).

Sets forth specified employment protections and contract requirements for alien physicians working in underserved areas.

Increases the number of alien physicians that a state may be allocated from 30 to 35 per fiscal year in specified circumstances. Provides for additional increases or decreases based upon demand.

Provides up to three visa waivers per fiscal year per state for physicians in academic medical centers.

Permits dual intent for an alien coming to the United States to receive graduate medical education or training, or to take examinations required for graduate medical education or training.

Exempts H-1B nonimmigrant aliens seeking to enter the United States to pursue graduate medical education or training from specified entry limitations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
