<bill session="114" type="s" number="2131" updated="2018-06-02T07:10:36Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-06">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">An Act Making Appropriations for Law Enforcement and for Other Purposes, 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Department of Commerce Appropriations Act, 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Science Appropriations Act, 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill making appropriations for Departments of Commerce and Justice, and Science, and Related Agencies and Department of Homeland Security for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2016, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">An Act Making Appropriations for Law Enforcement and for Other Purposes, 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000567"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2015-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000320" joined="2015-10-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-05">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-10-06" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="250">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 250.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2578"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3128"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1619"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2029"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Commission on Civil Rights"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA)"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC)"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="General science and technology matters"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Legal Services Corporation"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Marine Mammal Commission"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Office of the U.S. Trade Representative"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Space flight and exploration"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
    <term name="State and local courts"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="U.S. International Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">An Act Making Appropriations for Law Enforcement and for Other Purposes, 2016 

Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 

Provides FY2016 appropriations to: the Department of Commerce; the Department of Justice (DOJ); science agencies, including the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) and the National Science Foundation (NSF); the Department of Homeland Security (DHS); and several related agencies.

Department of Commerce Appropriations Act, 2016 

Provides appropriations to the Department of Commerce for the International Trade Administration, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative, the Bureau of Industry and Security, the Economic Development Administration, the Minority Business Development Agency, Economic and Statistical Analysis, the Bureau of the Census, the National Telecommunications and Information Administration, the U.S Patent and Trademark Office, the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and Departmental Management.

Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 2016 

Provides appropriations to DOJ for: General Administration; the U.S. Parole Commission; Legal Activities; the U.S. Marshals Service; the National Security Division; Interagency Law Enforcement; the Federal Bureau of Investigation; the Drug Enforcement Administration; the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives; and the Federal Prison System.

Provides appropriations to DOJ for State and Local Law Enforcement Activities, including the Office on Violence Against Women, the Office of Justice Programs, and Community Oriented Policing Services (COPS).

Science Appropriations Act, 2016 

Provides appropriations to the Office of Science and Technology Policy, NASA, and the NSF.

Provides appropriations to related agencies, including the Commission on Civil Rights, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, the U.S. International Trade Commission, the Legal Services Corporation, the Marine Mammal Commission, and the State Justice Institute.

Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2016 

Provides FY2016 appropriations to the Department of Homeland Security (DHS).

Provides appropriations for Departmental Management and Operations for the Office of the Secretary and Executive Management, the Office of the Under Secretary for Management, the Office of the Chief Financial Officer, the Office of the Chief Information Officer, Analysis and Operations, and the Office of Inspector General.

Provides appropriations for Security, Enforcement, and Investigations for the U.S. Customs and Border Protection, the U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, the Transportation Security Administration, the U.S. Coast Guard, and the U.S. Secret Service.

Provides appropriations for Protection, Preparedness, Response, and Recovery for the National Protection and Programs Directorate, the Office of Health Affairs, and the Federal Emergency Management Agency.

 Provides appropriations for Research, Development, Training, and Services for the U.S. Citizen and Immigration Services, the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center, Science and Technology, and the Domestic Nuclear Detection Office.

Sets forth permissible, restricted, and prohibited uses for funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
