<bill session="115" type="h" number="7217" updated="2019-04-18T16:28:37Z">
  <state datetime="2018-12-11T16:48:10-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-12-11T16:48:10-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-12-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to provide States with the option of providing coordinated care for children with complex medical conditions through a health home, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">IMPROVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">IMPROVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Improving Medicaid Programs and Opportunities for Eligible Beneficiaries Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Improving Medicaid Programs and Opportunities for Eligible Beneficiaries Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IMPROVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IMPROVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Medicaid Programs and Opportunities for Eligible Beneficiaries Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Medicaid Programs and Opportunities for Eligible Beneficiaries Act</title>
    <title type="display">IMPROVE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000213"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001257" joined="2018-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001066" joined="2018-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000624" joined="2018-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2018-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000410" joined="2018-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000558" joined="2018-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001056" joined="2018-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000031" joined="2018-12-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-12-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-11T12:38:56-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Barton moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-11T12:39:31-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-11T12:39:37-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 7217.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-11T13:22:34-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-11T16:24:51-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="H10043-10052" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="428" datetime="2018-12-11T16:48:10-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 400 - 11 (Roll no. 428).</text>
      <reference ref="H10043-10047" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-12-11T16:48:11-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="7223"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3702"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-12-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Improving Medicaid Programs and Opportunities for Eligible Beneficiaries Act or the IMPROVE Act

This bill establishes a state Medicaid option to provide for medical assistance with respect to coordinated care provided through a health home (i.e., a designated provider or team of health-care professionals) for children with medically complex conditions. States must determine payment methodologies in accordance with specified requirements; payments also temporarily qualify for an enhanced federal matching rate.

The bill also makes a series of reductions relating to federal Medicaid expenditures. Among other changes, the bill reduces the federal matching rate for states that do not have required asset-verification programs for determining Medicaid eligibility.

Further, drug manufacturers with Medicaid rebate agreements for covered outpatient drugs must disclose drug product information. Manufacturers are subject to civil penalties for knowingly misclassifying drugs. Manufacturers are also required to compensate for rebates that were initially underpaid as a result of misclassification (whether or not such misclassification was committed knowingly).

Finally, the bill excludes specified wheelchairs and associated accessories from Medicare's competitive acquisition program (in which rates are set through a competitive bidding program rather than by an established fee schedule).</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
