<bill session="114" type="s" number="617" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:34Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that owners of all motor vehicles in use on United States roadways are made aware of, and obtain repairs for, manufacturer-issued safety recalls in a timely manner.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RECALL Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Repairing Every Car to Avoid Lost Lives Act</title>
    <title type="display">RECALL Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2015-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-02T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Repairing Every Car to Avoid Lost Lives Act or the RECALL Act

This bill declares that a state is in compliance with safety recall requirements if the state agency responsible for motor vehicle registration ensures, by a motor vehicle identification number search of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration's recall database, that each registered owner of a motor vehicle registered in the state is notified of all recalls issued by the vehicle's manufacturer by certain deadlines, depending on when the vehicle is registered.

A state must also require that owners complete all recall remedies as a prerequisite for motor vehicle registration renewal, with the following exceptions:

 the owner had not been notified of the recall before being notified of the need to renew; the manufacturer, through a local dealership, has not given the owner reasonable opportunity to complete a recall remedy because of a shortage of parts or qualified labor; or the owner demonstrates to the state that he or she has not had reasonable opportunity to complete the recall remedies, in which case the state may grant a temporary registration for 60 days during which time the owner must complete the recall remedies. The Secretary of Transportation shall withhold 5% of federal highway funds from a state that is not in compliance with these requirements.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
