<bill session="114" type="s" number="2355" updated="2018-06-02T07:13:32Z">
  <state datetime="2015-12-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-12-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Credit Access and Inclusion Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act to clarify Federal law with respect to reporting certain positive consumer credit information to consumer reporting agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Credit Access and Inclusion Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000360"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2015-12-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3035"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4172"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-12-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Credit Access and Inclusion Act of 2015

This bill amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to authorize a person or the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to furnish to a consumer reporting agency information relating to the performance of a consumer in making payments: (1) under a lease agreement for a dwelling, including a lease in which HUD provides subsidized payments; or (2) pursuant to a contract for a utility or telecommunications service.

Information about a consumer's usage of any utility or telecommunications services may be furnished to a consumer reporting agency only to the extent that the information relates to payment by the consumer for such services or other terms of the provision of such services, including any deposit, discount, or conditions for interruption or termination of service.

An energy utility firm may not report payment information to a consumer reporting agency with respect to an outstanding balance of a consumer as late if the firm and the consumer have entered into a payment plan and the consumer is meeting the obligations of such plan.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
