<bill session="114" type="s" number="3511" updated="2019-03-03T14:41:18Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Defense to expand the Secretarial Designee Program of the Department of Defense to include victims of acts of terror.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jessica Kensky and Patrick Downes Act</title>
    <title type="display">Jessica Kensky and Patrick Downes Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-12-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Jessica Kensky and Patrick Downes Act

This bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to expand eligibility for its Secretarial Designee Program to include the provision of health care at military treatment facilities for: (1) victims of acts of terror that occur in the United States, and (2) U.S. residents who are victims of acts of terror outside the United States.

 Individuals who become eligible for the program shall remain eligible on a space available and fully reimbursable basis in accordance with DOD policy governing such program. DOD may provide expedited program eligibility to individuals with severe injuries.

DOD may not release an individual who is receiving care under the program to a health care provider in the private sector until a comprehensive treatment plan is communicated to the individual and such provider.

DOD shall establish procedures to implement such program expansion, which shall include procedures for:

 conducting timely outreach and communication to local medical facilities after an act of terror in the United States; promptly contacting, coordinating, and providing medical expertise to such facilities that are treating serious injuries; and providing medical evaluations for victims who were exposed to blast and other types of injuries.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
