<bill session="115" type="h" number="4749" updated="2019-04-18T16:19:25Z">
  <state datetime="2018-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 to establish a program to enhance transparency and traceability of food products and ingredients that are exported to the United States in order to protect American consumers and American food manufacturers against mislabeling, adulteration, and fraud.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Truth in Certification for Foreign Food Ingredients Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Truth in Certification for Foreign Food Ingredients Act</title>
    <title type="display">Truth in Certification for Foreign Food Ingredients Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001200"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Livestock and Foreign Agriculture" code="HSAG29" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural trade"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-01-09T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Truth in Certification for Foreign Food Ingredients Act 

This bill amends the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 to require the Foreign Agricultural Service (FAS) to carry out a program to enhance transparency and traceability of food products and ingredients that are exported to the United States in order to protect consumers and food manufacturers against mislabeling, adulteration, and fraud.

Under the program, the FAS must provide foreign government officials, agricultural producers, and exporters of food products and ingredients to the United States with technical assistance and best practices to improve: (1) transparency, traceability and fraud prevention; and (2) cooperation with private certification and verification bodies to ensure the accuracy and integrity of their food product and ingredient certification and verification.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
