<bill session="115" type="h" number="1735" updated="2019-04-18T16:05:33Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-27">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to issue guidance regarding implementation of certain buy-outs or the acquisition of property for open space as a flood mitigation measure, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Community Empowerment for Mitigated Properties Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Community Empowerment for Mitigated Properties Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Empowerment for Mitigated Properties Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Empowerment for Mitigated Properties Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Community Empowerment for Mitigated Properties Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001291"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000126" joined="2017-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E390"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-27">
      <text>Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-07-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-11-21">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 115-417.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-11-21" calendar="Union" number="309">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 309.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3041"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="4667"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-11-21T13:33:51Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">Community Empowerment for Mitigated Properties Act of 2017

(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to issue guidance regarding the acquisition of property for open space as a hazard mitigation measure under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, which shall include:

 a process by which the state hazard mitigation officer appointed for such acquisition shall, within 60 days after an applicant for assistance enters into the acquisition agreement, provide written notification to each affected local government that includes the location and a description of the acquisition, the state-local assistance agreement for the hazard mitigation grant program, and a copy of the deed restriction; and recommendations for entering into and implementing a memorandum of understanding between local governments and covered entities that allows an affected local government to use and maintain the open space created by such a project, consistent with such Act and all adjoining property and subject to the notification of the adjoining property, so long as the maintenance cost is borne by the local government, and to maintain the open space pursuant to standards exceeding any local government standards defined in the agreement with FEMA. A "covered entity" includes the grantee or subgrantee receiving assistance for an open space project, the state in which such project is located, and the applicable regional administrator of FEMA.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-417</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
