<amendment session="113" chamber="h" number="959" updated="2016-10-25T12:44:12Z">
  <amends type="h" number="6" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2014-06-25T13:31:54-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000562"/>
  <offered datetime="2014-06-25"/>
  <description>Manager's amendment strikes the subsection requiring a 90 day decision deadline and replaces it with a 30 day decision deadline requiring DOE to issue a final decision on applications to export LNG following the conclusion of the NEPA environmental review of the LNG facilities. For the purposes of the 30 day decision deadline, the NEPA review would be considered concluded: for a project requiring an Environmental Impact Statement, 30 days after publication of a Final Environmental Impact Statement; for a project for which an Environmental Assessment has been prepared, 30 days after publication by DOE of a Finding of No Significant Impact; and upon determination by the lead agency that an application is eligible for a Categorical Exclusion pursuant to NEPA.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment No. 1 printed in part A of House Report 113-492 to strike the subsection requiring a 90 day decision deadline and replace it with a 30 day decision deadline requiring DOE to issue a final decision on applications to export LNG following the conclusion of the NEPA environmental review of the LNG facilities. For the purposes of the 30 day decision deadline, the NEPA review would be considered concluded: for a project requiring an Environmental Impact Statement, 30 days after publication of a Final Environmental Impact Statement; for a project for which an Environmental Assessment has been prepared, 30 days after publication by DOE of a Finding of No Significant Impact; and upon determination by the lead agency that an application is eligible for a Categorical Exclusion pursuant to NEPA.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2014-06-25T13:31:54-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Gardner amendment (A001) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25T13:18:21-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Gardner.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5741-5743" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5741-5742" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25"/>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25T13:18:21-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Gardner.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5741-5743" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5741-5742" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25T13:31:54-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Gardner amendment (A001) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25T13:31:54-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
