<bill session="114" type="hr" number="814" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:36Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Calling on the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) to invoke Article 5 of the North Atlantic Treaty and conduct a military campaign against the Islamic State of Iraq and Syria (ISIS).</title>
    <title type="display">Calling on the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) to invoke Article 5 of the North Atlantic Treaty and conduct a military campaign against the Islamic State of Iraq and Syria (ISIS).</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001284" joined="2016-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000378" joined="2016-07-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Belgium"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="France"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Condemns the Islamic State of Iraq and Syria (ISIS), its ideology, its past attacks, and its ongoing campaign of atrocities.

Calls upon the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) to: (1) invoke Article 5 of the North Atlantic Treaty and declare that the ISIS attacks against France, Belgium, the United States, and Turkey represent attacks against all NATO members; (2) organize and conduct a military campaign against ISIS with the objective of the destruction of the terrorist organization; (3) increase information and intelligence sharing between NATO members with the goal of improving counterterrorism capabilities and operations; (4) increase coordination and information sharing with the European Union; and (5) reassess its counterterrorism strategy in order to more effectively address the threat from ISIS.

Calls upon all NATO members to participate in combat operations against ISIS in Iraq, Syria, and elsewhere as needed.

Reaffirms the U.S. commitment to supporting the NATO alliance and destroying ISIS.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
