<bill session="114" type="s" number="2668" updated="2018-06-02T07:15:44Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide housing opportunities for individuals living with HIV or AIDS.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to provide housing opportunities for individuals living with HIV or AIDS.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2016-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2016-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2016-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2016-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001141" joined="2016-04-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3083"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4707"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="HIV/AIDS"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill amends the AIDS Housing Opportunity Act to revise the formula and requirements for distributing funds under the Housing Opportunities for Persons With Aids (HOPWA) Program.

 A grantee that received an allocation in FY2016 shall continue to be eligible for such allocations in subsequent fiscal years, subject to approval by the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) and the amounts available from appropriations Acts.

HUD shall:

 redetermine a grantee's eligibility at least once every 10 years, and ensure that a grantee that received an allocation in the prior fiscal year does not receive an allocation 5% less than or 10% greater than the share of total available formula funds allocated to that grantee in the preceding fiscal year. HUD may also award such funds to an alternative grantee if the original grantee agrees in a written document meeting HUD approval.

References to "cases of AIDS" and "AIDS cases" shall be replaced by "individuals living with HIV or AIDS," which means, with respect to the counting of cases in a geographic area during a period of time, the sum of:

 the number of living non-AIDS cases of HIV in the area, and the number of living cases of AIDS in the area.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
