<bill session="115" type="s" number="1940" updated="2019-04-18T16:39:35Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-10-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Fish and Wildlife Act of 1956 to reauthorize the volunteer services, community partnership, and refuge education programs of the National Wildlife Refuge System, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keep America's Refuges Operational Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keep America's Refuges Operational Act</title>
    <title type="display">Keep America's Refuges Operational Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2017-10-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-10-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="3979"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-10-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Keep America's Refuges Operational Act

This bill amends the Fish and Wildlife Act of 1956 to reauthorize through FY2022: (1) the volunteer services, community partnerships, and national wildlife refuge education programs of the National Wildlife Refuge System; and (2) provisions authorizing the Department of the Interior to accept and use gifts, devises, or bequests of real and personal property for the benefit of the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service in the performance of its activities and services.

The bill eliminates the prohibition on the use for the operation or administration of any nonfederal entity of any federal funds that are used for a project or program for a national wildlife refuge or a complex of geographically related refuges under a cooperative agreement between Interior and a partner organization, academic institution, state or local government agency, or other person under the community partnerships program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
