<bill session="114" type="h" number="48" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:35Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Fly for Foreign Fighters Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require a review of the completeness of the Terrorist Screening Database (TSDB) maintained by the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the derivative terrorist watchlist utilized by the Transportation Security Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">No Fly for Foreign Fighters Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2015-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">No Fly for Foreign Fighters Act 

This bill requires the Director of the Terrorist Screening Center to: (1) review the completeness of the Terrorist Screening Database and the terrorist watch list utilized by the Transportation Security Administration to determine if an individual who may seek to board a U.S.-bound or domestic flight, and who poses a threat to aviation or national security or a threat of terrorism and is known or suspected of being a member of a foreign terrorist organization, is included in the Database and on such watch list; and (2) report findings to the House Committee on Homeland Security and the Senate Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
