<bill session="114" type="h" number="2356" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:31Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Access to Investment Research Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Fair Access to Investment Research Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Securities and Exchange Commission to provide a safe harbor related to certain investment fund research reports, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Fair Access to Investment Research Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001072"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001083" joined="2015-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-13">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises Prior to Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-05-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 48 - 9.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-01-28">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 114-401.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-01-28" calendar="Union" number="304">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 304.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises" code="HSBA16" name="House Financial Services" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1675"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5983"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-01-28T15:06:01Z" status="Reported to House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Fair Access to Investment Research Act of 2015

(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to revise a specified regulation to create a safe harbor for certain publications or distributions of research reports by brokers or dealers distributing securities.

The revised regulation shall declare that, even if a broker or dealer participates in the registered offering of a covered investment fund's securities, the investment fund research report shall not be deemed to constitute an offer for sale nor an offer to sell a security that is the subject of the offering pursuant to a registration statement that the issuer proposes to file, or has filed, or that is effective.

The covered investment fund research report shall indeed be deemed to satisfy the regulation's requirements as well as those of any self-regulatory organization.

 The SEC shall not impose specified conditions and requirements when implementing the safe harbor.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-401</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
