<bill session="113" type="s" number="2757" updated="2016-10-25T16:32:03Z">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">America COMPETES Reauthorization Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">America Creating Opportunities to Meaningfully Promote Excellence in Technology, Education, and Science Reauthorization Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">National Nanotechnology Initiative Amendments Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to invest in innovation through research and development, to improve the competitiveness of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">America Creating Opportunities to Meaningfully Promote Excellence in Technology, Education, and Science Reauthorization Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000361"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2014-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000590" joined="2014-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Space flight and exploration"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-07-31T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">America COMPETES Reauthorization Act of 2014 or America Creating Opportunities to Meaningfully Promote Excellence in Technology, Education, and Science Reauthorization Act of 2014 - Establishes, revises, and extends specified science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) programs, as well as education, research, and training programs.

Amends the America Competes Reauthorization Act of 2010 to revise requirements for updating the five-year STEM education strategic plan and require the Office of Science and Technology Policy to convene a subcommittee on research productivity.

 Amends the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 to revise requirements for prize competitions to stimulate innovation.

Establishes requirements for educational and outreach activities of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and the National Institute of Standards and Technology.

Reauthorizes specified National Institute of Standards and Technology programs and amends the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act to modify the Manufacturing Extension Partnership.

Reauthorizes specified National Science Foundation (NSF) programs and establishes requirements for grants and educational programs. Establishes grants and requirements for specified activities to promote STEM education and teacher training.

Requires the NSF to encourage the development of the Innovation Corps and other training programs that focus on graduate student professional development. Establishes grants for traineeship programs.

Requires the National Science Board to assess metrics for evaluating science and engineering comprehension in grades K-12.

Requires the Department of Education (DOE) to award grants for STEM secondary schools.

Reauthorizes the Department of Commerce's Regional Innovation Program and permits loan guarantees for science park infrastructure.

National Nanotechnology Initiative Amendments Act of 2014 - Amends the 21st Century Nanotechnology Research and Development Act to revise requirements for management and review of the National Nanotechnology Initiative.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
