<bill session="113" type="h" number="916" updated="2018-06-05T16:06:34Z">
  <state datetime="2014-07-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Land Asset Inventory Reform Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Federal Land Asset Inventory Reform Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve Federal land management, resource conservation, environmental protection, and use of Federal real property, by requiring the Secretary of the Interior to develop a multipurpose cadastre of Federal real property and identifying inaccurate, duplicate, and out-of-date Federal land inventories, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Federal Land Asset Inventory Reform Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000188"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000369" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001250" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001076" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001077" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000556" joined="2014-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000292" joined="2013-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000295" joined="2014-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001149" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000933" joined="2014-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000588" joined="2013-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000265" joined="2013-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000523" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2013-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-05">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-16">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-16">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-22">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-688.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-22" calendar="Union" number="519">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 519.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-12-22T13:22:41Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">Federal Land Asset Inventory Reform Act of 2014 - (Sec. 2) Directs the Secretary of the Interior to develop and maintain a current, accurate multipurpose cadastre of federal real property (an inventory of real property of the federal government) to assist with federal land management activities, including, but not limited to, resource development and conservation, travel management, agricultural use, active forest management, environmental protection, and use of real property. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into cost-sharing agreements with states to include any non-federal lands in a state in such cadastre. Limits the federal share of any such agreement to 50% of the total cost to a state for the development of the cadastre of the non-federal lands in the state.

Requires Interior to submit a report, covering all cadastres and inventories authorized, operated, or maintained by all executive agencies, on: (1) existing real property inventories or any components of any cadastre, (2) consolidation of inventories and components, (3) the use of existing inventories and components of any cadastre, (4) cost savings that will be achieved, and (5) recommendations for legislation.

(Sec. 4) Requires Interior to: (1) make the cadastre available on the Internet in a graphically geo-enabled and searchable format; (2) ensure that the inventory required by this Act includes the identification of all lands and parcels suitable for disposal by Resource Management Plans conducted pursuant to the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976; and (3) prevent the disclosure of any parcels of land, buildings or facilities thereon, or related information, if this would impair or jeopardize national security or homeland defense.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 113-688</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
