<bill session="114" type="h" number="4875" updated="2019-01-09T21:26:28Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-22">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Semiquincentennial Commission Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">United States Semiquincentennial Commission Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">United States Semiquincentennial Commission Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">United States Semiquincentennial Commission Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the United States Semiquincentennial Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">United States Semiquincentennial Commission Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001296" joined="2016-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001227" joined="2016-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001106" joined="2016-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000043" joined="2016-04-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-05T20:57:19-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Chaffetz moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-05T20:57:36-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4258-4260" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-05T20:57:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4875.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2016-07-05T21:03:09-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4258-4260" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-07-05T21:03:11-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2016-07-12" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5010" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2016-07-22" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="114-196" type="public" datetime="2016-07-22">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 114-196.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="2815"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-23T03:59:58Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the House on July 5, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

United States Semiquincentennial Commission Act of 2016

(Sec. 4) This bill establishes the United States Semiquincentennial Commission to plan, develop, and coordinate the commemoration of U.S. history leading up to the 250th anniversary of the founding of the United States.

(Sec. 5) The Commission shall: (1) prepare an overall program for the commemoration; (2) plan, encourage, develop, and coordinate observances and activities commemorating the historic events associated with the Semiquincentennial; (3) emphasize the planning of events in locations of historical significance to the United States; and (4) give special emphasis to the role of persons and locations with significant impact on U.S. history beginning on the date of execution of the Declaration of Independence and to the ideas associated with that history.

(Sec. 6) The Department of the Interior shall study and report to the Commission on appropriate actions that might be taken to further preserve and develop historic sites and battlefields to ensure that fitting observances and exhibits may be held at such sites during the celebration.

 The Federal Council on the Arts and the Humanities, the National Endowment for the Arts, the National Endowment for the Humanities, the Library of Congress, the Smithsonian Institution, and the National Archives shall cooperate with the Commission. The Secretary of State shall coordinate the participation of foreign nations in the celebration.

Interior shall, through a competitive process, seek to enter into an arrangement with a nonprofit organization, the mission of which is consistent with the purpose of this bill, under which such nonprofit shall:

 serve as the secretariat of the Commission; house the administrative offices of the Commission; assume responsibility for funds of the Commission; and provide to the Commission financial and administrative services related to budgeting, accounting, financial reporting, personnel, and procurement. (Sec. 10) The Commission shall terminate on December 31, 2027.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
