<bill session="114" type="h" number="4410" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:50Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fresh Start Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To permit expungement of records of certain nonviolent criminal offenses, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Fresh Start Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2016-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2016-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000984" joined="2016-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2016-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2016-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2016-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2016-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2016-02-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E86"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-01T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Fresh Start Act of 2016

This bill amends the federal criminal code to allow an individual convicted of a nonviolent criminal offense to file a petition for expungement of the record of such conviction. It allows expungement if such individual: (1) has never been convicted of any criminal offense other than the nonviolent offenses committed in a single criminal episode that includes the offense for which expungement is sought; (2) has fulfilled all requirements of the sentence of the court, including payment of all fines, restitution, or assessments and completion of terms of imprisonment and probation; and (3) has remained free (if required by the court's sentence) from dependency on or abuse of alcohol or a controlled substance for at least one year.

 The Department of Justice must maintain an unaltered nonpublic copy of expunged criminal records, to be disclosed for limited purposes to federal, state, or local law enforcement agencies.

The bill amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to increase by 5% grant funding under the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program to states that implement expungement procedures substantially similar to the procedures enacted by this Act. It decreases such grant funding by 5% for states that fail to adopt expungement procedures.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
