<bill session="113" type="h" number="5065" updated="2016-10-25T16:14:59Z">
  <state datetime="2014-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safeguarding America's Future and Environment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish an integrated Federal program to respond to ongoing and expected impacts of extreme weather and climate change by protecting, restoring, and conserving the natural resources of the United States, and to maximize government efficiency and reduce costs, in cooperation with State, local, and tribal governments and other entities.</title>
    <title type="display">SAFE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001032" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001166" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000933" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001191" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2014-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000465" joined="2014-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000799" joined="2014-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="identical" number="1202"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-07-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Safeguarding America's Future and Environment Act or SAFE Act - Requires the President to establish an interagency Natural Resources Climate Change Adaptation Panel to adopt the National Fish, Wildlife, and Plants Climate Adaptation Strategy (released March 26, 2013) to protect, restore, and conserve natural resources so that natural resources become more resilient, adapt to, and withstand the impact of extreme weather and climate change. Requires the Panel to review and revise the strategy every four years.

Requires each agency represented on the panel to integrate the elements of the strategy that relate to conservation, restoration, and management of natural resources into agency plans, environmental reviews, and programs.

Requires the Secretary of the Interior to establish a National Climate Change and Wildlife Science Center within the United States Geological Survey (USGS) to assess and develop scientific information, tools, strategies, and techniques to be used to address the impact of extreme weather and climate change on natural resources.

Requires the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of the Interior to establish a Science Advisory Board to advise the panel on the state of the science regarding the impact of extreme weather and climate change on natural resources and strategies and mechanisms for natural resources adaptation. Requires each agency represented on the panel to submit to the President a natural resources adaptation plan and implement the plan upon approval by the President.

Requires states, in order to be eligible to receive funding under this Act, to submit to the Secretary of the Interior and, as applicable, the Secretary of Commerce for review and approval a state natural resources adaptation plan that details efforts to address the impact of climate change on natural resources and coastal areas.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
