<bill session="114" type="h" number="4401" updated="2018-08-16T22:36:56Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-29T16:55:30-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-02-29T16:55:30-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ALERT Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Amplifying Local Efforts to Root out Terror Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">ALERT Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Amplifying Local Efforts to Root out Terror Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security to provide countering violent extremism training to Department of Homeland Security representatives at State and local fusion centers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Amplifying Local Efforts to Root out Terror Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000583"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001038" joined="2016-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001073" joined="2016-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000386" joined="2016-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000375" joined="2016-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2016-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001197" joined="2016-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000604" joined="2016-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000601" joined="2016-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000578" joined="2016-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000030" joined="2016-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2016-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000132" joined="2016-02-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-02-02" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-02-29">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 114-437.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-02-29" calendar="Union" number="334">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 334.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-02-29T16:32:22-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Loudermilk moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-29T16:32:36-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1010-1013" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-29T16:32:38-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4401.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2016-02-29T16:55:30-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="H1010-1011" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-02-29T16:55:33-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-01">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5471"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3072"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-29T14:33:42Z" status="Passed House amended">Amplifying Local Efforts to Root out Terror Act of 2016 or the ALERT Act of 2016

(Sec. 2) This bill authorizes the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to provide training at state and major urban area fusion centers for the purpose of administering community awareness briefings and related activities in furtherance of its efforts to counter violent extremism, identify and report suspicious activities, and increase awareness of and more quickly identify terrorism threats, including the travel or attempted travel of individuals from the United States to support a foreign terrorist organization abroad. (A "fusion center" serves as a focal point within the state and local environment for the receipt, analysis, gathering, and sharing of threat-related information between the federal government and state, local, tribal, territorial and private sector partners.)

(Sec. 3) The bill directs DHS to assess its efforts to support countering violent extremism at the state, local, tribal, and territorial levels. Such assessment shall include:

 a cataloging of DHS efforts to assist state, local, tribal, and territorial governments in countering violent extremism; a review of cooperative agreements between DHS and such governments relating to countering violent extremism; and an evaluation of DHS plans and any potential opportunities to better support such governments that are in furtherance of DHS's countering violent extremism objectives and consistent with all relevant constitutional, legal, and privacy protections. (Sec. 4) DHS shall notify Congress of the number of employees of state, local, tribal, and territorial governments with security clearances sponsored by DHS, including a detailed list of the agencies that employ such employees, the level of clearance held, and whether such employees are assigned as representatives to state and major urban area fusion centers.

(Sec. 5) The bill prohibits the authorization of additional funds to carry out this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-437</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
