<bill session="113" type="h" number="4251" updated="2016-10-25T16:11:40Z">
  <state datetime="2014-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Traumatic Brain Injury Research and Treatment Improvement Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, to establish a surveillance system regarding traumatic brain injury, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">National Traumatic Brain Injury Research and Treatment Improvement Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000096"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2014-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000043" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000583" joined="2014-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-03-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">National Traumatic Brain Injury Research and Treatment Improvement Act of 2014 - Requires the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to: (1) evaluate existing surveillance and data collections systems that track the incidence and circumstances of traumatic brain injury, including concussion; (2) establish a statistically sound, scientifically credible, and integrated National Traumatic Brain Injury Surveillance System; and (3) ensure that the System is designed in a manner that facilitates further research on brain injury.

Authorizes the Director to award grants to, or enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with, public or private nonprofit entities to carry out activities under this Act.

 Requires the Director to: (1) make information and analysis in the System available to the public, including researchers, and to other federal agencies, including the National Institutes of Health (NIH), the Health Resources and Services Administration, the Food and Drug Administration (FDA), the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality, and the Departments of Education, Veterans Affairs (VA), and Defense (DOD); and (2) ensure that privacy and security protections applicable to the System are at least as stringent as those under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA).</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
