<amendment session="115" chamber="h" number="354" updated="2018-09-19T13:31:40Z">
  <amends type="h" number="3354" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2017-09-07T21:57:21-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000289"/>
  <offered datetime="2017-09-07"/>
  <description>At the end of division A (before the short title), insert the following:    SEC. __. None of the funds made available by this Act may be used by the Environmental Protection Agency to take any of the actions described as a "backstop" in the December 29, 2009, letter from EPA's Regional Administrator to the States in the Watershed and the District of Columbia in response to the development or implementation of a State's watershed implementation and referred to in enclosure B of such letter.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 50 printed in House Report 115-297 to prohibit the Environmental Protection Agency from using any funds to take retaliatory, or EPA described "backstop" actions, against any of the six states in the Chesapeake Bay Watershed in the event that a state does not meet the goals mandated by the EPA's Chesapeake Bay Total Maximum Daily Load.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2017-09-07T21:57:21-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="479">
      <text>On agreeing to the Goodlatte amendment (A082) Agreed to by recorded vote: 214 - 197 (Roll no. 479).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-09-07T20:12:24-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A082) offered by Mr. Goodlatte.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7157-7158, H7169-7170" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7157" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-07"/>
    <action datetime="2017-09-07T21:57:21-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-07T21:57:21-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-07T21:57:21-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Goodlatte amendment (A082) Agreed to by recorded vote: 214 - 197 (Roll no. 479).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-07T20:12:24-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A082) offered by Mr. Goodlatte.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7157-7158, H7169-7170" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7157" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-07">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
