<bill session="114" type="sr" number="370" updated="2018-06-02T06:19:14Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution recognizing that for nearly 40 years, the United States and the Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN) have worked toward stability, prosperity, and peace in Southeast Asia.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution recognizing that for nearly 40 years, the United States and the Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN) have worked toward stability, prosperity, and peace in Southeast Asia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2016-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2016-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2016-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2016-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2016-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2016-02-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S825-827" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Brunei"/>
    <term name="Burma"/>
    <term name="Cambodia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Indonesia"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Laos"/>
    <term name="Malaysia"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Philippines"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Singapore"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Thailand"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Welcomes the leaders of the Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN) to the United States for the February 2016 U.S.-ASEAN summit meeting at Rancho Mirage, California.

 Supports the elevation of the United States-ASEAN relationship to a strategic partnership and recommits the United States to ASEAN centrality.

Urges ASEAN to continue its efforts to foster greater integration and unity.

Supports efforts by ASEAN nations to address maritime and territorial disputes through peaceful, diplomatic, and legitimate regional and international arbitration mechanisms.

Urges all parties to maritime and territorial disputes in the Asia-Pacific region to: (1) respect the status quo; (2) cease land reclamation activities; and (3) refrain from inhabiting or garrisoning or otherwise militarizing uninhabited islands, reefs, shoals, and other features.

Opposes: (1) unilateral declarations of administrative and military districts in contested areas in the South China Sea, (2) the imposition of new fishing regulations covering disputed areas in the South China Sea, and (3) actions to prevent another country from exercising its sovereign rights to the resources of the exclusive economic zone and continental shelf.

Urges parties to refrain from unilateral actions that cause permanent physical change to the marine environment.

Supports efforts by ASEAN and China to develop an effective Code of Conduct.

Urges ASEAN to reaffirm the decision of the Permanent Court of Arbitration in The Hague's ruling with respect to the case between the Philippines and China.

Supports efforts by U.S. partners and allies in ASEAN to enhance the maritime capabilities of a country or regional organizations to respond to emerging maritime threats and illegal activities in the Asia-Pacific region.

Reaffirms the enhancement of U.S.-ASEAN economic engagement, including the elimination of barriers to cross-border commerce.

Supports: (1) the Lower Mekong Initiative, (2) the Young Southeast Asian Leaders Initiative, and (3) capacity building for the promotion of human rights.

Reaffirms the commitment of the United States to continue joint efforts with ASEAN to halt human smuggling and trafficking of persons.

Encourages the President to communicate to ASEAN leaders the importance of releasing political prisoners and ending politically motivated prosecutions.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
