<bill session="115" type="h" number="2580" updated="2019-04-18T16:09:15Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To simplify and improve the Federal student loan program through income-contingent repayment to provide stronger protections for borrowers, encourage responsible borrowing, and save money for taxpayers.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Earnings Contingent Education Loans Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Earnings Contingent Education Loans Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ExCEL Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ExCEL Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">ExCEL Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Z000017"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-19T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Earnings Contingent Education Loans Act of 2017 or the ExCEL Act of 2017

This bill amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to replace several existing federal student loan programs with a single repayment plan that caps annual debt repayments based on the borrower's income.

The bill terminates the authority of the Department of Education (ED) to make federal Direct Stafford Loans, Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loans, and Direct PLUS loans, subject to exceptions for existing student borrowers, PLUS loans made to parents of undergraduates, and Direct Consolidation Loans.

To replace the programs, the bill establishes the Income Dependent Education Assistance (IDEA) Loan Program and the IDEA Loan Repayment Program, which limit annual repayments based on the borrower's income and prohibit the accrual of interest on loans for active duty service members. Loans under the program are not eligible for the federal public service loan forgiveness program.

ED must provide through the Internet a tool to enable borrowers to make payments and access specified details regarding loans.

The bill amends the Social Security Act (SSAct) to provide ED with access to information in the National Directory of New Hires to identify when borrowers are hired and remind them of their repayment status and obligation to provide accurate employment information.

The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to require: (1) reporting on W-2 forms the total amount deducted and withheld under the IDEA Loan Repayment Program, and (2) the Department of the Treasury to disclose to ED tax return information necessary to carry out the IDEA Loan Repayment Program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
