<bill session="114" type="hr" number="125" updated="2018-06-02T01:16:47Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-26T15:12:07-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-02-26T15:12:07-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for further consideration of the bill (H.R. 5) to support State and local accountability for public education, protect State and local authority, inform parents of the performance of their children's schools, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Providing for further consideration of the bill (H.R. 5) to support State and local accountability for public education, protect State and local authority, inform parents of the performance of their children's schools, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000450"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-25">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 114-29, by Ms. Foxx.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-25T21:56:01-05:00">
      <text>The rule provides for further consideration of H.R. 5. The rule provides that an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules Committee Print 114-8, modified by the amendment printed in part A of the Rules Committee report, shall be considered as adopted. No further amendment to the bill shall be in order except those printed in part B of the report of the Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-02-25" state="REPORTED" calendar="House" number="11">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 11.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-02-26T12:43:12-05:00">
      <text>By direction of the Committee on Rules, Ms. Foxx called up H. Res. 125 and asked for its immediate consideration.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1180-1182" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-26T12:46:13-05:00">
      <text>POINT OF ORDER AGAINST CONSIDERATION - Mr. Polis made a point of order against consideration of H. Res. 125 on the grounds that it violated section 426(a) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974. The Chair announced that the point of order met the threshold burden under the rule and recognized Mr. Polis and a Member opposed for up to twenty minutes of debate, equally divided and controlled, on the question of consideration. Following debate, the Chair would then put the question of consideration as the statutory means of disposing of the point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-26T13:21:54-05:00">
      <text>On consideration of the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 224 - 167 (Roll no. 91).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1181-1182" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-26T13:22:11-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1180-1192" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-26T13:23:52-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 125.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-26T15:04:01-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 234 - 177 (Roll no. 92).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1191-1192" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="text CR H1191"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="93" datetime="2015-02-26T15:12:07-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 234 - 184 (Roll no. 93).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1180" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-02-26T15:12:07-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="procedurally-related" number="5"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-25T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 5 (Student Success Act).</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-29</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
