<bill session="114" type="s" number="1803" updated="2018-06-02T06:57:51Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Coal Combustion Residuals Regulation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend subtitle D of the Solid Waste Disposal Act to encourage recovery and beneficial use of coal combustion residuals and establish requirements for the proper management and disposal of coal combustion residuals that are protective of human health and the environment.</title>
    <title type="display">Improving Coal Combustion Residuals Regulation Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2015-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1734"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2446"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5788"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Improving Coal Combustion Residuals Regulation Act of 2015

This bill amends the nonhazardous waste provisions of subtitle D of the Solid Waste Disposal Act (commonly known as the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act) to establish a federal permit program for coal combustion residuals (coal ash) that states may elect to administer. The program outlines the criteria that a state must use if it chooses to adopt and enforce a permit program regulating the management and disposal of coal ash generated by electric utilities and independent power producers. The program applies to the disposal of coal ash into: (1) landfills or surface impoundments, (2) sand or gravel pits, (3) quarries, or (4) lateral expansions of the previously mentioned structures.

A state that chooses to adopt a coal ash program is given sole enforcement authority. The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) must implement a program for a state if: (1) a state's program fails to meet those criteria, or (2) a state does not implement a program. A coal ash permit program implemented by the EPA may not apply to the utilization, placement, and storage of coal ash at surface or underground coal mining and reclamation operations.

The bill revises the EPA rule governing the disposal of coal ash, entitled "Hazardous and Solid Waste Management System; Disposal of Coal Combustion Residuals from Electric Utilities." The rule may be implemented only through the permit program established by the bill. When the requirements of the bill and the rule conflict, the requirements of the bill must be followed.

Under the program, the implementing agency must use baseline criteria, including criteria with respect to coal ash for:

 structures' design, location, and structural integrity; groundwater and surface water protections; structures closing; and air quality with respect to fugitive dust. The agency implementing the permit program must ensure that certain information concerning the program is publicly available.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
