<bill session="113" type="h" number="4260" updated="2016-10-25T16:11:43Z">
  <state datetime="2014-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ryan White Patient Equity and Choice Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that the Ryan White Comprehensive AIDS Resources Emergency Act program is as effective as possible in saving lives and preventing the spread of the HIV epidemic by ensuring that funding allocations are evidenced-based and by promoting greater utilization of patient-centered care.</title>
    <title type="display">Ryan White Patient Equity and Choice Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000291"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2014-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000126" joined="2014-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001180" joined="2014-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001137" joined="2014-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000933" joined="2014-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2014-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="HIV/AIDS"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-03-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Ryan White Patient Equity and Choice Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to report to Congress on whether the allocation of funding under the HIV Health Care Services Program enables areas where the HIV epidemic is growing to meet the need for medical services.

Restricts approval of a waiver allowing use of less than 75% of emergency relief, care grant, and early intervention funds for core medical services unless approval of the waiver will positively contribute to all eligible individuals being identified and retained in care.

Includes as core medical services HIV care continuum services consisting of early intervention HIV and sexually transmitted disease testing, referral, and case management services.

Requires HHS to ensure that: (1) individuals receiving such core medical services have an identified medical home that includes a primary care team led by an experienced HIV medical provider, and (2) those receiving HIV primary care and case management services obtain the care and coordination through the medical home approach.

Includes testing for other sexually transmitted diseases among early intervention services. Expands early intervention linkage-to-care services to include the following:

 education of those with HIV/AIDS at the time of diagnosis about the benefits of HIV care, ensuring attendance at first doctor visits, coordination with medical case managers, assistance to re-engage for those who have dropped out of care, and ensuring the identification of a medical home. Requires states providing drug assistance to offer pharmaceutical services through extensive pharmacy networks, including specialty pharmacies and pharmacies that focus on the HIV population.

Adds as a criterion for award of grants for HIV care the degree to which funding will promote the incorporation of principles of patient-centered care into providing support services. Describes "patient-centered care" as care adhering to principles of customization to reflect patient needs, values, and choices; patient safety; transparency; patient control; and caregiver cooperation. Provides guidelines for funding patient-centered model of care projects, to be carried out through individual savings accounts known as Ryan White Savings Accounts.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
