<bill session="114" type="s" number="3060" updated="2018-06-02T07:46:27Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Health Care Relief Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide an exception from certain group health plan requirements for qualified small employer health reimbursement arrangements.</title>
    <title type="display">Small Business Health Care Relief Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2016-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2016-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000174" joined="2016-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2016-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2016-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001069" joined="2016-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2016-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2016-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2016-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2016-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2016-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2016-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2016-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2016-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2016-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2016-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000127" joined="2016-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2016-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3985" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5447"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Small Business Health Care Relief Act of 2016

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA), and other laws to exempt qualified small employer health reimbursement arrangements (HRAs) from certain requirements that apply to group health plans.

A qualified small employer HRA is offered by employers that have fewer than 50 full-time employees and do not offer group health plans to any of their employees. A qualified small employer HRA must:

 be provided on the same terms to all eligible employees of the employer; be funded solely by the employer without salary reduction contributions; provide, after an employee provides proof of coverage, for the payment or reimbursement of medical expenses of the employee and family members; and limit annual payments and reimbursements to specified dollar amounts. HRAs that meet these requirements are not considered group health plans and are exempt from various requirements that apply to group health plans, including coverage and cost-sharing requirements. (Under current law, employers that sponsor group health plans that do not meet specified requirements are subject to an excise tax.)

Coverage and payments under a qualified HRA are excluded from gross income, unless the employee does not have minimum essential coverage for the month in which the medical care was provided.

Employers offering a qualified HRA must notify employees in advance regarding permitted benefits and report benefit information on W-2 forms and to health exchanges.

The bill sets forth requirements for determining whether an employee covered under an HRA is also eligible for premium subsidies under PPACA.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
