<bill session="114" type="s" number="54" updated="2018-06-02T06:29:05Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Regulatory Fairness Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to confirm the scope of the authority of the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to deny or restrict the use of defined areas as disposal sites.</title>
    <title type="display">Regulatory Fairness Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000127"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="234"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="54"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Regulatory Fairness Act of 2015

This bill amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to define the period of time in which the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) is authorized to restrict or deny a permit for the discharge of dredged or fill materials into navigable waters as the period that:

 begins on the date that the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers publishes a notice for the discharge of dredged or fill material into navigable waters at specified disposal sites, and ends on the date that the Army Corps issues the permit. The EPA must make all the information and data that it reviewed in making a determination publicly available.

The EPA's authority to withdraw a specification of a defined area as a disposal site for the discharge of dredged or fill materials is eliminated.

Any previous action by the EPA that occurred outside of this period to deny or restrict a permit or to prohibit the specification of any defined area as a disposal site is nullified.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
