<bill session="114" type="h" number="2323" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:20Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States International Communications Reform Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance the missions, objectives, and effectiveness of United States international communications, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">United States International Communications Reform Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000487"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000266" joined="2015-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2015-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000610" joined="2015-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2015-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000179" joined="2015-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000375" joined="2015-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2015-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000594" joined="2015-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000592" joined="2015-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000409" joined="2015-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000435" joined="2015-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000018" joined="2015-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2015-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001165" joined="2015-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000522" joined="2015-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-05-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting Board of Governors"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Espionage and treason"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sound recording"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">United States International Communications Reform Act of 2015

Revises U.S. international broadcasting and communications structures, missions, and objectives.

Requires U.S. international broadcasting to incorporate specified standards.

Establishes the United States International Communications Agency (USICA), consisting of the Voice of America (VOA) and the offices of the International Broadcasting Bureau.

Directs USICA and the Freedom News Network (FNN) to ensure that U.S. international broadcasting is conducted only to countries and regions that: (1) lack democratic rule and domestic media that provides accurate news, and (2) would benefit U.S. national security.

Expresses the sense of Congress that VOA: (1) has been an indispensable element of U.S. foreign policy and public diplomacy efforts, and (2) would benefit from a recalibration of federal international broadcasting agencies and resources.

Requires VOA to adhere to specified principles and carry out specified duties and responsibilities.

Requires Radio Marti and Television Marti, which constitute the Office of Cuba Broadcasting, to: (1) continue programming and content production consistent with their mission under the Radio Broadcasting to Cuba Act and the Television Broadcasting to Cuba Act, and (2) continue to exist within VOA.

Requires USICA and FNN to consult with the Department of State, the U.S. Agency for International Development, the Department of Defense, and the Office of the Director of National Intelligence in order to assess international developments.

Repeals the United States International Broadcasting Act of 1994.

Expresses the sense of Congress that RFE/RL, Incorporated, Radio Free Asia, and the Middle East Broadcasting Networks, Incorporated share a common mission with distinct geographic foci, and should therefore be merged into a single organization with distinct marketing brands to provide news and related programming and content in countries where free media are not established.

Consolidates RFE/RL Incorporated, Radio Free Asia, and the Middle East Broadcasting Networks, Incorporated into FNN to carry out all international broadcasting activities supported by the U.S. government. Retains the brand names of the individual grantees.

Specifies FNN standards and principles, including consistency with broad U.S. foreign policy objectives.

Directs USICA and FNN to establish procedures to vet and monitor employees for affiliations to terrorist organizations, foreign governments to protect against espionage, sabotage, foreign propaganda messaging, and other subversive activities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
