<bill session="115" type="s" number="1417" updated="2019-06-13T20:52:53Z">
  <state datetime="2018-09-06">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-09-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Interior to develop a categorical exclusion for covered vegetative management activities carried out to establish or improve habitat for greater sage-grouse and mule deer, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Sage-Grouse and Mule Deer Habitat Conservation and Restoration Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Sage-Grouse and Mule Deer Habitat Conservation and Restoration Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sage-Grouse and Mule Deer Habitat Conservation and Restoration Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sage-Grouse and Mule Deer Habitat Conservation and Restoration Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Sage-Grouse and Mule Deer Habitat Conservation and Restoration Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2017-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-27">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 115-112.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-06">
      <text>Senate Committee on Environment and Public Works discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-06">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6102-6103" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2018-09-06" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-09-07">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-07T16:49:12-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="3543"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2068"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4012"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2017-06-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Sage-Grouse and Mule Deer Habitat Conservation and Restoration Act of 2017

This bill directs the Department of Interior to categorically exclude vegetative management activities that establish or improve habitat for greater sage-grouse and mule deer from environmental review requirements under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA). Examples of vegetative management activities include restoring native vegetation following a natural disturbance or preventing the expansion of nonnative or invasive vegetation into such habitat.

A categorical exclusion under NEPA is a category of actions which do not have a significant effect on the human environment and for which neither an Environmental Assessment nor an Environmental Impact Statement is required. The bill prohibits the categorical exclusion from including: (1) activity conducted in a wilderness area or wilderness study area, or (2) activity for the construction of a permanent road or trail.

Before commencing a vegetative management activity that is covered by a categorical exclusion, Interior must develop a long-term monitoring and maintenance plan, covering at least 20 years, to ensure that management of the treated area does not degrade the habitat gains secured by the vegetative management activity.

Vegetative material resulting from vegetative management activity may be: (1) used for fuel wood or other products; or (2) piled or burned, or both.

Native vegetative cover must be reestablished on a temporary road constructed in connection with a categorically excluded vegetative management activity in order to minimize soil erosion from areas disturbed by the temporary road.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
