<bill session="115" type="h" number="5682" updated="2019-04-18T16:23:04Z">
  <state datetime="2018-05-22T17:33:38-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-05-22T17:33:38-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for programs to help reduce the risk that prisoners will recidivate upon release from prison, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Formerly Incarcerated Reenter Society Transformed Safely Transitioning Every Person Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Lieutenant Osvaldo Albarati Correctional Officer Self-Protection Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">FIRST STEP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Formerly Incarcerated Reenter Society Transformed Safely Transitioning Every Person Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Formerly Incarcerated Reenter Society Transformed Safely Transitioning Every Person Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Lieutenant Osvaldo Albarati Correctional Officer Self-Protection Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Lieutenant Osvaldo Albarati Correctional Officer Self-Protection Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FIRST STEP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FIRST STEP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Formerly Incarcerated Reenter Society Transformed Safely Transitioning Every Person Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Formerly Incarcerated Reenter Society Transformed Safely Transitioning Every Person Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Lieutenant Osvaldo Albarati Correctional Officer Self-Protection Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Lieutenant Osvaldo Albarati Correctional Officer Self-Protection Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">FIRST STEP Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001093"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001270" joined="2018-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001294" joined="2018-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001049" joined="2018-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001107" joined="2018-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2018-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000571" joined="2018-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000289" joined="2018-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001078" joined="2018-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000294" joined="2018-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000126" joined="2018-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001179" joined="2018-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001159" joined="2018-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001137" joined="2018-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000598" joined="2018-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2018-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000244" joined="2018-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001199" joined="2018-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001201" joined="2018-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000819" joined="2018-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-05-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-05-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 25 - 5.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 115-699.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-05-22" calendar="Union" number="541">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 541.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T13:07:23-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Goodlatte moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T13:07:43-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4302-4319" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T13:07:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5682.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T13:46:48-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T17:27:15-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4366-4367" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="215" datetime="2018-05-22T17:33:38-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 360 - 59 (Roll no. 215).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4302-4310" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T17:33:39-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2795"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2471"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="613"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3649"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1084"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-05-22T08:27:06Z" status="Passed House amended">Formerly Incarcerated Reenter Society Transformed Safely Transitioning Every Person Act or the FIRST STEP Act

TITLE I--RECIDIVISM REDUCTION

(Sec. 101) This bill amends the federal criminal code to direct the Department of Justice to establish a risk and needs assessment system to assess and classify the recidivism risk of prisoners; to guide housing, grouping, and program assignments; and to incentivize and reward participation in and completion of recidivism reduction programs and productive activities.

(Sec. 102) The Bureau of Prisons (BOP) must implement the risk and needs assessment system.

The bill modifies the computation of good time credit to allow a prisoner to earn a maximum of 54 days per year of the sentence imposed (instead of 54 days per year of the sentence actually served).

(Sec. 103) The Government Accountability Office must audit the use of the risk and needs assessment system at BOP facilities.

(Sec. 104) The bill authorizes funds for FY2019-FY2023 to carry out this title. Of the amount appropriated, 80% is reserved for use by the BOP to implement the risk and needs assessment system.

(Sec. 105) The bill states that it does not authorize prerelease custody for an individual serving a prison term for a state offense.

(Sec. 106) It prohibits discrimination against a program, treatment, regimen, group, company, charity, person, or entity based on the fact that it may be or is faith-based.

TITLE II--BUREAU OF PRISONS SECURE FIREARMS STORAGE

Lieutenant Osvaldo Albarati Correctional Officer Self-Protection Act of 2018

(Sec. 202) The bill amends the federal criminal code to require the BOP to allow federal correctional officers to securely store and carry concealed firearms on BOP premises outside the security perimeter of a prison.

TITLE III--RESTRAINTS ON PREGNANT PRISONERS PROHIBITED

(Sec. 301) The bill amends the federal criminal code to prohibit, subject to specified conditions, the use of restraints on federal prisoners who are pregnant or in postpartum recovery.

TITLE IV--MISCELLANEOUS CRIMINAL JUSTICE

(Sec. 401) The bill amends the federal criminal code:

 to direct the BOP to place a prisoner in a facility that is not more than 500 driving miles away from the prisoner's primary residence, subject to bed availability and the prisoner's security designation; and to specify that the designation of a prison placement is not reviewable by a court. (Sec. 402) The BOP must place low-risk prisoners on home confinement for the maximum amount of time permitted.

(Sec. 403) The bill amends the Second Chance Act of 2007 to reauthorize through FY2022 and modify eligibility for an elderly offender early release pilot program.

(Sec. 404) The BOP must, as part of prerelease planning procedures, help a prisoner obtain identification, including a Social Security card, driver's license or other official photo identification, and a birth certificate.

(Sec. 405) The bill authorizes Federal Prison Industries to sell products to new markets such as the District of Columbia government and nonprofit organizations.

(Sec. 406) The BOP must incorporate specialized and comprehensive de-escalation procedures into its training programs.

(Sec. 407) The BOP must report on its capacity to treat heroin and opioid abuse through evidence-based programs, including medication-assisted treatment.

The Administrative Office of the U.S. Courts must report on the capacity of treatment-service providers to provide medication-assisted treatment for opioid and heroin abuse to prisoners serving a term of supervised release, including plans to expand access.

(Sec. 408) The BOP must establish pilot programs: (1) on youth mentorship; and (2) on service to abandoned, rescued, or vulnerable animals.

(Sec. 409) Probation and pretrial services officers must perform court-directed supervision of sex offenders conditionally released from civil commitment.

(Sec. 410) The bill expands data collection requirements regarding the National Prisoner Statistics Program.

(Sec. 411) The BOP must make tampons and sanitary napkins available free of charge.

(Sec. 412) This bill amends the Prison Rape Elimination Act of 2003 to require auditors who monitor compliance with national prison rape standards to be certified.

(Sec. 413) The bill amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to require at least 8% of funds for the Justice and Mental Health Collaboration Program to be used to provide technical assistance.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-699</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
