<bill session="113" type="s" number="407" updated="2016-10-25T16:21:14Z">
  <state datetime="2013-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reinvesting In Vital Economic Rivers and Waterways Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RIVER Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide funding for construction and major rehabilitation for projects located on inland and intracoastal waterways of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Reinvesting In Vital Economic Rivers and Waterways Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000360" joined="2013-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000206" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000550" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2013-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1149"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Army Corps of Engineers"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-02-28T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reinvesting In Vital Economic Rivers and Waterways Act of 2013 or RIVER Act - Directs the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, to promulgate regulations that, at a minimum, require certain delivery process criteria for qualifying construction and major rehabilitation projects for navigation infrastructure of inland and intracoastal waterways.

Directs the Secretary, in conjunction with the Inland Waterways Users Board, to submit to Congress a 20-year program for making capital investments on inland and intracoastal waterways. Allows such program to be based on the 20-year capital investment strategy contained in the Inland Marine Transportation System Capital Projects Business Model, Final Report published on April 13, 2010, as approved by the Board.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to limit expenditures from the Inland Waterways Trust Fund to 50% of the total cost of the construction or rehabilitation project. Makes Fund amounts unavailable for: (1) construction or rehabilitation of dams, or (2) rehabilitation expenditures that do not equal or exceed $50 million.

Increases the Inland Waterways Trust Fund financing rate (user fee) from 20 cents to 29 cents after 2013.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
