<bill session="114" type="h" number="2804" updated="2019-05-09T23:32:57Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish an integrated national approach to respond to ongoing and expected effects of extreme weather and climate change by protecting, managing, and conserving the fish, wildlife, and plants of the United States, and to maximize Government efficiency and reduce costs, in cooperation with State, local, and tribal governments and other entities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safeguarding America's Future and Environment Act</title>
    <title type="display">SAFE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001292" joined="2016-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2015-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2015-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2016-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2015-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2015-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000375" joined="2016-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000559" joined="2015-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2015-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2016-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2015-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001166" joined="2016-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2015-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2016-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2015-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2015-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2015-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2015-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000480" joined="2016-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2016-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000465" joined="2015-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000131" joined="2015-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000799" joined="2015-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water, Oceans, and Wildlife" code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indigenous Peoples of the United States" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1601"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Scientific communication"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Safeguarding America's Future and Environment Act or the SAFE Act 

This bill requires the President to establish an interagency National Fish, Wildlife, and Plants Climate Adaptation Strategy Joint Implementation Working Group to adopt the National Fish, Wildlife, and Plants Climate Adaptation Strategy (released March 26, 2013) to protect, manage, and conserve fish, wildlife, and plants to maintain the inherent resilience and adaptability of fish, wildlife, and plants to withstand the ongoing and expected effects of extreme weather and climate change.

Each federal agency must integrate the elements of the strategy that relate to conservation, management, and protection of fish, wildlife, and plants into agency plans, environmental reviews, and programs.

The Department of the Interior must establish a National Climate Change and Wildlife Science Center to assess and develop scientific information, tools, strategies, and techniques to support the Working Groups and other interested parties in addressing the effects of extreme weather and climate change on fish, wildlife, and plants.

Interior must establish an Advisory Committee on Climate Change and Natural Resource Sciences to advise the working group on the state of the science regarding the effects of extreme weather and climate change on fish, wildlife, and plants and strategies and mechanisms for fish, wildlife, and plants adaptation.

To be eligible to receive funding under the bill, the states (including the District of Columbia, Samoa, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, Puerto Rico and the Virgin Islands) must submit to Interior and the Department of Commerce for review and approval a state fish, wildlife, and plant adaptation plan that details efforts to address the effects of climate change on fish, wildlife, and plants and coastal areas.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
