<bill session="115" type="h" number="4976" updated="2019-04-18T16:20:14Z">
  <state datetime="2018-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a grant program to support landscape-scale restoration and management, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Empowering State Forestry to Improve Forest Health Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Empowering State Forestry to Improve Forest Health Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Empowering State Forestry to Improve Forest Health Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000800"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000467" joined="2018-02-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Conservation and Forestry" code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="962"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-02-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Empowering State Forestry to Improve Forest Health Act of 2018

This bill amends the Cooperative Forestry Assistance Act of 1978 to direct the Forest Service to establish a landscape-scale restoration program to provide financial and technical assistance for landscape-scale restoration projects on state and private forest lands that maintain or improve benefits from trees and forests on such lands.

The program shall:

 address the national private forest conservation priorities specified under the Act; and enhance public benefits from trees and forests, as identified in a state-wide assessment and a long-term state-wide forest resource strategy under the Act. The program shall also have one or more objectives, including to:

 protect or improve water quality or quantity; reduce wildfire risk, including through hazardous fuels treatment; protect or enhance wildlife habitat; improve forest health and forest ecosystems, including addressing native, nonnative, and invasive pests; or enhance opportunities for new and existing markets in which the production and use of wood products strengthens local and regional economies. The Forest Service shall allocate from the amounts made available under this bill:

 50% for the competitive process for distributing funds for landscape-scale restoration projects; and 50% proportionally to states to maximize the achievement of the restoration program's objectives and to address the highest national priorities, as identified in state-wide assessments and long-term state-wide forest resource strategies. The bill amends the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 to allocate funds and use specified authorities of the Department of Agriculture or of the Department of the Interior, as appropriate, to assist cross-boundary hazardous fuel reduction and wildfire mitigation projects.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
