<bill session="113" type="h" number="4575" updated="2016-10-25T16:12:53Z">
  <state datetime="2014-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to acquire land to operate a visitor center for Joshua Tree National Park, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to acquire land to operate a visitor center for Joshua Tree National Park, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001094"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-05-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends the California Desert Protection Act of 1994 to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to acquire up to five acres of land and interests in land, and improvements on it, outside the boundaries of Joshua Tree National Park in California, in the unincorporated village of Joshua Tree, California, for the purpose of operating a visitor center.

Instructs the Secretary to modify the boundary of the Park to include the acquired land as a noncontiguous parcel.

Allows the lands and facilities acquired under this Act to: (1) include the property currently owned by the Joshua Tree National Park Association and commonly referred to as the "Joshua Tree National Park Visitor Center"; (2) be administered as part of the Park; and (3) be acquired only with the owner's consent by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, or by exchange.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
