<bill session="114" type="h" number="3766" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:26Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-15">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the President to establish guidelines for United States foreign development and economic assistance programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by senate">A bill to direct the President to establish guidelines for covered United States foreign assistance programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000592"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2015-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001284" joined="2015-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2015-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000266" joined="2015-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2015-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2015-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001045" joined="2015-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000625" joined="2015-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001051" joined="2015-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001057" joined="2015-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000294" joined="2015-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2015-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001187" joined="2015-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000170" joined="2015-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000605" joined="2015-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000587" joined="2015-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000487" joined="2015-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2015-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001165" joined="2015-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000510" joined="2015-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000475" joined="2015-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2015-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000065" joined="2015-11-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-11-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-12-08T17:33:05-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Poe (TX) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-08T17:33:17-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9063-9067" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-08T17:33:19-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3766.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2015-12-08T17:58:34-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9063-9065" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-12-08T17:58:37-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-12-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="318">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 318.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-06-28">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4680" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2016-06-28" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-06-29">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-05T21:32:04-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Royce moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4267-4270" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-05T21:32:32-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the motion to suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments to H.R. 3766.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="pingpong" datetime="2016-07-05T21:42:13-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4267-4269" label="text as House agree to the Senate amendments"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-07-05T21:42:14-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2016-07-08">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2016-07-15" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="114-191" type="public" datetime="2016-07-15">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 114-191.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2184"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4928"/>
    <amendment number="s4927"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2016-07-16T03:59:58Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on July 5, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2016

(Sec. 2) This bill defines "covered U.S. foreign assistance" as assistance authorized under:

 part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (development assistance), except for title IV of chapter 2 (relating to the Overseas Private Investment Corporation), and chapter 3 (relating to International Organizations and Programs); chapter 4 of part II of such Act (Economic Support Fund); the Millennium Challenge Act of 2003; and the Food for Peace Act. (Sec. 3) The President shall within 18 months prescribe guidelines for establishment of goals, performance metrics, and monitoring and evaluation plans for covered U.S. foreign assistance.

 The guidelines shall direct federal departments and agencies that administer such assistance on how to:

 establish annual monitoring and evaluation agendas and objectives; develop specific project monitoring and evaluation plans; apply monitoring and evaluation methodologies to covered U.S. foreign assistance programs; disseminate guidelines for the development and implementation of monitoring and evaluation programs to all personnel responsible for program design, implementation, and management of covered U.S. foreign assistance programs; establish data collection methodologies; evaluate, at least once in their lifetime, all programs whose dollar value equals or exceeds the median program size for the relevant office or bureau; develop a clearinghouse capacity for the collection and dissemination of knowledge and lessons learned that serve as benchmarks for future programs; distribute evaluation reports internally; publicly report evaluations and related recommendations; undertake collaborative partnerships and coordinate efforts with academic, national and international institutions; make verifiable and timely data available to monitoring and evaluation personnel; and ensure that standards of professional evaluation organizations for monitoring and evaluation efforts are employed. The President shall within 18 months give Congress a detailed description of these guidelines.

 The Government Accountability Office shall analyze the guidelines and assess their implementation by the appropriate agencies, bureaus, and offices.

(Sec. 4) The Department of State shall within 90 days update its Internet website, ForeignAssistance.gov, to make publicly available comprehensive and accessible information on covered U.S. foreign assistance programs.

The head of each federal department or agency that administers such assistance shall give the State Department comprehensive program information each quarter.

Assistance program information shall be published: (1) on an award-by-award and country-by-country basis, or (2) on an award-by-award and region-by-region basis if provided on a regional level.

Such information shall include: (1) links to all regional, country, and sector assistance strategies, annual budget documents, congressional budget justifications, and evaluations; (2) basic descriptive summaries for foreign development and economic assistance programs and awards under such programs; and (3) obligations and expenditures.

If a federal department or agency determines that the inclusion of a required item of information online would jeopardize the health or security of an implementing partner or program beneficiary, or would require the release of proprietary information, it shall give Congress that determination in writing.

If the State Department determines that online inclusion of a required item of information would be detrimental to U.S. national interests, it shall also give Congress that determination in writing.

The bill expresses the sense of Congress that the State Department and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) should, by the end of FY2018, coordinate data collection consolidation for the State Department's website, ForeignAssistance.gov, and USAID's website, Explorer.USAID.gov.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
