<bill session="114" type="h" number="4061" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:23Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Food Labeling Modernization Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to strengthen requirements related to nutrient information on food labels, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Food Labeling Modernization Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000216" joined="2015-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000559" joined="2016-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2016-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2016-02-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="2301"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Allergies"/>
    <term name="Chemistry"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Grain"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-18T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Food Labeling Modernization Act of 2015

This bill amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (FFDCA) to require the front of food packages to bear a nutrition label that complies with Food and Drug Administration (FDA) regulations. The bill specifies principles for such regulations, including that there should be a standard, easily understood symbol system for calorie and nutrient information.

Only under specified conditions may the front of a food package include: (1) descriptions of whole grain content, (2) the term "wheat" or "whole wheat," or (3) a reference to a characterizing ingredient.

If a food contains added coloring, non-caloric sweetener, or flavoring, that fact must be stated on the front of the package.

The FDA must regulate food labels that make claims about the mechanism by which a nutrient affects the body. Food manufacturers must substantiate health claims on a label upon request from the FDA. Labeling regarding trans fat and cholesterol is restricted. The FDA must establish a level of added sugars above which a food is disqualified from making health claims on the label.

Regarding food labels, the FDA must: (1) regulate use of "natural," (2) prohibit use of "healthy" on certain foods, and (3) establish formatting requirements for ingredient lists.

Food labels must include the percent of recommended daily calories and daily added sugars per serving. Labels must disclose the amount of added sugars in teaspoons and grams.

Foods containing caffeine must be labeled with the amount.

Sesame is added to the list of major food allergens.

The names of major food allergens in nonpackaged food offered for sale at retail must be on a sign adjacent to the food.

Food manufacturers and importers must submit to the FDA for publication the information to be included on a food's label and keep this information updated.

"Artificial" and "synthetic" are defined for purposes of the FFDCA.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
