<bill session="114" type="h" number="6437" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:37Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-12-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reclamation of War Powers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit funds available for the United States Armed Forces to be obligated or expended for introduction of the Armed Forces into hostilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Reclamation of War Powers Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001047"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-12-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, and Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, and Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, and Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Reclamation of War Powers Act

This bill prohibits funds made available for the U.S. Armed Forces from being obligated or expended for the introduction of the Armed Forces into hostilities, or into situations where imminent involvement in hostilities is clearly indicated by the circumstances, in the absence of: (1) a declaration of war; (2) specific statutory authorization; or (3) a national emergency created by an attack or imminent threat of attack upon the United States, its territories or possessions, or the Armed Forces.

Funds may be obligated or expended for the introduction of Armed Forces into hostilities, or into situations where involvement in hostilities is imminent, by reason of a national emergency for only 60 days.

It shall not be in order in the House of Representatives or the Senate to consider any legislation that would make funds available in violation of such provisions.

The President shall, in the case of a declaration of war or specific authorization for such use of the Armed Forces, report to Congress every 90 days on:

 an analysis of the threat; the specific objectives to be achieved and justification for such objectives; and a description of the scope and duration, cost, and likelihood of success of such use of the Armed Forces. The President shall submit such a report in the case of an introduction of the Armed Forces by reason of a national emergency within 48 hours of, and again not later than 60 days after, such introduction.

The War Powers Resolution and specified other prior authorizations for the use of the Armed Forces are repealed.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
