<amendment session="114" chamber="s" number="4787" updated="2019-02-17T14:41:27Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2578" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2016-06-20">offered</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000303"/>
  <offered datetime="2016-06-20"/>
  <description>To amend section 2709 of title 18, United States Code, to clarify that the Government may obtain a specified set of electronic communication transactional records under that section, and to make permanent the authority for individual terrorists to be treated as agents of foreign powers under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978.</description>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-23">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4521" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-22">
      <text>Motion by Senator McConnell to reconsider the vote by which cloture on amendment SA 4787 was not invoked (Record Vote No. 108) entered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4437" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-22">
      <text>Cloture on amendment SA 4787 not invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 58 - 38. Record Vote Number: 108.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4437" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4437" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-22">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4433, S4437" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-21">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4383, S4386-4391, S4393-4396" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-20">
      <text>Cloture motion on amendment SA 4787 presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4353" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4353" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-20">
      <text>Amendment SA 4787 proposed by Senator McConnell for Senator McCain to Amendment SA 4685. (consideration: CR S4353; text: CR S4353) To amend section 2709 of title 18, United States Code, to clarify that the Government may obtain a specified set of electronic communication transactional records under that section, and to make permanent the authority for individual terrorists to be treated as agents of foreign powers under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-20"/>
    <action datetime="2016-06-22">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Cloture on amendment SA 4787 not invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 58 - 38. Record Vote Number: 108.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4437" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4437" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-20">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 4787 proposed by Senator McConnell for Senator McCain to Amendment SA 4685.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4353" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4353" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-20">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
