<bill session="114" type="s" number="2859" updated="2018-06-02T07:18:17Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">College Access Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a competitive grant program to incentivize States to implement comprehensive reforms and innovative strategies to significantly improve postsecondary outcomes for low-income and first generation college students, including increasing postsecondary enrollment and graduation rates, to reduce the need of postsecondary students for remedial education, to increase alignment of high school and postsecondary education, and to promote innovation in postsecondary education, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">College Access Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000457"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Adult education and literacy"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">College Access Act of 2016

This bill establishes a competitive grant program for states to develop or implement comprehensive plans to improve post-secondary outcomes for students.&#160;

A state's plan&#160;must include reforms to: (1) implement measures to maintain or increase fiscal support for post-secondary education; (2) increase the transparency of, and access to, information about the costs and outcomes of attaining post-secondary credentials at the state's institutions; and (3) improve post-secondary education remediation, remove barriers to innovation in postsecondary education, or improve the transition of students to and from post-secondary institutions.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
