<bill session="115" type="h" number="5125" updated="2019-05-08T13:34:54Z">
  <state datetime="2018-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve and expand authorities, programs, services, and benefits for military spouses and military families, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Spouse Employment Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Spouse Employment Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Military Spouse Employment Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001200"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2018-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2018-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2018-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3319"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="2379"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-02-27T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Military Spouse Employment Act of 2018

This bill expands authorities, programs, services, and benefits for military spouses and their families. Specifically, the bill:

 expands the authority for noncompetitive appointments of military spouses by federal agencies to include spouses of active duty military personnel or disabled or deceased personnel, requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to ensure that military spouses are aware of the My Career Advancement Account program and their eligibility to participate in it, facilitates child care services for military families, expands the period of availability of the Military OneSource Program for retired and discharged members of the Armed Forces and their immediate families, and provides transition assistance for military spouses. DOD must report to Congress on:

 methods to increase its participation in defense contracts that provide employment for military spouses; public-private partnerships to support and enhance the health, safety, welfare, and morale of military families; small businesses activities of military spouses on military installations; and an assessment of the effects of frequent changes of duty stations on employment stability of military spouses.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
