<bill session="115" type="s" number="1852" updated="2019-04-18T16:39:12Z">
  <state datetime="2017-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the cancellation of removal and adjustment of status of certain aliens who are long-term United States residents and who entered the United States as children, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Solution for Undocumented Children through Careers, Employment, Education, and Defending our Nation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Solution for Undocumented Children through Careers, Employment, Education, and Defending our Nation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SUCCEED Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SUCCEED Act</title>
    <title type="display">SUCCEED Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000476"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2017-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2017-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-09-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1468"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-09-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Solution for Undocumented Children through Careers, Employment, Education, and Defending our Nation Act or the SUCCEED Act

This bill authorizes the Department of Homeland Security to cancel the removal of otherwise inadmissible or deportable aliens who entered the United States as children and grant them conditional permanent resident status. The conditional permanent resident status of such aliens shall be valid for an initial period of five years if they came to the United States before the age of 16 and have lived in the United States continuously since June 15, 2012. Such aliens must demonstrate that they were younger than age 31 on June 15, 2012, and had no lawful status in the United States.

The bill imposes other requirements upon such aliens, including educational attainments, good moral character, lack of criminal history, and compliance with tax responsibilities. The bill extends conditional permanent resident status for an additional five years if an alien continues to show good moral character, has no tax liabilities, is not receiving federal benefits, has graduated from college or attended a postsecondary school, or has served in the military.

The bill permits alien children to apply for the removal of conditional status after 10 years and adjust to lawful permanent residence upon a showing that they have been a conditional permanent resident for at least 10 years, have demonstrated good moral character during that period, have met other age and residency requirement, and have not abandoned residence in the United States. An alien may apply for naturalization five years after adjustment of status to lawful permanent residence under the terms of this bill.

Aliens who violate the requirements of this bill or commit certain crimes are subject to expedited removal without an immigration court hearing.

Aliens with conditional or lawful permanent resident status under this bill may not sponsor family members, including spouses and children, to obtain legal status in the United States.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
