<bill session="114" type="h" number="161" updated="2019-04-11T15:41:45Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-21T15:44:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-01-21T15:44:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the timely consideration of all licenses, permits, and approvals required under Federal law with respect to the siting, construction, expansion, or operation of any natural gas pipeline projects.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Natural Gas Pipeline Permitting Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Natural Gas Pipeline Permitting Reform Act</title>
    <title type="display">Natural Gas Pipeline Permitting Reform Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000602"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001255" joined="2015-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001289" joined="2015-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001051" joined="2015-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001092" joined="2015-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2015-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000614" joined="2015-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2015-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000460" joined="2015-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000459" joined="2015-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2015-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001051" joined="2015-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000292" joined="2015-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000296" joined="2015-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000376" joined="2015-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000363" joined="2015-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2015-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2015-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000566" joined="2015-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000576" joined="2015-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001179" joined="2015-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001180" joined="2015-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001190" joined="2015-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001151" joined="2015-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000168" joined="2015-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000606" joined="2015-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000611" joined="2015-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000585" joined="2015-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000018" joined="2015-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2015-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001192" joined="2015-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000816" joined="2015-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000017" joined="2015-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000018" joined="2015-01-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-20T16:29:39-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 38 Reported to House. The rule provides for one hour of debate on each measure. The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the bills. The resolution provides that the bills shall be considered as read. The resolution waives all points of order against provisions in the bills. The resolution provides one motion to recommit per bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-21T14:16:12-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 38.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H453-460" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-21T14:16:17-05:00">
      <text>The rule provides for one hour of debate each on H.R. 161 and H.R. 36. The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the bills. The resolution provides that the bills shall be considered as read. The resolution waives all points of order against provisions in the bills. The resolution provides one motion to recommit per bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-21T14:16:35-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provsions of H. Res. 38, the House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 161.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-21T14:54:21-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H458" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-21T14:55:03-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Pallone moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H458-459" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H458" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-21T14:55:25-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Pallone motion to recommit with instructions, pending reservation of a point of order. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment ensuring that the provisions in the bill do not take effect unless the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) determines that: (1) taxpayers will not be held liable for any repair or environmental cleanup from a natural gas pipeline explosion and (2) pipeline owners will bear full responsibility for damages in any community resulting from a natural gas pipeline explosion, including loss of life. Subsequently, the reservation of a point of order was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-21T15:04:53-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H459" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-21T15:33:29-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 182 - 241 (Roll no. 40).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="41" datetime="2015-01-21T15:44:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 253 - 169 (Roll no. 41).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H453" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-01-21T15:44:02-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy" code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="114" relation="unknown" number="38"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-21T14:07:20Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Natural Gas Pipeline Permitting Reform Act

 Amends the Natural Gas Act to direct the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to approve or deny a certificate of public convenience and necessity for a prefiled project within 12 months after receiving a complete application that is ready to be processed.

 Defines "prefiled project" as a project for the siting, construction, expansion, or operation of a natural gas pipeline with respect to which a prefiling docket number has been assigned by FERC pursuant to a prefiling process established by FERC for the purpose of facilitating the formal application process for obtaining a certificate of public convenience and necessity.

Requires the agency responsible for issuing any federal license, permit, or approval regarding the siting, construction, expansion, or operation of a project for which a certificate is sought to approve or deny issuance of the certificate within 90 days after FERC issues its final environmental document regarding the project.

Requires FERC to grant an agency request for a 30-day extension of the 90-day time period if the agency demonstrates that it cannot otherwise complete the process required to approve or deny the license, permit, or approval, and therefore will be compelled to deny it.

Authorizes FERC, in granting such an extension, to offer technical assistance to the agency in order to address conditions preventing completion of the application review.

Declares that, if the agency fails to approve or deny issuance of a permit, license, or approval within the prescribed time-frame, the license, permit, or approval shall take effect upon expiration of 30 days after the period's end.

 Directs FERC to incorporate into the terms of a license, permit, or approval any conditions proffered by the agency that FERC does not find to be inconsistent with the final environmental document.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
