<bill session="114" type="s" number="1199" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:53Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize Federal agencies to provide alternative fuel to Federal employees on a reimbursable basis, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to authorize Federal agencies to provide alternative fuel to Federal employees on a reimbursable basis, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001111"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2015-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-19">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill allows federal agencies to: (1) construct, operate, and maintain alternative fuel infrastructure on their property; and (2) provide alternative fuel on a reimbursable basis on their property for use by privately-owned vehicles used by federal employees, members of a uniformed service, contractors, or a visitor to a federal agency or facility (covered individuals).

Agencies: (1) cannot provide compensation, benefits, or any other payment to covered individuals for purchasing alternative fuel; and (2) must charge fees for alternative fuel provided that are sufficient to cover the costs of only the alternative fuel.

After collected fees or commissions are put into the appropriate account in the Treasury, they will be available to the agency that collected them during the fiscal year the fees or commissions were collected and the following fiscal year.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
