<bill session="115" type="sr" number="302" updated="2019-04-18T16:29:54Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-24">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-10-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution authorizing limited still photography of the Senate Wing of the United States Capitol and authorizing the release of preexisting photographs of the Senate Chamber and Senate Wing of the United States Capitol for a book on the history of the Senate.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution authorizing limited still photography of the Senate Wing of the United States Capitol and authorizing the release of preexisting photographs of the Senate Chamber and Senate Wing of the United States Capitol for a book on the history of the Senate.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000355"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2017-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2017-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000320" joined="2017-10-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-10-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2017-10-24" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6774" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6770-6771" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Art, artists, authorship"/>
    <term name="Books and print media"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Photography and imaging"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="U.S. Capitol"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-10-24T13:51:14Z" status="Passed Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

(Sec. 1) Suspends specified provisions of Rule IV of the Rules for the Regulation of the Senate Wing of the U.S. Capitol and Senate Office Buildings (prohibiting the taking of pictures in the Senate Chamber) to release a limited number of preexisting photographs of the Senate Chamber and to permit taking a limited number of pictures in such wing and office buildings until January 31, 2018.

Authorizes the Majority and the Minority Leaders of the Senate and the Chairman and Ranking Member of the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration to enter into a memorandum of understanding with an individual or entity seeking to take such photographs and make use of preexisting photographs for a book on the history of the Senate to formalize an agreement on conditions, locations, and times for taking photographs and the use of the photographs taken.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
