<bill session="114" type="h" number="2231" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:23Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Housing Tenant Protection and Reinvestment Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Choice Neighborhoods Initiative Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Public Housing One-for-One Replacement and Tenant Protection Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Public Housing Preservation and Rehabilitation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Together We Care Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To transform neighborhoods of extreme poverty by reforming the public housing demolition and disposition rules to require one-for-one replacement and tenant protections, and to provide public housing agencies with additional resources and flexibility to preserve public housing units, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Public Housing Tenant Protection and Reinvestment Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000187"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001281" joined="2015-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2015-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001064" joined="2015-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000562" joined="2015-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000130" joined="2015-10-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3467"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3537"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Allied health services"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-01T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Public Housing Tenant Protection and Reinvestment Act of 2015

Public Housing One-for-One Replacement and Tenant Protection Act of 2015

 Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 with respect to: (1) demolition, disposition, or both pursuant to conversion of any public housing unit; and (2) the taking of public housing units through the use of eminent domain.

Exempts from specified requirements for demolition and disposition of public housing any public housing projects removed from a public housing agency (PHA) inventory under the program for conversion of demolished or distressed public housing dwelling units to tenant-based assistance.

Excludes real property containing dwelling units in public housing from federal regulations of the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) or any substantially similar regulations, with respect to:

 certain real estate; and implementing HUD requirements for demolition or disposition of public housing projects, and conversion of public housing to tenant-based assistance. Public Housing Preservation and Rehabilitation Act of 2015

Reauthorizes for FY2016-FY2025 the public housing Capital and Operating Funds.

Authorizes HUD to guarantee notes or other obligations issued by PHAs to finance: (1) the rehabilitation of PHA public housing; (2) the modernization of such housing through energy efficiency improvements; or (3) the construction, rehabilitation, purchase, or conversion of public housing units to replace any demolished, disposed of, or converted.

Prescribes requirements for PHAs that utilize housing tax credits under the Internal Revenue Code for rental housing units.

Removes a specified limitation on the use of amounts from the Capital Fund or Operation Fund by a PHA to construct new public housing units.

Choice Neighborhoods Initiative Act of 2015

 Requires HUD to make competitive grants to local governments, PHAs, or nonprofit entities owning a major housing project to implement transformational programs in eligible neighborhoods with a concentration of extreme poverty and severely distressed housing.

Together We Care Act of 2015

 Requires HUD to establish a competitive grant pilot program for eligible entities to train public housing residents as home health aides and as providers of home-based health services for residents of public housing or federally-assisted rental housing who are elderly, disabled, or both.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
