<bill session="114" type="h" number="2463" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:42Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Dispose Responsibly of your Pills Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DROP Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Attorney General to provide grants for drug disposal sites.</title>
    <title type="display">DROP Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001287"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001273" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000613" joined="2015-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2015-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000451" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000263" joined="2015-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2015-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000582" joined="2015-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001187" joined="2015-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="953"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="524"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Dispose Responsibly of your Pills Act of 2015 or the DROP Act of 2015

Authorizes the Attorney General, in coordination with the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA), the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the Director of the Office of National Drug Control Policy, to make grants to eligible entities to expand or make available disposal sites for unwanted prescription medications.

Defines "eligible entity" to include:

 a state, local, or tribal law enforcement agency; a manufacturer, distributor, or reverse distributor of prescription medications; a retail pharmacy; a registered narcotic treatment program; a hospital or clinic with an on-site pharmacy; and an eligible long-term care facility. Requires a recipient to use a grant for:

 expenses of a prescription drug disposal site; implementing disposal procedures and processes and community education strategies; replicating a prescription drug take back initiative throughout multiple jurisdictions; and training of law enforcement officers and other community participants. Limits grants to not more than $250,000 for not longer than two years.

Directs the Attorney General to make a grant: (1) to provide technical assistance and training for a grant recipient, and (2) for evaluation of each recipient's performance. Requires recipients to report each fiscal year on: (1) the effectiveness of their prescription drug take back programs, and (2) the effect of disposal efforts on drug circulation.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
