<bill session="114" type="s" number="2257" updated="2018-08-16T22:54:00Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Park Service Centennial Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">National Park Foundation Endowment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prepare the National Park Service for its Centennial in 2016 and for a second century of protecting our national parks' natural, historic, and cultural resources for present and future generations and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">National Park Service Centennial Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000127"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7820-7822" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-08">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 114-492.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3556"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Art, artists, authorship"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Park Service Centennial Act

This bill establishes the National Park Centennial Challenge Fund in the Treasury to finance signature projects and programs to enhance the National Park System (NPS) as it approaches its centennial in 2016.

 There is also established in the Treasury a Public Lands Centennial Fund.

The Department of the Interior and the Department of Agriculture shall jointly establish a program under which funds from the Centennial Fund are made available to federal land or water management agencies to support projects that:

 enhance visitor services and outdoor recreational opportunities, restore lands and waters, repair facilities or trails, or increase energy and water efficiency. National Park Foundation Endowment Act

The National Park Foundation shall establish the Second Century Endowment for the National Park Service.

The National Park Service Second Century Fund is established in the Treasury.

Interior shall undertake a broad program of the highest quality interpretation and education.

This bill makes permanent the Volunteers in the Parks Program.

Interior may establish a Visitor Services Management Authority (VSMA) to administer commercial visitor services programs and activities of the NPS, including the award and administration of commercial visitor facilities and services management contracts pursuant to this Act.

A VSMA revolving fund is established for expenses necessary for the management, improvement, enhancement, operation, construction, and maintenance of commercial visitor services and facilities and payment of possessory interest and leasehold surrender interest.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
