<bill session="115" type="h" number="7183" updated="2019-04-18T16:28:31Z">
  <state datetime="2018-11-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-11-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-11-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To develop a report regarding possible duplication of Federal damage assessments, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Disaster Assistance Coordination Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Disaster Assistance Coordination Act</title>
    <title type="display">Federal Disaster Assistance Coordination Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001187"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-11-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-11-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-11-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-11-28T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Disaster Assistance Coordination Act

This bill directs the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to convene a working group on a regular basis with the Department of Labor, the Office of Management and Budget, the Department of Health and Human Service, the Small Business Administration, the Department of Transportation, the Department of Commerce, and other appropriate agencies to:

 develop a report that identifies and describes the potential areas of duplication or fragmentation in post-disaster declarations in federal assessments of data collection methods and data collected and program delivery after post-disaster declarations; determine the applicability of having one federal agency make the assessments for all agencies; identify potential emerging technologies, such as Unmanned Aircraft Systems, to expedite the administration of disaster assistance assessments; and develop and submit to Congress a report on the working group's findings that may include recommendations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
