<bill session="113" type="h" number="5836" updated="2016-10-25T16:17:45Z">
  <state datetime="2014-12-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-12-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rare Cats and Canids Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To assist in the conservation of rare felids and rare canids by supporting and providing financial resources for the conservation programs of nations within the range of rare felid and rare canid populations and projects of persons with demonstrated expertise in the conservation of rare felid and rare canid populations.</title>
    <title type="display">Rare Cats and Canids Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000551"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2014-12-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" code="HSII22" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-12-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Rare Cats and Canids Act of 2014

This bill establishes a Rare Cats and Canids Conservation Fund as a separate account within the Multinational Species Conservation Fund. The Department of the Interior must use amounts in the fund to provide assistance for the conservation of rare felids and rare canids. Grant amounts may not be used for captive breeding unless it is a part of an accredited reintroduction or restoration program.

Rare felids or rare canids are any population in the family Felidae (cats) or Canidae (dogs), respectively, that are listed in the Red List of Threatened Species Maintained by the World Conservation Union as near-threatened, vulnerable, endangered, or critically endangered, excluding any population native to the United States or Canada. Tigers are not considered to be rare felids.

 Interior may convene an advisory group of individuals representing organizations actively involved in the conservation of felids and canids.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
