<bill session="114" type="h" number="4671" updated="2018-11-21T20:56:54Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Protection Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to eliminate Federal Prison Industries advantages over the private sector and small business in the procurement of commercially available goods and services.</title>
    <title type="display">Small Business Protection Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001058"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2016-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2016-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000606" joined="2016-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000611" joined="2016-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Federal Prison Industries, Inc."/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-02T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Small Business Protection Act of 2016

This bill amends the federal criminal code to repeal the requirement that federal departments and agencies purchase prison-made products.

Federal Prison Industries shall be ineligible to produce any product under a contract awarded for the sale of government property to a small business concern under the Small Business Act.

No executive agency head may enter into any contract with Federal Prison Industries under which an inmate worker would have access to classified data, personal or financial information about any individual private citizen without the individual's consent, or geographic data regarding the location of:

 surface and subsurface infrastructure providing communications or water or electrical power distribution; pipelines for the distribution of natural gas, bulk petroleum products, or other commodities; or other utilities. The Attorney General shall report to Congress on the extent of re-entry employment preparation provided to inmates by participation in Federal Prison Industries.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
