<amendment session="114" chamber="h" number="65" updated="2019-01-09T21:07:54Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2015-07-08T18:09:08-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000193"/>
  <offered datetime="2015-02-27"/>
  <description>Amendment sought to require that the Student Success Act shall not go into effect until the Secretary of Education determines that its enactment will not reduce the college and career readiness of racial or ethnic minority students, students with disabilities, English learners, and low-income students and provides written notification to Congress on such determination.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 43 printed in Part B of House Report 114-29 to require that the Student Success Act shall not go into effect until the Secretary of Education determines that its enactment will not reduce the college and career readiness of racial or ethnic minority students, students with disabilities, English learners, and low-income students and provides written notification to Congress on such determination.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2015-07-08T18:09:08-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="418">
      <text>On agreeing to the Thompson (MS) amendment (A042) Failed by recorded vote: 189 - 241 (Roll no. 418).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4930" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-02-27T12:09:26-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A042) offered by Mr. Thompson (MS).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1393-1394" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1393" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-27"/>
    <action datetime="2015-07-08T18:09:08-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-08T18:09:08-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-08T18:09:08-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Thompson (MS) amendment (A042) Failed by recorded vote: 189 - 241 (Roll no. 418).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4930" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-27T12:09:26-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A042) offered by Mr. Thompson (MS).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1393-1394" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1393" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-27">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
