<bill session="113" type="h" number="4662" updated="2016-10-25T16:13:19Z">
  <state datetime="2014-06-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bureau Advisory Opinion Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 to establish an advisory opinion process for the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Bureau Advisory Opinion Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000599"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000812" joined="2014-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit Prior to Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 32 - 27.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" code="HSBA15" name="House Financial Services" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-05-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Bureau Advisory Opinion Act - Amends the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 to require the Director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) to: (1) establish a procedure to respond to specific inquiries by a covered person concerning conformance of prospective conduct with federal consumer financial law, and (2) issue an opinion in response to the inquiry within 90 days (with a single allowable extension of another 45 days).

(A "covered person" under the Act is: (1) any person that engages in offering or providing a consumer financial product or service, and (2) any affiliate of that person if the affiliate acts as a service provider to the person.)

Creates a rebuttable presumption in any action brought under federal consumer financial law that any conduct for which the Director has issued an opinion that it is in conformity with the opinion is indeed in compliance with federal consumer financial law.

Exempts such inquiries and advisory opinions from disclosure under the Freedom of Information Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
