<bill session="115" type="s" number="3109" updated="2019-04-18T16:44:14Z">
  <state datetime="2018-06-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill making appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2019, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001047"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-06-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-21">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Capito. With written report No. 115-283.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-06-21" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="481">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 481.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="6776"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-06-21T12:27:47Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2019

Provides FY2019 appropriations to the Department of Homeland Security.

Provides appropriations for Departmental Management, Operations, Intelligence, and Oversight for:

 the Office of the Secretary and Executive Management; the Management Directorate; Intelligence, Analysis, and Operations Coordination; and the Office of Inspector General. Provides appropriations for Security, Enforcement, and Investigations for:

 U.S. Customs and Border Protection, U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, the Transportation Security Administration, the U.S. Coast Guard, and the U.S. Secret Service. Provides appropriations for Protection, Preparedness, Response, and Recovery for:

 the National Protection and Programs Directorate, the Office of Health Affairs, and the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA). Provides appropriations for Research, Development, Training, and Services for:

 U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services, the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers, the Science and Technology Directorate, and the Domestic Nuclear Detection Office. Sets forth requirements and restrictions for using funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-283</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
