<bill session="113" type="s" number="2977" updated="2016-10-25T16:32:52Z">
  <state datetime="2014-12-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-12-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medical Electronic Data Technology Enhancement for Consumers' Health Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MEDTECH Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to provide for the regulation of patient records and certain decision support software.</title>
    <title type="display">MEDTECH Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001267"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2014-12-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-12-04T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Medical Electronic Data Technology Enhancement for Consumers&#8217; Health Act or the MEDTECH Act - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to exclude from regulation as a medical device:

 administrative, operational, or financial records software used in health care settings; products intended for health maintenance outside of medical treatment; electronic patient records, excluding diagnostic image data, provided that related software is validated prior to marketing, consistent with the standards for devices; software for clinical laboratory test reports; and software that provides medical recommendations and the basis for those recommendations to health care professionals, with exceptions for products related to regulated devices.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
