<bill session="114" type="s" number="393" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:49Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Berryessa Snow Mountain National Monument Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate the Berryessa Snow Mountain National Monument in the State of California, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Berryessa Snow Mountain National Monument Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000711"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2015-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="761"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Berryessa Snow Mountain National Monument Act

 Establishes the Berryessa Snow Mountain National Monument, to consist of federal land and interests in federal land within Napa, Lake, Mendocino, Solano, Glenn, Colusa, and Yolo counties in California.

Continues to provide historical and adequate access to private inholdings in the Monument.

 Requires a comprehensive plan for the protection and management of the federal land included within the Monument. Requires such plan to: (1) include a weed management component, (2) include a native fish passage and habitat quality improvement component, and (3) include a component that addresses public safety and environmental clean-up issues associated with illegal marijuana production.

Permits grazing in the Conservation Area: (1) to continue, if established before this Act's enactment; (2) if not established before enactment, only to the extent that it is consistent with the purposes for which the Monument was established; or (3) through issuing annual targeted permits for the control of noxious weeds, fire suppression, or to provide other ecological benefits.

Establishes the Berryessa Snow Mountain National Monument Advisory Council to advise with respect to the preparation and implementation of the management plan. Requires the appointment of one Council member to represent Indian tribes.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
