<bill session="115" type="s" number="2426" updated="2019-04-18T16:41:36Z">
  <state datetime="2018-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Agricultural Act of 2014 to return premiums paid under the margin protection program for dairy producers to participating dairy operations.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Dairy Premium Refund Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Dairy Premium Refund Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Dairy Premium Refund Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000555"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-02-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-02-14T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Dairy Premium Refund Act of 2018 

This bill amends the Agricultural Act of 2014, with respect to the Dairy Margin Protection Program, to require the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to repay certain premiums to participating dairy operations.

(The Dairy Margin Protection Program is a voluntary program that makes payments to participating dairy operations when a formula-based national margin [the difference between the national all milk price and the national average feed cost] falls below a producer-selected insured margin.)

For 2015 and each succeeding year, USDA must repay to participating dairy operations an amount equal to the difference between:

 the total amount of premiums paid by participating dairy operations under the program for the year; and the sum of: (1) the total payments made to participating dairy operations under the program for the year, and (2) the costs of carrying out the program for the year. A repayment made to a participating dairy operation must be reduced by the amount of payments made to the operation under the program during the year.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
