<bill session="116" type="h" number="2500" updated="2019-07-19T07:38:38Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-12T13:29:32-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-07-12T13:29:32-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2020 for military activities of the Department of Defense, for military construction, and for defense activities of the Department of Energy, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2020 for military activities of the Department of Defense and for military construction, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">National Defense Strategy Implementation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">National Defense Strategy Implementation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">White Sands National Park Establishment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">White Sands National Park Establishment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">White Sands National Park Establishment Act</title>
    <title type="display">National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000510"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000238" joined="2019-05-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Intelligence and Emerging Threats and Capabilities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Seapower and Projection Forces.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Strategic Forces.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Tactical Air and Land Forces.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-04">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-04">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-04">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-04">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-04">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-04">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-04">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-04">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-04">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-04">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-04">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-04">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by the Yeas and Nays: 10 - 8 .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-06-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 33 - 24.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Armed Services. H. Rept. 116-120.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-06-19" calendar="Union" number="88">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 88.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-06-27">
      <text>Supplemental report filed by the Committee on Armed Services, H. Rept. 116-120, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-09T11:50:01-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 476 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2500 with 1 hour of general debate. Motion to recommit with or without instructions allowed. The resolution provides for a motion to suspend the rules relating to H.R. 1327 on the legislative days of July 11, 2019, or July 12, 2019.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T16:48:52-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 476 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T17:01:39-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 476.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5337-5576" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5351-5533" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T17:01:44-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2500 with 1 hour of general debate. Motion to recommit with or without instructions allowed. The resolution provides for a motion to suspend the rules relating to H.R. 1327 on the legislative days of July 11, 2019, or July 12, 2019.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T17:01:53-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 476 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T17:01:54-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Henry Cuellar to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T17:02:42-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2500.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T18:30:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Smith (WA) amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T18:41:22-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Smith (WA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Stefanik demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T18:42:34-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Smith (WA) en bloc No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T18:53:21-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Speier amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T19:06:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Speier amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Speier demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T19:08:22-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Speier amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T19:16:30-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Speier amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Speier demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T19:17:34-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brindisi amendment No. 9.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T19:25:53-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Brindisi amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Thornberry demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T19:26:48-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Torres (CA) amendment No. 10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T19:36:49-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Torres (CA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Barr demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T19:37:47-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Connolly amendment No. 11.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T19:48:07-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Connolly amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Hice (GA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T19:49:22-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Connolly amendment No. 12.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T19:58:17-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Shalala amendment No. 14.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T20:10:23-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Shalala amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Foxx (NC) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T20:11:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Omar amendment No. 17.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T20:23:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Omar amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Lamborn demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T20:24:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Smith (WA) amendment No. 19.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T20:33:30-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Smith (WA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Hice (GA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T20:35:42-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Smith (WA) en bloc No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T20:36:30-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Smith (WA) en bloc No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T20:38:32-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Smith (WA) en bloc No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T20:42:27-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (WA) moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T20:42:54-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10T20:43:12-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2500 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T12:16:20-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5594-5724" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T12:20:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T12:21:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Sherman amendment No. 21.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T12:30:49-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Sherman amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Wright demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T12:31:35-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ted Lieu amendment No. 23.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T12:35:46-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ted Lieu amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Zeldin demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T12:36:22-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ted Lieu amendment No. 24.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T12:45:59-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ted Lieu amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Zeldin demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T12:46:35-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Smith (WA) amendment No. 26.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T12:58:20-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Smith (WA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Zeldin demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T12:58:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cicilline amendment No. 27.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T13:05:52-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Cicilline amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Thornberry demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T13:06:45-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Engel amendment No. 29.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T13:16:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Engel amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Stefanik demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T13:17:01-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Engel amendment No. 31.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T13:28:54-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Engel amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Cheney demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T13:29:49-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on adoption of amendments, which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T15:14:41-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Blumenauer amendment No. 32.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T15:28:24-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Blumenauer amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Turner demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T15:29:12-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Blumenauer amendment No. 33.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T15:41:33-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Blumenauer amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Blumenauer demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T15:43:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Frankel amendment No. 34.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T15:55:43-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Frankel amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Lamborn demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T15:57:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Langevin amendment No. 35.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T16:10:27-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Smith (WA) en bloc No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T16:26:08-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Takano amendment No. 39.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T16:35:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ted Lieu (CA) amendment No. 44.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T16:48:10-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ted Lieu (CA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Gibbs demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T16:49:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Raskin amendment No. 45.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T17:00:55-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Raskin amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Lamborn demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T17:01:37-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Huffman amendment No. 46.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T18:06:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pappas amendment No. 48.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T18:18:01-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lee (CA) amendment No. 49.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T18:34:12-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Lee (CA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T18:35:05-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Amash amendment No. 50.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T18:44:28-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Amash amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Thornberry demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T18:45:23-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Smith (WA) en bloc No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T19:03:24-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Smith (WA) en bloc No. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T19:27:56-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Kendra S. Horn en bloc No. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T19:41:07-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Kendra S. Horn en bloc No. 9.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T19:57:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Kendra S. Horn en bloc No. 10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T20:10:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Kendra S. Horn en bloc No. 11.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T20:12:10-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Kendra S. Horn en bloc No. 12.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T20:16:02-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Kendra S. Horn en bloc No. 13.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T20:17:55-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Kendra S. Horn en bloc No. 14.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T20:19:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Kendra S. Horn en bloc No. 15.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T20:23:08-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Smith (WA) en bloc No. 16.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T20:29:20-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Khanna amendment No. 217.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T20:33:10-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tipton amendment No. 375.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T20:41:23-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Tipton amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Tipton demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T20:41:42-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Turner amendment No. 386.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T20:54:02-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Turner amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Turner demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T20:54:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Khanna amendment No. 423.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T21:23:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Khanna amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Thornberry demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T21:23:43-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lee (CA) amendment No. 424.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T21:34:01-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Lee (CA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. McCaul demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T21:34:39-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lee (CA) amendment No. 425.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T21:46:22-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Lee (CA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. McCaul demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T21:47:12-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Garcia (TX) amendment No. 428.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T21:55:58-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Garcia (TX) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Rogers (AL) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T21:56:42-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ocasio-Cortez amendment No. 429.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T22:04:34-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ocasio-Cortez amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Rogers (AL) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T22:05:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ocasio-Cortez amendment No. 430.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T22:10:44-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ocasio-Cortez amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Rogers (AL) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T22:11:24-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (WA) moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T22:11:37-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11T22:11:45-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2500 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-12T09:19:11-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5733-5743"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-12T09:19:24-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-12T09:21:21-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Thompson (MS) amendment No. 437.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-12T09:29:42-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Thompson (MS) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Thornberry demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-12T09:30:41-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Malinowski amendment No. 438.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-12T09:40:58-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Malinowski amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mrs. Wagner demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-12T09:41:45-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Dingell amendment No. 440.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-12T09:54:46-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jayapal amendment No. 441.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-12T10:16:10-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Jayapal amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Thornberry demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-12T10:18:42-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 476, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Smith (WA) en bloc No. 17.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-12">
      <text>Approved Further Amendments To Measure Previously Reported.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-12T10:38:44-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (WA) moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-12T10:39:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-12T10:39:12-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2500 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-12T11:30:52-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5750-5764" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-12T11:31:56-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-12T13:02:55-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2500.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-12T13:03:38-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-12T13:04:52-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thornberry moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5760-5762" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-12T13:05:08-04:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Thornberry motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to add the following new titles to the bill: Increase in Funding for Operation and Maintenance, Increase in Funding for Military Personnel, and Increase in Basic Pay.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-12T13:16:33-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-12T13:23:15-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 204 - 212 (Roll no. 472).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="473" datetime="2019-07-12T13:29:32-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 220 - 197 (Roll no. 473).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-07-12T13:29:36-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-12T13:38:43-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-12T13:38:44-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 2500.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Strategic Forces" code="HSAS29" name="House Armed Services" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Readiness" code="HSAS03" name="House Armed Services" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Intelligence and Emerging Threats and Capabilities" code="HSAS26" name="House Armed Services" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Seapower and Projection Forces" code="HSAS28" name="House Armed Services" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Tactical Air and Land Forces" code="HSAS25" name="House Armed Services" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3567"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="116" relation="procedurally-related" number="476"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3505"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3174"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3173"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1761"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1739"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1679"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1582"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1526"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1493"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1471"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1383"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1320"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1218"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1151"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="986"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="974"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="965"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="871"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="858"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="846"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="772"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="771"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="191"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3313"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3309"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3266"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3227"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3216"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3202"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3178"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3177"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3176"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3175"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3166"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3148"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3135"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3132"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3093"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3087"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3072"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3065"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3046"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3038"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3034"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3014"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2954"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2944"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2892"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2880"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2756"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2739"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2618"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2617"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2345"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2331"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2254"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2249"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2204"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2033"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2016"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1891"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1863"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1801"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1649"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1064"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="663"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="563"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="227"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="226"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="224"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="136"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="135"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="116" relation="unknown" number="417"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="116" relation="unknown" number="416"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="116" relation="unknown" number="269"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="116" relation="unknown" number="39"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1790"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1237"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1215"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h564"/>
    <amendment number="h563"/>
    <amendment number="h562"/>
    <amendment number="h561"/>
    <amendment number="h560"/>
    <amendment number="h559"/>
    <amendment number="h558"/>
    <amendment number="h557"/>
    <amendment number="h556"/>
    <amendment number="h555"/>
    <amendment number="h554"/>
    <amendment number="h553"/>
    <amendment number="h552"/>
    <amendment number="h551"/>
    <amendment number="h550"/>
    <amendment number="h549"/>
    <amendment number="h548"/>
    <amendment number="h547"/>
    <amendment number="h546"/>
    <amendment number="h545"/>
    <amendment number="h544"/>
    <amendment number="h543"/>
    <amendment number="h542"/>
    <amendment number="h541"/>
    <amendment number="h540"/>
    <amendment number="h539"/>
    <amendment number="h538"/>
    <amendment number="h537"/>
    <amendment number="h536"/>
    <amendment number="h535"/>
    <amendment number="h534"/>
    <amendment number="h533"/>
    <amendment number="h532"/>
    <amendment number="h531"/>
    <amendment number="h530"/>
    <amendment number="h529"/>
    <amendment number="h528"/>
    <amendment number="h527"/>
    <amendment number="h526"/>
    <amendment number="h525"/>
    <amendment number="h524"/>
    <amendment number="h523"/>
    <amendment number="h522"/>
    <amendment number="h521"/>
    <amendment number="h520"/>
    <amendment number="h519"/>
    <amendment number="h518"/>
    <amendment number="h517"/>
    <amendment number="h516"/>
    <amendment number="h515"/>
    <amendment number="h514"/>
    <amendment number="h513"/>
    <amendment number="h512"/>
    <amendment number="h511"/>
    <amendment number="h510"/>
    <amendment number="h509"/>
    <amendment number="h508"/>
    <amendment number="h507"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2019-05-02T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020

This bill authorizes FY2020 appropriations and sets forth policies for Department of Defense (DOD) programs and activities, including military personnel strengths. It does not provide budget authority, which is provided in subsequent appropriations legislation.

The bill authorizes appropriations to DOD for

 Procurement, including aircraft, weapons and tracked combat vehicles, shipbuilding and conversion, missiles, and space procurement; Research, Development, Test, and Evaluation; Operation and Maintenance; Working Capital Funds; Chemical Agents and Munitions Destruction; Drug Interdiction and Counter-Drug Activities; the Defense Inspector General; the Defense Health Program; the Armed Forces Retirement Home; Overseas Contingency Operations; and Military Construction. The bill authorizes the FY2020 personnel strength for active duty and reserve forces and sets forth policies regarding military personnel, acquisition policy and management, international programs, and National Guard and Reserve Forces facilities.

The bill also authorizes appropriations for base realignment and closure activities.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-120,Part 2</report>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-120</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
