<bill session="114" type="h" number="2648" updated="2019-01-09T21:26:07Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Truth in Settlements Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require adequate information regarding the tax treatment of payments under settlement agreements entered into by Federal agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Truth in Settlements Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2015-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000754" joined="2016-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2016-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000043" joined="2015-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2016-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2015-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2015-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000185" joined="2015-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000034" joined="2015-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2015-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="1109"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-04T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Truth in Settlements Act of 2015

 Sets forth new requirements for the public disclosure of any covered settlement agreement entered into by a federal executive agency.&#160; Defines "covered settlement agreement" as a settlement agreement (including a consent decree) that: (1) is entered into by an executive agency, (2) relates to an alleged violation of federal civil or criminal law, and (3) requires the payment of not less than $1 million by one or more non-federal persons (entities not within the federal government).

Requires the head of each executive agency to make publicly available on the agency website&#160;a list of each covered settlement agreement entered into by the agency, which shall include:&#160;(1) the names of the parties to the settlement&#160;agreement and the date of such agreement; (2) a description of the claims that were settled under the agreement; (3) the amount each party to the agreement is obligated to pay under the terms of the agreement and the total amounts required to be paid; and (4) for each settling party, the amount the settling party is obligated to pay that has been expressly specified as a civil penalty or fine and as not deductible for tax purposes. Requires: (1) such information to remain publicly available for not less than 5 years, beginning on the date of the agreement; and (2) a copy of a covered settlement agreement to remain publicly available for a period of not less than 1 year, beginning on the date of the agreement, or for not less than 5 years for an agreement under which a non-federal person is required to pay not less than $50 million.

Limits the disclosure of provisions of a covered settlement agreement that are subject to a confidentiality agreement.

Requires the issuer of securities subject to reporting requirements under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to describe in required reports any claim of a tax deduction relating to a payment under a covered settlement agreement.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
