<bill session="115" type="h" number="5797" updated="2019-06-13T18:20:12Z">
  <state datetime="2018-06-20T16:21:58-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-06-20T16:21:58-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to allow States to provide under Medicaid services for certain individuals with opioid use disorders in institutions for mental diseases.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">IMD CARE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Individuals in Medicaid Deserve Care that is Appropriate and Responsible in its Execution Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Individuals in Medicaid Deserve Care that is Appropriate and Responsible in its Execution Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">IMD CARE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Individuals in Medicaid Deserve Care that is Appropriate and Responsible in its Execution Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Individuals in Medicaid Deserve Care that is Appropriate and Responsible in its Execution Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IMD CARE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IMD CARE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Individuals in Medicaid Deserve Care that is Appropriate and Responsible in its Delivery Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Individuals in Medicaid Deserve Care that is Appropriate and Responsible in its Delivery Act</title>
    <title type="display">Individuals in Medicaid Deserve Care that is Appropriate and Responsible in its Execution Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000820"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2018-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000558" joined="2018-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001072" joined="2018-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000387" joined="2018-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000791" joined="2018-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-05-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-06-12">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 115-723.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-06-12" calendar="Union" number="558">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 558.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-06-19T21:01:37-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 949 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 6, H.R. 5797 and H.R. 6082. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 6 and H.R.5797 under structured rules; and provides for consideration of H.R. 6082 under a closed rule. Additionally, the rule directs the Clerk to, in the engrossment of H.R. 6, add the text of H.R. 2851, H.R. 5735, and H.R. 5797 as passed by the House as a new matter at the end of H.R. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-20T13:45:28-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 949.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5335-5344" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5338-5339" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-20T13:45:33-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 6, H.R. 5797 and H.R. 6082. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 6 and H.R.5797 under structured rules; and provides for consideration of H.R. 6082 under a closed rule. Additionally, the rule directs the Clerk to, in the engrossment of H.R. 6, add the text of H.R. 2851, H.R. 5735, and H.R. 5797 as passed by the House as a new matter at the end of H.R. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-20T13:45:43-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 949 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-20T13:45:44-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Mike Bost to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-20T13:46:28-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 5797.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-20T14:10:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 949, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rush amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-20T14:20:19-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 949, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kildee amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-20T14:26:41-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 949, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Fitzpatrick amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-20T14:31:22-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 5797.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-20T14:32:16-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-20T14:32:25-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-20T14:33:04-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Castor (FL) moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5342-5343" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-20T14:33:19-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Castor motion to recommit with instructions pending a reservation of a point of order. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to strike all that follows after section 1 and insert a section entitled Medicaid State Plan Option to Provide Services for Certain Individuals with Substance Use Disorders in Qualified Institutions for Mental Diseases. Subsequently, the reservation was removed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-20T14:42:45-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on Castor (FL) motion to recommit with instructions, the Chair put the question on the motion, and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Castor (FL) demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the motion to recommit with instructions until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-20T15:46:25-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5344-5345" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-20T16:13:46-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 190 - 226 (Roll no. 275).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="276" datetime="2018-06-20T16:21:58-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 261 - 155 (Roll no. 276).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-06-20T16:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-21">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="procedurally-related" number="949"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="6"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h795"/>
    <amendment number="h794"/>
    <amendment number="h793"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2018-06-20T13:23:13Z" status="Passed House amended">Individuals in Medicaid Deserve Care that is Appropriate and Responsible in its Execution&#160;Act or the IMD CARE Act

(Sec. 2) This bill temporarily allows states to apply to receive federal Medicaid payment for services provided in institutions for mental diseases (IMDs) and for other medically necessary services for enrollees (aged 21 to 64) with opioid-use or cocaine-use disorders. Services may be covered for a total of up to 30 days in a 12-month period for an eligible enrollee. States must include specified information in their applications, including plans to improve access to outpatient care.

Current law generally prohibits federal payment under Medicaid for services provided in IMDs for individuals under the age of 65 (although states may receive payment through certain mechanisms, such as through a Medicaid demonstration waiver).

(Sec. 3) Additionally, the bill temporarily eliminates the enhanced federal matching rate for Medicaid expenditures regarding specified medical services provided by certain managed care organizations.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-723</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
