<bill session="114" type="h" number="6239" updated="2019-02-14T23:05:49Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Improve Grants for Higher Education &amp; Repayment of Expensive Debt Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HIGHER ED Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to improve Federal Pell Grants and loans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">HIGHER ED Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000191"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-10-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Antitrust, Commercial, and Administrative Law" code="HSJU05" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3451"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4223"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5310"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1556"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Helping Improve Grants for Higher Education &amp; Repayment of Expensive Debt Act or the HIGHER ED Act

This bill amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to:

 modify the Federal Pell Grant program to increase the maximum award and restore year-round grants, make graduate and professional students eligible to receive subsidized Stafford Loans under the Federal Direct Loan program, direct the Department of Education to refinance outstanding federal student loans for Direct Loan and Federal Family Education Loan program borrowers, include a part-time job as a faculty member within the definition of "public service job" for purposes of the public service loan forgiveness program, and establish additional terms and conditions applicable to the income-based and income-contingent repayment plans. Additionally, the bill amends the federal bankruptcy code to permit a borrower to discharge in bankruptcy a nonprofit, government, or private student loan, or an obligation to repay an educational benefit, scholarship, or stipend.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
