<bill session="115" type="s" number="3405" updated="2019-07-16T21:20:12Z">
  <state datetime="2018-09-26">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-09-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize the Chemical Facility Anti-Terrorism Standards Program of the Department of Homeland Security.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Protecting and Securing Chemical Facilities from Terrorist Attacks Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Protecting and Securing Chemical Facilities from Terrorist Attacks Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting and Securing Chemical Facilities from Terrorist Attacks Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting and Securing Chemical Facilities from Terrorist Attacks Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Protecting and Securing Chemical Facilities from Terrorist Attacks Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000293"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2018-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2018-11-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-09-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-09-26" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-09-28">
      <text>Star Print ordered on the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-11-26">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 115-384.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-11-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="670">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 670.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="6992"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-09-04T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting and Securing Chemical Facilities from Terrorist Attacks Act of 2018

This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to reauthorize and make changes in its Chemical Facility Anti-Terrorism Standards (CFATS) program. The CFATS program regulates "high-risk" chemical facilities to reduce the risk of terrorist attacks.

The program shall evaluate and maintain (currently, limited to establishing) risk-based performance standards designed to address high levels of security risk at certain chemical facilities. The bill prohibits the inclusion of any standard relating to cybersecurity.

DHS shall: (1) establish a CFATS Recognition Program to leverage CFATS regulations and industry stewardship programs to further enhance security relating to hazardous chemicals, and (2) commission a third-party study to assess the effectiveness of the program in maintaining security risks and in developing and using appropriate metrics and analysis capabilities to measure risk reduction.

The Government Accountability Office shall report on CFATS inspector training with recommendations for improving such training.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-384</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
