<bill session="114" type="s" number="1733" updated="2018-08-16T23:01:10Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Forest Incentives Program Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a forest incentives program to keep forests intact and sequester carbon on private forest land of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Forest Incentives Program Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-16">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Materials"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-09T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Forest Incentives Program Act of 2015

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish a forest incentives program to achieve supplemental greenhouse gas emission reductions and carbon sequestration on U.S. private forest land (eligible land) through:

 carbon incentives contracts, and conservation easement agreements. In selecting projects under such program, USDA shall give priority to contracts and agreements that:

 sequester the most carbon on a per acre basis; and create forestry jobs or protect habitats and achieve significant other environmental, economic, and social benefits. To participate in such program, an owner of eligible land must enter into a carbon incentives contract.

USDA shall make financial incentive payments to owners of eligible land for:

 certain forestry practices that measurably increase carbon sequestration and storage over a designated period on eligible land, and conservation easements on eligible land covered under a conservation easement agreement. The Department of the Interior may set aside a portion of program funds to develop specified forest carbon modeling and methodologies and for other specified purposes.

Interior shall establish a greenhouse gas incentives program to achieve supplemental greenhouse gas emission reductions from material choices in buildings.

Interior shall provide owners of nonresidential buildings used for commercial or state or local government purposes incentive payments for the use of commercial or industrial products composed of biological products for sequestering carbon in those buildings. Program participants shall receive their payments upon the completion of the construction or renovation of the applicable building.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
