<amendment session="114" chamber="h" number="1161" updated="2019-04-11T15:40:30Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5278" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2016-06-09T17:35:11-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000614"/>
  <offered datetime="2016-06-09"/>
  <description>Amendment temporarily eliminates a statutory cap in Puerto Rico that limits the total number of census tracts within a Metropolitan Statistical Area that can be designated as qualified census tracts under the Small Business Administration's HUBZone program. Amendment also requires the SBA to implement a risk-based approach to requesting and verifying information from firms applying to be designated or re-certified as a qualified HUBZone small business.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 7 printed in House Report 114-610 to temporarily eliminate in Puerto Rico a statutory cap that limits the total number of census tracts within a Metropolitan Statistical Area that can be designated as qualified census tracts under the Small Business Administration's HUBZone program. The amendment requires the SBA to implement a risk-based approach to requesting and verifying information from firms applying to be designated or re-certified as a qualified HUBZone small business.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2016-06-09T17:35:11-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Duffy amendment (A006) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-06-09T17:28:11-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A006) offered by Mr. Duffy.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3631-3632" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3631" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-09"/>
    <action datetime="2016-06-09T17:28:11-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A006) offered by Mr. Duffy.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3631-3632" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3631" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-09T17:35:11-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-09T17:35:11-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Duffy amendment (A006) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-09">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
