<bill session="114" type="h" number="4158" updated="2019-02-01T21:05:42Z">
  <state datetime="2015-12-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-12-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring Investment in ATB Student Education Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RISE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to reinstate the ability-to-benefit eligibility.</title>
    <title type="display">RISE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000564"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000386" joined="2016-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2015-12-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Investment" code="HSED13" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2721"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-12-02T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Restoring Investment in ATB Student Education Act or the RISE Act

This bill amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to modify the federal student aid eligibility requirements for students who are not high school graduates.

Currently, a student without a high school diploma or homeschool credential is eligible to receive federal student aid if such student is enrolled in a career pathway program and demonstrates an ability to benefit from an institution's education or training program.

This bill eliminates enrollment in a career pathway program as a federal student aid eligibility requirement. A student without a high school diploma or homeschool credential is eligible to receive federal student aid by demonstrating an ability to benefit from an institution's education or training program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
