<bill session="113" type="s" number="2140" updated="2016-10-25T16:29:20Z">
  <state datetime="2014-04-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the transition between experimental permits and commercial licenses for commercial reusable launch vehicles.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to improve the transition between experimental permits and commercial licenses for commercial reusable launch vehicles.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001046"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2014-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2014-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2014-04-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-04-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-04">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-04" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="612">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 612.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-12">
      <text>By Senator Rockefeller from Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation filed written report. Report No. 113-318.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="3038"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-12-04T15:38:13Z" status="Reported to Senate amended">Revises requirements for experimental permits related to commercial space launch activities.

Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation to issue an experimental permit for a particular reusable suborbital vehicle (RSV) for research and development to test design concepts, equipment, or operating techniques, regardless of whether they are new (as under current law) or already existing.

Strikes the requirement that crew training for which the permit may be used must occur before a commercial license for launch or reentry is obtained.

Allows a permit to authorize an unlimited number of launches and reentries for a particular RSV rocket design (as well as for a particular RSV, as under current law).

Repeals the prohibition against issuance of a permit, and the automatic invalidation of an existing permit, after a license has been issued for the launch or reentry of an RSV of a particular design.

Authorizes the Secretary to issue a permit regardless of whether a license has already been issued. Declares that the issuance of a license may not invalidate a permit.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 113-318</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
