<bill session="114" type="h" number="3663" updated="2019-02-14T23:05:46Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prevent certain discriminatory taxation of natural gas pipeline property.</title>
    <title type="display">To prevent certain discriminatory taxation of natural gas pipeline property.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000461"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000410" joined="2015-10-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Antitrust, Commercial, and Administrative Law" code="HSJU05" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2117"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Property tax"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-01T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill describes acts that unreasonably burden and discriminate against interstate commerce with respect to natural gas pipeline property. It prohibits states, political subdivisions, and any other taxing authority from: (1) assessing natural gas pipeline property at a value that has a higher ratio to its true market value than the ratio used to assess other commercial and industrial property in the same assessment jurisdiction, (2) levying or collecting a tax on such an assessment, (3) levying or collecting an ad valorem property tax on natural gas pipeline property at a rate that exceeds the rate applicable to commercial and industrial property in the same assessment jurisdiction, or (4) imposing any other tax that discriminates against a natural gas pipeline providing transportation subject to the jurisdiction of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.

The bill grants jurisdiction to U.S. District Courts for claims involving discriminatory taxation of natural gas pipeline property and provides for relief for such claims.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
