<bill session="114" type="h" number="772" updated="2018-06-02T02:21:48Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Aviation and Flight Enhancement Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to issue regulations to improve flight recorder and aircraft crash location requirements on certain commercial passenger aircraft in accordance with new International Civil Aviation Organization flight recorder standards.</title>
    <title type="display">Safe Aviation and Flight Enhancement Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000533"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2015-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2015-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000523" joined="2015-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Aviation" code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Safe Aviation and Flight Enhancement Act of 2015

 Directs the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to require all commercial passenger aircraft ordered by an air carrier on or after January 1, 2017, to be equipped with a deployable recorder system as the second combination FDR/CVR recorder system installed under International Civil Aviation Organization (ICAO) flight recorder standards.

Defines: (1) "commercial passenger aircraft" to mean a jet aircraft with a maximum certificated take-off mass over 15,000 kilograms that is required to be equipped with two combination recorder systems in accordance with ICAO requirements; and (2) "deployable recorder system" to mean a flight data recorder, cockpit voice recorder, and emergency locator transmitter housed in one crash protected, floatable unit that meets the performance specifications under specified standards of the FAA and the European Organization for Civil Aviation Equipment.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
