<bill session="114" type="s" number="920" updated="2018-06-02T06:44:56Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Spouse Job Continuity Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a credit against income tax for amounts paid by a spouse of a member of the Armed Forces for a new State license or certification required by reason of a permanent change in the duty station of such member to another State.</title>
    <title type="display">Military Spouse Job Continuity Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Hatch. With written report No. 114-30.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-04-14" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="53">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 53.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1100"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="210"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-14T15:23:09Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Military Spouse Job Continuity Act of 2015

(Sec. 2) Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow the spouse of a member of the Armed Forces (military spouse) who moves with such member to another state under a permanent change of station order a tax credit for up to $500 of qualified relicensing costs incurred by such spouse for each change of duty station. Defines "qualified relicensing costs" as costs for a state license or certification to engage in the profession that such military spouse engaged in while residing in the former state and which are paid or incurred during the period beginning when the relocation order is issued and ending one year after the reporting date specified in such order. Requires a reduction in the amount of such credit by any tax deduction or other credit allowed for qualified relicensing costs. Makes this tax credit effective for taxable years beginning after 2014.

(Sec. 3) Increases from 30% to 40% the rate of the continuous levy on payments to Medicare providers and suppliers for unpaid taxes, effective for payments made after 180 days after the enactment of this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-30</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
