<bill session="115" type="s" number="3157" updated="2019-04-18T16:44:26Z">
  <state datetime="2018-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to streamline siting processes for small cell deployment.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STREAMLINE Small Cell Deployment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STREAMLINE Small Cell Deployment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Streamlining The Rapid Evolution And Modernization of Leading-edge Infrastructure Necessary to Enhance Small Cell Deployment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Streamlining The Rapid Evolution And Modernization of Leading-edge Infrastructure Necessary to Enhance Small Cell Deployment Act</title>
    <title type="display">STREAMLINE Small Cell Deployment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2018-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-06-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates and fees"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-06-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Streamlining The Rapid Evolution And Modernization of Leading-edge Infrastructure Necessary to Enhance Small Cell Deployment Act or the STREAMLINE Small Cell Deployment Act

This bill amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require that the regulation of the placement, construction, or modification of small personal wireless service facilities by any state or local government: (1) not unreasonably discriminate among providers of the same service using comparable equipment; and (2) only permit a state or local government to approve or deny a permit or other permission to deploy such a facility.

A state or local government may charge a fee to consider an application for such placement, construction, or modification, or to use a right-of-way or a facility in a right-of-way owned or managed by the state or local governmen if the fee is: (1) competitively neutral, technology neutral, and nondiscriminatory; (2) publicly disclosed; and (3) based on actual and direct costs.

The Government Accountability Office shall study and report on deployment of broadband infrastructure on tribal land or near trust land.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
