<bill session="114" type="s" number="2014" updated="2018-06-02T07:09:19Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Next Generation Researchers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Next Generation Researchers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to demonstrate a commitment to our Nation's scientists by increasing opportunities for the development of our next generation of researchers.</title>
    <title type="display">Next Generation Researchers Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000360" joined="2016-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2015-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-02-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-04-04">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Alexander with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-04" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="410">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 410.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="3466"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-04T13:46:51Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Next Generation Researchers Act

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to establish the Next Generation of Researchers Initiative in the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to promote, provide, and improve opportunities for new researchers and earlier research independence. The initiative must: (1) coordinate with agencies, academic institutions, and others to improve and update existing information on the biomedical research workforce, and (2) take into consideration the recommendations of the National Academies of Sciences regarding the next generation of researchers and report on actions taken based on those recommendations.

(Sec. 3) The bill revises loan repayment programs for health professionals conducting research to increase the maximum repayment amount and to give the NIH the authority to expand eligibility for the programs based on workforce and scientific priorities.

The Government Accountability Office must report on NIH efforts to attract, retain, and develop emerging scientists.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
