<bill session="114" type="s" number="2390" updated="2018-06-02T07:13:47Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Bureau of Investigation Whistleblower Protection Enhancement Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Federal Bureau of Investigation Whistleblower Protection Enhancement Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide adequate protections for whistleblowers at the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</title>
    <title type="display">Federal Bureau of Investigation Whistleblower Protection Enhancement Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2016-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2016-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2016-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2016-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2016-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2015-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2016-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2016-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2016-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2016-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2016-02-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8605" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
      <reference ref="CR S8606-8607" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-04-14">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Grassley with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="421">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 421.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25">
      <text>By Senator Grassley from Committee on the Judiciary filed written report. Report No. 114-261.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5790"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-14T12:48:41Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Federal Bureau of Investigation Whistleblower Protection Enhancement Act of 2016

(Sec. 2) This bill revises whistle-blower protections for a Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) employee or job applicant who discloses wrongdoing to an appropriate official.

Specifically, it prohibits an FBI or Department of Justice (DOJ) employee from taking or failing to take a personnel action (e.g., demotion) with respect to an FBI employee or applicant because of a protected disclosure. A protected disclosure is a disclosure of information to an appropriate official which an employee or applicant reasonably believes evidences: (1) a violation of a law, rule, or regulation; or (2) waste, fraud, or abuse. The bill expands the list of appropriate officials who may receive a protected disclosure to include a supervisor in an employee's direct chain of command.

 Additionally, the bill sets forth procedures for filing, investigating, adjudicating, and reviewing whistle-blower retaliation complaints.

An FBI employee or applicant may file a complaint with DOJ's Office of Inspector General (OIG), which must investigate and decide whether reasonable grounds exist to believe that a prohibited personnel action occurred.

If either party files an objection to the OIG's decision, then an administrative law judge (ALJ) must review it, on the record, and issue a written decision. The ALJ's determination becomes final, unless it is appealed to or reviewed by DOJ. Any ALJ or DOJ determination is subject to judicial review.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-261</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
