<bill session="114" type="h" number="3715" updated="2018-06-02T04:44:50Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-23T16:38:33-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-05-23T16:38:33-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Final Farewell Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Final Farewell Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to permit interments, funerals, memorial services, and ceremonies of deceased veterans at national cemeteries and State cemeteries receiving grants from the Department of Veterans Affairs during certain weekends if requested for religious reasons.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to permit interments, funerals, memorial services, and ceremonies of deceased veterans at national cemeteries and State cemeteries receiving grants from the Department of Veterans Affairs during certain weekends.</title>
    <title type="display">Final Farewell Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000911"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-13">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-05-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-05-23T16:34:39-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Miller (FL) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-23T16:34:49-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2913-2914" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-23T16:34:51-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3715.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2016-05-23T16:38:33-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2913-2914" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-05-23T16:38:35-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-23T16:38:38-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-23T14:00:01Z" status="Passed House amended">Final Farewell Act of 2016 

(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs to permit the interment or funeral, memorial service, or ceremony of a deceased veteran at a national cemetery during weekends, other than federal holiday weekends, upon the request of the veteran's next-of-kin.

 Any grant to assist a state in establishing a veterans' cemetery shall require that the cemetery permits the interment or funeral, memorial service, or ceremony of a deceased veteran during weekends, other than federal holiday weekends, upon the request of the veteran's next-of-kin.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
