<bill session="114" type="s" number="2053" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:57Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Maritime and Energy Workforce Technical Training Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Energy to award grants to expand programs in maritime and energy workforce technical training, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Maritime and Energy Workforce Technical Training Enhancement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2015-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2015-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2016-01-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2923"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Maritime and Energy Workforce Technical Training Enhancement Act

This bill directs the Department of Energy (DOE) to award grants to enable eligible community colleges and other public postsecondary institutions of higher education that are located near marine or port facilities in the Gulf of Mexico, Atlantic Ocean, Pacific Ocean, or Great Lakes to expand upon existing programs in maritime and energy workforce technical training, including by admitting more students, training faculty, expanding facilities, creating new maritime career pathways from an associate degree to a baccalaureate degree, awarding credit for prior learning experience, and increasing cooperation with an appropriate federal agency or the National Science Foundation.

DOE shall give priority to institutions that have entered into a partnership with an appropriate federal agency.

Recipients shall use grant amounts for:

 training related to maritime or energy transportation, logistics, and supply chain management or to shipbuilding and ship repair; enhancement of academic and workforce training programs for maritime and energy employment; salary supplementation for faculty in maritime or energy training and education; operation and maintenance of maritime or energy related equipment and technology for use in instructional programs; acquisition of marine vessels and other assets and equipment for use in maritime or energy related training and education; renovation or construction of buildings to house maritime or energy training and education programs; or tuition reimbursement for successful completion of a maritime or energy course, program, or certification. DOE may also award a grant to an eligible nonprofit organization (one with at least 10 years of expertise in working with community colleges on developing workforce development programs) to provide assistance in carrying out this Act.

DOE shall award a grant to to enable up to 10 eligible institutions that offer accredited programs in academic areas relevant to maritime or energy-related workforce training to: (1) establish Centers of Excellence in Maritime and Energy Workforce Technical Training; and (2) improve and expand maritime and energy workforce training opportunities through such Centers for veterans, members of the Armed Forces, federal employees, and civilians by implementing new training programs and providing job placement services in maritime and energy employment fields.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
