<bill session="115" type="h" number="4056" updated="2019-04-18T16:16:32Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-10-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act and other laws to return primary responsibility for disaster relief to the States, to establish a private corporation to insure States against risks and costs of disasters otherwise borne by the States, and to provide for reimbursable Federal assistance to States for activities in response to disasters, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disaster Insurance Risk Equality Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disaster Insurance Risk Equality Act</title>
    <title type="display">Disaster Insurance Risk Equality Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000188"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-10-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Highways and Transit" code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-10-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Disaster Insurance Risk Equality Act

This bill amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to establish the National Disaster Insurance Corporation, which shall establish and carry out an insurance program to provide coverage to states against certain losses and costs arising from disasters. The program must be funded solely by state premiums and payments and operated on an actuarially sound basis.

The corporation shall: (1) adjust and pay all claims for proved and approved losses and costs covered by insurance, and (2) establish and manage a reserve account for the operation of the insurance program.

The bill establishes a Disaster Insurance Advisory Commission to assist the corporation in establishing the terms and conditions of the insurance program and to review the annual state premium charges.

The bill conditions assistance on a state agreeing to reimburse the United States for disaster-related expenses, including temporary housing assistance, crisis counseling assistance and training, emergency public transportation, and fire suppression.

The President may lend or advance to a state assistance for damages caused by a major disaster if the President determines that such damages are so overwhelming and severe that the state is unable to accept immediate financial responsibility for them and that the state has the ability to repay any such loans or advances.

 The Department of Transportation shall withhold 10% of the amount required to be apportioned to a state under federal-aid highway provisions if the state is not is a participant in the corporation. Emergency relief for repair of highways may only be provided to a state that agrees to reimburse the United States for all expenses incurred in providing such assistance.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
