<bill session="114" type="h" number="4390" updated="2019-01-09T21:10:16Z">
  <state datetime="2016-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Johnson-O'Malley Supplemental Indian Education Program Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend and reform the Johnson-O'Malley Act to award contracts to certain tribal organizations, Indian corporations, school districts, States, and consortia of tribal organizations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Johnson-O'Malley Supplemental Indian Education Program Modernization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001143"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2016-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2016-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2016-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2016-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2016-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2016-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2016-01-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2842"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational guidance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-01-13T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Johnson-O'Malley Supplemental Indian Education Program Modernization Act

This bill amends the Johnson-O'Malley Act to establish a program through which the Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA) shall contract with eligible entities for the purpose of providing educational benefits to Indian students. An eligible entity is an entity that educates or serves Indian students and is either a tribal organization, an Indian corporation, a school district, a state, or a consortium of tribal organizations.

An eligible entity shall use the funds to establish or expand programs to: (1) provide remedial instruction, counseling, cultural programs, school supplies, and specified courses and activities; (2) establish targeted, culturally sensitive, dropout prevention activities; and (3) purchase equipment to facilitate training in trade skills and college preparation.

In general, BIA shall base the amount of a contract on the number of eligible Indian students educated or served by an eligible entity.

With respect to these contracts, BIA must ensure full geographic coverage and the full participation of eligible entities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
