<bill session="113" type="hr" number="663" updated="2016-10-25T15:55:51Z">
  <state datetime="2014-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives on the current situation in Iraq and the urgent need to protect religious minorities from persecution from the Sunni Islamist insurgent and terrorist group the Islamic State in Iraq and Levant (ISIL) as it expands its control over areas in northwestern Iraq.</title>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives on the current situation in Iraq and the urgent need to protect religious minorities from persecution from the Sunni Islamist insurgent and terrorist group the Islamic State in Iraq and Levant (ISIL) as it expands its control over areas in northwestern Iraq.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000130"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-10">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="113" relation="unknown" number="683"/>
    <bill type="sr" session="113" relation="unknown" number="530"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-07-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Reaffirms the commitments of the House of Representatives to promoting and protecting religious freedom around the world and providing relief to minority groups facing persecution.

Calls on the Department of State to work with the Kurdistan Regional Government, the Iraqi central government, neighboring countries, the diaspora community in the United States, the United Nations (U.N.) High Commissioner for Refugees, and other key stakeholders to help secure safe havens for persons claiming amnesty in Iraq.

Requests the addition of a Special Representative for Religious Minorities to be included in Prime Minister al-Maliki's newly reconstructed government.

Urges the Administration to expedite the visa processing for Iraq's minority groups and to lift the quota cap for Iraqi-Christians in order to streamline the process of accepting refugees.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
