<bill session="114" type="h" number="5222" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:49Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Iran Cyber Sanctions Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To impose sanctions with respect to persons responsible for knowingly engaging in significant activities undermining cybersecurity on behalf of or at the direction of the Government of Iran, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Iran Cyber Sanctions Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000601"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2756"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Iran Cyber Sanctions Act of 2016

This bill requires the President to report to Congress at least every 180 days regarding significant activities undermining cybersecurity conducted by persons on behalf of or at the direction of the government of Iran (including members of paramilitary organizations such as Ansar-e-Hezbollah and Basij-e Mostaz'afin) against the United States (including U.S. persons, entities, or federal, state, or local governments). The reports must: (1) identify persons that have knowingly facilitated, participated or assisted in, engaged in, directed, or provided material support for such activities; (2) describe their conduct; (3) assess the Iranian government's or other foreign governments' direction, facilitation, or material support in such activities; and (4) provide a strategy to counter efforts by persons to conduct such activities, which shall include engaging foreign governments to halt the capabilities of such persons.

The President must include on the Office of Foreign Assets Control's specially designated nationals and blocked persons list persons who are: (1) identified in such reports; or (2) indicted by the Department of Justice in connection with such activities undermining U.S. cybersecurity. Under an exception, the President may exclude such a person from the list by submitting an explanation to Congress.

The President must use Executive Order 13694 (relating to blocking the property of certain persons engaging in significant malicious cyber-enabled activities) to impose sanctions against persons included on such list.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
