<bill session="115" type="s" number="953" updated="2019-04-18T16:35:23Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the United States Secret Service to make certain White House visitor logs available to the public, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">White House Visitor Logs Transparency Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">White House Visitor Logs Transparency Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">White House Visitor Logs Transparency Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001046"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">White House Visitor Logs Transparency Act of 2017

This bill amends the federal criminal code to require the following records created or maintained by the U.S. Secret Service in carrying out protective services to be made available to the public upon request:

 the name of each individual who visits the White House for the purpose of conducting business and meets with the President or an employee of the Executive Office of the President; the date and time each such visitor entered and left the White House; and the name of each individual in the White House, including the President if applicable, with whom each such visitor met. The following records created or maintained by the Secret Service shall not be disclosed to the public:

 information relating to an individual whose visit to the White House was as a guest of the President or the President's family and entirely personal in nature; information that, if disclosed to the public, would cause a threat to national security interests; and time-sensitive information concerning particularly sensitive meetings.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
