<bill session="114" type="s" number="1797" updated="2018-06-02T06:57:48Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Connect with Veterans Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a voluntary national directory of veterans to support outreach to veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Connect with Veterans Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001069"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2015-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2015-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2015-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5163-5165" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Connect with Veterans Act of 2015

Requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to establish a program to facilitate VA outreach to veterans, primary state agencies for the administration of veterans' benefits and services, political subdivisions of states, and Indian tribes.

Requires the VA, to carry out such program, to: (1) establish a national veterans directory, and (2) share directory information with any such entities from which a participating individual has expressed interest in receiving information.

Prohibits: (1) the VA from selling information collected under this Act, (2) the VA or any participating entity from sharing such information with a non-participating entity, or (3) any participating entity from using any such information for any political communication or from requiring any participating individual to purchase any product or service.

Requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to: (1) provide to each member of the Armed Forces separating from service a form for the collection of information to be included in the directory, (2) ensure that completion of the form is voluntary, and (3) take steps to protect the privacy of individuals and the security of information.

Directs DOD and the Department of Labor jointly to take steps to integrate the collection of information under this Act into the Transition Assistance Program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
