<bill session="114" type="s" number="2385" updated="2018-06-02T07:13:45Z">
  <state datetime="2015-12-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-12-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Eliminate, Neutralize, and Disrupt Wildlife Trafficking Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to strengthen protections for the remaining populations of wild elephants, rhinoceroses, and other imperiled species through country-specific anti-poaching efforts and anti-trafficking strategies, to promote the value of wildlife and natural resources, to curtail the demand for illegal wildlife products in consumer countries, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Eliminate, Neutralize, and Disrupt Wildlife Trafficking Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2016-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000444" joined="2015-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2016-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2016-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2016-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crimes against animals and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Thailand"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-12-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Eliminate, Neutralize, and Disrupt Wildlife Trafficking Act

This bill directs the Presidential Task Force on Wildlife Trafficking to:

 identify countries of concern regarding the supply, poaching, or transit of wildlife and wildlife products; collaborate with the national wildlife service of a country of concern to analyze the threats to wildlife in that country, and to prepare a strategic plan with recommendations for addressing wildlife crime; coordinate efforts to implement strategic plans among federal agencies and non-federal partners; and coordinate with stakeholders qualified to provide assistance regarding anti-poaching activities, law enforcement efforts, and strategies to reduce illicit trade and reduce consumer demand for illegally traded wildlife and wildlife products. The Task Force shall terminate five years after enactment of this Act.

The Department of State may provide defense articles, services, and training to security forces of a country of concern to counter wildlife trafficking and poaching.

 The State Department and the U.S. Agency for International Development, with respect to countries of concern, may:

 provide assistance to carry out strategic plan recommendations, including improving the effectiveness of wildlife law enforcement; design and implement programs to increase the investigational capacity of wildlife law enforcement and customs and border security officers and to combat the transnational trade in illegal wildlife; and take actions to strengthen international cooperation and partnerships to combat the global wildlife crime crisis. The State Department may also provide support in countries of concern to the development and replication of community-owned wildlife conservancies and community-based conservation programs.

It is the sense of Congress that the United States should continue to work with foreign countries, including China, Thailand, and Vietnam to combat global wildlife trafficking.

The State Department should implement agreements with China and initiate negotiations with Thailand and Vietnam aimed at reducing demand for ivory and rhinoceros horn (Vietnam), and eliminating illegal trade in wildlife and wildlife products.

 It is the sense of Congress that efforts to find funds to carry out this Act should not result in an increase in amounts authorized to be appropriated for a fiscal year to provide additional funds for overseas contingency operations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
