<bill session="114" type="s" number="2994" updated="2018-06-02T07:45:47Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DXM Abuse Prevention Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to prevent the abuse of dextromethorphan, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">DXM Abuse Prevention Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2016-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3250"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">DXM Abuse Prevention Act of 2016

This bill amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to prohibit the sale of a drug containing dextromethorphan (DXM) to an individual under age 18 unless the individual has a prescription or is actively enrolled in the military. Civil monetary penalties that escalate upon repeated violation are imposed.

To possess or receive unfinished DXM, a person must be registered with the Department of Health and Human Services as a producer of a drug or medical device or otherwise allowed to engage in the practice of pharmacy, pharmaceutical production, or manufacture or distribution of drug ingredients. Unfinished DXM may be distributed only to these authorized persons. Common carriers distributing unfinished DXM between authorized persons are exempted. Civil monetary penalties are imposed for possession and distribution violations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
