<bill session="115" type="h" number="6194" updated="2019-04-18T16:25:26Z">
  <state datetime="2018-06-27">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reduce costs of Federal real estate, improve building security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Real Estate Assets and Leasing Reform Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Real Estate Assets and Leasing Reform Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REAL Reform Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REAL Reform Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">REAL Reform Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001269"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000625" joined="2018-08-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000587" joined="2018-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001187" joined="2018-07-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27">
      <text>Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-06-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1174"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-06-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Real Estate Assets and Leasing Reform Act of 2018 or REAL Reform Act of 2018



This bill modifies requirements with respect to leases for federal buildings.

Specifically, the bill:

 directs the General Services Administration (GSA) to establish, and operate through 2023,&#160;a pilot program to execute lease agreements using alternative procedures; temporarily authorizes the GSA to submit consolidated prospectuses for leases and projects to Congress for approval; requires approval by congressional resolution of&#160;an appropriation for&#160;any costs and expenses associated with administering an acquisition by exchange involving real property or in-kind consideration valued at or over a specified amount; sets a specified limitation regarding bargain-price purchase options; requires certain public buildings containing a public restroom to also contain a lactation room; authorizes the Department of Commerce to release the federal government's interest in certain economic adjustment grants; and requires the GSA to provide specified additional notice and justification to Congress regarding certain projects. The Government Accountability Office must conduct biennial audits of the GSA National Broker Contract and a review of the application of certain enhanced competition requirements.

The GSA must sell or exchange part of the Department of Energy (DOE) Forrestal complex to fund the construction of a new DOE headquarters.

In addition, the bill allows&#160;the Department of Homeland Security to authorize and train security personnel contracted to protect certain federal buildings&#160;or grounds&#160;to carry firearms and, under specified circumstances,&#160;detain individuals without a warrant.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
