<bill session="114" type="hr" number="600" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:30Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Reaffirming the right for the United States to use all available options, including the use of military force, to prevent Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon.</title>
    <title type="display">Reaffirming the right for the United States to use all available options, including the use of military force, to prevent Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001196"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001275" joined="2016-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2016-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000620" joined="2016-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2016-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000571" joined="2016-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000379" joined="2016-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000382" joined="2016-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001177" joined="2016-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000586" joined="2016-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000587" joined="2016-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000602" joined="2016-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000588" joined="2016-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Reaffirms: (1) the right for the United States to use all available options, including military force, to prevent Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon; and (2) that it is U.S. policy to prevent Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon for the life of the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPA) and afterward.

Supports Israel's right to defend itself from nations and non-state actors that wish to do it harm.

Calls on the Administration to provide Israel with military and intelligence support and cooperation to confront new threats to Israel's security by maintaining its strategic and qualitative military edge.

Calls on United Nations member states to take all necessary measures to prevent the transfer of ballistic or cruise missile technology or technical assistance to Iran.

Calls on the President to engage with Congress and international partners to ensure that the International Atomic Energy Agency receives the full yearly amount necessary to fulfill its JCPA verification responsibilities.

Supports full funding for the Department of State's Coordinator for Iran Nuclear Implementation and for the Department of the Treasury's Office of Foreign Assets Control.

Remains committed to confronting the Iranian regime's destabilizing actions in the Middle East through increased cooperation with U.S. regional partners.

Demands action by the Administration to raise Iran's recent ballistic missile testing with the Security Council and seek an appropriate response for Iran's disregard for Security Council Resolution 1929.

Calls on the Iranian government to assist in the investigation of the disappearance of U.S. citizens within its borders.

Condemns Iran's record of human rights violations and supports the Iranian people's pursuit of civil liberties.

Reaffirms that nothing in the JCPA limits the ability of Congress to pass sanctions legislation to address future Iranian terrorism activities, ballistic or cruise missile development, human rights abuses, or to reauthorize existing sanctions that are not lifted under the JCPA.

Calls on the Administration to keep Congress informed about how it will work with other P5+1 countries to respond to JCPA violations.

Calls for the creation of a bipartisan Iran Study Group composed of senior and expert policy-makers to report to Congress on a broader Middle East strategy to counter Iran and leverage more constructive Iranian behavior.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
