<amendment session="113" chamber="h" number="483" updated="2016-10-25T17:04:12Z">
  <amends type="h" number="3080" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2013-10-23T18:02:06-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000461"/>
  <offered datetime="2013-10-23"/>
  <description>Amendment prohibits programs or actions authorized under this Act from further implementation of coastal and marine spatial planning and ecosystem-based management components under Executive Order 13547; requires the Secretary of the Army to conduct and submit a study detailing all activities engaged in and resources expended in furtherance of Executive Order 13547; requires such study to include any budget requests for fiscal year 2014 for support of implementation of Executive Order 13547; and requires that the study be submitted to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 3 printed in House Report 113-251 to prohibit programs or actions authorized under this Act from further implementation of coastal and marine spatial planning and ecosystem-based management components under Executive Order 13547. Requires the Secretary of the Army to conduct and submit a study detailing all activities engaged in and resources expended in furtherance of Executive Order 13547. The study also should include any budget requests for fiscal year 2014 for support of implementation of Executive Order 13547, and be submitted to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2013-10-23T18:02:06-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="557">
      <text>On agreeing to the Flores amendment (A003) Agreed to by recorded vote: 225 - 193 (Roll no. 557).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-10-23T16:07:06-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A003) offered by Mr. Flores.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6741-6744, H6755-6756" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6741" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-23"/>
    <action datetime="2013-10-23T18:02:06-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-23T18:02:06-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-23T18:02:06-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Flores amendment (A003) Agreed to by recorded vote: 225 - 193 (Roll no. 557).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-23T16:07:06-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A003) offered by Mr. Flores.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6741-6744, H6755-6756" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6741" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-23">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
