<bill session="114" type="h" number="4347" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:32Z">
  <state datetime="2016-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Debt Collection Practices Harmonization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act to extend the provisions of that Act to cover a debt collector who is collecting debt owed to a State or local government, to index award amounts under such Act for inflation, to provide for civil injunctive relief for violations of such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Debt Collection Practices Harmonization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001137"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-01-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-01-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Debt Collection Practices Harmonization Act

This bill amends the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act to:

 cover debt owed to a state, and require the Consumer Financial Protection Board to prescribe a percentage increase based on the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers in order to index annually for inflation civil damages awarded for abusive practices by a debt collector. The bill also empowers the court to award injunctive relief for violations of the Act.

The Department of the Treasury may not contract with any debt collector or other private party to recoup overpayments of disaster assistance to an individual or household by the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
