<bill session="114" type="h" number="1329" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:38Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ATF Elimination Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To abolish the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, transfer its functions relating to the Federal firearms, explosives, and arson laws, violent crime, and domestic terrorism to the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and transfer its functions relating to the Federal alcohol and tobacco smuggling laws to the Drug Enforcement Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">ATF Elimination Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000587" joined="2015-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2015-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Alcoholic beverages"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA)"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-04T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">ATF Elimination Act

 Rescinds the hiring authority of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives (ATF).

Requires ATF, the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), and the Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA) to jointly develop and submit a plan for winding up the affairs of ATF that, without compromising core functions, eliminates and reduces duplicative, unnecessary functions or waste.

Requires the FBI to transmit to the General Services Administration a report that specifies the property to be transferred to the FBI pursuant to this Act that the FBI has determined will not be needed.

Abolishes ATF.

Transfers ATF functions relating to the investigation and enforcement of: (1) criminal and regulatory violations of the federal firearms, explosives, and arson laws, and the investigation of violent crime and domestic terrorism to the Attorney General, who shall delegate them to the FBI; and (2) criminal and regulatory violations of the federal alcohol and tobacco smuggling laws to the Attorney General, who shall delegate them to the DEA.

Transfers: (1) the contracts, liabilities, records, property, and other assets and interests associated with such transferred functions to the Attorney General for appropriate allocation; and (2) personnel employed in connection with the transferred functions to the Attorney General.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
