<bill session="113" type="h" number="5311" updated="2016-10-25T16:15:51Z">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rocky Mountain Recreation and Wilderness Preservation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To designate certain lands in the State of Colorado as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System, to designate the Tenmile Recreation Management Area and Porcupine Gulch Protection Area, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Rocky Mountain Recreation and Wilderness Preservation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000598"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-07-31T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Rocky Mountain Recreation and Wilderness Preservation Act - Amends the Colorado Wilderness Act of 1993 to designate certain federal lands in the White River National Forest in Colorado as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System as follows:

 approximately 6,349 acres identified as the Proposed Ute Pass Wilderness, Proposed Acorn Creek Wilderness, and Proposed Ptarmigan Additions Wilderness; approximately 5,172 acres as the Hoosier Ridge Wilderness; approximately 7,577 acres as the Tenmile Wilderness; approximately 9,338 acres as the Williams Fork Wilderness; approximately 3,942 acres as a part of the Holy Cross Wilderness; and approximately 7,082 acres, identified as the Proposed Freeman Creek Wilderness and Proposed Spraddle Creek Wilderness, as part of the Eagles Nest Wilderness. Designates certain federal lands in such forest, comprising approximately 2,338 acres and identified as the Proposed Spraddle Creek Potential Wilderness as a potential wilderness area, and as specified, to be designated as wilderness and incorporated in and deemed to be a part of the Eagles Nest Wilderness.

Designates certain federal lands in such forest, comprising approximately 11,417 acres, as the Tenmile Recreation Management Area.

Designates certain federal lands in such forest, comprising approximately 5,204 acres, as the Porcupine Gulch Protection Area.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
