<bill session="115" type="h" number="1728" updated="2019-04-18T16:05:31Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To modify the boundaries of the Morley Nelson Snake River Birds of Prey National Conservation Area, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To modify the boundaries of the Morley Nelson Snake River Birds of Prey National Conservation Area, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001148"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000573" joined="2017-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water, Oceans, and Wildlife" code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2104"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill modifies the boundary of the Morley Nelson Snake River Birds of Prey National Conservation Area in Idaho to: (1) include specified Bureau of Land Management (BLM) administered land and certain Bureau of Reclamation administered land, and (2) exclude specified lands identified as the Segment 8 Revised Proposed Route and as the Segment 9 Revised Proposed Route.

The Department of the Interior shall issue to Gateway West (a high-voltage transmission line project in Idaho and Wyoming) a right-of-way for such proposed routes, which is to be used for the construction and maintenance of transmission lines and for access roads and activities related to fire prevention and suppression, subject to construction mitigation and conservation requirements.

Interior shall: (1) administer the BLM and Reclamation administered lands as part of the National Landscape Conservation System, and (2) continue to administer the proposed route lands as lands that are not included in the conservation area.

The bill transfers from Reclamation to the BLM administrative jurisdiction over the Reclamation administered lands.

Interior shall amend the management plan for the conservation area in order to address the long-term management of the BLM and Reclamation administered lands, including for livestock grazing, hunting, fishing, and motorized access.

Specified federal land in the Cotterel Wind Power Project area may not be used for producing electricity from wind.

Interior shall establish a Bureau of Land Management Foundation and grant it the same authorities granted to the National Park Foundation for National Park Service activities, for the purpose of providing opportunities for the BLM to address specific challenges that may be better addressed with the support of a foundation.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
