<bill session="114" type="s" number="1860" updated="2018-06-02T06:58:16Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FIRST Freedom Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Further Independence of Religion for Security and Tolerance Freedom Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect and promote international religious freedom.</title>
    <title type="display">FIRST Freedom Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2015-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2015-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2015-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5533-5537" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3194"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Further Independence of Religion for Security and Tolerance Freedom Act of 2015 or the FIRST Freedom Act

This bill expresses the sense of Congress that:

 the protection and promotion of international human rights, including religious freedom, should be an important U.S. priority; and the United States should pursue new strategies to deter and punish the perpetrators of severe violations of religious freedom, including non-state actors, and to protect the victims of such violations. The Immigration and Nationality Act is amended to authorize the Department of State to designate refugee groups:

 whose resettlement in the United States is justified by humanitarian concerns or is otherwise in the national interest; and who share common characteristics that identify them as targets of persecution on account of race, religion, nationality, membership in a particular social group, or political opinion, or having been so identified share a common need for resettlement. The one-year time limit for filing an asylum claim is eliminated. A two-year window is provided for certain aliens to reopen a claim denied because of failure to file within one year.

The U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom is authorized to study: (1) whether immigration officers are engaging in improper conduct, and (2) the impact of interview delays on asylum claims.

The International Religious Freedom Act is amended to authorize appropriations for the Commission through FY2017.

Any alien who was responsible for, or directly carried out, at any time, particularly severe violations of religious freedom is inadmissible or deportable. (Current law is limited to foreign government officials who commit such acts.)

The federal criminal code is amended to require that any person who outside the United States commits, or attempts or conspires to commit, religious persecution against a U.S. person: (1) be fined, imprisoned for not more than 20 years, or both; and (2) if the death of any person results from the violation, be fined and imprisoned for any term of years or for life.

No person may be prosecuted, tried, or punished for such a violation unless the indictment or the information is filed within 10 years after commission of the offense.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
