<bill session="114" type="h" number="3336" updated="2019-02-13T17:31:14Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Colorado Wilderness Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To designate certain lands in the State of Colorado as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Colorado Wilderness Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000197"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-08-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-08-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water, Oceans, and Wildlife" code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Colorado Wilderness Act of 2015

 Amends the Colorado Wilderness Act of 1993 to add specified lands in Colorado managed by the Bureau of Land Management (proposed as the Powderhorn Wilderness Addition) of the Department of the Interior to the Powderhorn Wilderness.

Designates specified lands in Colorado managed by the BLM or the U.S. Forest Service of the Department of Agriculture as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System.

Designates specified lands in Colorado administered by the BLM, Forest Service, and Bureau of Reclamation as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System. Incorporates such lands into the West Elk Wilderness.

Allows Interior to continue authorizing competitive running events currently permitted in the Redcloud Peak Wilderness and Handies Peak Wilderness Areas.

Authorizes the Colorado Army National Guard, through the High-Altitude Army National Guard Aviation Training Site, to conduct aerial navigation training maneuver exercises over the wilderness areas designated by this Act.

Designates specified lands managed by the BLM as: (1) potential wilderness areas, and (2) as the Deep Creek Wilderness and the Pisgah Mountain Wilderness upon publication by Interior of a notice in the Federal Register that all nonconforming uses of such lands authorized by this Act for the conduct of such exercises and overflights of military helicopters in violation of the Wilderness Act have ceased.

Provides for the securing, adjudication, and use of U.S. water rights for certain of the wilderness areas designated by this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
