<bill session="114" type="s" number="1600" updated="2018-06-02T06:56:07Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Judicial Redress Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend Privacy Act remedies to citizens of certified states, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Judicial Redress Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001169"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2015-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="1428"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Judicial Redress Act of 2015

Authorizes the Department of Justice (DOJ) to designate foreign countries or regional economic integration organizations whose natural citizens may bring civil actions under the Privacy Act of 1974 against certain U.S. government agencies for purposes of accessing, amending, or redressing unlawful disclosures of records maintained by an agency.

Allows DOJ, with the concurrence of the Department of State, the Department of the Treasury, and the Department of Homeland Security, to designate countries or organizations whose citizens may pursue such civil remedies if the person's country or organization has appropriate privacy protections for sharing information with the United States to prevent, investigate, detect, or prosecute criminal offenses.

Exempts DOJ's designations from judicial or administrative review.

Grants the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia exclusive jurisdiction over any claim arising under this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
