<bill session="115" type="s" number="1123" updated="2019-04-18T16:36:08Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize the Office of National Drug Control Policy, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Office of National Drug Control Policy Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Office of National Drug Control Policy Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Office of National Drug Control Policy Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2017-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Colombia"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Peru"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Office of National Drug Control Policy Reauthorization Act of 2017

This bill reauthorizes the Office of National Drug Control Policy through FY2023. It amends the definition of "demand reduction" in a National Drug Control Program to include screenings, interventions, promoting availability of and access to health care services, and support for long-term recovery from substance abuse disorders. It defines "illicit drug use," "illegal drug use," and like terms to include the illegal use of prescription drugs.

The Director of the National Drug Control Policy (Director) shall be directly responsible for demand reduction activities, supply reduction activities, and for state, local, and tribal affairs.

The Director shall require each National Drug Control Program agency to submit to the Director on an annual basis an evaluation of progress by the agency regarding implementation of drug recovery programs. The Director shall also ensure that drug recovery research is effectively disseminated by the National Drug Control Program agencies to state and local governments and nongovernmental agencies involved in demand reduction.

The President shall submit to Congress a National Drug Control Strategy, which shall set forth a comprehensive plan for the year to reduce illicit drug use and the consequences of such use by promoting prevention, early intervention, treatment, and recovery support for individuals with substance abuse disorders.

The Director shall submit to Congress a report evaluating high intensity drug trafficking areas (HIDTAs) as part of the National Drug Control Strategy, assessing drug enforcement task forces in HIDTAs, and assessing law enforcement intelligence sharing in HIDTAs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
