<bill session="114" type="h" number="1465" updated="2018-11-21T20:30:40Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medical Evaluation Parity for Servicemembers Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to provide an individual with a mental health screening before the individual enlists in the Armed Forces or is commissioned as an officer in the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Medical Evaluation Parity for Servicemembers Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000467"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2015-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000605" joined="2015-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2015-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2015-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1774"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="646"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-19T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Medical Evaluation Parity for Servicemembers Act of 2015

Directs the Secretary of the military department concerned to: (1) provide an individual with a mental health screening before such individual enlists or is commissioned as an officer in the Armed Forces, and (2) use such results as a baseline for any subsequent mental health examinations.

Prohibits the Secretary from considering the results of such screening in determining the promotion of a member of the Armed Forces.

Directs the Secretary to treat a screening in the same manner as medical records with respect to laws and regulations relating to the privacy of information.

Requires the National Institute of Mental Health of the National Institutes of Health to submit to Congress and the Department of Defense (DOD) a report on preliminary mental health screenings of members of the Armed Forces, including recommendations regarding: (1) establishing preliminary mental health screenings to establish parity with physical screenings; and (2) the composition of the mental health screening, evidenced-based best practices, and how to track changes relating to traumatic brain injuries, post-traumatic stress disorder, and other conditions.

Directs DOD and the Government Accountability Office to report on the efficacy of preliminary mental health screenings. Requires DOD to report on the efficacy of the mental health components of the physical examinations to members of the Armed Forces who are separated from active duty.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
