<bill session="114" type="h" number="2200" updated="2019-02-14T22:57:10Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-25T12:47:52-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-06-25T12:47:52-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CBRN Intelligence and Information Sharing Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">CBRN Intelligence and Information Sharing Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">CBRN Intelligence and Information Sharing Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear intelligence and information sharing functions of the Office of Intelligence and Analysis of the Department of Homeland Security and to require dissemination of information analyzed by the Department to entities with responsibilities relating to homeland security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">CBRN Intelligence and Information Sharing Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001197"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001284" joined="2015-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2015-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2015-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001181" joined="2015-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000604" joined="2015-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2015-05-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Counterterrorism and Intelligence.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Preparedness, Response and Communications.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-20">
      <text>Subcommittee on Counterterrorism and Intelligence Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-05-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-06-17">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 114-164.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-06-17" calendar="Union" number="120">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 120.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-06-23T17:09:38-04:00">
      <text>Ms. McSally moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-23T17:09:55-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4576-4578" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-23T17:09:57-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2200.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-23T17:18:23-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25T12:39:37-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4698-4699" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="389" datetime="2015-06-25T12:47:52-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 420 - 2 (Roll no. 389).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 6/23/2015 H4576" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25T12:47:53-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-07">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Intelligence and Counterterrorism" code="HSHM05" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Emergency Preparedness, Response, and Communications" code="HSHM12" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Reporting, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-25T15:10:02Z" status="Passed House amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on June 17, 2015. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

CBRN Intelligence and Information Sharing Act of 2015

 (Sec. 2) Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Office of Intelligence and Analysis of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) support homeland security-focused intelligence analysis of terrorist actors, their claims, and their plans to conduct attacks involving chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear materials against the nation and of global infectious disease, public health, food, agricultural, and veterinary issues; (2) support homeland security-focused risk analysis and risk assessments of such homeland security hazards, including the transportation of chemical, biological, nuclear, and radiological materials, by providing relevant quantitative and nonquantitative threat information; (3) leverage homeland security intelligence capabilities and structures to enhance prevention, protection, response, and recovery efforts with respect to a chemical, biological, radiological, or nuclear attack; and (4) share information and provide tailored analytical support on these threats to state, local, and tribal authorities as well as other national biosecurity and biodefense stakeholders and other federal agencies, as appropriate.

Requires the Office to coordinate with other DHS components, the Intelligence Community, and federal, state, local, and tribal authorities, including officials from high-threat areas, state and major urban area fusion centers, and local public health departments where appropriate, and enable such entities to provide recommendations on optimal information sharing mechanisms and on how they can provide information to DHS.

Directs DHS to report annually on: (1) intelligence and information sharing activities to counter the threat from attacks using chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear materials, and (2) DHS's activities in accordance with relevant intelligence strategies. Terminates this reporting requirement after the end of the five-year period beginning on this Act's enactment.

(Sec. 3) Requires DHS to ensure that homeland security information analyzed by it concerning terrorist threats is provided to state, local, tribal, and private entities and the public.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-164</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
