<bill session="115" type="h" number="6569" updated="2019-04-18T16:26:41Z">
  <state datetime="2018-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require a waiver if the installation of differently colored tiles in certain tunnel projects is expected to create additional costs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Removing Extra Transportation Infrastructure Luxury Expenses Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Removing Extra Transportation Infrastructure Luxury Expenses Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RETILE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RETILE Act</title>
    <title type="display">RETILE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000464"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-07-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Highways and Transit" code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-07-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Removing Extra Transportation Infrastructure Luxury Expenses Act or the RETILE Act

This bill prohibits a state or local government, for purposes of a project that receives public assistance disaster-related grants, from installing differently-colored tiles in a tunnel if such installation is reasonably expected to incur a higher cost than the installation of same-color tiles, and a waiver has not been obtained from the Department of Homeland Security (DHS). DHS may grant a waiver based on safety, historic preservation, or other factors.

DHS must withhold funding for a federal-aid highway project if such project uses differently colored tiles in a tunnel and the installation of such tiles is reasonably expected to incur a higher cost than the installation of same-color tiles and DHS has not issued a waiver.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
