<bill session="114" type="h" number="2860" updated="2019-01-09T21:26:08Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Major General David F. Wherley, Jr. District of Columbia National Guard Retention and College Access Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Mayor of the District of Columbia to establish a District of Columbia National Guard Educational Assistance Program to encourage the enlistment and retention of persons in the District of Columbia National Guard by providing financial assistance to enable members of the National Guard of the District of Columbia to attend undergraduate, vocational, or technical courses.</title>
    <title type="display">To direct the Mayor of the District of Columbia to establish a District of Columbia National Guard Educational Assistance Program to encourage the enlistment and retention of persons in the District of Columbia National Guard by providing financial assistance to enable members of the National Guard of the District of Columbia to attend undergraduate, vocational, or technical courses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E947"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends the District of Columbia Code to add the Major General David F. Wherley, Jr. District of Columbia National Guard Retention and College Access Act.

Directs the Mayor of the District of Columbia, in coordination with the commanding general of the District of Columbia National Guard, to establish a program that allows the Mayor to provide educational assistance for a first undergraduate, masters, vocational, or technical degree or certification to a member of the District of Columbia National Guard who:

 has satisfactorily completed initial active duty service, agrees to serve for at least six years, and is not receiving a Reserve Officer Training Corps scholarship.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
