<bill session="115" type="h" number="6248" updated="2019-04-18T16:25:37Z">
  <state datetime="2018-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to require radio and television broadcasters to provide free broadcasting time for political advertising, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fairness in Political Advertising Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fairness in Political Advertising Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Fairness in Political Advertising Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2018-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2018-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E935"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-06-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Fairness in Political Advertising Act of 2018

This bill amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require television broadcasting station licensees and cable operators to make available annually free broadcast or cable time for political advertising. For political candidates in a statewide or national election whose parties received more than 2% of total votes in the most recent statewide or national election, the bill requires such television broadcast station licensees and cable operators to allot an equal amount (at least two hours) of free broadcast time each even-numbered year to each candidate. The bill also sets forth standards for allotting free broadcast time during the hours of 7:00 p.m. to 10:00 p.m., during specific periods before an election, and at comparable times of day and days of the week to candidates for the same office.

Nothing in this bill, and no use of allotted free broadcast time, shall be construed to restrict a candidate's right to purchase other broadcast time.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
