<bill session="114" type="s" number="2751" updated="2018-08-16T23:10:42Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Support Startup Businesses Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to create a pilot program permitting businesses receiving Phase II awards under the SBIR program to use not more than 5 percent of the amount of the award for commercialization-related services.</title>
    <title type="display">Support Startup Businesses Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2016-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2016-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Support Startup Businesses Act of 2016

This bill amends the Small Business Act to authorize a small business concern receiving a Phase II award (grants of up to $1 million, for up to 2 years, to facilitate expansion of Phase I startup results) under the Small Business Innovation Research program, for FY2017-FY2019, to use up to 5% of the Phase II award for commercialization-related services, including market validation, intellectual property protection, business model development, market research, and other reasonable services that support market entry.

These services may be performed directly by the small business concern or obtained from a public or private nonprofit organization, a state agency, or another state-funded entity that facilitates or accelerates the commercialization of technologies or assists in the creation and growth of private enterprises that are commercializing technology.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
