<amendment session="113" chamber="h" number="918" updated="2016-10-25T16:44:11Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4870" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2014-06-19T22:57:11-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000556"/>
  <offered datetime="2014-06-19"/>
  <description>At the end of the bill (before the short title), insert the following:    SEC.___. None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to transfer aircraft (including unmanned aerial vehicles), armored vehicles, grenade launchers, silencers, toxicological agents (including chemical agents, biological agents, and associated equipment), launch vehicles, guided missiles, ballistic missiles, rockets, torpedoes, bombs, mines, or nuclear weapons (as identified for demilitarization purposes outlined in Department of Defense Manual 4160.28) through the Department of Defense Excess Personal Property Program established pursuant to section 1033 of Public Law 104-201, the "National Defense Authorization Act For Fiscal Year 1997".</description>
  <purpose>An amendment to prohibit use of funds to transfer aircraft (including unmanned aerial vehicles), armored vehicles, grenade launchers, silencers, toxicological agents, launch vehicles, guided missiles, ballistic missiles, rockets, torpedoes, bombs, mines, or nuclear weapons through the DOD Excess Personal Property Program established pursuant to the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1997.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2014-06-19T22:57:11-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="329">
      <text>On agreeing to the Grayson amendment (A052) Failed by recorded vote: 62 - 355 (Roll no. 329).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19T19:32:05-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A052) offered by Mr. Grayson.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5531-5532, H5553-5554" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5531" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19"/>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19T22:57:11-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19T22:57:11-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19T22:57:11-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Grayson amendment (A052) Failed by recorded vote: 62 - 355 (Roll no. 329).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19T19:32:05-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A052) offered by Mr. Grayson.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5531-5532, H5553-5554" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5531" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
