<bill session="114" type="s" number="1068" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:55Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Power Act to protect the bulk-power system from cyber security threats.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Federal Power Act to protect the bulk-power system from cyber security threats.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000584"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2015-04-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-09">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2012"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2089"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill amends the Federal Power Act to authorize the Secretary of Energy to require an entity that owns, controls, or operates a bulk-power system facility to take whatever actions the Secretary determines will best avert or mitigate a cyber security threat pursuant to a written notice from the President that immediate action is necessary to protect the bulk-power system from such threat.

The Secretary is encouraged to coordinate with Canadian and Mexican officials responsible for the protection of cyber security of the interconnected North American electricity grid.

The Secretary, before exercising this authority, shall consult about the cyber security threat with: (1) the entities indicated, (2) the Electric Reliability Organization, (3) the Electricity Sub-sector Coordinating Council, and (4) other appropriate federal officials.

The Federal Energy Regulatory Commission shall establish a mechanism that permits owners, operators, or users of the bulk-power system to seek recovery of prudently incurred costs required to implement actions ordered by the Secretary.

Rates or charges approved under this mechanism must be just and reasonable, and neither unduly discriminatory nor preferential.

Emergency orders under the bill are limited to a 30-day period unless the Secretary: (1) provides interested persons an opportunity to submit written data, recommendations, and arguments; and (2) affirms, amends (for up to 90 days), or repeals the order.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
