<bill session="114" type="h" number="1254" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:38Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Recidivism Clarification Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter 44 of title 18, United States Code, to clarify the circumstances under which the enhanced penalty provisions for subsequent convictions apply.</title>
    <title type="display">Recidivism Clarification Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000185"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-04T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Recidivism Clarification Act of 2015

 Amends the federal criminal code, with respect to additional penalties for using or carrying a firearm in the commission of a crime of violence or drug trafficking crime, to: (1) modify the penalty to require an additional prison term of not more than 5 years, not more than 7 years if the firearm is brandished, and not more than 10 years if the firearm is discharged (currently, not less than 5, 7, or 10 years respectively); (2) allow a prison term for any term of years (currently, minimum mandatory term of 25 years) for a person who has a prior conviction that has become final; (3) require an additional prison term of not more than 15 years (currently, not less than 15 years) for using, carrying, or possessing armor piercing ammunition during the commission of a crime of violence or drug trafficking crime; and (4) eliminate the death penalty for cases in which the use of such ammunition results in a death.

Makes this Act applicable to conduct engaged in and sentences imposed before, on, or after the date of this Act's enactment.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
