<bill session="114" type="s" number="2117" updated="2018-06-02T07:10:28Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prevent certain discriminatory taxation of natural gas pipeline property.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to prevent certain discriminatory taxation of natural gas pipeline property.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7103-7104" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3663"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Property tax"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-01T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill prohibits states, political subdivisions, and any other taxing authority from: (1) assessing natural gas pipeline property at a value that has a higher ratio to its true market value than the ratio used to assess other commercial and industrial property in the same assessment jurisdiction, (2) levying or collecting a tax on such an assessment, (3) levying or collecting an ad valorem property tax on natural gas pipeline property at a rate that exceeds the rate applicable to other commercial and industrial property in the same assessment jurisdiction, or (4) imposing any other tax that discriminates against a natural gas pipeline providing transportation or storage subject to the jurisdiction of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.

The bill: (1) grants jurisdiction to U.S. district courts to prevent violations of this Act, and (2) sets forth criteria governing relief for claims relating to violations of this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
