<bill session="114" type="s" number="883" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:54Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Mineral Security Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to facilitate the reestablishment of domestic, critical mineral designation, assessment, production, manufacturing, recycling, analysis, forecasting, workforce, education, and research capabilities in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">American Mineral Security Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2015-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2015-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2015-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-12">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 114-141.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2012"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">American Mineral Security Act of 2015

 This bill amends the National Materials and Minerals Policy, Research and Development Act of 1980 to direct the President to: (1) establish an analytical and forecasting capability for identifying critical mineral market factors so as to avoid supply shortages, mitigate price volatility, and prepare for demand growth and other market shifts; and (2) encourage federal agencies to facilitate development and production of domestic resources to meet national critical material and minerals needs.

The Director of the U.S. Geological Survey (Director) shall publish in the Federal Register a methodology for determining which minerals qualify as critical minerals, and review it at least every two years.

The Director is also required, within four years after enactment of this Act, to complete a comprehensive national assessment of each critical mineral.

Both the Bureau of Land Management of the Department of the Interior and the Forest Service of the Department of Agricultureshall: (1) complete federal permitting and review processes governing critical mineral production on federal land with maximum efficiency and effectiveness, and (2) report to Congress on additional measures and implementation options.

 Prescribes a Federal Register notice process for the issuance of a critical mineral exploration or mine permit.

The Department of Energy shall conduct research and development to promote: (1) the production, use, and recycling of critical minerals throughout the supply chain; and (2) develop alternatives to critical minerals that do not occur in significant abundance in the United States.

The Director shall publish an annual report that includes, as part of the Mineral Commodity Summaries, a comprehensive review of critical mineral production, consumption, and recycling patterns.

The Department of Labor (DOL) must assess the domestic availability of technically trained personnel with the necessary skillset for critical mineral activities.

The Director and the DOL shall jointly arrange with the National Academy of Sciences and the National Academy of Engineering to coordinate with the National Science Foundation on a study to design an interdisciplinary program on critical minerals that will support the critical mineral supply chain and increase domestic critical mineral development.

The Director and the DOL shall also jointly conduct a competitive grant program for institutions of higher education to implement integrated critical mineral education, training, and workforce development programs.

The National Critical Materials Act of 1984 is repealed.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
