<bill session="114" type="h" number="3087" updated="2019-04-11T15:42:41Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to assure educational stability for children in foster care, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Education Stability for Foster Youth Act</title>
    <title type="display">Education Stability for Foster Youth Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000096"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001270" joined="2015-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1177"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1639"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Education Stability for Foster Youth Act

This bill amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require a state plan for academic content and achievement standards to describe how the state will ensure the educational stability of children in foster care. Specifically, a state plan must include assurances that: (1) a foster child will remain or be enrolled in the child&#8217;s school of origin absent a determination that such enrollment is not in the child&#8217;s best interest; (2) if such a determination is made, the child will be immediately enrolled in a new school, which must immediately contact the child&#8217;s previous school to obtain relevant records; and (3) the state will designate a point of contact for child welfare agencies, who shall also oversee implementation of the state&#8217;s responsibilities under the bill.

Relatedly, a local educational agency (LEA) plan must provide assurances that the LEA will develop and implement procedures governing the provision and funding of transportation services necessary to maintain a foster child&#8217;s enrollment in the child&#8217;s school of origin.

This bill amends the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act to alter the definition of &#8220;homeless children and youths&#8221; to no longer include children who are awaiting foster care placement.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
