<bill session="114" type="h" number="4015" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:21Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cardiomyopathy Health Education, Awareness, Risk Assessment, and Training in the Schools (HEARTS) Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title III of the Public Health Service Act to authorize and support the creation of cardiomyopathy education, awareness, and risk assessment materials and resources by the Secretary of Health and Human Services through the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the dissemination of such materials and resources by State educational agencies to identify more at-risk families.</title>
    <title type="display">Cardiomyopathy Health Education, Awareness, Risk Assessment, and Training in the Schools (HEARTS) Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000034"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-16T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Cardiomyopathy Health Education, Awareness, Risk Assessment, and Training in the Schools (HEARTS) Act of 2015

This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), in conjunction with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to develop, publish, and disseminate to school personnel, state and local health departments, health professionals, and others public education and awareness materials and resources that include: (1) background information to increase education and awareness of cardiomyopathy (a disease of the heart muscle) among school administrators, educators, and families; (2) a cardiomyopathy risk assessment worksheet for use by parents, guardians, or other caregivers; (3) guidelines regarding the placement of automated external defibrillators in schools and child care centers; (4) training information on defibrillators and cardiopulmonary resuscitation (commonly known as "CPR"); and (5) recommendations for how schools and child care centers can develop and implement a cardiac emergency response plan.

The CDC must update these materials and resources as necessary and, in support of such effort, HHS is encouraged to establish an advisory panel and engage in a memorandum of understanding or cooperative agreement with a national nonprofit advocacy organization with expertise in cardiomyopathy.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
