<bill session="114" type="s" number="1443" updated="2019-06-21T11:07:12Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Demonstration Act of 1992 to facilitate the ability of Indian tribes to integrate the employment, training, and related services from diverse Federal sources, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Consolidation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Consolidation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Consolidation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Consolidation Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2015-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2015-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-10-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-03-09">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Barrasso without amendment. With written report No. 114-225.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-03-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="385">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 385.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="2016-07-14" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5187-5190" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5187-5190" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-07-15">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-18T14:35:24-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-18T16:42:13-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="329"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T14:39:26Z" status="Passed Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Consolidation Act of 2015

 (Sec. 2) This bill amends the Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Demonstration Act of 1992 to rename the Act to the Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Act of 1992 and to revise the program that provides for the integration of employment, training, and related services programs for Indian tribes.

(Sec. 6) The bill revises the types of programs that may be integrated. (Sec. 8) The bill revises the process for: (1) federal agencies to grant or deny a tribe's request to waive statutory, regulatory, or administrative requirements to efficiently implement an integration plan; and (2) the Department of the Interior to approve or disapprove an integration plan. A tribe is granted certain hearing and appeal rights if Interior disapproves its plan.

 (Sec. 10) Tribal authority to use funds to place participants in training positions with employers is revised.

 (Sec. 13) The Bureau of Indian Affairs must receive and distribute funds for use in accordance with an approved integration plan.

(Sec. 14) Funds transferred to a tribe must be treated as non-federal funds for purposes of meeting matching requirements. Civil liability limitations apply to approved integration plans.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-225</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
