<bill session="115" type="h" number="6196" updated="2019-04-18T16:25:27Z">
  <state datetime="2018-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require local educational agencies to implement a policy on allergy bullying in schools.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alerting Local Leaders and Ensuring Responsible Guidelines for Youth Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alerting Local Leaders and Ensuring Responsible Guidelines for Youth Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ALLERGY Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ALLERGY Act</title>
    <title type="display">ALLERGY Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001090"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Allergies"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-06-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Alerting Local Leaders and Ensuring Responsible Guidelines for Youth Act or the ALLERGY Act

This bill amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to require a local educational agency (LEA), as a condition of receiving funds under the ESEA, to establish and implement a policy on allergy bullying that requires schools to:

 educate students, school personnel, and parents about allergy bullying; clearly define what the punishment or response may be for violating rules against allergy bullying; encourage each victim of allergy bullying to report the bullying to school personnel; and comply with&#160;the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act and the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 in carrying out these requirements. An LEA shall&#160;certify annually that it has established and implemented such a policy.

"Allergy bullying" is an&#160;unwanted, aggressive behavior by a student toward another student who has&#160;an allergy, including: (1) a real or perceived imbalance of power due to the student's allergy; and (2) actions such as making threats, spreading rumors, making physical or verbal attacks, and purposefully excluding the student from a group.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
