<bill session="115" type="hr" number="446" updated="2019-04-18T15:54:11Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-26">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Of inquiry requesting the President and directing the Attorney General to transmit, respectively, certain documents to the House of Representatives relating to the removal of former Federal Bureau of Investigation Director James Comey.</title>
    <title type="display">Of inquiry requesting the President and directing the Attorney General to transmit, respectively, certain documents to the House of Representatives relating to the removal of former Federal Bureau of Investigation Director James Comey.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000298"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001270" joined="2017-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001304" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2017-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2017-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2017-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2017-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000610" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000296" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000574" joined="2017-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2017-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000535" joined="2017-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2017-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000294" joined="2017-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2017-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000391" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2017-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2017-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000480" joined="2017-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001200" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2017-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000096" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2017-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000588" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000486" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001190" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000248" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001170" joined="2017-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2017-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000510" joined="2017-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001193" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000474" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000081" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000187" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2017-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-07-26" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 15 - 13.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-09-08">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 115-300.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-09-08" calendar="House" number="82">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 82.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="unknown" number="488"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Senate Select Committee on Intelligence"/>
    <term name="Sound recording"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-09-08T11:40:32Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">Requests the President and directs the Department of Justice (DOJ) to transmit to the House of Representatives copies of any document or communication in their possession that refers or relates to the firing of the former Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) Director James B. Comey in the following respects:

 then-Attorney General Loretta Lynch directing Comey to refer to the investigation into the handling of classified data and use of an unauthorized email server by former Secretary of State Hillary Clinton as a matter, rather than a criminal investigation; Comey's leaks to Columbia University law professor Daniel Richman regarding conversations between Lynch and President Trump and how the leaked information was released to lead to the appointment of special counsel Robert Mueller; the propriety and consequence of immunity deals given to Cheryl Mills, Heather Samuelson, John Bentel, and potentially others by the FBI during the criminal investigation into Clinton's conduct; Comey's decision to usurp Lynch's authority in announcing that criminal charges would not be brought against Clinton regarding her use of a private email server and handling of classified information; Comey's knowledge and impressions of any ex-parte conversation between Lynch and former President Bill Clinton on June 27, 2016, at a Phoenix airport on a private jet; Comey's knowledge of the company Fusion GPS and its creation of a dossier on Donald Trump; any potential leaks by Comey to author Michael Schmidt dating back to 1993; Comey's knowledge of the purchase of a majority stake in Uranium One by Rosatom; Comey's refusal to investigate Hillary Clinton regarding selling access to the Department of State through Clinton Foundation donations, Huma Abedin's dual employment at such entities simultaneously, or utilization of the State Department to further paid speaking opportunities for her husband; any collusion between Comey and Robert Mueller; whether Comey had any knowledge of efforts made by any federal agency to monitor communications of then-candidate Donald Trump, to assess Comey's knowledge about the unmasking of individuals on Donald Trump's campaign team, transition team, or both, to assess the role that former National Security Adviser Susan Rice played in the unmasking of such individuals, or to reveal the purpose served by unmasking any individuals serving on the staff of Donald Trump; and whether Comey had any knowledge of the dissemination of unredacted information to various intelligence agencies and of any attempts to use surveillance of Donald Trump to damage the credibility of his campaign, presidency, or both.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-300</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
