<bill session="115" type="h" number="1282" updated="2019-04-18T16:03:26Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-21T15:03:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-06-21T15:03:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish the Acquisition Review Board in the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish Acquisition Review Boards in the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">DHS Acquisition Review Board Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">DHS Acquisition Review Board Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">DHS Acquisition Review Board Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">DHS Acquisition Review Board Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DHS Acquisition Review Board Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DHS Acquisition Review Board Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">DHS Acquisition Review Board Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000580"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2017-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-03-08" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-03-23">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 115-57.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-03-23" calendar="Union" number="32">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 32.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-06-21T14:52:16-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Garrett moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-21T14:52:43-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5020-5022" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-21T14:52:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1282.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2017-06-21T15:03:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5020-5021" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-06-21T15:03:02-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-21T15:03:04-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Reporting, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="886"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2825"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-21T14:53:19Z" status="Passed House amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on March 23, 2017. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

DHS Acquisition Review Board Act of 2017

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security of 2002 to require the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish an Acquisition Review Board to strengthen accountability and uniformity within the DHS acquisition review process, review major acquisition programs (programs estimated to require a total expenditure of at least $300 million over their life cycle costs), and review the use of best practices.

The board shall convene at DHS's discretion and whenever: (1) a major acquisition program requires authorization to proceed from one acquisition decision event to another, is in breach of its approved requirements, or requires additional review; or (2) a non-major acquisition program requires review.

The board's responsibilities are to:

 determine whether a proposed acquisition has met the requirements of key phases of the acquisition life cycle framework and is able to proceed to the next phase and eventual full production and deployment; oversee whether a proposed acquisition's business strategy, resources, management, and accountability is executable and aligned to strategic initiatives; support the acquisition decision authority in determining the appropriate direction at key acquisition decision events; conduct systematic reviews to ensure that acquisitions are progressing in compliance with the approved documents for their current acquisition phases; review the acquisition documents of each major acquisition program to ensure the reliability of underlying data; and ensure that practices are implemented to require consideration of tradeoffs among cost, schedule, and performance objectives as part of the process for developing requirements for major acquisition programs prior to initiating the second acquisition decision event. If the person exercising acquisition decision authority over a major acquisition program approves such program to proceed into the planning phase before such program has a DHS-approved acquisition program baseline, DHS shall: (1) create and approve a baseline report regarding such approval; (2) notify Congress within 7 days after an acquisition decision memorandum is signed; and (3) within 60 days after such signing, report on the rationale for such decision and a plan of action to require an acquisition program baseline for such program.

DHS shall report annually to specified congressional committees through FY2022 on the board's activities, including information on:

 any acquisition decision memoranda for each meeting of the board, results of the systematic reviews, results of acquisition document reviews, and activities to ensure that practices are adopted and implemented throughout DHS regarding such tradeoffs.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-57</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
