<bill session="115" type="s" number="2867" updated="2019-07-16T21:20:11Z">
  <state datetime="2018-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the Junior Reserve Officers' Training Corps programs, to authorize an expansion of their presence in low-income, rural, and underserved areas of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">JROTC Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">JROTC Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">JROTC Opportunities for Transformational Change Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">JROTC Opportunities for Transformational Change Act</title>
    <title type="display">JROTC Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000437"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-05-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-05-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">JROTC Opportunities for Transformational Change Act or the JROTC Act

 This bill provides that if a military department is notified by a local educational agency of the intent of the agency to close its Junior Reserve Officers' Training Corps (JROTC) unit, the military department shall offer the agency the option of converting the program to a National Defense Cadet Corps program unit in lieu of closing the unit.

The military departments shall: (1) undertake initiatives designed to promote flexibility in the hiring and compensation of instructors for the JROTC program under the jurisdiction of such departments; and (2) take appropriate actions to provide so-called regional directors of such programs located at remote rural schools enhanced discretion in the allocation and use of funds for travel in connection with program activities.

The Department of Defense shall take appropriate actions to standardize the data collected and maintained on such programs in order to facilitate and enhance the collection and analysis of such data.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
