<bill session="113" type="h" number="644" updated="2018-06-05T16:03:31Z">
  <state datetime="2013-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Delaware River Basin Conservation Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish a program to build on and help coordinate funding for restoration and protection efforts of the 4-State Delaware River Basin region, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Delaware River Basin Conservation Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001083"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000210" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001269" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001227" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000604" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000179" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000451" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000372" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000549" joined="2013-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000564" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001032" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000567" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000554" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001181" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001188" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000594" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001162" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000522" joined="2013-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2013-03-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" code="HSII22" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2306"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Delaware"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-02-13T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Delaware River Basin Conservation Act of 2013 - Requires the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service to establish a Delaware River Basin restoration program, under which the Director shall: (1) draw on management plans for the Basin or portions of the Basin and work in consultation with applicable management entities, including representatives of the Partnership for the Delaware Estuary, the Delaware River Basin Commission, the federal government, other state and local governments, and regional and nonprofit organizations, to identify, prioritize, and implement restoration and protection activities within the Basin; and (2) adopt a Basin-wide strategy that supports the implementation of a shared set of science-based restoration and protection activities, targets cost-effective conservation projects, supports measurable conservation efforts, and maximizes conservation outcomes with no net gain of federal full-time equivalent employees.

Defines "Basin" as the four-state Delaware Basin region, including all of Delaware Bay and portions of Delaware, New Jersey, New York, and Pennsylvania located in the Delaware River watershed.

Requires the Director to establish the Delaware River Basin restoration grant program to provide competitive matching grants to carry out the restoration program. Requires the Director to develop criteria to ensure that funded activities: (1) restore or protect fish and wildlife and their habitats; (2) improve or protect water quality by reducing pollutants and restoring headwater areas and drinking water basins; (3) improve the management of water volume and mitigation of flood damage to support the ecological needs of fish and wildlife and their habitats; (4) include priority needs or actions identified in the Basin-wide strategy; and/or (5) include restoration and protection activities with multiple benefits in the Basin, including habitat, water quality, and flood damage mitigation. Limits the federal share of the total cost of a funded project to 50%. Authorizes the Director to contract with the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation or another organization that offers grant management services.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
