<bill session="115" type="h" number="5399" updated="2019-04-18T16:21:34Z">
  <state datetime="2018-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to clarify that grants made pursuant to the Urban Area Security Initiative and the State Homeland Security Grant Program may be used to increase the preparedness of high-risk State, local, territorial, and tribal governments against weapons of mass destruction and biological and chemical attacks, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Civil Defense Preparedness Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Civil Defense Preparedness Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Civil Defense Preparedness Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001245" joined="2018-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000580" joined="2018-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001050" joined="2018-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000600" joined="2018-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2018-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-03-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Preparedness, Response and Communications.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Emergency Preparedness, Response, and Communications" code="HSHM12" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-03-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Civil Defense Preparedness Act of 2018

This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize the use of grants under the Urban Area Security Initiative (UASI) and the State Homeland Security Grant Program (SHSGP) to assist high-risk urban areas and high-risk states, respectively, to increase preparedness against rocket-propelled or other forms of kinetically-delivered weapons of mass destruction (WMD), including nuclear, biological, and chemical attacks.

The bill includes a rocket-propelled or other form of kinetically-delivered WMD among the types of threats to critical infrastructure sectors and to U.S. populations that the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) must assess.

FEMA must permit a grant recipient under the UASI and the SHSGP to use grant funds for joint projects with governmental entities for the procurement of WMD protective equipment and nuclear weapons attack building reinforcement.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
