<bill session="113" type="h" number="421" updated="2018-06-05T16:01:13Z">
  <state datetime="2013-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COPS Improvement and Reauthorization Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to enhance the COPS ON THE BEAT grant program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">COPS Improvement and Reauthorization Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000578"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000210" joined="2013-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001271" joined="2013-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2013-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000617" joined="2014-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000292" joined="2014-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001051" joined="2014-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001032" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2013-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000554" joined="2013-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000096" joined="2013-01-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, And Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2254"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-01-25T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">COPS Improvement and Reauthorization Act of 2013 - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to modify the public safety and community policing grant program (COPS ON THE BEAT grant program) to: (1) establish within the Department of Justice (DOJ), under the general authority of the Attorney General, the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services to be headed by a Director; and (2) authorize the Attorney General to carry out more than one such program.

Repeals provisions authorizing: (1) the Attorney General to give preferential consideration to applications for hiring and rehiring additional career law enforcement officers that involve a non-federal contribution exceeding a 25% minimum; and (2) the use of such grants to develop and implement either innovative programs to permit members of the community to assist state, tribal, and local law enforcement agencies in the prevention of crime in the community or new administrative and managerial systems to facilitate the adoption of community-oriented policing as an organization-wide philosophy.

Authorizes the use of such grants to: (1) hire school resource officers and establish local partnerships to enhance school safety and to combat crime, gangs, drug activities, and other problems in elementary and secondary schools; (2) establish and implement innovative programs to reduce and prevent illegal drug manufacturing, distribution, and use; (3) meet emerging law enforcement needs; (4) hire former members of the Armed Forces to serve as career law enforcement officers for deployment in community-oriented policing; and (5) develop new technologies to assist state and local law enforcement agencies in crime prevention and training.

Requires an application for a grant for officers performing homeland security duties to explain how the applicant intends to coordinate with federal law enforcement in support of the applicant's homeland security mission.

Increases the limit on grant funding provided for hiring or rehiring a career law enforcement officer, unless the Attorney General grants a waiver, from $75,000 to $125,000.

Extends the authorization of appropriations for the program for FY2013-FY2017.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
