<bill session="115" type="h" number="4622" updated="2019-04-18T16:18:56Z">
  <state datetime="2017-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reduce the number of preventable deaths and injuries caused by underride crashes, to improve motor carrier and passenger motor vehicle safety, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Underrides Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Underrides Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Stop Underrides Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001112" joined="2018-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2017-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000623" joined="2017-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2018-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2018-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000127" joined="2017-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2018-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000523" joined="2018-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-12-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1689"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Highways and Transit" code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="2219"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-12-12T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop Underrides Act of 2017

This bill amends federal transportation law to require the Department of Transportation (DOT) to issue a final rule to require the installation of rear underride guards that meet a specified performance standard on all trailers, semi-trailers, and single unit trucks with a gross vehicle weight rating of more than 10,000 pounds that are manufactured on or after the effective date of the rule.

DOT shall issue a final rule requiring the installation of side underride guards that meet a specified performance standard on all trailers, semi-trailers, and single unit trucks with a gross vehicle rating of more than 10,000 pounds manufactured on or after the effective date of the rule.

DOT shall issue a final rule requiring all commercial motor vehicles with a gross vehicle weight rating of more than 10,000 pounds manufactured on or after the effective date of the rule to be equipped with front underride guards. It shall complete research on equipping commercial motor vehicles with a gross weight rating of more than 10,000 pounds with a front underride guard to prevent trucks from overriding the passenger vehicle and submit to the congressional transportation committees a report on such research.

The bill sets forth provisions regarding retrofit and maintenance requirements, and requires post-accident inspections and pre-trip inspections by drivers.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
