<bill session="113" type="h" number="1041" updated="2016-10-25T16:00:27Z">
  <state datetime="2013-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PRE-K Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Resources Early for Kids Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to improve early education.</title>
    <title type="display">PRE-K Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000309"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001287" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2013-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001171" joined="2013-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2014-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2013-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000523" joined="2014-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2013-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001162" joined="2013-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001193" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000808" joined="2013-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="identical" number="519"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-03-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Providing Resources Early for Kids Act of 2013 or the PRE-K Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to award matching grants to states to enhance or improve state-funded preschool programs.

Sets forth a grant formula favoring states that: (1) have curricula aligned with state early learning standards; (2) use nationally-established, or better, best practices for class size and teacher-to-student ratios; (3) require each teacher to have at least an associate degree in early childhood education or a related field; (4) require such programs to operate for at least a full academic year; and (5) have a plan for meeting the requirement, within five years of receiving such grant, that teachers have at least a baccalaureate degree in early childhood education or have such degree in a related field, but have also completed specialized training in early childhood education.

Directs the Secretary to establish a competitive process for awarding grants to other states that demonstrate that they will meet such requirements within two fiscal years.

Prohibits state grantees from reducing their preschool or child care expenditures.

Requires states to give priority, in using grant funds, to preschool programs in communities with high concentrations of impoverished children.

 Includes among grant uses: (1) increasing the qualifications of, and benefits provided to, teachers, teacher aides, and program directors; (2) decreasing class size and improving teacher-to-student ratios; (3) providing certain comprehensive services that support healthy child development; (4) extending program duration; (5) improving program monitoring and learning environments; and (6) providing classroom supplies or equipment.

Reserves funds for competitive grants to Indians for their preschool programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
