<bill session="114" type="h" number="3577" updated="2018-06-02T04:42:58Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Unnecessary Government Printing Reform Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 44, United States Code, to restrict the printing and distribution of paper copies of Congressional documents.</title>
    <title type="display">Unnecessary Government Printing Reform Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001191" joined="2015-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001193" joined="2015-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="614"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3300"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1888"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Unnecessary Government Printing Reform Act of 2015

This bill requires the Government Publishing Office (GPO) to make any document of the House of Representatives or Senate available only in an electronic format accessible through the Internet, and prohibits printing or distribution of a printed copy.

 Upon the request of any person to whom GPO would have been required to provide a printed copy before this requirement, GPO may print and distribute it for the person's use, except that:

 the number of printed copies may not exceed the number GPO would have provided had this requirement not been in effect; and GPO may print and distribute copies to the person only upon payment of printing and distributing costs. Any Member of Congress office shall be exempt from these requirements.

Members and committees providing documents in electronic format are deemed to have met requirements of House and Senate rules and regulations with respect to distribution of printed copies of any document (including bills or resolutions).</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
