<bill session="114" type="s" number="3256" updated="2018-06-02T07:47:39Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Education for All Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to provide assistance for developing countries to promote quality basic education and to establish the goal of all children in school and learning as an objective of the United States foreign assistance policy, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Education for All Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2016-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2016-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2016-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2016-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2016-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2016-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2016-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2016-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2016-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2016-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2016-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2016-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2016-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4481"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Education for All Act of 2016

This bill expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) it is in the U.S. national security interest to promote universal basic education that includes gender parity in developing countries; and (2) education lays the foundation for increased civic participation, democratic governance, sustained economic growth, and more stable societies.

The Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 is amended to state that it is U.S. policy to work with partner countries, multilateral institutions, the private sector, and nongovernmental and civil society organizations to promote sustainable, quality basic education by: (1) aligning with the needs and capacities of developing countries to strengthen educational systems, improve teacher skills, and support parental engagement in their children's education; and (2) promoting education as the foundation for economic development.

The President shall ensure that assistance provided to support programs and activities pursuant to such policy is aligned with U.S. diplomatic, economic, and national security interests and that priority is given to developing countries in which: (1) there is the greatest need and opportunity to expand access to basic education, including for marginalized and vulnerable groups, particularly women and girls, or populations affected by conflict or crisis; and (2) such assistance can substantially impact children and educational systems.

The President shall develop a comprehensive U.S. strategy to promote quality basic education in partner countries.

 The bill establishes within the U.S. Agency for International Development a Senior Coordinator of United States International Basic Education Assistance, who shall have primary responsibility for the oversight and coordination of all U.S. government resources and activities relating to the promotion of international basic education programs and activities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
