<bill session="115" type="s" number="1294" updated="2019-06-21T11:07:17Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expand opportunity for Native American children through additional options in education, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native American Education Opportunity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native American Education Opportunity Act</title>
    <title type="display">Native American Education Opportunity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000303"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2017-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Native American Education Opportunity Act

This bill amends the Education Amendments of 1978 to require the Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA), at the request of a federally recognized Indian tribe, to &#160;provide funds for tribal education savings account programs to make grants to education savings accounts for students who: (1)&#160;attended or will be eligible to attend a BIA-funded school; (2) will not be attending a BIA-funded school, receiving an education savings account from another tribe, or attending public elementary or secondary school while participating in the program; and (3) meet program eligibility requirements.

Funds may be used for:

 private school tuition and fees; textbooks, curriculum, and instructional materials; academic, Native language, or cultural tutoring; educational services and therapies for students with special needs; tuition and fees for a private online learning program; educational technology; examination fees; or transportation to and from school. Three years after this bill's enactment, the Government Accountability Office must review the implementation of the bill, including any factors impacting increased participation in education savings account programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
