<bill session="114" type="s" number="2915" updated="2018-06-02T07:18:39Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Research Transparency and Accountability Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance public awareness of federally funded research and development projects, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Federal Research Transparency and Accountability Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000444"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Federal Research Transparency and Accountability Act of 2016

This bill directs the Office of Management and Budget to coordinate with each federal agency that provides funding to entities to carry out research and development to establish a system for the detection of potential duplicative applications for funding in order to prevent duplicative funding.

Each federal agency shall include in a publicly accessible database a searchable listing of each unclassified research and development project the agency funds, including contracts, grants, cooperative agreements, or task orders.

The acknowledgment section in each study carried out in whole or in part with federal funds and published, presented at a conference or meeting, or otherwise made publicly available shall include:

 the name of the agency that provided funding for the study, the project or award number associated with the study, and an estimate of the study's total cost. The Government Accountability Office shall study agency compliance with these requirements.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
