<bill session="114" type="h" number="1252" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:38Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Sentencing Clarification Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To apply reduced sentences for certain cocaine base offenses retroactively for certain offenders, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Fair Sentencing Clarification Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000185"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000510" joined="2016-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-04T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Fair Sentencing Clarification Act of 2015

 Directs: (1) a court, in cases in which a sentence has not yet been imposed with respect to the application of the penalty&#160;amendments of the Fair Sentencing Act of 2010 to cocaine base offenses committed prior to the enactment of such Act, to impose such sentence as if such amendments were in effect on the date the offense was committed; and (2) the Court of Appeals to remand for resentencing consistent with such amendments such cases in which a sentence has already been imposed, if subject to a pending appeal on or after August 3, 2010.

Authorizes the sentencing court, in the case of a defendant who has been convicted of such an offense committed before August 3, 2010, for which a term of imprisonment has been imposed, to reduce the term of imprisonment for that crime consistent with the amendments made by that Act on motion of the defendant or the Director of the Bureau of Prisons, or on its own motion.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
