<bill session="114" type="s" number="2079" updated="2018-06-02T07:10:09Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Commission on International Religious Freedom Reauthorization Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">United States Commission on International Religious Freedom Reauthorization Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2015-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2015-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2015-09-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="2078"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-24T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">United States Commission on International Religious Freedom Reauthorization Act of 2015

This bill reauthorizes the U.S.&#160;Commission on International Religious Freedom (USCIRF) through FY2019.

The Chair and Vice Chair of USCIRF must at least biennially carry out a strategic policy and organizational review and submit a strategic plan to Congress concerning: (1) prioritized actions for USCIRF, (2) any changes it considers necessary with regard to the scope, content, and timing of USCIRF's annual report; (3) any changes USCIRF considers necessary with regard to personnel matters; and (4) USCIRF's funding requirements.

If unanimous agreement is not possible, items for inclusion in the strategic plan may, at the joint discretion of the Chair and Vice Chair, be approved by: (1) a majority of Commissioners appointed by an elected official from the political party of the President, and (2) a majority of Commissioners appointed by an elected official from the political party that is not the party of the President.

The Vice Chair for such purposes must be appointed by an elected official from the political party that is different from the political party of the elected official who appointed the Chair.

USCIRF is authorized to implement provisions related to personnel and the annual report that are included in the strategic plan.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
