<bill session="115" type="s" number="1154" updated="2019-04-18T16:36:17Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 37, United States Code, to provide for the housing treatment of members of the Armed Forces and their spouses and dependents undergoing a permanent change of station in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Family Stability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Family Stability Act</title>
    <title type="display">Military Family Stability Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000575"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2017-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2017-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2017-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2017-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2017-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2017-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2017-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2810"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="2487"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Military Family Stability Act

This bill directs the Department of Defense (DOD) to prescribe regulations that permit an eligible member of the Armed Forces who is undergoing a permanent change of station within the United States to request specified housing treatment during the period from 180 days before to 180 days after such change.

An "eligible member" is a member who:

 has a spouse who is gainfully employed or enrolled in a degree, certificate, or license granting program at the beginning of such period; has one or more dependents attending an elementary or secondary school at the beginning of such period; has one or more dependents enrolled in the Exceptional Family Member Program; or is caring for an immediate family member with a chronic or long-term illness at the beginning of such period. If a spouse or other dependent of a member whose request for such housing treatment is approved: (1) resides in government-owned or government-leased housing at the beginning of such period, he or she may continue to reside there during such period; and (2) relocates at a time different from the member, the member may be assigned to housing intended for members without a spouse or dependent until the member's detachment date or the spouse or other dependent's arrival date, if such housing is available without displacing a member without a spouse or dependent. (The bill specifies alternatives for the basic housing allowance to be provided in such case.)

The Government Accountability Office shall report to Congress on potential DOD actions to enhance the well-being of military families undergoing a permanent change of station.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
