<bill session="114" type="s" number="717" updated="2018-06-02T06:40:53Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Provider Readiness Recognition Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate certain non-Department mental health care providers who treat members of the Armed Forces and veterans as providers who have particular knowledge relating to the provision of mental health care to members of the Armed Forces and veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Community Provider Readiness Recognition Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000607"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2015-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-06">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Community Provider Readiness Recognition Act of 2015

Directs the Departments of Defense and Veterans Affairs to jointly develop a system by which a non-Department mental health care provider who provides health care to members of the Armed Forces or veterans shall receive a mental health provider readiness designation if such provider meets eligibility criteria relating to: (1) knowledge, comfort, and understanding with respect to the culture of members of the Armed Forces, veterans, and family members and caregivers of such members and veterans; and (2) knowledge regarding evidence-based treatments that have been approved by such Departments for the treatment of mental health issues among such members and veterans.

Requires such Departments to: (1) jointly establish and update a registry, which shall be available to the public, of all non-Department mental health care providers that are currently so designated, and (2) update all lists maintained by such Departments of such non-Department providers by indicating the providers that are currently so designated.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
