<bill session="114" type="s" number="1583" updated="2018-08-16T22:54:04Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the expansion of an existing hydroelectric project.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to authorize the expansion of an existing hydroelectric project.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4204-4205" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-08">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 114-381.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-11-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-12-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 114-185.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-12-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="330">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 330.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4193"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-12-16T13:22:09Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">(Sec. 1) This bill authorizes the licensee for the Terror Lake Hydroelectric Project (Federal Energy Regulatory Commission [FERC] project number 2743) to occupy up to 20 acres of federal land to construct, operate, and maintain the Upper Hidden Basin Diversion Expansion without further authorization of the Department of the Interior or under the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act.

This is the expansion of the Terror Lake Hydroelectric Project described in the Upper Hidden Basin Grant Application dated July 2, 2014, as submitted by Kodiak Electric Association, Inc., to the Alaska Energy Authority Renewable Energy Fund Round VIII.

The Expansion must meet the terms and conditions contained in any amendment to a license which may be issued by FERC subsequent to its environmental review under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-185</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
