<bill session="113" type="h" number="5156" updated="2016-10-25T16:15:17Z">
  <state datetime="2014-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wildlife Disease Emergency Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to identify and declare wildlife disease emergencies and to coordinate rapid response to these emergencies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Wildlife Disease Emergency Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2014-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000127" joined="2014-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2014-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2014-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-17">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-17">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Rural Development, and Credit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Livestock and Foreign Agriculture" code="HSAG29" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" code="HSII22" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine and animal diseases"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-07-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Wildlife Disease Emergency Act of 2014 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with governors of potentially affected states, to declare a wildlife disease emergency for any wildlife disease occurring within the United States or, if outside the United States, with the potential to enter the United States.

Defines "wildlife disease emergency" as the occurrence of a non-zoonotic pathological condition in a wildlife population that:

 is infectious and caused by a newly discovered pathogen or is a known infectious wildlife disease that is expanding in range or other impacts, or poses significant threats to the sustainability of wildlife or to the overall health of a functioning ecosystem. Directs the Secretary, upon making such a declaration, to lead a coordinated response to the emergency.

 Directs the Secretary to implement a grant program to provide funding to state wildlife agencies and Indian tribes to address wildlife disease emergencies.

 Establishes in the Treasury a Wildlife Disease Emergency Fund.

 Allows the Secretary to establish a Wildlife Disease Committee to assist the Secretary in increasing the level of preparedness needed to address emerging wildlife diseases.

 Authorizes the Secretary to convene rapid response teams to address any particular wildlife disease emergency.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
