<bill session="113" type="h" number="3699" updated="2016-10-25T16:09:33Z">
  <state datetime="2013-12-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Structured Settlement Claimants Rights Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 28, United States Code, to protect the right of a claimant in a civil action before a Federal court to retain a structured settlement broker to negotiate the terms of payment of an award, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Structured Settlement Claimants Rights Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001259" joined="2013-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2013-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000588" joined="2013-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" code="HSJU05" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-12-11T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Structured Settlement Claimants Rights Act of 2013 - Amends the federal judicial code to declare that a claimant in any civil action before a federal court shall have the right to retain a structured settlement broker to act on behalf of that claimant for purposes of negotiating a schedule of payments or other terms of payment previously agreed to be paid by or on behalf of the defendant in satisfaction of a judgment against that defendant or in accordance with the terms of a settlement.

Requires that a party to an administrative proceeding have the same right to retain such a structured settlement broker for negotiations with other parties.

Directs: (1) the court or the agency in an administrative proceeding to inform the claimant of this right at the appropriate time, and (2) the defendant to provide timely notice of any current or previous professional relationship between the defendant and the broker.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
