<bill session="114" type="s" number="244" updated="2018-06-02T06:31:54Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require an independent comprehensive review of the process by which the Department of Veterans Affairs assesses cognitive impairments that result from traumatic brain injury for purposes of awarding disability compensation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to require an independent comprehensive review of the process by which the Department of Veterans Affairs assesses cognitive impairments that result from traumatic brain injury for purposes of awarding disability compensation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-29">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-22T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to seek to enter into an agreement with the Institute of Medicine to conduct a comprehensive review of VA examinations that assess the cognitive impairments of individuals who submit claims for compensation for service-connected traumatic brain injury.

Requires: (1) the Institute, in conducting the review, to convene a group of experts in clinical neuropsychology and other related disciplines; and (2) the review to include a determination of the adequacy of the VA's tools and protocols used in conducting such examinations and the credentials that are necessary for health care specialists and providers to perform the portions of such examinations that assess cognitive functions.

Directs the Secretary to submit to Congress any Institute recommendations for legislative or administrative action to improve the adjudication of claims.

Requires Secretary to seek to enter an agreement with a similar nongovernmental, nonprofit organization to conduct such review if the Secretary is unable to enter into an acceptable agreement with the Institute.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
