<bill session="114" type="h" number="1996" updated="2018-11-09T00:08:43Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Social Security Numbers and Benefits for Illegal Aliens Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title II of the Social Security Act to prohibit the assignment of social security account numbers to certain individuals seeking employment in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">No Social Security Numbers and Benefits for Illegal Aliens Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2016-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000362" joined="2015-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2015-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000182" joined="2015-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000582" joined="2015-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000462" joined="2015-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000816" joined="2015-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2015-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Social Security" code="HSWM01" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">No Social Security Numbers and Benefits for Illegal Aliens Act of 2015

 Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to prohibit the Commissioner of Social Security from assigning a Social Security account number to any individual who receives deferred action on removal in accordance with certain Department of Homeland Security memoranda dated June 15, 2012 and November 20, 2014, and who would be subject to removal but for such memoranda.

Prohibits the payment of OASDI benefits to such individuals.

Denies the crediting of quarters of coverage toward benefits for earnings from unauthorized work by an individual who is not a U.S. citizen or national and who was not authorized to be employed in the United States.

Prohibits counting an individual's annual wages or self-employment income for any year for which no quarter of coverage may be credited.

Directs the Commissioner and the Secretary to enter into an agreement to establish a system to transmit to the Secretary any Social Security account number assigned to an individual after the enactment of this Act, as well as other identifying information, in any case in which the individual is not a U.S. citizen or national at the time that number is assigned.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
