<bill session="114" type="sr" number="537" updated="2018-06-02T06:21:26Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-06">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-12-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing profound concern about the ongoing political, economic, social and humanitarian crisis in Venezuela, urging the release of political prisoners, and calling for respect of constitutional and democratic processes.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution expressing profound concern about the ongoing political, economic, social and humanitarian crisis in Venezuela, urging the release of political prisoners, and calling for respect of constitutional and democratic processes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2016-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2016-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5172-5173" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-12-06" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-12-07">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Corker with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title and with an amended preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-12-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="708">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 708.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="114" relation="identical" number="851"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Venezuela"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-07T16:19:54Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Expresses concern about widespread shortages of essential medicines and basic food products faced by the people of Venezuela and urges President Maduro to permit the delivery of humanitarian assistance.

Calls on the government of Venezuela to:

 immediately release all political prisoners and to respect internationally recognized human rights; ensure the neutrality and professionalism of all security forces and to respect the Venezuelan people's rights to freedom of expression and assembly; and halt its efforts to undermine the principle of separation of powers, its circumvention of the democratically elected legislature, and its subjugation of judicial independence. Expresses support for: (1) meaningful efforts towards a dialogue that leads to respect for Venezuela's constitutional mechanisms and resolves the country's political, economic, social, and humanitarian crisis; and (2) Organization of American States (OAS) Secretary General Almagro's invocation of Article 20 of the Inter-American Democratic Charter. Urges the OAS Permanent Council to undertake a collective assessment of the constitutional and democratic order in Venezuela.

Stresses the urgency of strengthening the rule of law and increasing efforts to combat impunity and public corruption in Venezuela.

Urges the President of the United States to provide full support for OAS efforts in favor of constitutional and democratic solutions to the political impasse and to instruct appropriate federal agencies to hold officials of the Venezuelan government accountable for violations of U.S. law and abuses of internationally recognized human rights.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
