<bill session="114" type="s" number="1120" updated="2018-06-02T06:46:16Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make aliens associated with a criminal gang inadmissible, deportable, and ineligible for various forms of relief.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to make aliens associated with a criminal gang inadmissible, deportable, and ineligible for various forms of relief.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2015-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. (Sponsor introductory remarks on measure:CR S2478-2479))</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="4856"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to define "criminal gang."

An alien who is or was a member of a criminal gang, or who participated in gang activity knowing that such participation will promote the gang's illegal activity, shall be inadmissible and deportable.

The Department of Homeland Security may designate a group or association as a criminal gang.

Detention shall be mandatory for anyone found inadmissible or deportable for criminal street gang membership.

Individuals found inadmissible or deportable for criminal gang membership shall be barred from:

 asylum; withholding of removal; temporary protected status; special immigrant juvenile status; deferred action; and parole, unless assisting the United States in a law enforcement matter and required by the government to be present with respect to such assistance. An alien found at a U.S. land border or port of entry who is determined to be inadmissible and a threat to public safety (certain criminals, terrorists, street gang members) shall be subject to expedited removal.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
