<bill session="114" type="h" number="6422" updated="2018-11-09T00:09:29Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-12-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-12-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Commuter Access Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to treat qualified alternative commuter programs as an excludable qualified transportation fringe benefit.</title>
    <title type="display">Commuter Access Reform Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000580"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2016-12-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-12-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-01T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Commuter Access Reform Act 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to treat transportation provided by an employer's qualified alternative commuter program as a qualified transportation fringe benefit that is excluded from an employee's gross income.

A "qualified alternative commuter program" reimburses an employee for the cost of certain ride-share commuting transportation between the employee's residence, place of employment, or a mass transit facility.

The benefit applies to ride-sharing commuting transportation in a commuter vehicle provided by a transportation network company if: (1) it is designed to provide service to multiple passengers with fully or partially overlapping journeys, and (2) the fare for each passenger is determined at the beginning of the trip and is based on the transportation having multiple riders.

The benefit is subject to a limit on the aggregate amount of transportation fringe benefits for parking and an alternative commuter program that may be excluded from gross income.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
