<bill session="114" type="h" number="1440" updated="2019-01-09T21:09:44Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 to treat employment as a field emergency medical service practitioner in the same manner as employment as a firefighter for purposes of such Act.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 to treat employment as a field emergency medical service practitioner in the same manner as employment as a firefighter for purposes of such Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000616"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000459" joined="2015-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Workforce Protections" code="HSED10" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Age discrimination"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 to treat field emergency medical service practitioners in the same manner as firefighters or law enforcement officers for purposes of exempting state employers from otherwise prohibited age discrimination practices.

Allows an employer that is a state, political subdivision, and interstate agency to fail or refuse to hire, or to discharge, any such practitioner because of the individual's age if the employer provides the practitioner an annual opportunity to demonstrate physical and mental fitness by passing a job performance test identified by the Department of Health and Human Services in order to continue employment.

Defines "field emergency medical service practitioner" as an employee, the duties of whose position are primarily to perform work directly connected with the responsibility of administration of specialized pre-hospital emergency care for victims of acute illnesses or injury, including an employee engaged in such activity who is transferred to a supervisory or administrative position.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
