<bill session="114" type="h" number="5987" updated="2018-06-02T05:30:28Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for recreational access for floating cabins on the Tennessee River System, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To provide for recreational access for floating cabins on the Tennessee River System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001187"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000459" joined="2016-09-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="612"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5303"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-09T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill authorizes the Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA) to approve and allow the construction and use of a floating cabin (a watercraft or other floating structure primarily designed and used for human habitation or occupation and not primarily designed or used for navigation or transportation on water) on TVA waters if: (1) such cabin is maintained by the owner to reasonable health, safety, and environmental standards; and (2) the TVA has authorized the use of recreational vessels on such waters. The TVA may levy necessary and reasonable fees on the owners of such cabins.

The TVA may not require removal of floating cabins located on TVA waters on the date of enactment of this bill for specified periods after enactment of this bill and must allow continued use of such cabins that meet the requirements of this bill for the duration of such periods.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
