<bill session="114" type="s" number="3081" updated="2018-06-02T07:46:38Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">WINGMAN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Working to Integrate Networks Guaranteeing Member Access Now Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to provide certain employees of Members of Congress with access to case-tracking information of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</title>
    <title type="display">WINGMAN Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2016-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2016-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2016-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2016-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-29">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5166"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Working to Integrate Networks Guaranteeing Member Access Now Act or the WINGMAN Act

This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to provide an accredited, permanent congressional employee with read-only remote access to the electronic Veterans Benefits Administration (VBA) claims records system of a represented veteran, regardless of whether the employee is acting under a power of attorney executed by the veteran.

The VA shall ensure that access does not allow the employee to modify system data.

An employee must complete the VA certification process required of agents or attorneys in order to have system access.

 Each Member of Congress who elects to have an employee have access to the system shall bear the certification cost, which shall be paid from the Member's representational allowance.

Information access by an employee shall be deemed: (1) a covered disclosure requiring prior consent, with specified exceptions; and (2) a permitted disclosure relating to the privacy of individually identifiable health information.

The VA may not recognize an employee for purposes of preparation, presentation, and prosecution of VA claims by reason of such system access.

"Accredited, permanent congressional employee" means an employee of a Member of Congress who assists constituents with issues regarding federal departments or agencies.

"Electronic VBA claims records system" means the VA system that provides claim status information, including information about medical records, compensation and pension exams records, rating decisions, a statement of the case and a supplementary statement of the case, a notice of disagreement, and Form-9.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
