<bill session="114" type="s" number="2996" updated="2018-06-02T07:45:47Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FAIR Energy Policy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fossil Aid is Inefficient and Regressive Energy Policy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to phase out tax preferences for fossil fuels on the same schedule as the phase out of the tax credits for wind facilities.</title>
    <title type="display">FAIR Energy Policy Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2016-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2016-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2016-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2016-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2016-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2016-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Earth sciences"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fossil Aid is Inefficient and Regressive Energy Policy Act or the FAIR Energy Policy Act 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to phase out certain tax provisions that apply to fossil fuels. The bill establishes a schedule for decreasing the benefits of the provisions for major integrated oil companies by specified percentages that reach 100% after December 31, 2019. The affected provisions include:

 the deduction for intangible drilling costs, the deduction for the percentage of depletion of oil and natural gas wells, the deduction for oil related qualified production activities income, the deduction for the amortization of geological and geophysical expenditures, the deduction for the percentage of depletion of oil shale, the deduction for exploration and development costs for oil shale, the capital gains treatment for royalties of coal, the deduction for tertiary injectants, the exception to the passive loss limitation for working interests in oil and natural gas properties, and the marginal wells tax credit.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
