<bill session="115" type="s" number="1538" updated="2019-04-18T16:37:52Z">
  <state datetime="2018-03-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Small Business Employee Ownership Promotion Enhancement Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Small Business Employee Ownership Promotion Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Small Business Employee Ownership Promotion Enhancement Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Small Business Employee Ownership Promotion Enhancement Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Employee Ownership Promotion Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Employee Ownership Promotion Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Small Business Act to establish awareness of, and technical assistance for, the creation of employee stock ownership plans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2017-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2017-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-03-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-03-19">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Reported by Senator Risch with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-03-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="348">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 348.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-12-19">
      <text>By Senator Risch from Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship filed written report. Report No. 115-436.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-03-19T14:27:25Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Small Business Employee Ownership Promotion Enhancement Act of 2018

This bill amends the Small Business Act to require the Service Corps of Retired Executives (SCORE) to appoint a SCORE Employee Ownership Director, whose duties shall relate to the various forms of employee ownership.

The director shall be responsible for:

 administering and disbursing materials that contain general information and technical assistance for the establishment of employee ownership structures; coordinating efforts for employee ownership with SCORE chapters located throughout the United States; providing technical assistance relating to a range of business forms and strategies that promote or facilitate employee ownership, including an employee stock ownership plan, a cooperative, and any other approach determined appropriate by the director; and providing the Small Business Administration and the Office of Entrepreneurial Development with statistics, including regional statistics from a SCORE chapter relating to services provided to small businesses potentially undertaking a form of employee ownership. The director may be a SCORE employee on the date of appointment.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-436</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
