<bill session="115" type="s" number="2809" updated="2019-04-18T16:43:01Z">
  <state datetime="2018-10-02">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-10-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the San Rafael Swell Western Heritage and Historic Mining National Conservation Area in the State of Utah, to designate wilderness areas in the State, to provide for certain land conveyances, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Emery County Public Land Management Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Emery County Public Land Management Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emery County Public Land Management Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emery County Public Land Management Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Emery County Public Land Management Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-05-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-08-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-10-02" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-12-05">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-12-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="721">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 721.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-12-19">
      <text>By Senator Murkowski from Committee on Energy and Natural Resources filed written report. Report No. 115-440.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="5727"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3803"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-05-09T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Emery County Public Land Management Act of 2018

This bill establishes the San Rafael Swell Western Heritage and Historic Mining National Conservation Area, consisting of 336,467 acres in Utah. The bill also amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate&#160;a 54-mile segment of Green River,&#160;which is located in the area,&#160;as a component of the national wild and scenic rivers system.

Over&#160;500,000 acres in Utah are designated as national wilderness areas, including Candland Mountain, Crack Canyon, Desolation Canyon, Devil's Canyon, Horseshoe Canyon (North), Mexican Mountain, Muddy Creek, Nelson Mountain, San Rafael Reef, and Sid's Mountain.

With respect to the newly established conservation area and wilderness areas, the bill:

 allows&#160;for commercial services to the extent necessary to fulfill the areas' recreational or other purposes; allows the grazing of livestock, if already established, to continue; allows for the "casual collection" (for noncommercial use) of plants, rocks, and minerals; and otherwise provides for management by the Department of the Interior. In addition, with respect to other land in Utah,&#160;the bill provides for:

 the cooperative (state and federal) management of the Temple Mountain Cooperative Management Area (7,792 acres); the management of the Goblin Valley State Park Expansion as a state park; the establishment and management of&#160;the Jurassic National Monument (2,534 acres); and public purpose conveyances, by Interior to the applicable&#160;local government entity,&#160;of the Huntington Airport (1,400 acres), the Emery City Recreation Area (640 acres), the State Road 6 Emery Sheriff's Office substation site (640 acres), and the Buckhorn Information Center (65 acres).</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-440</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
