<bill session="114" type="s" number="2404" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:37Z">
  <state datetime="2015-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Federal Trade Commission to prescribe regulations regarding the collection and use of personal information obtained by tracking the online activity of an individual, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Do Not Track Online Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Do Not Track Online Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2015-12-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-12-15T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Do Not Track Online Act of 2015

This bill requires the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to promulgate: (1) regulations that establish standards for the implementation of a mechanism by which individuals can indicate whether they prefer to have personal information collected by providers of online services, including by providers of mobile applications and services; and (2) rules that prohibit such providers from collecting personal information on, and from discriminating against, individuals who have expressed a preference not to have such information collected.

"Personal information" includes IP addresses, media access control addresses, and other unique device identifiers.

The rules must allow for the collection and use of personal information, notwithstanding the expressed preference of the individual, if: (1) the information is necessary to provide a service requested by the individual so long as identifying particulars are removed or the information is deleted upon the provision of such service; or (2) the individual receives clear, conspicuous, and accurate notice on, and consents to, such collection and use.

The bill provides for FTC and state enforcement of such rules and regulations. If permitted under state law, a person may bring a private action to enjoin a violation or to receive monetary damages.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
