<bill session="113" type="h" number="426" updated="2016-10-25T15:58:15Z">
  <state datetime="2013-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Race to the Top Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide incentives for States and local educational agencies to implement comprehensive reforms and innovative strategies that are designed to lead to significant improvement in outcomes for all students and significant reductions in achievement gaps among subgroups of students, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Race to the Top Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000598"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000598" joined="2013-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2014-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000562" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2013-01-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-01-25T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Race to the Top Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to states and local educational agencies (LEAs) to implement reforms and innovations designed to improve educational outcomes significantly for all students and reduce achievement gaps significantly among specified student subgroups.

Requires each grant applicant to have a comprehensive and coherent plan for doing so that includes, if applicable:

 improving the effectiveness of teachers and school leaders and promoting their equitable distribution; strengthening the use of data to improve education; implementing internationally benchmarked, college- and career-ready elementary and secondary academic standards; turning around its lowest-performing schools; supporting, or coordinating with, early learning programs for high-need children from birth through third grade; assessing kindergarten students' readiness for school success; and creating or maintaining successful conditions for high-performing charter schools and other innovative, autonomous public schools. Requires each grantee to establish performance measures that track its progress in implementing its plan and improving educational outcomes for students and specified student subgroups.

Gives grant priority to LEAs with the highest number or percentages of impoverished children and those that serve rural schools.

Requires each state grantee to use at least 50% of its grant for subgrants to LEAs that participate in its plan. Allows LEAs to receive a grant and subgrant for the same fiscal year.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
