<bill session="114" type="h" number="582" updated="2018-11-21T21:22:58Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Concussion Treatment and Care Tools Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ConTACT Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title III of the Public Health Service Act to provide for the establishment and implementation of guidelines on best practices for diagnosis, treatment, and management of mild traumatic brain injuries (MTBIs) in school-aged children, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">ConTACT Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000096"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000583" joined="2015-01-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="307"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="School athletics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-28T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Concussion Treatment and Care Tools Act of 2015 or the ConTACT Act of 2015

Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish guidelines for states on the implementation of best practices for diagnosis, treatment, and management of mild traumatic brain injuries (MTBIs) in school-aged children, including best practices relating to student athletes returning to play after an MTBI.

Requires the Pediatric MTBI Guideline Expert Panel of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to issue a final report on best practices by July 31, 2015.

Authorizes HHS to make grants to states to: (1) adopt, disseminate, and ensure schools implement the guidelines; and (2) ensure elementary and secondary schools implement computerized preseason baseline and post-injury neuropsychological testing for student athletes.

Directs HHS to require states receiving grants to utilize, to the extent practicable, applicable expertise and services offered by local chapters of national brain injury organizations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
