<bill session="114" type="h" number="5211" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:34Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CFPB Dual Mandate and Economic Analysis Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 to update the purpose of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">CFPB Dual Mandate and Economic Analysis Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000294"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001282" joined="2016-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000182" joined="2016-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000606" joined="2016-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001187" joined="2016-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5983"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">CFPB Dual Mandate and Economic Analysis Act

This bill amends the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 to revise the purpose of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) regarding competition in markets for consumer financial products and services. The CFPB shall implement and, where applicable, enforce federal consumer financial law consistently for the purpose of strengthening private sector participation in markets, without government interference or subsidies, to increase competition and enhance consumer choice.

The CFPB shall establish an Office of Economic Analysis (OEA) to:

 review all CFPB proposed guidance, orders, rules and regulations; assess their impact on consumer choice, price, and access to credit products; assess them again after 1, 2, 5, and 10 years; measure the success of the rule, regulation, guidance, or order in solving the problem it was intended to solve when issued; and report on these reviews and assessments in the Federal Register. Before issuing any guidance, order, rule, or regulation, the CFPB shall consider the OEA's review and assessment of it, giving notice and explanation if the CFPB disagrees with the OEA.

The CFPB shall also, in each proposed rulemaking, identify the problem the particular rule or regulations is seeking to solve, and specify the metrics by which success in solving the problem will be measured.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
