<bill session="114" type="h" number="1065" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:37Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">POST Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require that States receiving Byrne JAG funds to require sensitivity training for law enforcement officers of that State.</title>
    <title type="display">POST Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001049"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2302"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-25T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">POST Act of 2015

Directs states receiving funds under specified Bureau of Justice Assistance grant programs (whether characterized as the Edward Byrne Memorial State and Local Law Enforcement Assistance Programs, the Local Government Law Enforcement Block Grants Program, the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program, or otherwise), after a specified compliance period, to require all individuals enrolled in an academy of a law enforcement agency of the state and all law enforcement officers of the state to fulfill a training session on sensitivity each fiscal year, including training on ethnic and racial bias, cultural diversity, and police interaction with the disabled, mentally ill, and new immigrants. Requires an eight-hour session for individuals attending an academy and a four-hour session for all other law enforcement officers.

Subjects any state that fails to comply with such requirement to a reduction of up to 20% of the funds that would otherwise be allocated to such state for a fiscal year for such grant programs, at the discretion of the Attorney General.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
