<bill session="113" type="h" number="5805" updated="2016-10-25T16:17:38Z">
  <state datetime="2014-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Andrea Sloan Compassionate Use Reform and Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Andrea Sloan CURE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to expanding access for breakthrough drugs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Andrea Sloan CURE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001157"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-12-08T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Andrea Sloan Compassionate Use Reform and Enhancement Act or the Andrea Sloan CURE Act - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require the sponsor of a &#8220;breakthrough drug&#8221; (which is a drug that qualifies for expedited approval, is an infectious disease product, or qualifies the sponsor for a priority review voucher) to submit to the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) and make available to the public a policy on requests for access to the drug for compassionate use, including the minimum criteria for consideration or approval of requests and the time needed to make a decision.

Requires a breakthrough drug sponsor to explain a denied request for compassionate use to the person who made the request.

Directs HHS to establish an Expanded Access Task Force. Requires the Task Force and the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to evaluate patient access to investigational drugs and make recommendations for improving access.

Directs HHS to finalize the draft guidance entitled &#8220;Expanded Access to Investigational Drugs for Treatment Use--Qs &amp; As,&#8221; taking into account reports from the Task Force and GAO.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
