<bill session="115" type="s" number="2848" updated="2019-04-18T16:43:10Z">
  <state datetime="2018-05-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve Department of Transportation controlled substances and alcohol testing, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Fighting Opioid Abuse in Transportation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Fighting Opioid Abuse in Transportation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fighting Opioid Abuse in Transportation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fighting Opioid Abuse in Transportation Act</title>
    <title type="display">Fighting Opioid Abuse in Transportation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-05-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Thune with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 115-286.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-06-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="491">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 491.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-05-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fighting Opioid Abuse in Transportation Act

This bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to publish a final rule revising regulations for alcohol and controlled substances testing to designate rail mechanical employees and yardmasters as railroad employee responsible for safety-sensitive functions.

 The General Accountability Office shall review DOT's Drug and Alcohol Testing Management Information System and submit to Congress a report on the review, including appropriate recommendations.

The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) shall determine whether a revision of the Mandatory Guidelines for Federal Workplace Drug Testing Programs to expand the opiate category on the list of authorized drug testing to include fentanyl is justified, based on the reliability and cost-effectiveness of available testing.

If the expansion of the opiate category is determined to be justified, HHS shall publish a final notice of the revision of the Mandatory Guidelines for Federal Workplace Drug Testing Programs to expand the opiate category on the list of authorized drug testing to include fentanyl.

If the expansion of the opiate category is determined to be justified, and DOT concurs with that determination, DOT shall publish a final rule revising regulations for procedures for transportation workplace drug and alcohol testing programs to include fentanyl in DOT's drug-testing panel, consistent with the Mandatory Guidelines for Federal Workplace Drug Testing Programs as revised by HHS.

 HHS shall: (1) submit to Congress a report on the status of the hair testing guidelines, and (2) publish a final notice of the Mandatory Guidelines for Federal Workplace Drug Testing Programs using Oral Fluid.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-286</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
