<bill session="115" type="h" number="6749" updated="2019-04-18T16:27:13Z">
  <state datetime="2018-09-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-09-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide protections for amateur and professional athletes, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Collegiate Athletics Advancement Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Collegiate Athletics Advancement Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NCAA Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NCAA Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">NCAA Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000586"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001281" joined="2018-10-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-09-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Professional sports"/>
    <term name="School athletics"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-09-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">National Collegiate Athletics Advancement Act of 2018 or the NCAA Act of 2018

This bill amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require an institution of higher education or an eligible institution for purposes of any program participation agreement related to student assistance to comply with this bill's requirements.

An institution of higher education may not restrict, or be a member of an intercollegiate athletic association that restricts, amateur athletes from participating in amateur sports, with exceptions.

The bill sets forth restrictions on scholarships for student athletes. An institution of higher education that provides a scholarship to a student shall require the student to report to the institution any potential paid work opportunity the student intends to accept. In the case of a student at an institution of higher education who participates as an athlete in a collegiate revenue-generating sport, the institution shall ensure that the student is provided coverage at no cost for any medical costs incurred with respect to any injury attributable to participation in that sport.

A collective bargaining agreement between a professional sports league and a professional players' association entered into shall allow adults to enter the agreement at the same level as other adults with the same experience level in the league.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
