<amendment session="114" chamber="s" number="453" updated="2018-06-04T02:15:45Z">
  <amends type="sc" number="11" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2015-03-27">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001041"/>
  <offered datetime="2015-03-24"/>
  <description>To establish a spending-neutral reserve fund relating to ensuring that the Secretary of Transportation prioritizes the construction of projects that are of national and regional significance and projects in high priority corridors on the National Highway System, which will improve the safe, secure, and efficient movement of people and goods through the United States and facilitate economic development and create jobs in the United States.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2015-03-27" how="Unanimous Consent" result="pass">
      <text>Amendment SA 453 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1961" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Amendment SA 453 proposed by Senator Heller. (consideration: CR S1875-1877; text: CR S1875) To establish a spending-neutral reserve fund relating to ensuring that the Secretary of Transportation prioritizes the construction of projects that are of national and regional significance and projects in high priority corridors on the National Highway System, which will improve the safe, secure, and efficient movement of people and goods through the United States and facilitate economic development and create jobs in the United States.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-24"/>
    <action datetime="2015-03-27">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 453 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 453 proposed by Senator Heller.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1875-1877" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1875" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-24">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
