<bill session="115" type="s" number="2083" updated="2019-06-17T18:49:33Z">
  <state datetime="2017-11-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-11-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-11-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance cybersecurity information sharing and coordination at ports in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Cybersecurity Information Sharing and Coordination in Our Ports Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Cybersecurity Information Sharing and Coordination in Our Ports Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Strengthening Cybersecurity Information Sharing and Coordination in Our Ports Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2017-11-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-11-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Legislative Interest"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3101"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-11-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Strengthening Cybersecurity Information Sharing and Coordination in Our Ports Act of 2017

This bill requires the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to facilitate increased information sharing about cybersecurity among maritime interests.

DHS must:

 develop, implement, and&#160;continually&#160;review&#160;a maritime cybersecurity&#160;risk assessment model&#160;to evaluate current and future cybersecurity risks; seek input from at least one information sharing and analysis organization representing maritime interests in the National Cybersecurity and Communications Integration Center; establish voluntary reporting guidelines for maritime-related cybersecurity risks and incidents; and request that the National Maritime Security Advisory Committee report and make recommendations to DHS about methods to enhance cybersecurity and information sharing among security stakeholders from federal, state, local, and tribal governments; public safety and emergency response agencies; law enforcement and security organizations; maritime industry participants; port owners and operators; and maritime terminal owners and operators. Through the Coast Guard, DHS must also:

 direct each Area Maritime Security Advisory Committee to facilitate the sharing of information about, and development of plans to address, port-specific cybersecurity vulnerabilities; and&#160; require that area maritime security plans and facility security plans approved after enactment of this bill&#160;include mitigation measures to prevent, manage, and respond to cyber threats and vulnerabilities. The bill amends the federal shipping codes to include cybersecurity in facility and vessel vulnerability assessments.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
