<bill session="114" type="s" number="1943" updated="2018-08-16T22:54:07Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Shiloh National Military Park Boundary Adjustment and Parker's Crossroads Battlefield Designation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Shiloh National Military Park Boundary Adjustment and Parker's Crossroads Battlefield Designation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modify the boundary of the Shiloh National Military Park located in the States of Tennessee and Mississippi, to establish Parker's Crossroads Battlefield as an affiliated area of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Shiloh National Military Park Boundary Adjustment and Parker's Crossroads Battlefield Designation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000360"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-08-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-08-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-17">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-09-06">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski with amendments. With written report No. 114-321.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-09-06" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="594">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 594.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks" code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="87"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-06T15:29:31Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Shiloh National Military Park Boundary Adjustment and Parker's Crossroads Battlefield Designation Act

 (Sec. 3) This bill modifies the boundary of Shiloh National Military Park, located in Tennessee and Mississippi, to include the following areas: (1) Fallen Timbers Battlefield, (2) Russell House Battlefield, and (3) Davis Bridge Battlefield. The Department of the Interior may acquire lands by donation, purchase from willing sellers, or exchange.

(Sec. 4) The bill establishes Parker's Crossroads Battlefield in Tennessee as an affiliated area of the National Park System.

The city of Parkers Crossroads and the Tennessee Historical Commission shall jointly be the management entity for the affiliated area.

Interior may furnish technical assistance and enter into cooperative agreements with the management entity for financial assistance with marketing, interpretation, and preservation of the affiliated area.

Interior shall develop a general management plan for the affiliated area.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-321</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
