<bill session="114" type="s" number="323" updated="2018-06-02T06:32:42Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Responsible Use of Taxpayer Dollars for Portraits Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the use of Federal funds for the costs of official portraits of Members of Congress, heads of executive agencies, and heads of agencies and offices of the legislative branch.</title>
    <title type="display">Responsible Use of Taxpayer Dollars for Portraits Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Art, artists, authorship"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-29T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Responsible Use of Taxpayer Dollars for Portraits Act of 2015

 Prohibits federal funds from being used to pay for production of a portrait of: (1) a Member of Congress, (2) the head of an executive agency, or (3) the head of an agency or office of the legislative branch.

Authorizes up to $20,000 in federal funds to pay for production of a portrait of an individual in line of succession to the presidency.

Provides that nothing in this Act shall be construed to prohibit the use of:

 federal funds to publicly display a portrait of: (1) a Member of Congress, (2) the head of an executive agency, or (3) the head of an agency or office of the legislative branch; or nonfederal funds to produce a portrait of such individual, including, in the case of a portrait of an individual in line of succession to the presidency, the use of nonfederal funds to pay the entire cost of producing it or the portion of the cost that exceeds $20,000, if any.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
