<bill session="115" type="s" number="1185" updated="2019-04-18T16:36:25Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase public safety by punishing and deterring firearms trafficking.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Illegal Trafficking in Firearms Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Illegal Trafficking in Firearms Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Stop Illegal Trafficking in Firearms Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2017-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2017-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3043-3044" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="810"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stop Illegal Trafficking in Firearms Act of 2017

This bill amends the federal criminal code to establish stand-alone criminal offenses for trafficking in firearms and straw purchasing of firearms. The bill expands the categories of prohibited persons (i.e., persons barred from receiving or possessing a firearm or ammunition) to include persons who intend: (1) to sell or transfer a firearm or ammunition to a prohibited person; (2) to sell or transfer a firearm to further a crime of violence, a federal crime of terrorism, or a drug trafficking offense; or (3) to unlawfully export.

It increases the maximum prison term for the sale or transfer of a firearm to or the receipt or possession of a firearm by a prohibited person.

The bill revises existing prohibitions on: (1) transferring a firearm knowing that it will be used to commit a crime of violence or drug trafficking offense; and (2) smuggling a firearm into the United States with the intent to unlawfully import or to promote a crime of violence or drug trafficking offense. It broadens the scope of and increases the maximum prison term for violating the prohibitions.

The bill also makes it a crime to smuggle a firearm or ammunition out of the United States, or to conspire or attempt to do so, with the intent to unlawfully export or to promote a crime of violence, a federal crime of terrorism, or a drug trafficking offense.

 Finally, the bill prohibits the Department of Justice, or its law enforcement coordinate agencies, from facilitating the transfer of an operable firearm to a known or suspected agent of drug cartel, unless U.S. law enforcement personnel continuously monitor or control the firearm.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
