<bill session="115" type="s" number="1312" updated="2019-07-15T21:58:26Z">
  <state datetime="2018-12-21">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prioritize the fight against human trafficking in the United States.</title>
    <title type="short">Public-Private Partnership Advisory Council to End Human Trafficking Act</title>
    <title type="short">Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted" partial="1">Public-Private Partnership Advisory Council to End Human Trafficking Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate" partial="1">Public-Private Partnership Advisory Council to End Human Trafficking Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate" partial="1">Public-Private Partnership Advisory Council to End Human Trafficking Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Public-Private Partnership Advisory Council to End Human Trafficking Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate" partial="1">Public-Private Partnership Advisory Council to End Human Trafficking Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate" partial="1">Public-Private Partnership Advisory Council to End Human Trafficking Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2017-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2017-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2017-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2017-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2017-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2017-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001071" joined="2017-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2017-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2017-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2017-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2017-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2017-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000393" joined="2017-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2017-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2017-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2017-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2017-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2017-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2017-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2017-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2017-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2017-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2017-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2017-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3335-3336" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-06-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-08-01">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Grassley with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-08-01" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="189">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 189.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-09-11">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5179-5189" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-11">
      <text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2017-09-11" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5184-5189" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12T17:06:23-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Education and the Workforce, and Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Education and the Workforce, and Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Education and the Workforce, and Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-28">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-28">
      <text>Committee on Education and the Workforce discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-28">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Affairs discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-28T12:34:16-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Marino asked unanimous consent to discharge from committee and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-28T12:34:37-04:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9381-9390" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H9381-9386" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="without objection" type="vote2" datetime="2018-09-28T12:34:56-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-09-28T12:35:01-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-10-01">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendment to Senate bill.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="pingpong" datetime="2018-12-17" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Senate agreed to House amendment to S. 1312 by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7628" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7628" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-12-18">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2018-12-20">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2018-12-21" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="115-393" type="public" datetime="2018-12-21">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 115-393.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="7271"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3354"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1392"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1808"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="6223"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="4601"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h976"/>
    <amendment number="s937"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2018-12-22T04:59:58Z" status="Public Law">Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2017

TITLE I--FREDERICK DOUGLASS TRAFFICKING PREVENTION ACT OF 2017

(Sec. 101) This bill amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to specify that Community Oriented Policing Services program grants to hire school resource officers may also be used to train such officers to recognize and respond to signs of human trafficking.

(Sec. 102) It amends the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 to reauthorize through FY2022 the Creating Hope Through Outreach, Options, Services, and Education for Children and Youth (i.e., CHOOSE Children &amp; Youth) grant program.

TITLE II--JUSTICE FOR TRAFFICKING VICTIMS

(Sec. 201) The bill amends the federal criminal code to authorize the Department of Justice (DOJ) to bring a civil action to stop or prevent criminal offenses related to: (1) peonage, slavery, involuntary servitude, forced labor, and trafficking; (2) sexual exploitation and other abuse of children; or (3) sexual abuse.

(Sec. 202) This section amends the Missing Children's Assistance Act:

 to revise the definition of "missing child" to mean an individual under 18 years of age whose whereabouts are unknown to the individual's parent (currently, legal custodian), to specify that a parent includes a legal guardian or an individual who functions as a parent (e.g., a grandparent), to revise the functions and duties of the National Center on Missing and Exploited Children (NCMEC), and to require the NCMEC to make publicly available the annual report on missing children and the incidence of attempted child abductions. (Sec. 203) The bill amends the federal criminal code to broaden the authority of the U.S. Secret Service to provide forensic and investigative assistance to state and local law enforcement agencies by allowing assistance in support of any investigation&#8212;not just an investigation involving missing or exploited children.

TITLE III--SERVICES FOR TRAFFICKING SURVIVORS

(Sec. 301) The bill amends the Victims of Trafficking and Violence Protection Act of 2000 to reauthorize through FY2021: (1) the Human Trafficking and Smuggling Center, and (2) grants for trafficking victims inside the United States.

It amends the Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2005 to reauthorize through FY2021: (1) the annual human trafficking conference, and (2) grants to local law enforcement agencies for anti-trafficking programs.

The bill amends the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 to reauthorize through FY2021 the authority of HHS to appoint independent child advocates for trafficking victims and other vulnerable unaccompanied alien children.

It reinstates and reauthorizes through FY2021 grants to state and local law enforcement agencies to combat sex trafficking of minors.

(Sec. 302) It authorizes DOJ, with respect to trafficking victim services grants, to give priority to an applicant who: (1) uses grant funds to prevent, investigate, and prosecute human trafficking; and (2) provides dedicated resources to law enforcement officers for a period longer than the grant.

(Sec. 303) DOJ must: (1) compile and disseminate, to recipients of grants to provide victims' services, information about reliable and effective tools to identify victims of human trafficking; and (2) recommend, to recipients of grants to provide victim services to youth, practices for screening youth victims of human trafficking.

TITLE IV--IMPROVED DATA COLLECTION AND INTERAGENCY COORDINATION

(Sec. 401) DOJ must submit to Congress and publish a report on efforts by the National Institute of Justice to develop a methodology to assess the prevalence of human trafficking in the United States. The Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) must submit to Congress and publish a status report on the Innocence Lost National Initiative.

(Sec. 402) This section amends the Uniform Federal Crime Reporting Act of 1988: (1) to direct the FBI to coordinate with federal agencies and departments to implement required reports of crime statistics, and (2) to direct the FBI to report annually to Congress on the efforts of federal agencies and departments to comply.

(Sec. 403) This section requires ICE HSI to report to Congress on human trafficking investigations.

TITLE V--TRAINING AND TECHNICAL ASSISTANCE

(Sec. 501) The bill directs DOJ, the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), and the Department of Labor to periodically improve the human trafficking training programs for their employees.

DOJ and DHS must: (1) develop an advanced training curriculum to supplement the basic curriculum, and (2) provide the advanced training to employees and task force members who investigate human trafficking offenses.

(Sec. 502) The bill amends the Combat Human Trafficking Act of 2015 to require DOJ to include, in each anti-trafficking program, technical training on: (1) determining whether individuals suspected of engaging in commercial sex acts, illegal child labor, or forced labor are trafficking victims; and (2) limiting arrests or prosecutions of trafficking victims for crimes they commit as a direct result of their victimization.

DOJ must establish a victim screening protocol for use during anti-trafficking law enforcement operations.

(Sec. 503) It amends the Victims of Child Abuse Act of 1990 to direct the Office of Juvenile Justice Delinquency and Prevention, with respect to grants to juvenile and family courts, to give priority to programs that improve the judicial response to children who are vulnerable to human trafficking.

(Sec. 504) DOJ, in consultation with the Office of Tribal Justice, must implement a program for tribal law enforcement officials to receive technical training and assistance on victim-centered approaches to investigating and prosecuting severe forms of trafficking.

TITLE VI--ACCOUNTABILITY

(Sec. 601) The bill amends the Violence Against Women Reauthorization Act of 2013 to specify that accountability provisions apply to grants: (1) to develop model technical assistance and training programs to improve the judicial system's handling of child abuse and neglect cases, and (2) to state courts or judicial administrators for programs that provide or contract for the implementation of training and technical assistance to judicial personnel and attorneys in juvenile and family courts and administrative reform in juvenile and family courts.

TITLE VII--PUBLIC-PRIVATE PARTNERSHIP ADVISORY COUNCIL TO END HUMAN TRAFFICKING

Public-Private Partnership Advisory Council to End Human Trafficking Act

(Sec. 703) This bill establishes the Public-Private Partnership Advisory Council to End Human Trafficking to provide advice and recommendations to the Senior Policy Operating Group and the President's Interagency Task Force to Monitor and Combat Trafficking.

It sets forth functions of the council, including to review federal policy and programs to combat human trafficking.

(Sec. 704) The council must report on its review of federal policy and programs to combat human trafficking.

 (Sec. 705) The council terminates on September 30, 2020.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
