<bill session="115" type="s" number="1250" updated="2019-06-21T11:07:18Z">
  <state datetime="2018-04-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Indian Health Care Improvement Act to improve the recruitment and retention of employees in the Indian Health Service, restore accountability in the Indian Health Service, improve health services, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring Accountability in the Indian Health Service Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring Accountability in the Indian Health Service Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Restoring Accountability in the Indian Health Service Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2018-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2017-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-13">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 115-89.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-04-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="5874"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="2662"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employee performance"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Restoring Accountability in the Indian Health Service Act of 2017

This bill amends the Indian Health Care Improvement Act to require the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a pay system for health care professionals employed by Indian Health Service (IHS) that is competitive with the salary of health care professionals employed by the Veterans Health Administration. HHS may establish incentives related to IHS employee recruitment and retention by providing relocation costs and rental assistance to employees under certain circumstances.

In addition, IHS must: centralize its credentialing system for licensed health professionals seeking to provide health care services at its facilities, establish standards to measure the timeliness of health care services in its facilities, implement an annual mandatory program that provides cultural training for certain IHS employees and contractors, and establish a demonstration project to provide additional staffing resources to understaffed IHS facilities. Liability protections are given to certain health care professionals who volunteer at IHS facilities.

The bill expands the IHS student loan repayment program to include loan repayments for degrees related to health administration. HHS may: (1) directly hire candidates to positions within IHS; and (2) remove, transfer, or demote certain IHS employees based on performance or misconduct. HHS must establish a tribal consultation policy for IHS. The bill establishes: (1) whistle blower protections for IHS employees, and (2) requirements concerning IHS fiscal accountability and transparency.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
