<bill session="115" type="h" number="5840" updated="2019-05-03T17:48:18Z">
  <state datetime="2018-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To state the policy of the United States with respect to the extended nuclear deterrence posture of the United States in support of NATO and to direct the Secretary of Defense to provide Congress a briefing on such posture.</title>
    <title type="display">To state the policy of the United States with respect to the extended nuclear deterrence posture of the United States in support of NATO and to direct the Secretary of Defense to provide Congress a briefing on such posture.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001257"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001168" joined="2018-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-05-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Collective security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-05-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill states that it is the policy of the United States to: (1) maintain a modernized nuclear capability that provides for effective deterrence against peer, near-peer, and regional adversaries, consistent with the national security interests of the United States; (2) extend the nuclear deterrent of the United States to deter aggression against close allies of the United States, including members of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO); and (3) ensure the highest levels of reliability, credibility, safety, and security for all nuclear weapons of the United States, including those forward-deployed in support of NATO.

The Department of Defense shall provide Congress, upon request, a briefing regarding the current status of, and future plans for, the extended nuclear deterrence posture of the United States in support of NATO.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
