<bill session="114" type="s" number="2056" updated="2019-03-03T14:41:01Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the establishment of the National Volcano Early Warning and Monitoring System.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Volcano Early Warning and Monitoring System Act</title>
    <title type="display">National Volcano Early Warning and Monitoring System Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2015-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2016-04-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 114-509.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Earth sciences"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Volcano Early Warning and Monitoring System Act

This bill directs the United States Geological Survey (USGS) to establish the National Volcano Early Warning and Monitoring System to monitor, issue warnings of, and protect U.S. citizens from undue and avoidable harm from, volcanic activity.

The purposes of the System are to: (1) organize, modernize, standardize, and stabilize the monitoring systems of U.S. volcano observatories; and (2) unify such systems into a single interoperative system. The objective of the System is to monitor all U.S. volcanoes at a level commensurate with the threat posed by the volcanoes by: (1) upgrading existing networks on monitored volcanoes, and (2) installing new networks on unmonitored volcanoes.

The System shall include: (1) a national volcano watch office that is operational 24 hours a day and 7 days a week, (2) a national volcano data center, (3) an external grants program to support research in volcano monitoring science and technology, and (4) modernization activities including the comprehensive application of emerging technologies.

The USGS must: (1) submit to Congress a five-year management plan for establishing and operating the System, and (2) establish an advisory committee to assist in implementing the System.

 The USGS may enter into cooperative agreements designating institutions of higher education and state agencies as volcano observatory partners for the System.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
