<bill session="114" type="h" number="2045" updated="2019-01-29T22:16:11Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Targeting Rogue and Opaque Letters Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Targeting Rogue and Opaque Letters Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that certain bad faith communications in connection with the assertion of a United States patent are unfair or deceptive acts or practices, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Targeting Rogue and Opaque Letters Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001248"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001274" joined="2016-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000456" joined="2015-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001045" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000378" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000567" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001190" joined="2015-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-04-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 30 - 22.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-05-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-16">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 114-877.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-12-16" calendar="Union" number="688">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 688.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Consumer Protection and Commerce" code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="632"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-16T13:42:18Z" status="Reported to House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Targeting Rogue and Opaque Letters Act of 2015

(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Federal Trade Commission (FTC), and authorizes state attorneys general, to enforce against written communications (commonly referred to as demand letters) that represent in bad faith that the recipient bears liability or owes compensation for infringing an asserted patent. The pattern or practice of sending such bad faith demand letters shall be treated as an unfair or deceptive act or practice in violation of the Federal Trade Commission Act.

The bill sets forth the types of bad faith representations, assertions of legal action, claims of a sender holding an exclusive license, compensation requests, or omissions that are considered to be unfair or deceptive.

The bill provides an affirmative defense if the sender can show that statements, representations, or omissions were mistakes made in good faith, which may be demonstrated by a preponderance of evidence that the violation was not intentional and resulted from a bona fide error notwithstanding the maintenance of procedures reasonably adapted to avoid any such error.

(Sec. 3) The bill provides the FTC with authority to enforce against violations.

(Sec. 4) The bill preempts state or local laws expressly relating to the transmission or contents of communications regarding the assertion of patent rights. But the bill shall not be contrued to limit any other state laws, including those relating to consumer protection, fraud, deception, trespass, contracts, or torts.

State attorneys general may bring civil actions in federal court to enjoin violations or obtain civil penalties for violations of this bill. The maximum civil penalty for which a person may be liable for a series of related violations is $5 million.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-877</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
