<amendment session="113" chamber="h" number="89" updated="2016-10-25T16:33:32Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2216" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2013-06-04T18:00:19-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000556"/>
  <offered datetime="2013-06-04"/>
  <description>Amendment prevents the award of contracts of money allocated under the bill to offerors or principals of offerors who, within the 3-year period preceding the offer, have been convicted or had a civil judgement rendered against them for such action as fraud, theft, bribery, making false statements and tax evasion.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment to prohibit the use of funds to be used to enter into a contract with any offeror that within a three-year period preceeding the offer has been convicted of fraud or a criminal offense while obtaining a public contract; violation of antitrust statutes relating to the submission of offers; embezzlement, theft, forgery, bribery, falsification of records, tax evasion, or violating Federal criminal tax laws; or has been notified of any delinquent Federal taxes in an amount that exceeds $3,000 for which the liability remains unsatisfied.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2013-06-04T18:00:19-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Grayson amendment (A013) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-06-04T17:58:42-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A013) offered by Mr. Grayson.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3077" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3077" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-04"/>
    <action datetime="2013-06-04T18:00:19-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-04T18:00:19-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Grayson amendment (A013) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-04T17:58:42-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A013) offered by Mr. Grayson.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3077" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3077" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-04">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
