<bill session="114" type="h" number="5062" updated="2019-02-01T21:05:43Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">21st Century American Service Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a more inclusive voluntary civilian national service program to promote civic engagement, enhance national unity, and foster a sense of shared sacrifice by helping young Americans participate in national service, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">21st Century American Service Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000622"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000287" joined="2016-07-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2016-04-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Investment" code="HSED13" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4949"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Corporation for National and Community Service"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="National and community service"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">21st Century American Service Act

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to exclude from gross income any AmeriCorps educational awards provided under the National and Community Service Act of 1990.

The bill establishes within the Corporation for National and Community Service the 21st Century National Service Program Implementing Taskforce, which shall develop a 21st Century National Service Program to notify 18-year olds of opportunities to serve in a voluntary national service program.

The Taskforce shall develop a 10-year strategic implementation plan for the 21st Century National Service Program and publish it on the Corporation website.

The Corporation shall establish, with a certain number of participating states, a national service college compact pilot program under which eligible individuals may use an educational award to attend a public institution of higher education for a two- or four-year program of instruction, or a career or technical education program, at no additional charge.

 An eligible individual shall be one who completes successfully or agrees to complete:

 two required terms of full-time national service in an approved national service position for purposes of eligibility for two educational awards; and at least one calendar year of employment with a federal, state, or local government entity or a nonprofit organization. The Corporation and a state participating in the national service compact shall jointly select the individual eligible to receive an educational award for attending a public institution of higher education in the state.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
