<bill session="115" type="h" number="1548" updated="2019-04-18T16:04:33Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to require all political committees to notify the Federal Election Commission within 48 hours of receiving cumulative contributions of $1,000 or more from any contributor during a calendar year, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Real Time Transparency Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Real Time Transparency Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Real Time Transparency Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001190" joined="2018-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="589"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1880"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Real Time Transparency Act of 2017

This bill amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to revise the notification requirement for campaign contributions of $1,000 or more. The bill applies this requirement to any political committee, not just a candidate's principal campaign committee, regarding cumulative contributions (instead of single contributions) of $1,000 or more during a calendar year. Only the Federal Election Commission (FEC) must be notified, instead of the FEC and others.

Any amount transferred by a joint fundraising committee established by a candidate's authorized committee to any other authorized committee of that candidate shall be treated as a contribution.

Senate candidates must file designations, statements, and reports directly with the FEC instead of via the Senate.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
