<bill session="113" type="h" number="2153" updated="2018-06-05T16:23:17Z">
  <state datetime="2013-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Veterans Affairs Disease Reporting and Oversight Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to require the reporting of cases of infectious diseases at facilities of the Veterans Health Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Department of Veterans Affairs Disease Reporting and Oversight Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000482"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001185" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001151" joined="2013-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" code="HSVR08" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="identical" number="875"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-05-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Department of Veterans Affairs Disease Reporting and Oversight Act of 2013 - Requires the director of a Veterans Integrated Service Network, within 24 hours after confirming the presence of a notifiable infectious disease (any infectious disease that is either on a specified published list of nationally notifiable diseases or that is covered by a provision of law of a state that requires the reporting of infectious diseases) at a Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) facility under that director's jurisdiction, to notify: (1) the Central Office of the VA; (2) the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention; (3) the state and county in which the facility is located; (4) each individual at the facility who has contracted the disease or is at risk of doing so, as well as the individual's next of kin, the individual's primary health care provider, and the county in which the individual resides; and (5) each VA employee of such facility. Requires such director to comply with any earlier notification required by the state concerned.

Requires such director to: (1) confirm receipt of such notification, (2) develop and implement an action plan to manage and control the potential spread of the disease, and (3) keep records of any such notifications for at least 10 years. Requires an annual report from the VA Inspector General to Congress on directors' compliance with the requirements of this Act. Provides for Inspector General enforcement and appropriate director disciplinary action with respect to such requirements.

Directs the Under Secretary for Health of the Veterans Health Administration (VHA) to issue a directive to the VHA's pathology team, infection prevention team, facilities management team, and other appropriate VHA groups on the actions to be taken when a notifiable infectious disease is discovered in a VHA facility.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
