<bill session="115" type="hr" number="651" updated="2019-04-18T15:54:45Z">
  <state datetime="2017-12-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that Burundi is at risk of mass atrocities, and that the Government of Burundi should comply with constitutional limits on presidential terms and re-engage in regionally-brokered peace talks.</title>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that Burundi is at risk of mass atrocities, and that the Government of Burundi should comply with constitutional limits on presidential terms and re-engage in regionally-brokered peace talks.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000179"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001270" joined="2017-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001059" joined="2017-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2018-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-12-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Burundi"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-12-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Calls upon the government of Burundi to: (1) accept unarmed United Nations (U.N.) police to monitor the security and human rights situation, (2) disarm those engaged in political violence and the illegal possession of weapons, (3) investigate allegations of human rights violations and hold perpetrators accountable, (4) allow the full deployment of African Union human rights observers and military experts throughout the country, and (5) participate in the political dialogue led by the East African Community (EAC) without preconditions.

Calls on: (1) the political opposition in Burundi to renounce violence, (2) Burundian stakeholders to participate in the Inter-Burundian Dialogue to peacefully resolve contentious issues, (3) the EAC to guarantee the inclusiveness of the dialogue process, (4) the African Union to impose targeted sanctions on those perpetuating violence, and (5) the U.N. Security Council to impose targeted sanctions against all who threaten the peace and security of Burundi.

Calls on the President of the United States to impose specified additional targeted sanctions, including against any individuals responsible for or complicit in actions or policies that threaten the peace, security, or stability of Burundi or that undermine democratic processes.

Calls on the Department of State and the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) to use appropriated funds to: (1) continue U.S. humanitarian assistance and food aid for Burundians, (2) support media, civil society, and human rights actors on the ground to create opportunities for inclusive citizen participation in political dialogue, (3) develop a strategy and programming to address the medium-term risk of political violence, and (4) ensure that the USAID and the State Department are adequately staffed to monitor and develop strategies to rapidly respond to contingencies on the ground.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
