<bill session="115" type="h" number="4523" updated="2019-05-09T13:11:32Z">
  <state datetime="2017-12-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-12-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-12-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to expand retirement plan coverage, increase retirement security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Automatic Retirement Plan Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Automatic Retirement Plan Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Automatic Retirement Plan Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000015"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-12-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3219"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3902"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="854"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3910"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-12-01T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Automatic Retirement Plan Act of 2017 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to require certain employers to maintain automatic contribution retirement plans for employees. Governments, churches, small employers (10 or fewer employees), certain new businesses, and employers who already maintain certain retirement plans are exempt from the requirement.

Automatic contribution retirement plans are defined contribution plans, which must meet specified requirements regarding the eligibility of employees to enroll, automatic enrollment, investments, lifetime income, and fees.

The bill also:

 imposes an excise tax on employers who fail to maintain an automatic contribution plan; increases the dollar limitation for the tax credit for small employer pension plan startup costs; allows a tax credit for small employers who adopt automatic contribution retirement plans; modifies certain nondiscrimination rules that would otherwise apply to the automatic contribution plans; modifies certain fiduciary, qualification, and administrative rules that apply to multiple employer plans; allows states to continue certain programs that require automatic contribution plans; allows a refundable tax credit for certain retirement savings contributions and requires the Department of the Treasury to pay the credit as a contribution to the applicable retirement account; and provides for the portability of lifetime income investment options by permitting a rollover into another retirement plan if the investment is no longer authorized to be held as an investment option under an employer-sponsored plan.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
