<bill session="115" type="h" number="4181" updated="2019-04-18T16:17:07Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-10-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 regarding proprietary institutions of higher education in order to protect students and taxpayers.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">POST Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">POST Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Our Students and Taxpayers Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Our Students and Taxpayers Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">POST Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001068"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-10-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1463"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="2037"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-10-31T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Our Students and Taxpayers Act of 2017 or the POST Act of 2017

 This bill amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA) to modify requirements for a proprietary (i.e., for-profit) institution of higher education (IHE) to participate in title IV (Student Assistance) federal student aid programs.

Current law requires a proprietary IHE to derive at least 10% of its revenue from sources other than title IV federal student aid. This legislation requires a proprietary IHE to derive at least 15% of its revenue from sources other than federal funds (i.e., it replaces the so-called 90/10 rule with an 85/15 rule). It defines federal funds to mean title IV federal student aid, as well as education benefits for military personnel and veterans.

Additionally, the bill limits what a proprietary institution may treat as revenue to the school in calculating whether it derives at least 15% of its revenue from sources other than federal funds.

Finally, the bill moves the 85/15 rule from title IV to title I (General Provisions) of the HEA, making compliance a condition of institutional eligibility to participate in title IV federal student aid programs (i.e., failure to comply results in immediate loss of institutional eligibility). Currently, a proprietary IHE must violate the rule for two consecutive years before losing eligibility for title IV programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
