<bill session="115" type="hj" number="127" updated="2019-04-18T15:56:45Z">
  <state datetime="2018-01-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-01-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-01-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making continuing appropriations for military pay and for death gratuities and related survivor benefits for survivors of deceased military service members of the Department of Defense for fiscal year 2018, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pay Our Military Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Pay Our Military Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001077"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-01-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-01-19T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Pay Our Military Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2018 

This joint resolution provides FY2018 continuing appropriations to the Department of Defense (DOD) for military pay, death gratuities, and related benefits for survivors of deceased members of the military. The funding is available until the earlier of September 30, 2018, or the enactment of specified appropriations legislation.

The joint resolution provides continuing appropriations for:

 the payment of a death gratuity, the payment or reimbursement of funeral and burial expenses, the payment or reimbursement of authorized funeral travel and travel related to the dignified transfer of remains and unit memorial services, and the temporary continuation of a basic allowance of housing for dependents of members dying on active duty. It also provides continuing appropriations for pay and allowances of: (1) members of the Armed Forces, including reserve components, who perform active service during the period for which the funds are available; and (2) civilian personnel or contractors of DOD (and the Department of Homeland Security in the case of the Coast Guard) who are providing support to members of the Armed Forces.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
