<bill session="114" type="hj" number="66" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:21Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Iran Accountability and Enforcement Resolution</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the use of the Armed Forces of the United States against Iran if the President determines and certifies to Congress that Iran is not able to demonstrate that it has not sought, developed, or acquired nuclear weapons in violation of its commitments or obligations under the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Iran Accountability and Enforcement Resolution</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001048"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001094" joined="2015-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000378" joined="2015-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000603" joined="2015-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000804" joined="2015-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000018" joined="2015-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-09T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Iran Accountability and Enforcement Resolution

This resolution authorizes the President to use the U.S. Armed Forces against Iran if the President certifies to Congress that Iran is unable to demonstrate that it has not sought, developed, or acquired nuclear weapons in violation of its obligations under the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPA).

It is U.S. policy that Iran must comply with its reaffirmation in the JCPA that it will never seek, develop, or acquire a nuclear weapon.

Congress declares that this resolution is intended to constitute specific statutory authorization within the meaning of section 5(b) of the War Powers Resolution.

Nothing in this resolution supersedes any requirement of the War Powers Resolution.

The Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action means the agreement signed at Vienna July 14, 2015, by Iran and by China, France, Germany, the Russian Federation, the United Kingdom, and the United States, with the High Representative of the European Union for Foreign Affairs and Security Policy, and all implementing materials and agreements related to the JCPA.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
