<bill session="114" type="s" number="739" updated="2018-06-02T06:41:02Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Access to Extended Care Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modify the treatment of agreements entered into by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to furnish nursing home care, adult day health care, or other extended care services, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Veterans Access to Extended Care Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2015-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2015-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="1369"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Adult day care"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Veterans Access to Extended Care Act of 2015

This bill modifies the treatment of Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) agreements with service providers to furnish veterans with nursing home care, adult day health care, or other extended care services.

Any such agreement shall:

 not be treated as a federal contract for the acquisition of goods or services and shall be not subject to any provision of law governing federal contracts for the acquisition of goods or services, and include specified requirements (such as for medical licensing and VA review of staff and facilities) to ensure the safety and quality of care furnished to veterans pursuant to such agreement. The failure of a provider to comply with a provision of the agreement may result in VA termination of the agreement.

Such agreements are exempted from the application of certain public contract labor laws.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
