<bill session="114" type="s" number="951" updated="2018-06-02T06:45:03Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Taxpayer Bill of Rights Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to clarify that a duty of the Commissioner of Internal Revenue is to ensure that Internal Revenue Service employees are familiar with and act in accord with certain taxpayer rights.</title>
    <title type="display">Taxpayer Bill of Rights Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000368"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1058"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="943"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Taxpayer Bill of Rights Act of 2015

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to direct the Commissioner of the Internal Revenue Service (IRS)&#160;to ensure that all IRS employees are familiar with and act in accordance with taxpayer rights, including: (1) the right to be informed, including&#160;through reasonable access to tax forms and instructions and to written guidance that is accessible, consistent, written in plain language and easy to understand; (2) the right to be treated fairly, professionally, and courteously by IRS employees; (3) the right to pay no more than the correct amount of tax; (4) the right to challenge the position of the IRS and to be heard; (5) the right to appeal a decision of the IRS in an independent forum; (6) the right to finality, privacy, and confidentiality; (7) the right to retain representation; and (8) the right to a fair and just tax system that does not target individuals or organizations based upon their beliefs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
