<bill session="115" type="s" number="1711" updated="2019-04-26T14:00:49Z">
  <state datetime="2017-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to assist States in adopting updated interconnection procedures and tariff schedules and standards for supplemental, backup, and standby power fees for projects for combined heat and power technology and waste heat to power technology, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HEAT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HEAT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Heat Efficiency through Applied Technology Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Heat Efficiency through Applied Technology Act</title>
    <title type="display">HEAT Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-08-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Lighting, heating, cooling"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-08-02T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Heat Efficiency through Applied Technology Act or the HEAT Act

This bill directs the Department of Energy to establish model rules and procedures for (1)interconnection and its associated costs; and (2)determining fees or rates for supplementary power, backup or standby power, maintenance power, and interruptible power supplied to facilities that operate combined heat and power technology and waste heat to power technology. ("Interconnection" means service to an electric consumer under which an on-site generating facility on the consumer's premises is connected to the local distribution facilities.)

The bill also directs the Environmental Protection Agency to create a voluntary grant program to encourage states to update state or local air permitting procedures to incorporate output-based emission standards. ("Output-based emission standard" means a standard that relates emissions to the electrical, thermal, or mechanical productive output of a device or process rather than the heat input of fuel burned or pollutant concentration in the exhaust.)</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
