<bill session="114" type="h" number="2960" updated="2019-04-11T15:42:41Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to aid gifted and talented and high-ability learners by empowering the Nation's teachers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TALENT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">To Aid Gifted and High-Ability Learners by Empowering the Nation's Teachers Act</title>
    <title type="display">TALENT Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000598"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001248" joined="2015-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000066" joined="2015-07-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-08-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Research and Technology" code="HSSY15" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="363"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">To Aid Gifted and High-Ability Learners by Empowering the Nation's Teachers Act or the TALENT Act

This bill amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require state assessments of student proficiency to measure individual academic achievement, including above grade level achievement.

States must: (1) assist their local educational agencies (LEAs) and schools in providing additional educational assistance to advanced, gifted, and talented students; and (2) report annually a comparison of the performance of students between different LEAs at each level of achievement, disaggregated by specified student subgroups.

LEAs must identify gifted and talented students and support their learning needs and train educators to implement instructional practices that support their education.

The Institute of Education Sciences must: (1) continue research and development activities regarding the education of gifted and talented students; (2) support a National Research and Dissemination Center on the Gifted and Talented; (3) administer demonstration grants that enhance the ability of educators to support gifted and talented students; and (4) ensure that statistical data regarding the education of gifted and talented children is collected, reported, analyzed, and disseminated.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
