<bill session="115" type="h" number="5569" updated="2019-04-18T16:22:42Z">
  <state datetime="2018-04-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-04-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a pilot program to enhance the mapping of urban flooding and associated property damage and the availability of such mapped data to homeowners, businesses, and localities to help understand and mitigate the risk of such flooding, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Flood Mapping Modernization and Homeowner Empowerment Pilot Program Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Flood Mapping Modernization and Homeowner Empowerment Pilot Program Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Flood Mapping Modernization and Homeowner Empowerment Pilot Program Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Q000023"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001048" joined="2018-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000576" joined="2018-04-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-04-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2701"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-04-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Flood Mapping Modernization and Homeowner Empowerment Pilot Program Act of 2018

This bill directs the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to carry out a pilot program to make grants to local governments to enhance the mapping of urban flooding and associated property damage and the availability of such mapping data to homeowners, businesses, and localities to enable them to minimize flooding risk. The grants may only be made to local governments in urbanized areas with populations greater than 50,000 or to stormwater management authorities in those localities.

FEMA shall give priority to grant applicants in areas that (1) are highly vulnerable to a sea level rise, (2) include a military installation or other national security facility, or (3) have a population highly vulnerable to urban flooding and have an uneven capacity for flood mitigation and response efforts due to socioeconomic factors.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
