<bill session="114" type="s" number="3295" updated="2018-06-02T07:47:55Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Cybersecurity Preparedness Consortium Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security to work with cybersecurity consortia for training, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">National Cybersecurity Preparedness Consortium Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2016-11-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5373" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4743"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Cybersecurity Preparedness Consortium Act of 2016

This bill authorizes the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to work with a consortium, including the National Cybersecurity Preparedness Consortium, to support efforts to address cybersecurity risks and incidents, including threats or acts of terrorism.

DHS may work with such a consortium to assist its national cybersecurity and communications integration center to:

 provide training to state and local first responders and officials, develop curriculums, and provide technical assistance; conduct cross-sector cybersecurity training and simulation exercises for state and local governments, critical infrastructure owners and operators, and private industry; help states and communities develop cybersecurity information sharing programs; and help incorporate cybersecurity risk and incident prevention and response into existing state and local emergency plans and continuity of operations plans.

 DHS's authority to carry out this bill terminates five years after its enactment.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
