<bill session="113" type="h" number="1582" updated="2016-10-25T16:38:21Z">
  <state datetime="2013-08-01T15:41:30-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-08-01T15:41:30-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Consumers Relief Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Energy Consumers Relief Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Energy Consumers Relief Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect consumers by prohibiting the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency from promulgating as final certain energy-related rules that are estimated to cost more than $1 billion and will cause significant adverse effects to the economy.</title>
    <title type="display">Energy Consumers Relief Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001282" joined="2013-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2013-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001045" joined="2013-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000363" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001180" joined="2013-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000413" joined="2013-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-11">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 25 - 18.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-07-22">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 113-164.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-22" calendar="Union" number="118">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 118.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T20:00:03-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 315 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2218 and H.R. 1582.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T14:23:57-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 315 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31T18:38:27-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 315.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5242-5249" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5246-5247" label="text of admendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31T18:38:32-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2218 and H.R. 1582.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31T18:38:43-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 315 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31T18:38:44-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Ileana Ros-Lehtinen to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31T18:38:51-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1582.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31T19:26:07-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 315, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Waxamn amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31T19:33:28-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Waxman amendment No. 1, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Waxman demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31T19:34:56-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 315, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Connolly amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31T19:42:35-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Connolly amendment No. 3, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Connolly demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31T19:42:54-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Whitfield moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31T19:43:20-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31T19:43:34-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1582 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01T13:54:33-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5285-5288" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01T13:55:10-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01T13:56:13-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 315, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Woodall amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01T14:06:57-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 315, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Murphy (PA) amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01T14:20:28-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Murphy (PA) amendment No. 6, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Waxman demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01T14:21:08-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Cassidy moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01T14:21:27-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01T14:21:37-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1582 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01T14:35:01-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5288-5293" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01T14:35:15-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01T14:36:08-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01T15:15:41-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1582.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01T15:16:28-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5291" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01T15:17:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01T15:17:59-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Capps moved to recommit with instructions to Energy and Commerce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5291-5292" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5291" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01T15:18:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Capps motion to recommit with instructions, pending the reservation of a point of order. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House forthwith with an amendment to add a section prohibiting anything in the bill to apply with respect to rules that will result in reduced incidence of cancer, premature mortality, asthma attacks, or respiratory disease in children or seniors. Subsequently, the reservation of the point of order was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01T15:25:49-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5291-5292" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01T15:34:13-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 188 - 221 (Roll no. 431).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="432" datetime="2013-08-01T15:41:30-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 232 - 181 (Roll no. 432).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01T15:41:31-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Legislative Interest"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Power" code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="113" relation="procedurally-related" number="315"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1363"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="3355"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="5360"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="General energy matters"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h447"/>
    <amendment number="h446"/>
    <amendment number="h445"/>
    <amendment number="h444"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2013-08-01T15:40:49Z" status="Passed House amended">Energy Consumers Relief Act of 2013 - Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), before promulgating a final rule that regulates any aspect of the production, supply, distribution, or use of energy (or that provides for such regulation by state or local governments) and that is estimated by the Administrator or the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to impose aggregate costs of more than $1 billion, to submit a report that contains: (1) an estimate of the total costs and benefits of the rule, (2) an estimate of the increases in energy prices that may result from implementation or enforcement of the rule, and (3) a detailed description of the employment effects that may result from implementation or enforcement of the rule.

Requires the Secretary of Energy (DOE): (1) to prepare an independent analysis to determine whether such rule will cause any increase in energy prices for consumers, any impact on fuel diversity of the nation's electricity generation portfolio or on electric reliability, or any adverse effect on energy supply, distribution, or use; and (2) upon making such a determination, to determine whether the rule will cause significant adverse effects to the economy and publish such determination in the Federal Register.

Prohibits the Administrator from promulgating any such final rule if the Secretary determines that such rule will cause significant adverse effects to the economy.

Prohibits the Administrator from using the social cost of carbon in any cost-benefit analysis relating to an energy-related rule estimated to cost more than $1 billion unless and until a federal law is enacted authorizing such use.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 113-164</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
