<bill session="115" type="h" number="3340" updated="2019-04-18T16:13:10Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide taxpayer protection and assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Taxpayer Rights Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Taxpayer Rights Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Strengthening Taxpayer Rights Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000399"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2017-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2017-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000617" joined="2017-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001038" joined="2017-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000557" joined="2017-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000263" joined="2017-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001185" joined="2017-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2017-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Strengthening Taxpayer Rights Act of 2017 

This bill modifies requirements for the preparation of tax returns and Internal Revenue Service (IRS) procedures for the collection of taxes.

The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to:

 apply tax preparer penalties for the understatement of a taxpayer's liability and other violations to other submissions to the IRS, in addition to tax returns or refund claims; increase tax preparer penalties for gross misconduct and other violations; require identifying numbers to be included for all submissions to the IRS by tax return preparers (limited to tax returns or refund claims under current law); limit the disclosure of taxpayer information to the express purpose for which the taxpayer granted consent; provide for de novo review by the Tax Court of IRS innocent spouse relief determinations; specify that the determination of whether or not a debt has been discharged may not be based solely on a nonpayment period; and restrict the authority of the IRS to use a levy after the collection period has expired. The bill amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to reduce from seven years to two years the period that a tax lien may appear on a taxpayer's credit report.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
