<bill session="113" type="h" number="4874" updated="2016-10-25T16:14:08Z">
  <state datetime="2014-06-18">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SCRUB Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Searching for and Cutting Regulations that are Unnecessarily Burdensome Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">SCRUB Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">SCRUB Act of 2014Searching for and Cutting Regulations that are Unnecessarily Burdensome Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the establishment of a process for the review of rules and sets of rules, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SCRUB Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001195"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000013" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000266" joined="2014-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000556" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001093" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000621" joined="2014-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000460" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000448" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001059" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000569" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001179" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000592" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000812" joined="2014-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-17">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-17">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-17">
      <text>Referred to House Appropriations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-18">
      <text>Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 17 - 10.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-24">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 22 - 15.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-12">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 113-675, Part I.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" code="HSJU05" name="House Judiciary" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="3011"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-12-12T13:56:48Z" status="Reported to House without amendment, Part I">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Searching for and Cutting Regulations that are Unnecessarily Burdensome Act of 2014 or the SCRUB Act of 2014 - Title I: Retrospective Regulatory Review Commission - Establishes the Retrospective Regulatory Review Commission to review the Code of Federal Regulations (CFR) to identify, using specified criteria, rules and sets of rules that collectively implement a regulatory program&#160;that should be repealed to lower the cost of regulation to the economy, giving priority to major rules that: (1) have been in effect more than 15 years, (2) impose paperwork burdens that could be reduced substantially without significantly diminishing regulatory effectiveness,&#160;(3) impose disproportionately high costs on small business entities, and (4) could be strengthened in their effectiveness while reducing regulatory costs.&#160;

Title II: Regulatory Cut-go - Requires a federal agency that makes a new rule to&#160;repeal rules identified by the Commission to offset the cost to the economy of&#160;such new rule (cut-go procedures). Requires the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to review and certify the accuracy of agency determinations of the cost of new rules.

Title III: Retrospective Review of New Rules - Requires a federal agency that makes a new rule to include in the final issuance of such rule a plan for reviewing the rule not later than 10 years after it is promulgated.

Title IV: Judicial Review - Makes agency compliance with the requirements of this Act subject to judicial review.

Title V: Miscellaneous Provisions - Defines terms used in this Act and makes it effective upon enactment.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 113-675</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
