<bill session="114" type="h" number="5497" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:39Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hospital Price Transparency and Disclosure Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for the public disclosure of charges for certain hospital and ambulatory surgical center treatment episodes.</title>
    <title type="display">Hospital Price Transparency and Disclosure Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000563"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3409"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Surgery and anesthesia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Hospital Price Transparency and Disclosure Act of 2016

This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to require hospitals and ambulatory surgical centers to report to the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS): (1) the frequency of certain treatment episodes for the most frequently treated conditions in each setting, (2) the total number of such treatment episodes, and (3) the average charge for the insured and uninsured for such a treatment episode.&#160;

HHS must publish on its website: (1) such information in a manner that promotes charge comparisons among hospitals and among ambulatory surgical centers, and (2) a link to other consumer quality information maintained on an HHS or Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services website. Hospitals and ambulatory surgical centers must post prominently at each admission site a notice of the availability of such data.

Civil penalties are authorized for violations of this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
