<bill session="114" type="h" number="6113" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:54Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">End For-Profit Prisons Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To restrict the authority of the Attorney General to enter into contracts for Federal correctional facilities and community confinement facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">End For-Profit Prisons Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000822"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-10-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">End For-Profit Prisons Act of 2016

This bill requires the Department of Justice (DOJ) to phase out existing contracts with private prison companies and private community confinement facilities.

It amends the federal criminal code to require federal employees to perform the core correctional services&#8212;housing, safeguarding, protecting, and disciplining of offenders&#8212;at correctional facilities used by the Bureau of Prisons (BOP) or the U.S. Marshals Service.

The bill also prohibits the BOP from entering into or maintaining contracts with private companies to manage community confinement facilities (e.g., halfway houses).

DOJ must evaluate the effectiveness of and develop guidelines for recidivism reduction programs at community confinement facilities.

The Marshals Service must annually inspect each correctional facility it uses for confinement.

The BOP must provide to prisoners, as part of prerelease procedures, information and counseling about: criminal record expungement; educational, employment, and treatment programs; and applications for public assistance programs. The BOP must also provide prisoners with post-release information about fines, assessments, surcharges, restitution, and other penalties.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
