<bill session="114" type="h" number="655" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:00Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FCC "ABCs" Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to reform the Federal Communications Commission by requiring an analysis of benefits and costs during the rule making process and creating certain presumptions regarding regulatory forbearance and biennial regulatory review determinations.</title>
    <title type="display">FCC "ABCs" Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000566"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001257" joined="2015-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Communications and Technology" code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-02T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">FCC "ABCs" Act of 2015

Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to direct the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), in the case of a proposed or final rule (including a proposed or final amendment to an existing rule) that may have an economically significant impact, to include in the notice a cost-benefit analysis demonstrating that the benefits outweigh the costs, recognizing that some benefits and costs are difficult to quantify.

Defines "economically significant impact" as an effect on the economy of at least $100 million annually or a material adverse effect on the economy, a sector of the economy, productivity, competition, jobs, the environment, public health or safety, or state, local, or tribal governments or communities.

Prohibits any appropriations for the express purpose of carrying out such analysis and notice requirements.

Directs the FCC to presume, absent clear and convincing evidence to the contrary, that: (1) forbearance requirements are met when determining whether to forbear from applying any regulation or provision under such Act to a telecommunications carrier, service, or class; and (2) regulations considered in each biennial regulatory review are no longer necessary in the public interest as the result of meaningful economic competition between providers of telecommunications service.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
