<bill session="114" type="h" number="54" updated="2019-02-14T23:30:52Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Frank Lautenberg Memorial Secure Chemical Facilities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance the security of chemical facilities and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Frank Lautenberg Memorial Secure Chemical Facilities Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Security Technologies.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Innovation" code="HSHM08" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Environment and Climate Change" code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Frank Lautenberg Memorial Secure Chemical Facilities Act

Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to set forth provisions for the regulation of security practices at chemical facilities.

Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security to designate: (1) any chemical substance as a substance of concern and establish and adjust the threshold quantity for each such substance after considering the potential extent of death, injury, and serious adverse effects that could result from a chemical facility terrorist incident; and (2) a chemical facility as a covered chemical facility if the Secretary determines such facility is a sufficient security risk (e.g., a likely target of a chemical facility terrorist incident and close to large population centers).

Directs the Secretary to: (1) maintain a list of covered chemical facilities that are of sufficient security risk; (2) assign each covered facility to one of four risk-based tiers; (3) establish standards and procedures for security vulnerability assessments and site security plans; (4) require each facility owner or operator to submit and, once approved, to implement such an assessment and plan; and (5) establish risk-based chemical security performance standards for site security plans.

Permits the Secretary, under specified circumstances, to: (1) accept an alternate security program submitted by the owner or operator of the facility, (2) conduct facility security inspections, and (3) obtain access to and copy records necessary for reviewing or analyzing a security vulnerability assessment or site security plan.

Requires the Secretary to: (1) share threat information with owners, operators, or security officers of a covered chemical facility, with representative of bargaining agents at the facility, and with relevant state and local government authorities in a timely manner; (2) require a facility owner or operator to provide information concerning a threat to, or any unauthorized penetration of the physical security or cyber security of, the facility in a timely manner; and (3) disapprove and require revisions to a security vulnerability assessment or site security plan that does not comply with the requirements of this Act or that fails to meet security performance standards.

Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) issue an order assessing penalties for noncompliance with this Act, and (2) order a facility owner or operator that continues to be in noncompliance to cease facility operations.

Establishes whistleblower protections for employees of a covered chemical facility who report violations of this Act.

Prohibits the public disclosure of certain protected information related to security vulnerability assessments and site security plans developed pursuant to this Act.

Requires: (1) the Secretary to make available information on the use and availability of methods to reduce the consequences of a chemical facility terrorist attack; (2) site security plans to include an assessment of such methods; and (3) the owner or operator of a tier 1 or tier 2 facility to implement such methods if the Director of the Office of Chemical Facility Security determines that such implementation would significantly reduce the risk of death, injury, or serious adverse effects to human health resulting from a terrorist incident, can feasibly be incorporated into facility operations, and would not significantly impair the owner's or operator's ability to continue the business of the facility at its location.

Requires the Secretary to provide guidance and appropriate, tools, methodologies, or computer software to assist farm supplies merchant wholesalers and small covered chemical facilities in complying with this Act.

Exempts specified facilities from the requirements of this Act, including Department of Defense chemical facilities, Nuclear Regulatory Commission-regulated chemical facilities, public water systems, and treatment works.

Establishes in the Department of Homeland Security an Office of Chemical Facility Security.

Requires the Secretary to require covered chemical facilities to establish personnel surety for facility employees by conducting appropriate security background checks and ensuring appropriate credentials for unescorted facility visitors and personnel.

Authorizes civil actions and citizen petitions by individuals alleging violations of this Act.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish a notification system to report, via telephonic and Internet-based means, a suspected security deficiency or suspected noncompliance with the requirements of this Act; (2) assess and report on the emergency response resources that would be required to feasibly respond to a worst-case chemical facility terrorist incident; and (3) report annually for 10 years on progress in achieving compliance with this Act.

Authorizes appropriations for grants for methods to reduce the consequences of a terrorist attack FY2016-F2020.

Authorizes the Secretary, until final rules issued to carry out this Act take effect, to: (1) continue to carry out existing Chemical Facility Anti-Terrorism Standards regulations, and (2) amend such regulations as necessary to ensure that they are consistent with this Act.

Requires the Secretary to review the designation of sodium fluoroacetate as a substance of concern.

Prohibits the Secretary from using federal funds to approve a site security plan for a chemical facility unless the facility meets or exceeds security standards and requirements to protect the facility against acts of terrorism.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
