<bill session="113" type="s" number="288" updated="2016-10-25T16:20:47Z">
  <state datetime="2013-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Women and Minorities in STEM Booster Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase the participation of historically underrepresented demographic groups in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics education and industry.</title>
    <title type="display">Women and Minorities in STEM Booster Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000550"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2013-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2013-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2013-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000590" joined="2013-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="4833"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-02-12T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Women and Minorities in STEM Booster Act of 2013 - Requires the Director of the National Science Foundation (NSF), acting through the Human Resources Directorate and not less than one research directorate of the NSF, to award competitive grants to eligible entities to enable them to carry out the activities specified below in order to increase the participation of women and underrepresented minorities in the fields of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM).

Requires an eligible entity that receives a grant to use those grant funds to carry out the following activities designed to increase the participation of women and underrepresented minorities in STEM fields: (1) online workshops, (2) mentoring programs that partner STEM professionals with students, (3) internships for undergraduate and graduate students in STEM, and (4) conducting outreach programs providing elementary and secondary school students with opportunities to increase their exposure to STEM.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
