<bill session="114" type="s" number="3174" updated="2018-06-02T07:47:14Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LADDER Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Leveling Access to Demonstrated Drivers of Employment Results Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an Interagency Council on Workforce Attachment to promote effective and coordinated workforce attachment strategies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">LADDER Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000383"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor and aged"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Leveling Access to Demonstrated Drivers of Employment Results Act or the LADDER Act

This bill establishes in the executive branch an independent Interagency Council on Workforce Attachment to:

 facilitate the coordination of federal programs and activities to promote workforce attachment among populations of individuals who face a challenge in consistently maintaining full-time employment, collect evidence of effective strategies to promote workforce attachment among such populations at every level of government and within the private sector, fund demonstration projects to ensure the evaluation of the effectiveness of strategies to promote workforce attachment among such populations; and encourage the implementation of effective strategies. The council shall: (1) review all federal programs and activities designed to promote workforce attachment among such populations, (2) recommend federal and state agency action to increase coordination and reduce duplication among such programs and activities, and (3) ensure that these authorities are implemented in a manner that includes a review of recommendations related to Medicaid Buy-In programs.

The council shall develop a National Strategic Plan to Promote Workforce Attachment.

The council shall award grants to eligible entities to conduct demonstration projects designed to develop, implement, and evaluate strategies to promote workforce attachment among such populations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
