<bill session="114" type="s" number="3105" updated="2018-06-02T07:46:53Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Plymouth 400th Anniversary Commemorative Coin Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Treasury to mint coins in commemoration of the 400th anniversary of the landing and settlement of Plymouth Colony, the signing of the Mayflower Compact, and the role of the indigenous Wampanoag tribes in the realization of the settlement.</title>
    <title type="display">Plymouth 400th Anniversary Commemorative Coin Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2016-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2980"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1715"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="5598"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Plymouth 400th Anniversary Commemorative Coin Act of 2016

This bill directs the Department of the Treasury to issue up to 100,000 $5 gold coins, 500,000 $1 silver coins, and 750,000 half-dollar clad coins emblematic of the landing and settlement of Plymouth Colony, Massachusetts, the signing of the Mayflower Compact, and the role of the indigenous Wampanoag tribes in the realization of the settlement.

These coins may be issued only during a two-year period beginning January 1, 2020.

Sales of such coins shall include specified surcharges, which shall be paid by Treasury as follows:

 50% to Plymouth 400, Inc., to support the its work to develop, implement, and provide oversight for the commemorations surrounding the events of 2020-2021 and to be distributed, at the organization's discretion, to local historical preservation and cultural organizations to support their work in educating the public about the settlement of 1620 and their continued existence for the benefit of future generations; 15% to Plimoth Plantation to support its effort to maintain the replica of the 1627 Plantation, the Mayflower II, and the replica of the Wampanoag Village; 15% to a Wampanoag tribal organization to continue programs to educate people about the life of the Wampanoag people prior to the Plymouth settlement and their interactions with the settlers; 10% to the General Society of Mayflower Descendants to support the continued restoration of the main facility in Plymouth, to provide funding for its research library at that site, and for educational purposes; and 10% to the Pilgrim Society to continue its work in displaying the story of the settlement and settlement artifacts.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
