<bill session="114" type="s" number="2535" updated="2018-06-02T07:14:51Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide deadlines for corrosion control treatment steps for lead and copper in drinking water, and other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to provide deadlines for corrosion control treatment steps for lead and copper in drinking water, and other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2016-02-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4414"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2466"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill amends the Safe Drinking Water Act by requiring small or medium public water systems to sample their tap water for lead and copper in accordance with the Environmental Protection Agency's (EPA) monitoring requirements under the national primary drinking water regulations until the system: (1) exceeds the regulation's lead or copper limits, or (2) becomes eligible for reduced monitoring. Small or medium water systems that exceed the lead and copper limits must carry out certain corrosion control treatment steps by specified deadlines.

Public water systems must notify their customers of lead concentration levels in drinking water when the lead levels exceed those regulatory limits or when the EPA determines the lead concentration warrants notice. The EPA must notify the public about those lead concentrations by a certain deadline if the public water system or the state does not do so. The EPA may notify customers of a public water system or the local or state health department of the result of lead monitoring conducted by a public water system.

States must provide a short-term remedy, including bottled water or a water filtration system, to each affected household when a public water system exceeds lead limits or when the EPA determines the lead concentration warrants notice.

Each state must post online the annual consumer confidence report of each community water system.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
