<bill session="115" type="h" number="2833" updated="2019-04-18T16:10:59Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the President to assess the effects of the sale or export of major defense equipment to countries in the Middle East on the qualitative military edge of Israel, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Defending Israel's QME Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Defending Israel's QME Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Defending Israel's QME Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001190"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000478" joined="2017-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli relations"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-08T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Defending Israel's QME Act of 2017

This bill amends the Arms Export Control Act to require that a determination relating to the sale or export of major defense equipment to a country in the Middle East other than Israel include an assessment of: (1) Israel's ability to defend itself against military threats from regional non-state actors, (2) the risk posed by the sale or export of a subsequent unauthorized transfer or proliferation of the equipment for use against Israel, and (3) countermeasures available to Israel to defend against such unauthorized transfer or proliferation.

The President shall seek to consult with appropriate Israeli government officials for information regarding Israel's qualitative military edge before making a determination that a sale or export of the defense articles or services will not adversely affect Israel's qualitative military edge.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
