<bill session="115" type="s" number="2099" updated="2019-04-18T16:40:13Z">
  <state datetime="2017-11-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-11-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-11-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the management by the Secretary of Agriculture of certain Federal land, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Federal Land Management Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Federal Land Management Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Land Management Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Land Management Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Federal Land Management Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000307"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2017-11-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-11-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-11-16">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry. Reported by Senator Roberts without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-11-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="262">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 262.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1177"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1434"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2218"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2941"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3567"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="571"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="715"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="973"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1975"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2031"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Maine"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-11-16T14:07:14Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">Federal Land Management Act of 2017

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA), upon request of the city of Old Town, Maine, to convey to the city without consideration lands that: (1) were conveyed by the federal government to the city under the Bankhead-Jones Farm Tenant Act by the deed dated June 5, 1941, and (2) are proposed for conveyance for the purpose of economic development.

 The bill authorizes the USDA to sell or exchange 30 tracts of National Forest System land in Georgia totaling approximately 3,841 acres.

 The bill designates specified federal lands in the Cherokee National Forest in Tennessee as wilderness and as additions to the National Wilderness Preservation System.

 The bill requires specified lands in the George Washington National Forest (a part of the George Washington and Jefferson National Forests in Virginia, West Virginia, and Kentucky) to be: (1) incorporated in the Rough Mountain Wilderness, and (2) designated as a potential wilderness area for eventual incorporation in the Rich Hole Wilderness.

 The bill authorizes USDA to sell specified federal land in Winn Parish, Louisiana. USDA shall convey a portion of that land to Collins Camp Properties, Inc.

 The bill directs USDA to sell and quitclaim a parcel of real property, including improvements, located at 4500 Glenwood Drive in Riverside, California, consisting of approximately 8.75 acres and administered by the Natural Resources Conservation Service, to the Riverside Corona Resource Conservation District.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
