<bill session="114" type="h" number="1672" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:41Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Record Expungement Designed to Enhance Employment Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REDEEM Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the sealing or expungement of records relating to Federal nonviolent criminal offenses, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">REDEEM Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001270" joined="2015-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2015-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001097" joined="2015-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001049" joined="2015-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000984" joined="2015-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000015" joined="2015-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2015-10-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Nutrition, Oversight, and Department Operations" code="HSAG03" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Worker and Family Support" code="HSWM03" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="675"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1965"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Record Expungement Designed to Enhance Employment Act of 2015 or the REDEEM Act

Amends the federal criminal code to provide a process for the sealing or expungement of records relating to nonviolent criminal or juvenile offenses.

Requires a court considering a petition to seal a nonviolent offense to balance factors including the harm of the protected information to the ability of the petitioner to secure and maintain employment.

Sets forth limitations on involuntary room confinements at juvenile detention facilities.

Amends the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (PRWORA) to remove offenses relating to possession or use of a controlled substance from the categories of drug offenses that result in the convicted individual being ineligible for assistance under: (1) a state program funded with temporary assistance for needy families (TANF) grants under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act; or (2) the supplemental nutrition assistance program (SNAP, formerly the food stamp program) or any state program carried out under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008.

Prohibits the denial of such assistance and benefits if the convicted individual: (1) has completed, is participating in, or agrees to enroll in a substance abuse treatment program; (2) is a custodial parent; (3) is suffering from a serious illness; (4) is pregnant; or (5) is in compliance with the terms of a sentence imposed for the conviction. Includes employment services among the categories of federal benefits that are not to be denied under PRWORA.

Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to allow the Department of Justice (DOJ), in awarding public safety and community policing grants, to give preferential consideration to an applicant in a state with laws similar to this Act.

Directs DOJ to establish procedures for the prompt release of accurate records exchanged for employment-related purposes through the Federal Bureau of Investigation's background check system. Requires DOJ to: (1) obtain the consent of an individual to whom a record pertains as a condition to exchanging records with an entity requesting the information for employment, housing, or credit application purposes; and (2) allow individuals to challenge the accuracy and completeness of their records.

Prohibits exchanges of records regarding: (1) an arrest more than two years before a record request if the record does not also include the disposition of that arrest; (2) non-serious offenses, such as drunkenness, vagrancy, loitering, disturbing the peace, or curfew violations; or (3) circumstances that are not clearly arrests or dispositions.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
