<bill session="114" type="h" number="6484" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:51Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Commission to Study Family Reconstruction Proposals for African-Americans Unjustly Impacted by the "War on Drugs" Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To acknowledge the fundamental injustice and the subsequent de jure and de facto racial and economic discrimination against those African-Americans impacted by the "War on Drugs" and the subsequent disparate and discriminatory mass incarceration, to determine the role that private corporations played in the prison industrial complex, to determine the impact of these forces on their families, to make recommendations to the Congress on appropriate remedies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Commission to Study Family Reconstruction Proposals for African-Americans Unjustly Impacted by the "War on Drugs" Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000515"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-08T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Commission to Study Family Reconstruction Proposals for African-Americans Unjustly Impacted by the "War on Drugs" Act of 2016

This bill establishes a commission to examine and report on: the disparate incarceration and the institution of forced prison labor within the African-American community, government and private sector support for and profit from mass incarceration, discriminatory laws and other forms of discrimination in the public and private sectors, and the lingering negative effects of mass incarceration.

The commission must make recommendations for education and remedies.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
