<bill session="114" type="h" number="6307" updated="2019-05-09T23:32:59Z">
  <state datetime="2016-11-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-11-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-11-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Compact of Free Association of 1985 to provide for adequate Compact-impact aid to affected States and territories, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mark Takai Compact-Impact Aid Act</title>
    <title type="display">Mark Takai Compact-Impact Aid Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001245" joined="2016-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-11-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indigenous Peoples of the United States" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="854"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects/>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-11-14T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Mark Takai Compact-Impact Aid Act

 This bill amends the Compact of Free Association Act of 1985 to authorize and appropriate FY2017 funds to the Department of the Interior for: (1) grants to any local government of the United States that demonstrates financial strain due to demands on public services by significant immigration from the Federated States of Micronesia, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, and the Republic of Palau; and (2) aid in defraying costs incurred as a result of increased demands placed on health, educational, social, or public safety services, or infrastructure related to such services due to the residence of qualified nonimmigrants.

Interior shall provide for periodic enumerations of qualified nonimmigrants in the states and territories of the United States.

A "qualified nonimmigrant" is defined as a person admitted to the United States pursuant to: (1) section 141 of the Compact of Free Association set forth in title II of such Act, or (2) section 141 of the Compact of Free Association between the United States and the government of Palau.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
