<bill session="113" type="h" number="5573" updated="2016-10-25T16:16:48Z">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Alabama Hills National Scenic Area in the State of California, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To establish the Alabama Hills National Scenic Area in the State of California, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001094"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-09-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Establishes the Alabama Hills National Scenic Area, comprised of approximately 18,610 acres of land in Inyo County, California. Declares that the purpose of the Area is to conserve, protect, and enhance for the benefit, use, and enjoyment of present and future generations the nationally significant scenic, cultural, recreational, geological, educational, biological, historical, cinematographic, and scientific resources of the Area managed consistent with the multiple use principles defined in the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976.

Directs the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) manage the Area as a component of the National Landscape Conservation System, (2) allow existing recreational uses of the Area to continue except as the Secretary otherwise determines to be necessary for public health and safety, (3) permit the use of motorized vehicles in the Area only on roads and trails designated by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) as part of a management plan promoting a semi-primitive motorized experience or on county-maintained roads in accordance with applicable state and county laws, and (4) develop a comprehensive plan for the Area's long-term management.

Permits the Secretary to acquire non-federal land within the Area only through exchange, donation, or purchase from a willing seller. Withdraws the federal land within the Area from all forms of: (1) entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials.

Directs the Secretary to take approximately 132 acres of federal land into trust for the benefit of the Lone-Pine Paiute Shoshone Tribe, excluding a specified right-of-way granted to the City of Los Angeles. Prohibits gaming on such land.

Transfers administrative jurisdiction of approximately 40 acres of specified federal land from the U.S. Forest Service to BLM.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
