<bill session="114" type="h" number="1123" updated="2019-02-14T23:34:21Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Immigrants From Legal Exploitation Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for punishments for immigration-related fraud, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Protecting Immigrants From Legal Exploitation Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000454"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000371" joined="2016-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001036" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001097" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000623" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000610" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000553" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000535" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2015-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001188" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000130" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000131" joined="2015-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Citizenship" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-26T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Immigrants From Legal Exploitation Act of 2015

 Amends the federal criminal code to subject a person to fine, imprisonment, or both, who: (1) knowingly or recklessly executes a scheme in connection with any federal immigration law-related matter to defraud a person, or to obtain money or anything else of value from a person by means of false or fraudulent pretenses, representations, or promises; or (2) knowingly and falsely represents that such person is an attorney or an accredited representative in any federal immigration law-related matter.

Directs the Attorney General (DOJ) and the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS), to promulgate regulations, forms, and procedures defining the circumstances in which: (1) persons submitting immigration-related applications, petitions, motions, or other written materials must identify who (other than immediate family members) assisted them in preparing or translating such submissions; and (2) any person who received compensation (other than a normal fee for copying, mailing, or similar services) in connection with the preparation or submission of such materials must sign the form as a preparer and provide identifying information.

Authorizes the Attorney General to bring a civil injunction against an immigration service provider engaging in fraudulent conduct that substantially interferes with the administration of the immigration laws or who willfully misrepresents such provider's legal authority to provide representation before DOJ or DHS.

Authorizes an alien to withdraw an immigration-related application or other submission if the alien: (1) submits information indicating that the application or submission was prepared or submitted by an individual engaged in the unauthorized practice of law or immigration practitioner fraud, and (2) attests that he or she had no prior knowledge that the application or submission was prepared or submitted by such an individual.

Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to waive the bar on reentry for an alien who left the United States based on the erroneous advice of an individual engaged in the unauthorized practice of law or immigration practitioner fraud.

Directs the Secretary and the Attorney General, through the Director of the Office for Immigration Review, to carry out an outreach program to educate aliens regarding who may provide legal services and representation in immigration proceedings.

Directs the Secretary and the Attorney General to establish, within the U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services and the Executive Office for Immigration Review, programs to award grants to eligible nonprofit organizations for direct legal services to aliens.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
