<bill session="114" type="s" number="1814" updated="2018-06-02T06:57:57Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Sanctuary Cities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to withhold certain Federal funding from sanctuary cities.</title>
    <title type="display">Stop Sanctuary Cities Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000444" joined="2015-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2015-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000461" joined="2015-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stop Sanctuary Cities Act

This bill makes it unlawful for any state or political subdivision to:

 restrict or prohibit a government entity or official from sending to or receiving from the responsible federal immigration agency information regarding an individual's citizenship or immigration status, or from maintaining or exchanging information about an individual's status; or fail to comply with a immigration-related detainer that has been lawfully issued by the Department of Homeland Security (DHS). Any state or subdivision that:

 violates such prohibition shall be ineligible for State Criminal Alien Assistance Program funds; and does not come into compliance with such requirements within 180 days of receiving noncompliance notification from DHS shall be ineligible for assistance under the Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program. Funding may not be withheld until DHS has: (1) notified a state or subdivision of its noncompliance, and (2) determined that voluntary compliance cannot be secured.

No liability shall lie with a state or subdivision that is acting in compliance with a lawfully issued DHS detainer solely because the state or subdivision is holding an alien in compliance with such detainer.

Nothing in this Act may be construed to require law enforcement officials of a state or a subdivision to provide DHS with information related to a victim or a witness to a criminal offense.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
