<bill session="113" type="h" number="5878" updated="2016-10-25T16:17:54Z">
  <state datetime="2014-12-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Shahbaz Bhatti International Religious Freedom Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 to further express United States foreign policy with respect to, and to strengthen United States advocacy on behalf of, freedom of religion or belief abroad and individuals persecuted in foreign countries on account of religion or belief, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Shahbaz Bhatti International Religious Freedom Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000373"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2014-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Pakistan"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-12-11T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Shahbaz Bhatti International Religious Freedom Act of 2014 - Amends the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 to include violations of religious freedom by non-state actors in the annual Department of State report to Congress on international religious freedom.

Requires the House Foreign Affairs Committee and the Senate Foreign Relations Committee to hold hearings on specified Department and U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom reports concerning the status of religious freedom.

Amends the Foreign Service Act of 1980 to require Foreign Service officers to receive training about the religious demography, status of religious freedom, and U.S. strategies for advancing religious freedom in their country of posting.

Directs the Secretary of State to: (1) transmit to specified congressional committees certain lists of persons imprisoned, detained, or placed under house arrest; and (2) report to Congress on the best uses of foreign assistance to promote the goals of religious freedom and religious engagement.

Directs the Comptroller General to report to Congress after the date on which the President designates countries as a country of particular concern for religious freedom on the lack of the President's designation of Pakistan and and any other countries recommended for such designation by the Commission.

Directs the President to take specified actions in response to violations of religious freedom by non-state actors.

Authorizes certain funds for democracy programs to be used to implement innovative uses of the Internet and other electronic methods to support freedom of religion or belief abroad.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
