<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <orderedReported>1</orderedReported>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
        <placedOnCalendarGeneralOrders>1</placedOnCalendarGeneralOrders>
        <hearingsHeld>1</hearingsHeld>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
        <reportedToSenate>2</reportedToSenate>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>7</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-12-16</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 328.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-12-16</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>report No. 114-183</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-report/114th-congress/senate-report/183</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 114-183.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee>
          <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 114-183.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionDate>2015-12-16</actionDate>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>report No. 114-183</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-report/114th-congress/senate-report/183</url>
          </link>
        </links>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-11-19</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-03-12</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-02-25</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2015-02-25</actionDate>
        <links />
      </item>
    </actions>
    <updateDate>2018-08-16T22:54:04Z</updateDate>
    <recordedVotes />
    <congress>114</congress>
    <version>1.0.0</version>
    <title>Sportsmen's Act of 2015</title>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2016-05-18T18:29:57Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 556, Sportsmen’s Act of 2015</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/51597</url>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <cosponsors />
    <billType>S</billType>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <actionDate>2015-02-25</actionDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-01-13T18:41:01Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <updateDate>2015-02-25T05:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>Bipartisan Sportsmen's Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill revises a variety of existing programs to expand access to, and opportunities for, hunting, fishing, and recreational shooting. </p> <p>Federal public land management officials must facilitate hunting, fishing, and recreational shooting on certain federal public land. Land under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management or the Forest Service must be open for hunting, fishing, and recreational shooting unless the managing agency acts to close the land.</p> <p>The bill provides special rules to expand access to federal land and waterways for film crews of five people or fewer.</p> <p>The National Park Service may not prohibit individuals from transporting bows and crossbows if certain requirements are met. </p> <p>Funds from the Land and Water Conservation Fund are allocated for priority projects that secure public access to federal public lands for hunting, fishing, and other recreational purposes. </p>]]></text>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <actionDate>2015-12-16</actionDate>
          <versionCode>01</versionCode>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2017-01-17T19:39:22Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <updateDate>2015-12-16T13:11:12Z</updateDate>
          <actionDesc>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>Sportsmen's Act of 2015</b></p> <p>TITLE I--NATIONAL POLICY</p> <p>(Sec. 101) This bill states U.S. policy that federal departments and agencies must: </p> <ul> <li> facilitate the expansion and enhancement of hunting, noncommercial fishing, and recreational shooting opportunities on federal land; </li> <li> conserve and enhance aquatic systems and the management of game species and the habitat of those species on federal land; and </li> <li>consider hunting, fishing, and recreational shooting opportunities as part of all federal plans for land, resource, and travel management. </li> </ul> <p>TITLE II--SPORTSMEN'S ACCESS TO FEDERAL LAND</p> <p>(Sec. 201) The bill applies to federal land managed by: (1) the U.S. Forest Service; and (2) the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), except for lands located on the Outer Continental Shelf or lands held for the benefit of Indians, Aleuts, and Eskimos.</p> <p>(Sec. 202) Federal land must be open for hunting, fishing, and recreational shooting unless the managing agency acts to close the lands. The bill establishes procedures for closing the land, including reporting on the closures.</p> <p>(Sec. 204) The Forest Service or the BLM may lease or permit the use of federal land for a shooting range, except land within: </p> <ul> <li>a component of the National Landscape Conservation System;</li> <li>a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System; </li> <li>a primitive or semiprimitive area, an area that is designated as a wilderness study area, or an area administratively classified as wilderness-eligible or wilderness-suitable; </li> <li> a national monument, national volcanic monument, or national scenic area; or </li> <li> a component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System (including areas designated for study for potential addition to the system). </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 205) The bill amends the Equal Access to Justice Act and the federal judicial code by requiring the Administrative Conference of the United States to: (1) submit an annual report on the amount of fees and other expenses awarded under that Act; and (2) create and maintain a searchable, online database containing specified information with respect to each award. (The Equal Access to Justice Act allows a prevailing party to recover costs and attorneys' fees against the United States in both administrative and judicial proceedings, if the position of the United States was not substantially justified.)</p> <p>TITLE III--FILMING ON FEDERAL LAND MANAGEMENT AGENCY LAND</p> <p>(Sec. 301) The bill allows agencies to establish a fee schedule for commercial filming operations on federal land and provides special rules to expand access to federal land and waterways for film crews of three people or fewer.</p> <p>TITLE IV--BOWS, WILDLIFE MANAGEMENT, AND ACCESS OPPORTUNITIES FOR RECREATION, HUNTING, AND FISHING</p> <p>(Sec. 401) The National Park Service (NPS) may not prohibit individuals from transporting bows and crossbows if certain requirements are met. </p> <p>(Sec. 402) The NPS may use qualified volunteers to assist in wildlife management efforts in reducing the size of wildlife populations in the national park system.</p> <p>(Sec. 403) The Park Service, the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, the BLM, and the Forest Service must prepare a list that identifies land within their respective jurisdictions that is: (1) open to the public for hunting, fishing, or recreational uses; (2) not accessible to the public because the land does not have public entry or exit points or has significantly restricted public entry and exit points; and (3) more than 640 acres in size. Those federal entities must: (1) make this information available each year for a ten-year period and then every five years after that period, and (2) report on options for providing public entry and exit points for the land.</p> <p>TITLE V--FEDERAL LAND TRANSACTION FACILITATION ACT</p> <p>(Sec. 501) The bill amends the Federal Land Transaction Facilitation Act, including by permanently authorizing the Department of the Interior to sell certain public land and use the proceeds from those sales for acquiring land located within or adjacent to federal lands. </p> <p>TITLE VI--CONSERVATION REAUTHORIZATION</p> <p>(Sec. 601) The bill: (1) establishes a National Park Service Critical Maintenance and Revitalization Conservation Fund for high priority deferred maintenance needs of the National Park Service that support critical infrastructure and visitor services, and (2) transfers to the fund specified amounts from revenues due under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act. The funds may not be used for land acquisition.</p> <p>(Sec. 602) The bill: (1) makes permanent the Land and Water Conservation Fund (LWCF), and (2) revises requirements for the LWCF.</p> <p>((Sec. 603) The bill makes permanent the Historic Preservation Fund.</p> <p>TITLE VII--MISCELLANEOUS</p> <p>(Sec. 701) The bill does not modify the rights of Indian tribes nor federal law relating to migratory birds or endangered or threatened species.</p> <p>(Sec. 702) The bill does not provide a preference for hunting, fishing, or recreational shooting over any other use of federal land or water. </p>]]></text>
          <name>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</name>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-02-05</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>384</number>
        <latestTitle>Open Book on Equal Access to Justice Act</latestTitle>
        <type>HR</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-02-03</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>350</number>
        <latestTitle>Judgment Fund Transparency Act of 2015</latestTitle>
        <type>S</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>House</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-02-09</actionDate>
          <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 15.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>405</number>
        <latestTitle>Bipartisan Sportsmen's Act of 2015</latestTitle>
        <type>S</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2016-11-16</actionDate>
          <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>1669</number>
        <latestTitle>Judgment Fund Transparency Act of 2015</latestTitle>
        <type>HR</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-06-10</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>2401</number>
        <latestTitle>To direct the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to require annual permits and assess annual fees for commercial filming activities on Federal land for film crews of 5 persons or fewer, and for other purposes.</latestTitle>
        <type>HR</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-12-01</actionDate>
          <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>3279</number>
        <latestTitle>Open Book on Equal Access to Justice Act</latestTitle>
        <type>HR</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-04-30</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>1814</number>
        <latestTitle>To permanently reauthorize the Land and Water Conservation Fund.</latestTitle>
        <type>HR</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-12-18</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>4151</number>
        <latestTitle>To amend chapter 2003 of title 54, United States Code, to fund the Land and Water Conservation Fund and provide for the use of such funds, and for other purposes.</latestTitle>
        <type>HR</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-02-03</actionDate>
          <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 10.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>338</number>
        <latestTitle>A bill to permanently reauthorize the Land and Water Conservation Fund.</latestTitle>
        <type>S</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-10-21</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>2189</number>
        <latestTitle>Federal Land Transaction Facilitation Act Reauthorization of 2015</latestTitle>
        <type>S</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>House</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2016-02-24</actionDate>
          <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 371.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>659</number>
        <latestTitle>Bipartisan Sportsmen's Act of 2016</latestTitle>
        <type>S</type>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2015-12-16</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 328.</text>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <amendments />
    <notes />
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <title>Sportsmen's Act of 2015</title>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles Senate</parentTitleType>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Bipartisan Sportsmen's Act of 2015</title>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>A bill to protect and enhance opportunities for recreational hunting, fishing, and shooting, and for other purposes.</title>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Sportsmen's Act of 2015</title>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <laws />
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 114-183</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <introducedDate>2015-02-25</introducedDate>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <firstName>Lisa</firstName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1694</lisID>
          <gpoId>8234</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>M001153</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>M001153</bioguideId>
        <state>AK</state>
        <fullName>Sen. Murkowski, Lisa [R-AK]</fullName>
        <byRequestType />
        <middleName />
        <lastName>Murkowski</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <billNumber>556</billNumber>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of the Interior</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Forests, forestry, trees</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government liability</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Hunting and fishing</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Land transfers</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Land use and conservation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Legal fees and court costs</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Licensing and registrations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Motor vehicles</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Outdoor recreation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Parks, recreation areas, trails</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Television and film</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>User charges and fees</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Water use and supply</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Wildlife conservation and habitat protection</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <createDate>2015-02-26T06:14:50Z</createDate>
    <calendarNumbers>
      <item>
        <calendar>Senate Calendar of Business</calendar>
        <number>0328</number>
      </item>
    </calendarNumbers>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2015-12-16T18:06:16Z</date>
              <name>Reported by</name>
            </item>
            <item>
              <date>2015-11-19T14:30:00Z</date>
              <name>Markup by</name>
            </item>
            <item>
              <date>2015-03-12T14:00:00Z</date>
              <name>Hearings by</name>
            </item>
            <item>
              <date>2015-02-25T17:34:55Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <subcommittees />
          <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
          <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

