<bill session="115" type="h" number="4" updated="2019-06-13T20:34:07Z">
  <state datetime="2018-04-27T11:39:30-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-04-27T11:39:30-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize programs of the Federal Aviation Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">FAA Reauthorization Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">FAA Reauthorization Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Commercial Balloon Pilot Safety Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">FAA Leadership in Groundbreaking High-Tech Research and Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">FAA Leadership in Groundbreaking High-Tech Research and Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">FLIGHT R&amp;D Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">PREPARE Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">PREPARE Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Preparedness and Risk Management for Extreme Weather Patterns Assuring Resilience and Effectiveness Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Preparedness and Risk Management for Extreme Weather Patterns Assuring Resilience and Effectiveness Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FAA Reauthorization Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FAA Reauthorization Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">FAA Leadership in Groundbreaking High-Tech Research and Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">FAA Leadership in Groundbreaking High-Tech Research and Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">FLIGHT R&amp;D Act</title>
    <title type="display">FAA Reauthorization Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001154"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001269" joined="2018-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001037" joined="2018-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2018-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000612" joined="2018-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2018-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000577" joined="2018-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000546" joined="2018-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001048" joined="2018-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000387" joined="2018-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000560" joined="2018-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000554" joined="2018-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2018-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2018-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000583" joined="2018-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2018-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-04-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, Ways and Means, Science, Space, and Technology, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, Ways and Means, Science, Space, and Technology, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, Ways and Means, Science, Space, and Technology, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, Ways and Means, Science, Space, and Technology, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, Ways and Means, Science, Space, and Technology, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T12:32:22-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 839.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3590-3688" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3598-3636" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T12:32:27-04:00">
      <text>The rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4, under a structured rule, and H.R. 3144, under a closed rule. The rule makes in order only those amendments printed in Part A of the committee report for H.R. 4. The rule provides for 1 hour of general debate for both H.R. 4 and H.R. 3144. The rule provides for one motion to recommit for both bills. And, the rule provides that on any legislative day during the period from April 30, 2018 through May 4, 2018, the Journal of the proceedings of the previous day shall be considered as approved.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T12:32:45-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 839 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T12:32:46-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Daniel M. Donovan, Jr. to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T12:33:04-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T13:29:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Shuster amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T13:40:18-04:00">
      <text>The Committee rose informally to receive a message from the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T13:40:58-04:00">
      <text>The Committee resumed its sitting.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T13:41:49-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Shuster En bloc amendment No. 1, as modified.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T14:00:35-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Roskam amendment No. 13.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T14:04:50-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Denham amendment No. 17.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T14:13:10-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Shuster En bloc amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T14:25:58-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Higgins (LA) amendment No. 41.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T14:30:07-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the DeFazio amendment No. 42.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T14:39:51-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the DeFazio amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. DeFazio demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T14:41:55-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cohen amendment No. 46, as modified.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T14:45:09-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Burgess amendment No. 47.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T14:51:09-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perlmutter amendment No. 49.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T14:58:57-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rohrbacher amendment No. 60.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T15:06:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Rohrbacher amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Rohrbacher demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T15:07:14-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the King (IA) amendment No. 63.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T15:15:33-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the King (IA) amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. DeFazio demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T15:17:26-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Shuster En bloc amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T15:28:39-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Beyer amendment No. 67.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T15:33:41-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Beyer amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Beyer demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T15:34:28-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Smith (NE) amendment No. 68.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T15:39:32-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lewis (MN) amendment No. 75.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T15:46:28-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lipinski amendment No. 78.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T15:53:35-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Lipinski amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Lipinski demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T15:54:19-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Denham amendment No. 79.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T16:08:37-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDING - At the conclusion of debate on the Denham amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. DeFazio demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T16:08:38-04:00">
      <text>VACATED PROCEEDINGS - Mr. Shuster asked unanimous consent to vacate the proceedings on Beyer amendment No. 67 of House Report 115-650, which was postponed, to the end that the Chair put the question de novo. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T16:10:55-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gonzalez-Colon amendment No. 81.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T16:16:39-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Comstock amendment No. 84, as modified.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T16:22:12-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lynch amendment No. 87.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T16:29:37-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Lynch amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Lynch demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T16:30:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Meng amendment No. 88.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T16:34:33-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Zeldin amendment No. 96.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T16:42:56-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lawrence amendment No. 97.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T17:40:50-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Shuster moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T17:41:03-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26T17:41:15-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27T09:10:34-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3710-3722" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27T09:10:56-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27T09:11:52-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Shuster En bloc amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27T09:14:05-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Graves (LA) amendment No. 104.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27T09:21:22-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Graves (LA) amendment No. 107.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27T09:30:56-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Graves (LA) amendment No. 108.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27T09:35:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Babin amendment No. 110.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27T09:43:16-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McClintock amendment No. 112.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27T09:54:57-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the McClintock amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. McClintock demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27T09:55:45-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 839, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Duncan (TN) amendment No. 114.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27T10:05:30-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Duncan (TN) amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. DeFazio demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27T10:05:57-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Shuster moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27T10:06:12-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27T10:06:53-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27T10:40:27-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3722-3726" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27T10:40:37-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27T11:13:49-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27T11:14:40-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27T11:14:58-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27T11:15:49-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Velazquez moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3723-3724" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27T11:16:29-04:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Velazquez motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the same back to the House forthwith with an amendment to require the federal government to cover 100% of the costs for natural disasters in connection with Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, and the California Wildfires under the Stafford Act.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27T11:25:01-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27T11:31:43-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 182 - 223 (Roll no. 164).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="165" datetime="2018-04-27T11:39:30-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 393 - 13 (Roll no. 165).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27T11:39:32-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-27T12:06:14-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-07">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-05-08" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="401">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 401.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="5039"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="6862"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3511"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2150"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3198"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1167"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3509"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="4177"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="7043"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3041"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="unknown" number="839"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="276"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1183"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1665"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1678"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2928"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3062"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3176"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2348"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3183"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1386"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3007"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1424"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="4455"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3512"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Horticulture and plants"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h576"/>
    <amendment number="h575"/>
    <amendment number="h574"/>
    <amendment number="h573"/>
    <amendment number="h572"/>
    <amendment number="h571"/>
    <amendment number="h570"/>
    <amendment number="h569"/>
    <amendment number="h568"/>
    <amendment number="h567"/>
    <amendment number="h566"/>
    <amendment number="h565"/>
    <amendment number="h564"/>
    <amendment number="h563"/>
    <amendment number="h562"/>
    <amendment number="h561"/>
    <amendment number="h560"/>
    <amendment number="h559"/>
    <amendment number="h558"/>
    <amendment number="h557"/>
    <amendment number="h556"/>
    <amendment number="h555"/>
    <amendment number="h554"/>
    <amendment number="h553"/>
    <amendment number="h552"/>
    <amendment number="h551"/>
    <amendment number="h550"/>
    <amendment number="h549"/>
    <amendment number="h548"/>
    <amendment number="h547"/>
    <amendment number="h546"/>
    <amendment number="s3689"/>
    <amendment number="s3687"/>
    <amendment number="s3396"/>
    <amendment number="s3395"/>
    <amendment number="s3394"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2018-04-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">FAA Reauthorization Act of 2018

This bill reauthorizes and extends the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) and associated programs through FY2023 at increased levels.

The Department of Transportation's (DOT's) State block grant program is expanded.

The Air Traffic Control Contract Program is modified.

Grant authority for competitive land use planning and projects by state and local governments is extended.

Various requirements are imposed on the FAA, including those for: (1) conducting a review of the relationship between aircraft noise exposure and its effects on communities around airports; (2) establishing a Safety Oversight and Certification Advisory Committee; and (3) convening a multidisciplinary expert review panel to conduct a survey of Organization Designation Authorization (ODA) holders and ODA program applicants to document and assess FAA certification and oversight activities.

The General Accountability Office shall conduct a review to assess the workforce and training needs of the FAA Office of Aviation Safety in the anticipated budgetary environment.

Safety provisions are outlined, which include safety critical staffing provisions, as well as air service improvement provisions, which include a cell phone voice communication ban. Provisions with regard to aviation consumers with disabilities are also outlined.

The Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act is amended with respect to wild fire prevention, eligibility for code implementation and enforcement, and program improvements.

FAA Leadership in Groundbreaking High-Tech Research and Development Act or the FLIGHT R&amp;D Act

Appropriations are authorized with respect to various research and development (R&amp;D) related matters including Safety Research and Development programs.

FAA shall appoint an Associate Administrator for Research and Development.

Provisions are set forth regarding unmanned aircraft systems, cybersecurity, and FAA R&amp;D activities.

The Internal Revenue Code is amended with regard to: (1) expenditure authority from the airport and airway trust fund; and (2) extension of taxes funding such trust fund.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
