<bill session="114" type="h" number="4576" updated="2019-02-08T20:13:44Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-12T16:33:11-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-09-12T16:33:11-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Access to Pacific Fisheries Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Ensuring Access to Pacific Fisheries Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Convention Amendments Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Ensuring Access to Pacific Fisheries Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Convention Amendments Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To implement the Convention on the Conservation and Management of High Seas Fisheries Resources in the North Pacific Ocean, to implement the Convention on the Conservation and Management of High Seas Fishery Resources in the South Pacific Ocean, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Ensuring Access to Pacific Fisheries Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000600"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2016-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-01">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-12">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-09-06">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 114-718.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-09-06" calendar="Union" number="557">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 557.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-09-12T16:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Radewagen moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-12T16:26:23-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5280-5286" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-12T16:26:25-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4576.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2016-09-12T16:33:11-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5280-5285" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-09-12T16:33:13-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-13">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water, Oceans, and Wildlife" code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1336"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3269"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1335"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6452"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Biological and life sciences"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-12T14:58:39Z" status="Passed House amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on September 6, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Ensuring Access to Pacific Fisheries Act

TITLE I--NORTH PACIFIC FISHERIES CONVENTION IMPLEMENTATION

This bill authorizes the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to promulgate regulations to implement U.S. participation in the North Pacific Fisheries Convention and South Pacific Fisheries Convention. These conventions are designed to ensure the long-term conservation and sustainable use of fishery resources and marine ecosystems in the North Pacific and South Pacific Ocean of the United States.

(Sec. 102) The United Statesmust be represented by five commissioners on the North Pacific Fisheries Commission.

(Sec. 103)The Department of State has the authority to receive and transmit various communications concerning the North Pacific commission.

(Sec. 104)The bill details NOAA's authority in implementing this bill and measures adopted by the commission.

(Sec.105)NOAA and the U.S. Coast Guard are required to administer and enforce this bill.

(Sec. 106)This bill lists 15 fishing and shipping activities that are prohibited in the North Pacific Ocean.

(Sec. 107)NOAA may cooperate with public and private institutions in the United Statesand abroad to carry out this bill. Federal agencies are authorized to cooperate with NOAA in conducting research and providing facilities and personnel to assist the commission.

(Sec.108)The State Department must ensure that American Samoa, Guam, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands participate with the commission in the same manner as territories of other nations.

(Sec. 109)Operators of commercial fishing vessels that do not carry vessel monitoring systems capable of communicating with U.S. enforcement authorities must ensure that all fishing gear is stowed below deck and not readily available for fishing.

TITLE II--IMPLEMENTATION OF THE CONVENTION ON THE CONSERVATION AND MANAGEMENT OF HIGH SEAS FISHERY RESOURCES IN THE SOUTH PACIFIC OCEAN

(Sec.202)The United States must be represented by no more than three commissioners on the Commission of the South Pacific Regional Fisheries Management Organization.

(Sec.203)The State Department has the authority to receive and transmit various communications concerning the South Pacific commission, and can approve or disapprove bylaws and rules adopted by the commission.

(Sec.204)This bill details NOAA's authority in implementing this bill and measures adopted by the commission.

(Sec.205)NOAA and the U.S. Coast Guard are required to administer and enforce this bill.

(Sec.206)This bill lists 14 fishing and shipping activities that are prohibited in the South Pacific Ocean.

(Sec. 207)NOAA may cooperate with public and private institutions in the United Statesand abroad to carry out this bill. Federal agencies are authorized to cooperate with NOAA in conducting research and providing facilities and personnel to assist the commission.

(Sec.208)The State Department must ensure that American Samoa, Guam, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands participate with the commission in the same manner as territories of other nations.

(Sec. 209)Operators of commercial fishing vessels that do not carry vessel monitoring systems capable of communicating with U.S. enforcement authorities must ensure that all fishing gear is stowed below deck and not readily available for fishing.

TITLE III--WESTERN AND CENTRAL PACIFIC FISHERIES COMMISSION

(Sec. 301)The bill also amends the Western and Central Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act to include commercial fishing as practical experience the President must consider when selecting a commissioner for the Western and Central Pacific Fisheries Commission. The advisory committee is required to submit agenda recommendations at least 30 days prior to the annual Western and Central Pacific Fisheries Commission meeting. The recommendations must be considered in formulating the U.S. position for meetings and negotiations. In addition, NOAA must conduct negotiations to secure agreements with other nations to ensure access and equal treatment of United States fishing boats in the Western and Central Pacific Ocean while taking conservation and management measures into consideration.

TITLE IV--ILLEGAL, UNREGULATED, AND UNREPORTED FISHING

(Sec. 401)The bill amends the High Seas Drifnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act to direct NOAA to submit a biennial report on international compliance with fishery agreements to Congress by June 1 of the submission year.

TITLE V--NORTHWEST ATLANTIC FISHERIES CONVENTION AMENDMENTS ACT

Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Convention Amendments Act

(Sec. 509)The bill amends the Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Convention Act of 1995 to repeal the provisions requiring NOAA to establish and report a new fishing quota allocation practice in the northwestern Atlantic Ocean.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-718</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
