<bill session="114" type="s" number="981" updated="2018-06-02T06:45:15Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Invest In Transportation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for a repatriation holiday, to increase funding to the Highway Trust Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Invest In Transportation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000603"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2015-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2015-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2015-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2015-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2015-04-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Invest in Transportation Act 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a domestic corporation to elect to repatriate its overseas income earned prior to 2015 at an effective tax rate of 6.5%. The corporation must complete the repatriation of such income during a specified five-year period and establish a domestic reinvestment plan under which not less than 25% of such income is used for investment in the United States, including for increased hiring, wages, pension contributions, energy efficiency, environmental and capital improvements, and research and development. No funds may be spent on increases in executive compensation. Additionally, a corporation which enters into a stock inversion to avoid U.S. taxation within 10 years after repatriating overseas income at a preferential tax rate must recapture a portion of the income taxed at the preferential rate.

The bill requires the Department of the Treasury to make an initial estimate of the amount of tax revenue from repatriated income to be received by Treasury prior to October 1, 2019, and another estimate not later than October 1, 2023, and transfer such estimated amounts to the Highway and Mass Transit Accounts of the Highway Trust Fund.

The bill authorizes appropriations from the Highway Trust Fund for the repair, replacement, or rehabilitation of deficient bridges.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
