<bill session="114" type="s" number="1983" updated="2019-06-21T11:07:12Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-03">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Pechanga Band of Luiseno Mission Indians Water Rights Settlement, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pechanga Band of Luiseno Mission Indians Water Rights Settlement Act</title>
    <title type="display">Pechanga Band of Luiseno Mission Indians Water Rights Settlement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000711"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2015-08-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-08-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-08-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6390" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-02-03" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2848"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="612"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5984"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-08-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Pechanga Band of Luiseno Mission Indians Water Rights Settlement Act

Authorizes, ratifies, and confirms the Pechanga Settlement Agreement, entered into by the Pechanga Band of Luiseno Mission Indians, the Rancho California Water District (RCWD), and the United States, except to the extent that it is modified by or conflicts with this Act.

Confirms a Tribal Water Right that must be held in trust by the United States on behalf of the Band and its allottees. (Allottees are individuals who hold a beneficial real property interest in an Indian allotment that is located within the reservation and held in trust by the United States.)

Authorizes allottees to lease their lands together with any water right.

Requires the Band to enact a Pechanga Water Code that governs the storage, recovery, and use of the Tribal Water Right, subject to the Department of the Interior's approval.

Directs the Band and the United States (acting as trustee for the Band and allottees), to waive all claims for water rights within the Santa Margarita River Watershed.

States that the Band and the United States (acting as trustee for the Band), waive specified claims against the RCWD.

Authorizes the waiver of claims by the Band against the United States regarding specified water rights and damages.

Establishes in the Treasury the Pechanga Settlement Fund.

 Makes this Act enforceable on the date Interior publishes specified findings regarding despoits and approved agreements. Repeals this Act and voids any related agreements on May 1, 2021, or an alternative later date agreed to by the Band and Interior, if Interior does not publish those findings.

Prohibits Interior from being liable for failing to carry out any obligation or activity under this Act if there are insufficient appropriations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
