<bill session="115" type="s" number="3204" updated="2019-04-18T16:44:37Z">
  <state datetime="2018-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to authorize admission of Canadian retirees as long-term visitors for pleasure described in section 101(a)(15)(B) of such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Canadian Snowbirds Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Canadian Snowbirds Act</title>
    <title type="display">Canadian Snowbirds Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2018-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-07-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3513"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="979"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-07-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Canadian Snowbirds Act

 This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to authorize the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to admit into the United States as a nonimmigrant visitor for a period not to exceed 240 days during any single 365-day period a Canadian citizen who: (1) is at least 50 years old; (2) maintains a Canadian residence and owns a U.S. residence or has rented U.S. accommodations for the duration of such stay; (3) is not inadmissible or deportable; (4) will not work in the United States other than for a non U.S.-based person or entity that the person worked for in Canada; and (5) will not seek any federal means tested public benefit for five years, or any federal tax credits for child care, earned income, first time homebuyers, health insurance, or health care plans.

The spouse of such person may be admitted under the same terms except that he or she is not required to separately satisfy the residence/housing requirements.

 DHS shall have sole and unreviewable discretion to withhold or withdraw admission of such an alien.

The bill grants a person so admitted nonresident alien tax status.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
