<bill session="113" type="h" number="5753" updated="2016-10-25T16:17:25Z">
  <state datetime="2014-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Drinking Water Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to provide for the assessment and management of the risk of cyanotoxins in drinking water, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Drinking Water Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000566"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2014-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001150" joined="2014-12-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Environment and the Economy" code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-11-20T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Drinking Water Protection Act - Amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to direct the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to develop and submit to Congress a strategic plan for assessing and managing risks associated with cyanotoxins in drinking water provided by public water systems. (Cyanotoxins are naturally occurring toxins produced by cyanobacteria, also known as blue-green algae.)

Requires the plan to include steps and time lines to:

 evaluate the risk to human health from drinking water contaminated with cyanotoxins; establish, publish, and update a comprehensive list of cyanotoxins that are harmful to human health; summarize the known adverse human health effects of cyanotoxins and the factors that cause cyanobacteria to grow rapidly and make toxins; determine whether to publish health advisories for harmful cyanotoxins and establish relevant guidance; recommend feasible treatment options; and enter into cooperative agreements with, and provide technical assistance to, affected states and public water systems to manage risks associated with cyanotoxins.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
