<bill session="116" type="s" number="1215" updated="2019-07-20T09:27:45Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2020 for military activities of the Department of Defense and for military construction, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020</title>
    <title type="display">National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000024"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2019-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2437-2438" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2880"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1790"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2500"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces Retirement Home"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-04-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020

This bill authorizes FY2020 appropriations and sets forth policies for Department of Defense (DOD) programs and activities, including military personnel strengths and military construction. It does not provide budget authority, which is provided in subsequent appropriations legislation.

The bill authorizes appropriations to DOD for

 Procurement, including aircraft, weapons and tracked combat vehicles, shipbuilding and conversion, missiles, and space procurement; Research, Development, Test, and Evaluation; Operation and Maintenance; Working Capital Funds; the Joint Urgent Operational Needs Fund; Chemical Agents and Munitions Destruction; Drug Interdiction and Counter-Drug Activities; the Defense Inspector General; the Defense Health Program; the Armed Forces Retirement Home; the Space Force; and Overseas Contingency Operations. The bill also authorizes the FY2020 personnel strengths for active duty and reserve forces and sets forth policies regarding

 military personnel; compensation and other personnel benefits; health care; acquisition policy and management; DOD organization and management; civilian personnel matters; matters relating to foreign nations; strategic programs, cyber, and intelligence matters; and the establishment of the Space Force within the Air Force. The bill authorizes appropriations and sets forth policies regarding military construction for the Army, Navy, Air Force, defense agencies, the North Atlantic Treaty Organization Security Investment Program, and Guard and Reserve Forces facilities.

The bill authorizes appropriations for base realignment and closure activities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
