<bill session="114" type="h" number="2219" updated="2018-11-09T00:09:01Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Opportunity Kindling New Options for Career and Knowledge Seekers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Opportunity KNOCKS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that individuals who are in an authorized job training program or completing work for a degree or certificate remain eligible for regular unemployment compensation.</title>
    <title type="display">Opportunity KNOCKS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000619"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001287" joined="2015-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000581" joined="2015-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-01T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Opportunity Kindling New Options for Career and Knowledge Seekers Act or the Opportunity KNOCKS Act

 Amends the Internal Revenue Code and the Federal Unemployment Tax Act to deem approved by the Secretary of Labor any state laws that provide unemployment compensation to an individual for any week while in training, including: (1) any program on a state's eligible training provider list developed under the Workforce Investment Act of 1998, or (2) any coursework necessary to attain a recognized postsecondary credential if that individual is likely to exhaust his or her regular unemployment compensation.

Defines "recognized postsecondary credential" as a credential consisting of an industry-recognized certificate, a certificate of completion of an apprenticeship, or an associate or baccalaureate degree.

Amends the Federal-State Extended Unemployment Compensation Act of 1970 and the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2008 to authorize a state unemployment compensation agency to elect to approve job training or educational programs for purposes of an individual receiving extended or emergency unemployment compensation while in training.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
