<bill session="113" type="s" number="63" updated="2016-10-25T16:19:56Z">
  <state datetime="2013-01-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Made In America Manufacturing Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of Labor to establish the Made In America Incentive Grant Program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Made In America Manufacturing Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000555"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2013-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2013-01-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="375"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-01-22T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Made In America Manufacturing Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretaries of Commerce and Labor to establish a program for the joint award of incentive grants to a state or a regional partnership to support the U.S. manufacturing industry. Designates the program as the Made in America Incentive Grant Program. Limits single grants to $20 million, to be used by the recipient to carry out a manufacturing enhancement strategy. Requires, under such strategy: (1) establishing a revolving loan fund for loans to manufacturers for various business purposes, (2) retraining current and training new manufacturer employees, and (3) creating or expanding manufacturer export activity and domestic supply chain opportunities. Outlines recipient application requirements, including the submission of a proposed strategy and the establishment of a Made In America Partnership Board.

Gives grant priority to entities that identify and commit matching funds of at least 50% of the grant amount. Prohibits more than half of the grant amounts from being used for employee retraining and training. Requires annual reports from recipients to the Secretaries on the use of grant funds.

Directs the Secretaries to jointly establish an advisory committee for advice on implementing and evaluating the Program. Authorizes the Secretaries to review and evaluate recipient performance and, as appropriate, determine a recipient to be ineligible for additional grants due to noncompliance with the Program or strategy.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
