<amendment session="115" chamber="s" number="1428" updated="2019-04-18T16:57:27Z">
  <amends type="hc" number="71" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2017-10-19">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000577"/>
  <offered datetime="2017-10-19"/>
  <description>To modify a deficit neutral reserve fund relating to public land and the environment to address making payments under the payments in lieu of taxes program equivalent to the property tax revenue that would be due to a State or local government if the State or local government owned the land.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2017-10-19" how="roll" result="fail" roll="240">
      <text>Amendment SA 1428 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 50 - 50. Record Vote Number: 240.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-10-19">
      <text>Amendment SA 1428 proposed by Senator Enzi for Senator Lee to Amendment SA 1116. (consideration: CR S6625-6627; text: CR S6625) To modify a deficit neutral reserve fund relating to public land and the environment to address making payments under the payments in lieu of taxes program equivalent to the property tax revenue that would be due to a State or local government if the State or local government owned the land.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-19"/>
    <action datetime="2017-10-19">
      <text>Senate amendment not agreed to: Amendment SA 1428 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 50 - 50. Record Vote Number: 240.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-19">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 1428 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 50 - 50. Record Vote Number: 240.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-19">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 1428 proposed by Senator Enzi for Senator Lee to Amendment SA 1116.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6625-6627" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6625" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-19">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
