<bill session="114" type="s" number="2223" updated="2019-03-03T14:41:01Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to transfer administrative jurisdiction over certain Bureau of Land Management land from the Secretary of the Interior to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for inclusion in the Black Hills National Cemetery, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Black Hills National Cemetery Boundary Expansion Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Black Hills National Cemetery Boundary Expansion Act</title>
    <title type="display">Black Hills National Cemetery Boundary Expansion Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2016-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2015-11-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 114-500.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-09-06">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski with an amendment. With written report No. 114-325.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-09-06" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="598">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 598.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3839"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-06T15:32:44Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Black Hills National Cemetery Boundary Expansion Act 

(Sec. 3) This bill transfers jurisdiction over approximately 200 acres of Bureau of Land Management land from the Department of the Interior to the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) for inclusion in the Black Hills National Cemetery, South Dakota.

The VA shall reimburse Interior for reasonable transfer costs, including survey costs.

 The cemetery's boundary is modified to include such federal land.

For the period such land is under the administrative jurisdiction of the VA, it shall be withdrawn from all forms of appropriation under the public land laws, including the mining laws, the mineral leasing laws, and the geothermal leasing laws.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-325</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
