<bill session="115" type="h" number="5184" updated="2019-04-18T16:20:54Z">
  <state datetime="2018-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food Security Act of 1985 to improve conservation practice standards, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accelerating Innovative Conservation Technologies and Practices Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accelerating Innovative Conservation Technologies and Practices Act</title>
    <title type="display">Accelerating Innovative Conservation Technologies and Practices Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000580"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-03-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Conservation and Forestry" code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3042"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-03-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Accelerating Innovative Conservation Technologies and Practices Act 

This bill amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to require the Department of Agriculture (USDA), within 180 days of the enactment of this bill, to develop an administrative process for: (1) expediting the establishment and revision of conservation practice standards, and (2) considering conservation innovations with respect to the establishment or revision of the standards.

USDA must report to Congress on the administrative process developed under this bill, including conservation practice standards that were established and conservation innovations that were considered under the process.

Each state technical committee must regularly review new and innovative technologies and practices (including processes to conserve water) and make recommendations to USDA for further consideration of, and possible development of, standards that incorporate the technologies and practices.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
