<bill session="114" type="s" number="3009" updated="2018-08-16T23:11:09Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-08">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Guard and Reserve Entrepreneurship Support Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">National Guard and Reserve Entrepreneurship Support Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to support entrepreneurs serving in the National Guard and Reserve, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">National Guard and Reserve Entrepreneurship Support Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2016-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2016-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2016-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-06-08" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-06-09">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Reported by Senator Vitter with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-06-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="510">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 510.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-12-20">
      <text>By Senator Vitter from Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship filed written report under authority of the order of the Senate of 12/10/2016. Report No. 114-422.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-09T11:14:39Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">National Guard and Reserve Entrepreneurship Support Act of 2016

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Small Business Act and the Veterans Entrepreneurship and Small Business Development Act of 1999 to revise a condition on the extension of disaster loan assistance to a small business concern that has suffered, or that is likely to suffer, substantial economic injury as the result of an essential employee's being ordered to active military duty during a period of military conflict.

The condition "being ordered to active military duty during a period of military conflict" shall change to read "being ordered to deploy as part of active military duty." This change shall permit the extension of disaster assistance to a small business concern in such a circumstance even when deployment is not during a period of military conflict.

The same condition is revised in requirements for deferred repayment of principal and interest due on a direct loan to a qualified borrower who is an eligible armed forces reservist and who:

 received a direct loan, including a disaster loan, from the Small Business Administration (SBA) before being ordered to active duty; or is an essential employee ordered to active duty from a small business concern that received a direct loan, including a disaster loan, from the SBA. The President shall report semiannually to specified congressional committees on the number of loans, and their dollar amount, made under the Military Reservist Economic Injury Disaster Loan program, including the subsidy rate of those loans.

(Sec. 3) The SBA shall to make grants and enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with specified public and private entities for outreach programs for the spouses of veterans and members of a reserve component of the armed forces.

 In making such grants the SBA shall establish a National Guard and Reserve Deployment Support and Business Training Program to give training, counseling and other assistance to support members of a reserve component of the armed forces and their spouses.

In establishing this program the SBA may:

 modify existing programs and resources to disseminate pre-deployment and other information specific to members of a reserve component of the Armed Forces and their spouses; collaborate with the National Guard Bureau (NGB), State Adjutant Generals (or their designees), and other public and private partners; and furnish training, information, and other resources to the NGB and State Adjutant Generals (or designees) to support members of a reserve component of the armed forces, their spouses, and the spouses of veterans.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-422</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
