<bill session="115" type="h" number="4708" updated="2019-07-15T21:58:15Z">
  <state datetime="2018-02-14">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-12-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Secretary of Homeland Security to issue Department of Homeland Security-wide guidance and develop training programs as part of the Department of Homeland Security Blue Campaign, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Department of Homeland Security Blue Campaign Authorization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Department of Homeland Security Blue Campaign Authorization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of Homeland Security Blue Campaign Authorization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of Homeland Security Blue Campaign Authorization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Homeland Security Blue Campaign Authorization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Homeland Security Blue Campaign Authorization Act</title>
    <title type="display">Department of Homeland Security Blue Campaign Authorization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001157"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001077" joined="2017-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000386" joined="2017-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2017-12-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-12-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-11">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-11">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-11T11:47:05-05:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H161" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-11T11:47:05-05:00">
      <text>Mr. McCaul asked unanimous consent to discharge from the Committees on Homeland Security and the Judiciary and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="without objection" type="vote" datetime="2018-01-11T11:47:22-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H161" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-01-11T11:47:24-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-16">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="2018-01-30" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S591" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-01-30">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2018-02-06">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2018-02-14" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="115-125" type="public" datetime="2018-02-14">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 115-125.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1370"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1103"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-02-15T04:59:58Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the House passed version is repeated here.)

Department of Homeland Security Blue Campaign Authorization Act

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize in the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) a program to be known as the Blue Campaign, the purpose of which shall be to unify and coordinate DHS efforts to address human trafficking.

The campaign director shall issue DHS-wide guidance to and develop training programs for appropriate DHS personnel, coordinate departmental efforts, and provide guidance and training on trauma-informed practices to ensure that human trafficking victims are afforded prompt access to victim support service providers and assistance to address their immediate and long-term needs.

Such campaign shall provide guidance and training to DHS personnel and other federal, state, tribal, and law enforcement personnel regarding:

 programs to help identify instances of human trafficking; the types of information that should be collected and recorded in DHS information technology systems to identify individuals suspected or convicted of human trafficking; systematic and routine information sharing within DHS and among federal, state, tribal, and local law enforcement agencies regarding such individuals and patterns and practices of human trafficking; techniques to identify suspected victims of trafficking along the U.S. border and at airport security checkpoints; methods to be used by the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) and personnel from other appropriate agencies to train TSA employees to identify suspected trafficking victims and to serve as a liaison and resource regarding human trafficking prevention to appropriate state, local, and private sector aviation workers and the traveling public; utilizing resources to educate partners and stakeholders and increase public awareness of human trafficking; and leveraging partnerships with state and local governmental, non-governmental, and private sector organizations to raise public awareness of human trafficking. (Sec. 3) DHS shall: (1) ensure the integration of information technology systems utilized within DHS to record and track information regarding individuals suspected or convicted of human trafficking; and (2) report to Congress on the status and effectiveness of, and providing a recommendation regarding the appropriate office within DHS for, the Blue Campaign.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
