<bill session="114" type="h" number="1514" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:18Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CRAM</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Credit Reporting Act for Military Families</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act to provide protections for active duty military consumers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">CRAM</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001156"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001245" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001286" joined="2015-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001049" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000636" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000559" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000185" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2015-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1249"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-19T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Credit Reporting Act for Military Families or the CRAM

Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act with respect to an item of adverse information about an active duty military consumer.

Redefines "active duty military consumer" as one who is assigned to service away from the usual duty station for a period of not less than 90 days.

Declares that, if the action or inaction that gave rise to the item occurred while the consumer was an active duty military consumer, then: (1) the consumer may provide appropriate proof, including official orders, to a consumer reporting agency that the consumer was an active duty military consumer at the time the action or inaction occurred; and (2) any consumer report made by the agency including that item of information shall clearly and conspicuously disclose that the consumer was an active duty military consumer when the action or inaction that gave rise to the item occurred.

Requires a consumer reporting agency to notify promptly an active duty military consumer whenever it receives an item of adverse information about him or her, along with a description of the item and the method by which the consumer can dispute the validity of the item.

Requires an agency also to use any separate contact information an active duty military consumer has given it for all communications while the individual is an active duty military consumer.

Declares the sense of Congress that any person making use of a consumer report containing an item of adverse information that occurred while the consumer was an active duty military consumer should take that fact into account when evaluating the consumer's creditworthiness.

Requires a consumer reporting agency, with respect to an item of information under dispute by an active duty military consumer, to include in the consumer's file that he or she was an active duty military consumer at the time the action or inaction that gave rise to the disputed item occurred.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
