<bill session="115" type="s" number="3607" updated="2019-04-26T14:00:52Z">
  <state datetime="2018-10-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-10-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-10-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to strengthen the participation of elected national legislators in the activities of the Organization of American States and reaffirm United States support for Organization of American States human rights and anti-corruption initiatives, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Organization of American States Legislative Engagement Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Organization of American States Legislative Engagement Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Organization of American States Legislative Engagement Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2018-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2018-10-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-10-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-10-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-10-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Organization of American States Legislative Engagement Act of 2018

This bill directs the Department of State of State to establish procedures for the Organization of American States (OAS) that:

 increase the participation of elected national legislators from OAS member states in OAS activities, including activities that advance the principles of the Inter-American Democratic Charter; create an annual forum for the presidents of such legislatures to discuss issues of hemispheric importance, including efforts to combat corruption and defend human rights; permit such legislators to make presentations and provide expert advice to the OAS Secretariat, OAS Permanent Council, and OAS General Assembly; and strengthen OAS Secretariat programs that provide technical assistance for legislative modernization. The State Department shall:

 carry out diplomatic efforts to secure political and financial support for such procedures, and submit to Congress a strategy for supporting OAS anti-corruption and human rights promotion efforts.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
