<bill session="114" type="s" number="3109" updated="2018-06-02T07:46:54Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Inspector General Recommendation Transparency Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require Inspectors General to make open recommendations publicly available.</title>
    <title type="display">Inspector General Recommendation Transparency Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001069"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2016-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Inspector General Recommendation Transparency Act of 2016

This bill amends the Inspector General Act of 1978 to require each Inspector General, within one year after the first deadline for the semiannual report on its activities after enactment of this bill, to make available on its website a list of any recommendations by such Inspector General that have been open for more than one year. An "open" recommendation is one that has been made publicly available on such website but has not been adopted or implemented by such Inspector General's establishment.

The list shall include:

 the number of recommendations issued by the Inspector General for the fiscal year and the number that are open, each report in which an open recommendation was issued, the assigned number and a short description of each open recommendation, the date the open recommendation was first issued and its current status, and any comments of the Inspector General relating to why the recommendation remains open and any response from the establishment. The list shall be updated by the Inspector General at least every six months.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
