<bill session="114" type="h" number="3359" updated="2019-02-01T21:05:40Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Teacher Loan Repayment Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for loan repayment for teachers in high-need schools.</title>
    <title type="display">Teacher Loan Repayment Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000381"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001284" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001051" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2015-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000602" joined="2015-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2015-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Investment" code="HSED13" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="1892"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Teacher Loan Repayment Act of 2015

This bill amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to modify the financial aid programs for teachers.

Specifically, it terminates the authority of the Department of Education (ED) to: (1) award new grants under the Teacher Education Assistance for College and Higher Education (TEACH) Grant program and (2) enter new loan forgiveness agreements under the under the Teacher Loan Forgiveness program.

The bill authorizes and directs ED to administer a new loan repayment for teachers program. To qualify, a borrower must be a full-time teacher in a low-income school or location and meet other requirements. ED, on behalf of a qualified borrower, makes $250-$400 direct monthly payments on Federal Family Education Loan or Direct Loan program Subsidized, Unsubsidized, and, in certain circumstances, Consolidation Loans.

To remain eligible for loan repayment, a borrower must continue to be employed in the school or location of initial eligibility.

 The total maximum loan repayment amount is $23,400 over six years. A borrower must repay the remaining principal and interest.

An individual who currently participates in the Teacher Loan Forgiveness program may continue participating in such program or enter the new loan repayment for teachers program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
