<amendment session="114" chamber="s" number="867" updated="2018-06-04T02:15:44Z">
  <amends type="sc" number="11" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2015-03-26">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000802"/>
  <offered datetime="2015-03-25"/>
  <description>To establish a deficit-neutral reserve fund relating to making it more difficult for corporations and billionaires to secretly influence elections by making unlimited undisclosed campaign expenditures, and to prevent such entities from evading campaign finance law, including through making false statements to government agencies.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2015-03-26" how="roll" result="fail" roll="107">
      <text>Amendment SA 867 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 47 - 52. Record Vote Number: 107.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1961, S1992" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Amendment SA 867 proposed by Senator Whitehouse. (consideration: CR S1879; text: CR S1879) To establish a deficit-neutral reserve fund relating to making it more difficult for corporations and billionaires to secretly influence elections by making unlimited undisclosed campaign expenditures, and to prevent such entities from evading campaign finance law, including through making false statements to government agencies.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25"/>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 867 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 47 - 52. Record Vote Number: 107.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Senate amendment not agreed to: Amendment SA 867 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 47 - 52. Record Vote Number: 107.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 867 proposed by Senator Whitehouse.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1879" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1879" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
