<bill session="114" type="s" number="3361" updated="2018-06-02T07:48:17Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pulmonary Hypertension Research and Diagnosis Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish an interagency coordinating committee on pulmonary hypertension, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Pulmonary Hypertension Research and Diagnosis Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2016-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Pulmonary Hypertension Research and Diagnosis Act of 2016

This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish the Interagency Pulmonary Hypertension Coordinating Committee. The committee must monitor research and annually summarize research and medical advances regarding pulmonary hypertension.

The committee must develop a comprehensive strategic plan to improve health outcomes for individuals with pulmonary hypertension. The plan must include recommendations regarding pulmonary hypertension diagnosis, research, transplantation criteria, public awareness, and health care delivery.

HHS must report on activities related to improving health outcomes for individuals with pulmonary hypertension. The report must include information regarding pulmonary hypertension epidemiology, treatment, support available to individuals, and research.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
