<bill session="115" type="h" number="4900" updated="2019-04-18T16:19:58Z">
  <state datetime="2018-01-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-01-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-01-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize additional funding for the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Metro Accountability and Investment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Metro Accountability and Investment Act</title>
    <title type="display">Metro Accountability and Investment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001292" joined="2018-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001304" joined="2018-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000874" joined="2018-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2018-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2018-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001168" joined="2018-01-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-01-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-01-30T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Metro Accountability and Investment Act

This bill amends the Passenger Rail Investment and Improvement Act of 2008 to authorize additional funding to the Department of Transportation (DOT) for grants for capital and preventive maintenance projects for the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (WMATA) in increments over 10 fiscal years beginning in FY2020 or until expended, subject to specified limitations.

DOT may not provide such grants until it certifies that the Board of Directors of WMATA has passed a resolution, and is making progress implementing such resolution, that

 establishes an independent budget authority for the Office of Inspector General of WMATA, an independent procurement authority for such office, and an independent hiring authority for such office; ensures the inspector general can obtain legal advice from a counsel reporting directly to the office; and requires the inspector general to submit recommendations for corrective action to the General Manager, the board, and Congress, and to publish any recommendation on the office's website, with redactions to prevent security risks.. DOT may make additional grants to WMATA for the purpose of funding the capital and preventive maintenance projects included in the Capital Improvement Program approved by the board.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
