<bill session="115" type="h" number="4420" updated="2019-04-18T16:18:13Z">
  <state datetime="2017-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food Security Act of 1985 to address critical conservation conditions under the regional conservation partnership program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Chesapeake Bay Farm Bill Enhancements Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Chesapeake Bay Farm Bill Enhancements Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Chesapeake Bay Farm Bill Enhancements Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000185"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2017-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001304" joined="2017-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2018-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001105" joined="2017-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2017-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000984" joined="2017-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000620" joined="2017-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000874" joined="2017-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001200" joined="2017-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2017-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2017-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000576" joined="2017-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001168" joined="2017-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000804" joined="2017-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-11-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Conservation and Forestry" code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3042"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2139"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-11-16T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Chesapeake Bay Farm Bill Enhancements Act of 2017 

This bill amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to modify and increase funding for the Department of Agriculture (USDA) Regional Conservation Partnership Program (RCPP).

(The RCPP operates through several USDA conservation programs to provide funding for partners to join in efforts with producers to increase the restoration and sustainable use of soil, water, wildlife, and related natural resources on regional or watershed scales. The RCPP includes the purposes and functions of several conservation programs such as the Chesapeake Bay Watershed Initiative.)

The bill modifies the RCPP to:

 increase mandatory funding and revise the requirements for distributing funds, allow in-kind support to count toward a partner's matching contribution, allow partners to apply for a funding renewal of a partnership agreement, authorize USDA to provide information and feedback to applicants throughout the application process, authorize grants for partners to directly operate conservation projects, authorize USDA to advance funding to partners for technical assistance for project development and outreach activities, require USDA to make publicly available the amounts available for technical assistance under a partnership agreement, limit USDA costs for technical assistance to costs specific and necessary to carry out the objectives of the partnership agreement, modify the criteria for a critical conservation area, and revise the requirements for prioritizing applications.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
