<bill session="114" type="h" number="5786" updated="2018-06-02T05:28:09Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Protection and Preparedness Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to provide for a rail spill preparedness fund, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Community Protection and Preparedness Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2016-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000791" joined="2016-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" code="HSPW07" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Community Protection and Preparedness Act of 2016

This bill requires the Department of Transportation (DOT), annually, to impose a $1,500 fee for each DOT-111 specification railroad tank car used to transport Class 3 flammable liquids during the previous fiscal year that did not meet DOT-117, DOT-117P, or DOT-117R specifications at the time it was used. Such fee shall be paid by each person who causes such liquids to be transported by such car in commerce and not by the railroad carrier that transports such liquids.

Collected fees shall be deposited into a Rail Account established within the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund and shall be available only for: (1) the payment of removal and remediation costs and other costs, expenses, claims, and damages related to an accident or incident involving the transportation of Class 3 flammable liquids by rail; and (2) DOT grants to states and Indian tribes to develop emergency plans and to train regional hazardous material emergency response teams and public employees responding to such an accident or incident.

DOT shall issue such regulations as necessary to require each Class I railroad carrier to inspect all track where an accident or incident involving the transportation by rail of flammable liquids or material poisonous or toxic by inhalation could affect a "high consequence area" (a commercially navigable waterway, an area with a high or concentrated population, or an area that is unusually sensitive to environmental damage). The inspections shall be carried out on foot and by a gage restraint measurement system. An inspector who finds a deviation from requirements regarding track safety standards shall immediately initiate remedial action.

Necessary amounts are authorized for the Federal Railroad Administration to hire at least two additional track safety specialists per region.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
