<bill session="114" type="h" number="116" updated="2019-04-11T15:40:27Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To permit small business concerns operating in the United States to elect to be exempt from certain Federal rules and regulations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Freedom of Commerce Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Small Business Freedom of Commerce Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000548"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Small Business Freedom of Commerce Act of 2015

Allows a small business operating in the United States to elect to be exempt from any federal rule or regulation issued on or after January 20, 2009. Requires the small business to notify the federal agency that issued the rule or regulation that it has elected such exemption, and makes the exemption effective 30 days after such notification.

Requires an exempt small business to: (1) label any product affected by the exemption as no longer subject to such rule or regulation, and (2) include in any communication relating to the affected product or activity a notice that it is no longer so subject.

Prescribes penalties for small business noncompliance with such requirements.

Prohibits a small business from electing to be exempt from a rule or regulation issued by the Department of Defense (DOD) or Homeland Security (DHS) if the Secretary of Defense or Homeland Security has determined that the rule or regulation is necessary for U.S. security.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
