<bill session="114" type="s" number="1608" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:35Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect the safety of the national airspace system from the hazardous operation of consumer drones, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consumer Drone Safety Act</title>
    <title type="display">Consumer Drone Safety Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2015-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2015-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2015-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4300-4301" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Consumer Drone Safety Act

This bill directs the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to publish a final rule containing safety requirements for the operation of consumer drones.

The final rule shall apply to consumer drones that are:

 flown for hobby or recreational use, and not operated in accordance with a community-based set of safety guidelines and within the programming of a nationwide community-based organization. The final rule shall also contain requirements that include:

 a maximum altitude for flight of consumer drones, circumstances or areas where flights are restricted because of risk of unsafe interactions with manned aircraft and to persons or property on the ground, and conditions that may require limitations on flight (such as weather or time of day). The FAA must also publish a final rule applicable to the manufacturing of consumer drones. This rule shall require modification, at the manufacturer's expense, of existing consumer drones so that they meet the rule's requirements.

The FAA may exempt from the rule applicable to manufacturers certain types of consumer drones if certain conditions concerning feasibility, cost, and safety are met.

No person may operate a consumer drone in the national airspace system without specific authority from the FAA.

The U.S. Customs and Border Protection may use existing authority to enforce restrictions on the importation of consumer drones into the United States.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
