<bill session="114" type="s" number="714" updated="2018-06-02T06:40:52Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Frontline Mental Health Provider Training Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to jointly conduct a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of expanding the use by the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs of physician assistants specializing in psychiatric medicine, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Frontline Mental Health Provider Training Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000607"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2015-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Frontline Mental Health Provider Training Act

Requires the Department of Defense (DOD) and the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to jointly commence a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of expanding use of physician assistants specializing in psychiatric medicine at DOD and VA medical facilities in order to meet the increasing demand for mental health care providers at such facilities through the completion of two 18-month psychiatry fellowship programs for physician assistants.

Directs DOD to carry out the pilot program at not less than one military medical treatment facility under the jurisdiction of the Department of the Army, one under the jurisdiction of the Department of the Navy, and one under the jurisdiction of the Department of the Air Force. Requires the VA to carry out the program at not less than three VA medical centers. Requires each Department to select at least 12 physician assistants to participate in each fellowship program. Sets forth qualifications for eligible physician assistants.

Requires each fellowship program to: (1) meet the training model for acuity, mixture, and volume established for psychiatric residency programs; and (2) provide to the selected individuals training equivalent to that received during a psychiatric residency, education leading to a clinical doctorate of science in psychiatry, and education that addresses the particular needs of rural and other under served populations of members of the Armed Forces and veterans.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
