<bill session="114" type="h" number="2378" updated="2019-04-11T15:42:41Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish an Office of Specialized Instructional Support in the Department of Education and to provide grants to State educational agencies to reduce barriers to learning.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reducing Barriers to Learning Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Reducing Barriers to Learning Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000565"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001281" joined="2015-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2015-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2015-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000523" joined="2015-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000510" joined="2016-01-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational guidance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Reducing Barriers to Learning Act of 2015

This bill amends the Department of Education Organization Act to create an Office of Specialized Instructional Support within the Department of Education (ED) to improve specialized instructional support services in schools. "Specialized instructional support services" are assessment, diagnosis, counseling, educational, therapeutic, and other services provided by qualified professionals as part of a comprehensive program to meet student needs.

The bill amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to authorize ED to award competitive matching grants to states to: (1) establish or expand specialized instructional support services and programs at the state level that are designed to provide technical assistance, coordination, and support to specialized instructional support services and programs addressing barriers to learning within local educational agencies and individual schools; and (2) hire and support specialized instructional support services coordinators to provide such assistance, coordination, and support.

References to pupil services and pupil services personnel are replaced with references to specialized instructional support services and specialized instructional support personnel.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
