<bill session="114" type="s" number="1959" updated="2018-06-02T06:59:07Z">
  <state datetime="2015-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Close the Revolving Door Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide greater controls and restrictions on revolving door lobbying.</title>
    <title type="display">Close the Revolving Door Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001267"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2015-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2016-12-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-08-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-08-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-08-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Close the Revolving Door Act of 2015

This bill amends the federal criminal code to impose a lifetime ban on any former Senator, Member of the House of Representatives, or elected officer of the Senate or House of Representatives lobbying any current Member, officer, or employee of Congress or any employee of any other legislative office. (Currently the ban is for two years after a Senator leaves office and one year after a Member of the House of Representatives leaves office). The ban is extended from one to six years for officers and employees of the Senate, personal staff of Members, committee staff, leadership staff, and other legislative offices.

A registered lobbyist or agent of a foreign principal may not be hired for a six-year period by a Member of Congress or a congressional committee with which the lobbyist or agent has had a substantial lobbying contact.

This bill also amends the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 to:

 direct the Secretary of the Senate and the Clerk of the House of Representatives to maintain a joint lobbyist disclosure Internet database for information required to be publicly disclosed by that Act, require a substantial lobbying entity to file with Congress a list of each employee of, contractor with, or paid consultant to the substantial lobbying entity and who is a former Member of Congress or another highly-paid covered legislative branch official, and increase the civil penalty for violations of the disclosure or reporting requirements of such Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
