<bill session="115" type="hr" number="745" updated="2019-04-18T15:55:01Z">
  <state datetime="2018-02-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-02-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-02-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives with respect to enhanced relations with the Republic of Moldova and support for Moldova's territorial integrity.</title>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives with respect to enhanced relations with the Republic of Moldova and support for Moldova's territorial integrity.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000523"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001250" joined="2018-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2018-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001101" joined="2018-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2018-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000410" joined="2018-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001199" joined="2018-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001190" joined="2018-11-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000168" joined="2018-02-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000592" joined="2018-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000604" joined="2018-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2018-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000364" joined="2018-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2018-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000031" joined="2018-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000065" joined="2018-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-02-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="sr" session="115" relation="unknown" number="629"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Moldova"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-02-20T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Reaffirms that it is U.S. policy to support the sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity of Moldova.

 Supports the Strategic Dialogue as a means to strengthen U.S.-Moldova relations and enhance Moldova's democratic, economic, and security reforms.

Encourages enhanced U.S. partnerships with Moldova's government, private sector, and civil society and a focus of U.S. assistance on strengthening democratic institutions, diversifying and securing energy supplies, and promoting rural economic growth, trade, and job creation.

Encourages Moldova to continue implementing democratic reforms.

Encourages the President to expedite the implementation of Public Law 113-96 providing for U.S. international broadcast programming to counter Russian disinformation.

Supports efforts to counter disinformation campaigns in Eastern Europe.

Affirms Moldova's right to: (1) determine its own partnerships free of external pressure, and (2) associate with the European Union or any regional organization.

Calls upon the Russian Federation to withdraw its military forces from the internationally recognized territory of Moldova, refrain from economic threats against Moldova, and cease support of separatist movements within Moldova.

Supports efforts to resolve the Transnistria issue through a comprehensive settlement that secures Moldova's sovereignty and territorial integrity while providing a special status for the Transnistrian region within Moldova.

Urges all parties to refrain from unilateral actions that may undermine efforts to achieve a peaceful resolution or jeopardize existing agreements. Encourages Transnistrian leaders and the Moldovan government to continue negotiations toward a political settlement.

Affirms that Moldova's stability and security is a U.S. priority that can only be achieved if the territorial integrity and sovereignty of Moldova and other European countries are respected.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
