<bill session="114" type="h" number="85" updated="2019-02-14T22:54:53Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Terrorism Prevention and Critical Infrastructure Protection Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To codify the objective of Presidential Policy Directive 21 to improve critical infrastructure security and resilience, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Terrorism Prevention and Critical Infrastructure Protection Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2015-02-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Security Technologies.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Innovation" code="HSHM08" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Terrorism Prevention and Critical Infrastructure Protection Act of 2015

Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) work with critical infrastructure owners and operators and state, local, tribal, and territorial entities to take proactive steps to manage risk and strengthen the security and resilience of the nation's critical infrastructure against terrorist attacks; (2) establish terrorism prevention policy to engage with international partners to strengthen the security and resilience of domestic critical infrastructure and critical infrastructure located outside of the United States; (3) establish a task force to conduct research into the best means to address the security and resilience of critical infrastructure in an integrated, holistic manner to reflect critical infrastructure's interconnectedness and interdependency; (4) establish the Strategic Research Imperatives Program to lead DHS's federal civilian agency approach to strengthen critical infrastructure security and resilience; and (5) make available research findings and guidance to federal civilian agencies for the identification, prioritization, assessment, remediation, and security of their internal critical infrastructure to assist in the prevention, mediation, and recovery from terrorism events.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) appoint a research working group that shall study how best to achieve national unity of effort to protect against terrorism threats and investigate the security and resilience of the nation's information assurance components that provide such protection; and (2) establish a research program to provide strategic guidance, promote a national unity of effort, and coordinate the overall federal effort to promote the security and resilience of the nation's critical infrastructure from terrorist threats.

Sets forth the terrorism protection responsibilities of each federal agency designated for a critical infrastructure sector.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) facilitate the timely exchange of terrorism threat and vulnerability information as well as information that allows for the development of a situational awareness capability for federal civilian agencies during terrorist incidents; (2) implement an integration and analysis function for critical infrastructure that includes operational and strategic analysis on terrorism incidents, threats, and emerging risks; and (3) support greater terrorism cyber security information sharing by civilian federal agencies with the private sector that protects constitutional privacy and civil liberties rights.

Requires a DHS Privacy Officer to be appointed by the President.

Authorizes the Secretary to consult with other federal agencies on how best to align federally funded research and development activities that seek to strengthen the security and resilience of the nation's critical infrastructure.

Requires the Secretary to: (1) develop a description of the functional relationships within DHS and across the federal government related to critical infrastructure security and resilience, (2) analyze the existing public-private partnership model for terrorism information exchange, (3) convene a team of researchers to identify baseline data and systems requirements for such exchange; and (4) demonstrate a near real-time situational awareness, research-based pilot project for critical infrastructure.

Directs the Secretary to provide to the President: (1) a research report that outlines the National Infrastructure Protection Plan to address the implementation of this Act, the requirements of title II of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, and alignment with the National Preparedness Goal and System required by Presidential Policy Directive 8; and (2) a National Critical Infrastructure Security and Resilience Research and Development Plan.

Requires the Secretary to determine which critical infrastructure sectors and agencies should be engaged in efforts to detect, deter, mitigate, and lead recovery efforts related to terrorist incidents.

Directs the National Research Council to evaluate how well DHS is meeting the objectives of this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
