<amendment session="114" chamber="s" number="664" updated="2018-06-04T02:15:43Z">
  <amends type="sc" number="11" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2015-03-25">offered</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001095"/>
  <offered datetime="2015-03-25"/>
  <description>To establish a deficit-neutral reserve fund relating to construction of new facilities and improvements to existing facilities at the detention facilities at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.</description>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-27">
      <text>Amendment SA 664 ruled out of order by the chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-27">
      <text>Motion to waive all applicable budgetary discipline with respect to amendment SA 664 rejected in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 48 - 48. Record Vote Number: 129.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 3/26/2015 S2010-2011" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-27">
      <text>Point of order that the amendment violates section 305(b) of the CBA raised in Senate with respect to amendment SA 664.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Amendment SA 664 proposed by Senator Enzi for Senator Cotton. (consideration: CR S1995-1997, S2010-2011; text: CR S1996) To establish a deficit-neutral reserve fund relating to construction of new facilities and improvements to existing facilities at the detention facilities at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25"/>
    <action datetime="2015-03-27">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Motion to waive all applicable budgetary discipline with respect to amendment SA 664 rejected in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 48 - 48. Record Vote Number: 129.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 3/26/2015 S2010-2011" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 664 proposed by Senator Enzi for Senator Cotton.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1995-1997, S2010-2011" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1996" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
