<bill session="113" type="s" number="2055" updated="2016-10-25T16:29:01Z">
  <state datetime="2014-04-03">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Corps of Engineers Cooperative Joint Management Restoration Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Corps of Engineers Cooperative Joint Management Restoration Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to allow for the collection of certain user fees by non-Federal entities.</title>
    <title type="display">Corps of Engineers Cooperative Joint Management Restoration Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001236"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2014-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2014-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000590" joined="2014-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2014-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-04-03" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-12">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Boxer with amendments. With written report No. 113-309.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="652">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 652.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="4100"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation facilities"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-12-12T12:54:33Z" status="Reported to Senate amended">Corps of Engineers Cooperative Joint Management Restoration Act - Amends the Water Resources Development Act of 1992 to authorize the Secretary of the Army to allow a non-federal public or private entity that has entered into a cooperative agreement for the operation and management of recreation facilities and natural resources at civil works projects under the Secretary's jurisdiction to collect user fees for the use of developed recreation sites and facilities, whether developed or constructed by such entity or the Department of the Army.

Permits such an entity to: (1) use any visitor reservation service that the Secretary has provided for by contract or interagency agreement to manage fee collections and reservations, subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary deems appropriate; and (2) retain up to 100% of the fees collected and use them for operation, maintenance, and management at the recreation site where they were collected.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 113-309</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
