<bill session="115" type="h" number="4892" updated="2019-04-18T16:19:56Z">
  <state datetime="2018-01-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-01-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-01-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food Security Act of 1985 with respect to nutrient and soil health management and source water protection, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Collaborative Water and Soil Enhancement Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Collaborative Water and Soil Enhancement Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Collaborative Water and Soil Enhancement Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000455"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-01-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Conservation and Forestry" code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-01-29T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Collaborative Water and Soil Enhancement Act of 2018 

This bill amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to establish requirements for Department of Agriculture (USDA) conservation programs regarding: (1) nutrient and soil health management, and (2) source water protection.

In carrying out the Conservation Stewardship Program and the Environmental Quality Incentives Program, USDA must:

 enroll at least five million acres annually in watersheds where nutrient delivery to hypoxic (low oxygen) zones is highest; encourage water quality or water quantity practices that protect source waters for drinking water (including protecting against public health threats) while also benefitting agricultural producers; collaborate with community water systems and state technical committees to identify local priority areas for the protection of source waters for drinking water; offer increased incentives and higher cost-share rates for water quality or water quantity practices that result in benefits that primarily occur outside of the land on which the practices are implemented; and reserve at least 10% of the funds or acres available for the programs to target the most effective practices for improving the quality or quantity of source water. USDA must also provide a streamlined certification process for third-party technical service providers that have certain certifications from the American Society of Agronomy.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
