<bill session="113" type="hr" number="66" updated="2018-06-05T15:46:00Z">
  <state datetime="2013-02-14T15:32:41-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-02-14T15:32:41-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 273) to eliminate the 2013 statutory pay adjustment for Federal employees, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 273) to eliminate the 2013 statutory pay adjustment for Federal employees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000810"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-13">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 113-9, by Mr. Woodall.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-13T19:45:58-05:00">
      <text>Section 2 of the resolution provides that during any recess or adjournment of not more than three days, the Speaker or his designee may reconvene the House at a time other than that previously appointed, within the limits of clause 4, section 5, article I of the Constitution. Section 3 of the resolution authorizes the Speaker to entertain motions to suspend the rules through the legislative day of February 15, 2013, relating to a measure condemning the government of North Korea and its February 12, 2013 test of a nuclear device. Section 4 provides that on any legislative day from February 16, 2013 through February 22, 2013: (a) the Journal of the proceedings of the previous day shall be considered as approved; (b) the Chair may adjourn the House to meet at a date and time within the limits of clause 4, section 5, article I of the Constitution. Section 5 authorizes the Speaker to appoint Members to perform the duties of the Chair for the duration of the period addressed by section 4 as though under clause 8(a) of rule I.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-02-13" state="REPORTED" calendar="House" number="4">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 4.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14T13:31:01-05:00">
      <text>By direction of the Committee on Rules, Mr. Woodall called up H.Res. 66 and asked for its immediate consideration.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H516-519" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14T13:33:00-05:00">
      <text>POINT OF ORDER - Mr. Polis raised a point of order against the provisions of H.Res. 66 because it violates the Congressional Budget Act. The Chair announced that the disposition of the point of order would be resolved by the question of consideration of H.Res. 66. The House proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the point of order, at the end of which the Chair will put the question on consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14T13:51:09-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the House consider the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H519" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14T13:51:16-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H519-529" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14T13:55:17-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 66.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14T15:25:35-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 229 - 194 (Roll no. 41).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H528-529" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="42" datetime="2013-02-14T15:32:41-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 227 - 192 (Roll no. 42).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H516-517" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14T15:32:41-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="procedurally-related" number="273"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-02-13T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 273) to eliminate the 2013 statutory pay adjustment for Federal employees.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 113-9</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
