<bill session="115" type="s" number="2629" updated="2019-04-18T16:42:29Z">
  <state datetime="2018-04-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve postal operations, service, and transparency.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Postal Service Reform Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Postal Service Reform Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2018-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001069" joined="2018-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2018-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2018-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2018-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-03-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-22">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-04-09" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="366">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 366.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3532"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="7019"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="6076"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="756"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-03-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Postal Service Reform Act of 2018

This bill directs the Office of Personnel Management to establish the Postal Service Health Benefits Program (PSHBP) within the Federal Employee Health Benefits Program for all postal employees and annuitants. All Medicare-eligible postal annuitants and employees enrolled in PSHBP must also enroll in Medicare, including parts A, B, and D.

The bill eliminates the existing statutory pension payment schedule, cancels any outstanding payments, and amortizes payments over 40 years.

The U.S. Postal Service (USPS) may establish a program to enter into agreements with an agency of any state government, local government, or tribal government to provide property and services on behalf of such agencies for non-commercial products and services. Distilled spirits, wine, or malt beverages shall be considered mailable if specified conditions apply.

The USPS shall submit to its Board of Governors: (1) a plan describing the actions it intends to take to achieve long-term solvency, and (2) a financial plan and budget consistent with that goal. The USPS must establish reasonable targets for performance to ensure that mail service for postal customers meets the service standards for market-dominant products.

There is established within USPS the position of Chief Innovation Officer. The USPS must submit to Congress and to the Postal Regulatory Commission a comprehensive strategy for maximizing revenues through innovative products and services.

The bill provides for emergency suspensions of post offices.

There is established in the USPS the Office of the Inspector General.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
