<bill session="113" type="s" number="21" updated="2016-10-25T16:19:45Z">
  <state datetime="2013-01-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cybersecurity and American Cyber Competitiveness Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to secure the United States against cyber attack, to improve communication and collaboration between the private sector and the Federal Government, to enhance American competitiveness and create jobs in the information technology industry, and to protect the identities and sensitive information of American citizens and businesses.</title>
    <title type="display">Cybersecurity and American Cyber Competitiveness Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000361"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000174" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000261" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2013-01-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-01-22T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Cybersecurity and American Cyber Competitiveness Act of 2013 - Calls for the enactment of bipartisan legislation to improve communication and collaboration between the private sector and the federal government to secure the United States against cyber attack, enhance the competitiveness of the United States and create jobs in the information technology industry, and protect the identities and sensitive information of U.S. citizens and businesses by: (1) enhancing the security and resiliency of public and private communications and information networks against cyber attack; (2) establishing mechanisms for sharing cyber threat and vulnerability information between the government and the private sector; (3) developing a public-private system to improve the capability of the United States to assess cyber risk and prevent, detect, and respond to cyber attacks against critical infrastructure such as the electric grid, the financial sector, and telecommunications networks; (4) promoting research and development investments and professional training; (5) preventing and mitigating identity theft; (6) enhancing U.S. diplomatic capacity and public-private international cooperation to respond to emerging cyber threats; (7) expanding resources for investigating and prosecuting cyber crimes in a manner that respects privacy rights and civil liberties and promotes U.S. innovation; and (8) maintaining robust protections of the privacy of U.S. citizens and their online activities and communications.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
