<bill session="113" type="s" number="888" updated="2016-10-25T16:24:06Z">
  <state datetime="2013-05-08">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide end user exemptions from certain provisions of the Commodity Exchange Act and the Securities Exchange Act of 1934.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to provide end user exemptions from certain provisions of the Commodity Exchange Act and the Securities Exchange Act of 1934.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000291"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000243" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000607" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2013-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001049" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001069" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2013-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2014-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2014-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000355" joined="2013-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000320" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000461" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2013-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-07">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-05-08" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="67">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 67.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="634"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2330"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="5405"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="5461"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Commodities markets"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-05-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amends the Commodity Exchange Act (CEA) to exempt, from the rules of prudential regulators for swap dealers and major swap participants with respect to initial and variation margin requirements for swaps not cleared by a registered derivatives clearing organization, those swaps in which one of the counterparties: (1) is eligible for an exception from clearing requirements for certain significant price discovery agreements, contracts, or transactions in a commodity exempt from regulation by the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC); or (2) satisfies specified criteria governing treatment of affiliates in connection with clearing requirements.

Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, regarding registration and regulation of security-based swap dealers and major security-based swap participants, to exempt from initial and variation margin requirements for swaps not cleared by a registered derivatives clearing organization a security-based swap in which one of the counterparties: (1) qualifies for a specified exception from clearing requirements, or (2) satisfies certain criteria governing the treatment of affiliates.

 Requires that the amendments to CEA made by this Act be implemented: (1) without regard to federal information policy requirements or the notice and comment requirements of federal administrative procedure; and (2) through promulgation of an interim final rule, pursuant to which public comment will be sought before a final rule is issued.Limits the disregard of such federal information policy and notice and comment requirements solely to changes to rules and regulations, or proposed rule and regulations, that are limited to, and directly a consequence of, the amendments to CEA made by this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
