<bill session="115" type="s" number="1705" updated="2019-04-18T16:38:34Z">
  <state datetime="2017-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide to the Secretary of Agriculture the ability to enter into a lease agreement for administrative sites on National Forest System land, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Forest Service Flexible Partnerships Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Forest Service Flexible Partnerships Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Forest Service Flexible Partnerships Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001267"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2017-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-08-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-08-02T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Forest Service Flexible Partnerships Act of 2017

This bill authorizes the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to lease as an administrative site, for consideration that is at least the market value of the site:

 any facility or improvement that was acquired or is used for the administration of the National Forest System (NFS); any federal land associated with such a facility or improvement that was acquired or is used for the administration of Forest Service activities and underlies or abuts such facility or improvement; or per fiscal year, no more than 10 isolated, undeveloped parcels no larger than 40 acres each. The bill makes the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 applicable to the leasing of administrative sites, subject to an exception.

Cash consideration for an administrative site shall be available to USDA to pay:

 necessary and incidental costs incurred in acquiring, improving, maintaining, reconstructing, or constructing a facility or improvement for the NFS and the lease of such site; and reasonable commissions or fees for brokerage services obtained regarding the lease.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
