<bill session="114" type="s" number="2049" updated="2019-03-03T14:41:01Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish in the Department of Veterans Affairs a continuing medical education program for non-Department medical professionals who treat veterans and family members of veterans to increase knowledge and recognition of medical conditions common to veterans and family members of veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to establish in the Department of Veterans Affairs a continuing medical education program for non-Department medical professionals who treat veterans and family members of veterans to increase knowledge and recognition of medical conditions common to veterans and family members of veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 114-702.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="3580"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to establish a continuing medical education program for non-VA medical professionals, with the goal of: (1) increasing knowledge and recognition of medical conditions common to veterans and family members, and (2) improving outreach to veterans and family members.

The program must include education on: (1) dealing with patients who are veterans or family members; (2) identifying and treating common mental and physical conditions of veterans and family members; (3) programs and benefits available to veterans and family members through the VA, the Department of Labor, and other federal agencies and non-federal organizations; and (4) the VA health care system.

The VA shall: (1) carry out such program for five years on a VA website at no cost to participating non-VA medical professionals, and (2) ensure that the program is accredited in as many states as practicable.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
