<bill session="115" type="h" number="3028" updated="2019-04-18T16:11:47Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide training for school certifying officials.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bolstering Returning American Veterans Education Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bolstering Returning American Veterans Education Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BRAVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BRAVE Act</title>
    <title type="display">BRAVE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000475"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Bolstering Returning American Veterans Education Act or the BRAVE Act

This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to provide a standard training curriculum for school certifying officials regarding administrative responsibilities relating to VA educational assistance programs. Such curriculum shall be provided through an Internet website or taught at a VA-sponsored conference.

The VA shall require as a condition of course approval that the school certifying official of the educational institution offering the course must: (1) complete the training curriculum within 30 days of after first being designated as a school certifying official, and (2) receive a minimum 75% score on a test of the official's knowledge of the covered subjects.

A school certifying official is an educational institution official designated to: (1) sign or report enrollment certifications, or (2) sign the school portion of the application and enrollment certification for individualized tutorial assistance.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
