<bill session="114" type="h" number="6156" updated="2019-02-13T17:31:26Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Local Wilderness Management Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Wilderness Act and the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to require the management of a wilderness study area, not designated by statute, under the jurisdiction of the Forest Service or the Bureau of Land Management for multiple use pending congressional consideration of the recommendation for designation of the area as wilderness, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Local Wilderness Management Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001187"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-10-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-10-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Conservation and Forestry" code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Local Wilderness Management Act

This bill amends the Wilderness Act to require certain National Forest System lands, including those which have been designated, officially or defacto, by the Forest Service as wilderness study areas, to be managed by the Department of Agriculture (USDA) for multiple use purposes, including mining, grazing, conservation, recreation, and other uses until Congress enacts a law that designates such an area as wilderness or specifies an alternative management approach for it.

The bill amends the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to require certain public lands, including those which have been designated, officially or defacto, as wilderness study areas by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), to be managed by the Department of the Interior to promote multiple use purposes, including the continuation of existing mining and grazing uses and mineral leasing, until Congress enacts a law that designates such an area as wilderness or specifies an alternative management approach for it.

USDA (with respect to National Forest System land) and Interior (for public lands managed by the BLM) may not designate, officially or defacto, land as a wilderness study area without first obtaining the written consent of the governing body of the county in which such land is located.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
