<bill session="114" type="s" number="1648" updated="2018-06-02T06:56:41Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Emergency Acute Care Hospital Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to create a sustainable future for rural healthcare.</title>
    <title type="display">Rural Emergency Acute Care Hospital Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2015-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2015-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2015-12-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4546-4547" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Rural Emergency Acute Care Hospital Act

This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to designate as a rural emergency hospital any facility that as of December 31, 2014, was:

 a critical access hospital (CAH) or a hospital with at most 50 beds located in a county in a rural area or treated as located in a rural area, or one of such hospitals that ceased operations during the period beginning five years before enactment of this Act and ending on December 30, 2014. A rural emergency hospital:

 must provide 24-hour emergency medical care and observation care not exceeding an annual per patient average of 24 hours or more than 1 midnight, does not provide any acute care inpatient beds and has protocols in place for the timely transfer of patients who require acute care inpatient services or other inpatient services, has elected to be designated as a rural emergency hospital, has received approval to operate as one from the state, and is certified by the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS). Medicare part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance Benefits) shall cover rural emergency hospital emergency services as well as ambulance services provided by a rural emergency hospital or other provider to transport patients who require acute care inpatient services or other inpatient services from the rural emergency hospital to a hospital or a CAH.

Payment for rural emergency hospital outpatient services of a rural emergency hospital, including telehealth and ambulance services, shall be 110% percent of their reasonable costs.

Rural emergency hospitals must be approved by the state and certified by HHS.

States shall have the option of waiving a specified distance requirement between a CAH certified as a rural emergency hospital and another facility located in the state that is seeking designation as a CAH.

Primary health services which the National Health Service Corps may provide under the Public Health Service Act shall include emergency medicine provided by physicians in a rural emergency hospital.

Hospitals with approved residency programs in emergency medicine shall include time spent by interns and residents in the emergency department of a rural hospital in the full-time equivalent count with respect to reimbursement for the indirect (stipend, fringe benefit) and direct (all or substantially all training) costs of medical education in subsection (d) hospitals.

(Generally, a subsection [d] hospital is an acute care hospital, particularly one that receives payments under Medicare's inpatient prospective payment system [IPPS] when providing covered inpatient services to eligible beneficiaries.)</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
