<bill session="115" type="h" number="5559" updated="2019-04-18T16:22:39Z">
  <state datetime="2018-04-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-04-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To transfer functions related to the preparation of flood maps from the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to the Director of the United States Geological Survey, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Scientific Flood Mapping Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Scientific Flood Mapping Act</title>
    <title type="display">Scientific Flood Mapping Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2018-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000601" joined="2018-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001195" joined="2018-04-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-04-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-04-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Scientific Flood Mapping Act

This bill directs the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) and the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) to jointly prepare a report describing the process by which FEMA shall transfer to the USGS all functions related to the preparation of flood maps as required under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 that FEMA was previously responsible for performing. FEMA must transfer such functions by 18 months after enactment of this bill.

The bill changes the membership composition of the Technical Mapping Advisory Council.

The bill amends the National Flood Insurance Act to direct the USGS to charge policy holders a fee for the purpose of recovering the cost of mapping activities. FEMA shall deposit the fees collected into a Flood Insurance Risk Mapping Fund which shall be available to the USGS for mapping activities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
