<bill session="113" type="s" number="415" updated="2016-10-25T16:21:16Z">
  <state datetime="2013-06-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Disaster Reform Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Small Business Disaster Reform Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to clarify the collateral requirement for certain loans under section 7(d) of the Small Business Act, to address assistance to out-of-State small business concerns, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Small Business Disaster Reform Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000550"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2013-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001069" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2013-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000590" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2013-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1019-1022"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1022" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 113-309.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-06-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Reported by Senator Landrieu with an amendment. With written report No. 113-84. Minority views filed.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-31" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="161">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 161.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="identical" number="1974"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-07-31T13:31:20Z" status="Reported to Senate amended">Small Business Disaster Reform Act of 2013 - Amends the Small Business Act with respect to obtaining the best available collateral for a disaster loan of not more than $200,000 relating to damage to or destruction of the property of, or economic injury to, a small business concern. Prohibits the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA), in obtaining such collateral, from requiring the small business owner to use the owner's primary residence as collateral if the owner has other assets with a value equal to or greater than the loan amount that could be used as collateral for the loan.

Allows the Administrator to authorize a Small Business Development Center (SBDC) to provide assistance to small businesses outside the state of that SBDC, without regard to geographical proximity, if the small business is in an area for which the President has declared a major disaster.

Expresses the sense of Congress that the Administrator shall ensure that a SBDC is appropriately reimbursed for any legitimate expenses in carrying out such assistance.

Directs the Administrator to increase oversight of small businesses receiving economic injury disaster loans, including random site visits and random reviews of loan usage. Expresses the sense of Congress that no additional federal funds shall be made available for such increased oversight.

Expresses the sense of Congress that the Administrator should: (1) reduce paperwork burdens on small businesses applying for SBA disaster assistance loans; and (2) ensure that the application for such assistance facilitates deterring and detecting potential instances of waste, fraud, and abuse. Requires the Administrator to take steps to reduce, to the maximum extent practicable, such paperwork.

Requires a report from the Administrator to the congressional small business committees relating to the creation of a web portal to track the status of applications for SBA disaster assistance.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 113-84</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
