<bill session="114" type="h" number="3544" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:44Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safer Officers and Safer Citizens Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To help keep law enforcement officers and communities safer by making grants to purchase body worn cameras for use by State, local, and tribal law enforcement officers.</title>
    <title type="display">Safer Officers and Safer Citizens Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000293" joined="2015-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000454" joined="2015-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1313"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="1897"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Photography and imaging"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Safer Officers and Safer Citizens Act of 2015

 This bill amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to authorize the Department of Justice's Bureau of Justice Assistance to award matching grants to states, local governments, and Indian tribes to purchase body-worn cameras.

The Bureau of Justice Assistance must give preference to grant applications from jurisdictions that: (1) have comprehensive policies and procedures related to implementation of a body-worn camera program, (2) have high percentages of officers without access to body-worn cameras, (3) have violent crime rates above the national average, and (4) agree to submit metrics on the use of body-worn cameras.

To offset the cost, it requires the Office of Personnel Management to issue regulations to limit administrative leave for federal employees to 20 days per year, unless approved individually by the agency head. The Office of Management and Budget must ensure each agency adjusts the number of authorized full-time equivalent employees to reflect lower personnel requirements due to increased available work hours per employee.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
