<bill session="115" type="s" number="1961" updated="2019-04-18T16:39:39Z">
  <state datetime="2018-03-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SBIR and STTR Oversight and Pilot Program Extension Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">SBIR and STTR Oversight and Pilot Program Extension Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">SBIR and STTR Oversight and Pilot Program Extension Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">SBIR and STTR Oversight and Pilot Program Extension Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SBIR and STTR Oversight and Pilot Program Extension Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SBIR and STTR Oversight and Pilot Program Extension Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Small Business Act to temporarily reauthorize certain pilot programs under the Small Business Innovation Research Program and the Small Business Technology Transfer Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000584"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2018-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2017-10-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-10-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-03-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-03-19">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Reported by Senator Risch with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-03-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="349">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 349.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-12-20">
      <text>By Senator Risch from Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship filed written report. Report No. 115-450.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-10-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">SBIR and STTR Oversight and Pilot Program Extension Act of 2018

This bill amends the Small Business Act to extend through FY2018 pilot programs under the Small Business Innovation Research Program (SBIR) and the Small Business Technology Transfer Program (STTR), specifically:

 phase flexibility that allows, under specified conditions, the National Institutes of Health (NIH), the Department of Defense, and the Department of Education to each provide a small business award under Phase II (research and development) of the SBIR program for a project whether or not the business was provided an award under Phase I (proof of concept); awards for technology development, testing, evaluation, and commercialization assistance for SBIR and STTR Phase II technologies or to support the progress of research, research and development, and commercialization conducted under SBIR or STTR programs to Phase III (commercialization); the NIH Phase 0 Proof of Concept Partnership to accelerate the creation of small businesses and the commercialization of research innovations from qualifying institutions; and the authority of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to allow federal agencies to use up to 3% of SBIR program funds for administrative, oversight, and contract processing costs. The SBA shall establish the Regional SBIR State Collaborative Initiative Pilot Program to provide awards to specified regional collaboratives to address the needs of small businesses in order to:

 be more competitive in the proposal and selection process for SBIR and STTR program awards, and increase technology transfer and commercialization.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-450</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
