<bill session="115" type="s" number="1208" updated="2019-04-18T16:36:30Z">
  <state datetime="2017-12-21">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to provide for an option under the Secure Mail Initiative under which a person to whom a document is sent under that initiative may elect to have the United States Postal Service use the Hold for Pickup service or the Signature Confirmation service in delivering the document, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Strengthening the Department of Homeland Security Secure Mail Initiative Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Strengthening the Department of Homeland Security Secure Mail Initiative Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Strengthening the Department of Homeland Security Secure Mail Initiative Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Strengthening the Department of Homeland Security Secure Mail Initiative Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening the Department of Homeland Security Secure Mail Initiative Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening the Department of Homeland Security Secure Mail Initiative Act</title>
    <title type="display">Strengthening the Department of Homeland Security Secure Mail Initiative Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2017-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2017-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-07-26" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-10-16">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson with amendments. With written report No. 115-171.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-10-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="241">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 241.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2017-12-21" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8270-8271" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S8270-8271" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-12-22">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-22T14:05:51-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-22T15:19:34-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="2595"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3478"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="U.S. Postal Service"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-12-21T16:25:06Z" status="Passed Senate amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the Senate on October 16, 2017. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Strengthening the Department of Homeland Security Secure Mail Initiative Act

(Sec. 3) This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to provide for an option under which a person to whom a document is sent under the Secure Mail Initiative may elect to have the U.S. Postal Service (USPS) use the Hold for Pickup service or the Signature Confirmation service in delivering the document.

DHS shall require payment of a fee for such services, which shall be deposited into the Immigration Examinations Fee Account and used to cover DHS and USPS costs of providing such services. The USPS: (1) may promulgate regulations that minimize such costs and do not require it to incur additional expenses that are not recoverable, and (2) shall notify DHS of any changes to such services.

If DHS determines that substantially similar services offered by a private carrier would provide better service and value than the USPS services, it may discontinue use of the USPS services and enter into a contract with the private carrier.

(Sec. 4) DHS must report to Congress within two years of this bill's enactment describing the implementation of requirements under this bill, the fee imposed, and the number of times during the previous year that a person used a service under this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-171</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
