<bill session="114" type="h" number="4171" updated="2018-06-02T04:50:20Z">
  <state datetime="2015-12-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-12-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Silent Skies Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to prohibit the operation of certain aircraft not complying with stage 4 noise levels, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Silent Skies Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001101" joined="2016-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2015-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000057" joined="2015-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001137" joined="2015-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001188" joined="2015-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2015-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2015-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000602" joined="2015-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2015-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Aviation" code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Noise pollution"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-12-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Silent Skies Act of 2015

 This bill directs the Federal Aviation Administration to enter into a competitive cooperative agreement with an institution, entity, or consortium to carry out a program for the development of aircraft technology that will assist in-service and in-production civil turbojets not meeting stage 4 noise standards to comply with those or more stringent standards.

The Department of Transportation (DOT) must: (1) issue regulations to establish minimum standards to ensure that graduated percentages of civil turbojets weighing over 75,000 pounds comply with the stage 4 noise levels by specified dates, and (2) report annually on the progress made by air carriers in complying with such standards. 100% of such turbojets operating after December 31, 2037, must comply with stage 4 levels.

DOT shall request the International Civil Aviation Organization to add to its Work Programme the consideration of international standards for the phase-out of aircraft that do not comply with stage 4 noise levels.

The requirements of this Act shall not apply to civil turbojet aircraft that operate outside of the 48 contiguous states.

DOT may not issue a type certificate for: (1) a civil turbojet with a maximum weight of more than 75,000 pounds on and after December 31, 2017, unless the applicant demonstrates that such turbojet complies with stage 5 noise levels; and (2) any civil turbojet on and after December 31, 2020, unless the applicant demonstrates that such turbojet complies with stage 5 noise levels.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
