<bill session="115" type="h" number="5764" updated="2019-04-18T16:23:21Z">
  <state datetime="2018-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Agricultural Risk Protection Act of 2000 to require peer review for value-added agricultural product market development grants, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Growing Value-Added Economies Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Growing Value-Added Economies Act</title>
    <title type="display">Growing Value-Added Economies Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000570"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000449" joined="2018-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000580" joined="2018-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001185" joined="2018-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2018-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-05-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commodity Exchanges, Energy, and Credit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Commodity Exchanges, Energy, and Credit" code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-05-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Growing Value-Added Economies Act 

This bill amends the Agricultural Risk Protection Act of 2000 to reauthorize and modify the Department of Agriculture (USDA) Value-Added Producer Grants Program. (The program provides grants for the development and marketing of value-added agricultural products, which are products that have increased in value due to processing.)

The bill modifies the program to require USDA to:

 establish independent external review panels to review and evaluate each eligible application based on merit and relevance, develop and implement an outreach and technical assistance strategy, and provide for periodic evaluations that measure the impact of the program and the impact of projects on achieving the purposes of the program. The bill also: (1) provides mandatory funding for the program; and (2) prohibits more than 5% of the total annual funding for the program from being used for administrative expenses, program evaluation, outreach, and technical assistance.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
