<bill session="114" type="h" number="4322" updated="2019-04-11T15:40:30Z">
  <state datetime="2016-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To clarify the prohibition on affiliation under the Mentor-Protege Program of the Department of Defense, to amend the Small Business Act to improve cooperation between the mentor-protege programs of the Small Business Administration and the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mentor-Protege Cooperation Reform Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="display">Mentor-Protege Cooperation Reform Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000387"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2016-01-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-01-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4909"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4341"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-01-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Mentor-Protege Cooperation Reform Act of 2016

This bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1991 to revise the no-affiliation requirement in the eligibility criteria under the Mentor-Protege Program of the Department of Defense (DOD) for a mentor firm to receive the award of a federal contract and enter into an agreement with one or more protege firms to provide them certain assistance.

The bill establishes procedures for the Small Business Administration (SBA) or DOD to determine that no affiliation between mentor and protege exists.

The bill amends the Small Business Act to bar DOD from carrying out a Mentor-Protege Program for a small business unless: (1) it submits a plan to the SBA, and (2) the SBA approves that plan.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
