<bill session="114" type="h" number="4288" updated="2019-02-12T19:45:26Z">
  <state datetime="2015-12-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FEMA Help and Education for Local Partners Act (FEMA HELP Act)</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a multi-agency Federal team to improve and reform Federal disaster assistance.</title>
    <title type="display">FEMA Help and Education for Local Partners Act (FEMA HELP Act)</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1814"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-12-17T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">FEMA Help and Education for Local Partners Act (FEMA HELP Act)

This bill directs the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to establish and convene a multi-agency federal disaster assistance team to work and coordinate with state, local, tribal, and territorial leaders to develop a comprehensive approach to disaster recovery by using a full range of federal program funding resources through collaboration among FEMA, the Department of Housing and Urban Development, the Federal Highway Administration, the Small Business Administration, the Federal Transit Administration, the Department of Defense, the Army Corps of Engineers, and state, local, tribal, and territorial governments.

FEMA shall: (1) ensure that each coordinating officer is trained in a range of applicable disaster recovery funding programs across the team members, and (2) establish and publish guidelines and criteria for making and communicating decisions regarding funding eligibility and requirements for disaster recovery personnel across the team members.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
