<bill session="113" type="s" number="2746" updated="2016-10-25T16:32:01Z">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sudden Unexpected Death Data Enhancement and Awareness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to improve the health of children and help better understand and enhance awareness about unexpected sudden death in early life.</title>
    <title type="display">Sudden Unexpected Death Data Enhancement and Awareness Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2014-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2014-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2014-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2014-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2014-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000206" joined="2014-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2014-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2014-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2014-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2014-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2014-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2014-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="669"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-07-31T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Sudden Unexpected Death Data Enhancement and Awareness Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to continue activities relating to stillbirth, sudden unexpected infant death (SUID), and sudden unexpected death in childhood (SUDC).

Requires the CDC to provide for collection of epidemiologic information on stillbirths, including through existing surveillance systems. Requires the CDC to develop and periodically update a standard data collection protocol and guidelines for postmortem stillbirth evaluation.

Directs the CDC to provide for collection of sociodemographic, death scene investigation, clinical history, and autopsy information on SUID and SUDC cases through the review of existing records.

Requires the CDC to develop and periodically update standard protocols for data collection and death scene investigation for SUID. Sets forth goals for SUID surveillance, including: (1) collecting information about the environmental and medical circumstances of death, (2) supporting multidisciplinary infant death reviews to classify and characterize SUID, and (3) facilitating information sharing to improve reporting of SUID. Requires the death scene investigation protocol to include the collection of infant and family medical history, circumstances surrounding death, the infant's sleep position and sleep environment, and any accidental or environmental factors associated with the death.

Directs the CDC to develop and periodically update guidelines for standard autopsy protocols for SUID and SUDC.

Allows the Attorney General to conduct and support training for medical examiners, coroners, and others regarding standard protocols for death scene investigation and autopsies.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
