<bill session="115" type="h" number="4602" updated="2019-04-18T16:18:51Z">
  <state datetime="2017-12-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the full funding of part B of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act by making certain spending cuts to the Department of Defense.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Defending Special Education Students and Families Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Defending Special Education Students and Families Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Defending Special Education Students and Families Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000598"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-12-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-12-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Defending Special Education Students and Families Act of 2017

This bill amends the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA)&#160;to authorize appropriations for grants to assist states in providing special education and related services to children with disabilities. For FY2018-FY2022, the bill authorizes specified amounts. For FY2023 and each subsequent fiscal year, the bill authorizes amounts using a specified formula.

The bill also amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to modify the discretionary spending limits for FY2018-FY2021. For each fiscal year, the bill decreases the limit for security spending by a specified amount and increases the limit for nonsecurity spending by the same amount.&#160;The&#160;nonsecurity spending increases are the same amounts as are authorized in the&#160;bill&#160;for additional funding under the IDEA in&#160;those fiscal years.&#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
