<bill session="115" type="h" number="6317" updated="2019-04-18T16:25:50Z">
  <state datetime="2018-07-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide that direct primary care service arrangements do not disqualify deductible health savings account contributions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Primary Care Enhancement Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Primary Care Enhancement Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Primary Care Enhancement Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000594"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2018-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001199" joined="2018-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-07-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-07-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 26 - 12.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-07-19">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 115-852.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-07-19" calendar="Union" number="660">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 660.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="6199"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="6310"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-07-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow individuals who are eligible for a health savings account (HSA) to participate in a direct primary care service arrangement without losing their eligibility due to the arrangement, and (2) permit an HSA to be used to pay for a direct primary care service arrangement.

Under a direct primary care service arrangement, an individual receives medical care consisting solely of primary care services provided by primary care practitioners in exchange for a fixed periodic fee. The fees are subject to limits specified in the bill.

The primary care services covered by the arrangement may not include procedures that require the use of general anesthesia, prescription drugs (other than vaccines), and laboratory services not typically administered in an ambulatory primary care setting.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-852</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
