<bill session="114" type="s" number="700" updated="2018-06-02T06:40:48Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">READ Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reducing Exposure to Asbestos Database Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Asbestos Information Act of 1988 to establish a public database of asbestos-containing products, to require public disclosure of information pertaining to the manufacture, processing, distribution, and use of asbestos-containing products in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">READ Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2015-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2015-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2015-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2016-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2015-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2015-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1387-1388" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="2030"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reducing Exposure to Asbestos Database Act of 2015 or the READ Act

This bill amends the Asbestos Information Act of 1988 to require the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish and maintain a database of asbestos-containing products. The database must be accessible through EPA's website, publicly available, and searchable. An asbestos-containing product is any product to which asbestos is deliberately or knowingly added or in which asbestos is deliberately used or knowingly present in any concentration.

Any person who manufactured, processed, distributed, sold, imported, transported, or stored an asbestos-containing product must report to the EPA each year to identify the characteristics and location of the asbestos-containing products.

Civil penalties are imposed upon any person who knowingly: (1) manufactured, processed, distributed, sold, imported, transported, or stored an asbestos-containing product and who did not submit a report; or (2) provides false or inaccurate information in a report or fails to provide required information.

The Government Accountability Office must report on the utility of the database. The report must contain recommendations for measures to increase use of the database by consumers and further reduce the harm caused by exposure to asbestos.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
