<bill session="115" type="s" number="1224" updated="2019-04-18T16:36:33Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to carry out a Community Resilience Grant Program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BUILD Resilience Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BUILD Resilience Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Building Up Infrastructure and Limiting Disasters through Resilience Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Building Up Infrastructure and Limiting Disasters through Resilience Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">BUILD Resilience Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000384"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2017-10-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3148" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2583"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-24T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Building Up Infrastructure and Limiting Disasters through Resilience Act of 2017 or the BUILD Resilience Act of 2017

This bill requires the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to carry out a Community Resilience Grant Program to provide assistance to communities for increasing resilience to chronic stresses and acute shocks, including by improving long-term resilience of infrastructure and housing. A state, local government, or regional entity is eligible for such a grant if it is located in an area that has been declared a major disaster area within the previous five years.

HUD's Office of Policy Development and Research must select and award annual grants to a single nonprofit organization having a national reputation for expertise in resilience research and capacity building to develop, establish, and operate a National Research Center for Resilience. The center shall provide grants to institutions of higher education or other nonprofit organizations to establish a Regional Center for Resilience in each of HUD's 10 regions to serve as regional research partners with recipients of resilience grants.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
