<bill session="114" type="h" number="6192" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:47Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Responsible Law Enforcement Acquisition Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to permit the Secretary of Defense to transfer excess personal property of the Department of Defense to law enforcement agencies only by means of auction, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Responsible Law Enforcement Acquisition Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000051"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-10-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-10-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Readiness" code="HSAS03" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Responsible Law Enforcement Acquisition Act of 2016

This bill changes the program (known as the 1033 program) under which the Department of Defense (DOD) may transfer surplus military equipment to state and local law enforcement agencies at no cost to a program under which such property is transferred by auction and the proceeds are deposited in the Treasury.

The bill requires that the recipient be a state, local, or tribal law enforcement agency that is the high bidder at an auction that is open only to such agencies and is conducted by DOD or a DOD-contracted entity.

The program preference for property transfers for use in counter drug, counterterrorism, or border security activities is eliminated.

DOD is prohibited from transferring personal property to a recipient agency without charge.

The bill prohibits an executive agency from using available funds or fees to carry out or enforce any executive order, rule, regulation, or any other executive branch policy issued on or after January 16, 2015, that has the effect of establishing an interagency working group regarding: (1) the DOD transfer of personal property to state, local, or tribal law enforcement agencies; or (2) the use of such property.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
