<bill session="114" type="h" number="914" updated="2018-11-21T20:30:40Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to jointly operate the Federal Recovery Coordination Program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To direct the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to jointly operate the Federal Recovery Coordination Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000575"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001297" joined="2015-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-12T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to provide collaborative recovery coordinator training at a qualified nursing or medical school selected by the VA, to lead the systematic evidence review of care coordination and a consensus conference to build the model on evidence-based guidelines. Designates such school to lead: (1) the literature review and development of evidence-based guidelines for recovery coordination, training modules for care coordination, and software that is compatible with VA systems for recovery coordination; and (2) a consensus conference on evidence-based care coordination.

Directs the VA to: (1) subcontract with an appropriate entity for the development of care coordination software, (2) carry out a conference for recovery coordinator tool validation, and (3) carry out a software pilot program.

Authorizes the qualified nursing or medical school to train 45 recovery coordinators.

Directs the VA and the Department of Defense (DOD), in carrying out the Federal Recovery Coordination Program, to jointly develop, and enter a memorandum to carry out, a plan to ensure that:

 the Program is operated jointly by the Secretaries; the administration of the Program is not delegated to an individual outside the respective office of each Secretary; the Program assists members of the Armed Forces with severe or catastrophic injuries or illnesses who are unlikely to return to active duty and who will most likely be medically separated and members and veterans whose individual circumstances (including illness, injury, mental health, family situation, and unique benefit needs) cause difficulties in transitioning to civilian life; the VA Secretary and the Secretaries of the military departments refer members and veterans to the Program at the earliest possible time; and each federal agency provides a Federal Recovery Coordinator of the Program with the information, coordination, and cooperation necessary for the Coordinator to assist participating members and veterans.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
