<bill session="113" type="h" number="2664" updated="2016-10-25T16:05:43Z">
  <state datetime="2013-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Made in America Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Commerce to establish a voluntary program under which manufacturers may have products certified as meeting the standards of labels that indicate to consumers the extent to which the products are manufactured in the United States.</title>
    <title type="display">Made in America Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001083"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001259" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001275" joined="2013-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000620" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000451" joined="2013-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000569" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001053" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001181" joined="2014-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="4550"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-07-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Made in America Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of Commerce to establish: (1) a voluntary America Star Program under which manufacturers may have products certified as meeting the standards of labels that indicate to consumers the extent to which the products are manufactured in the United States; and (2) such America Star labels, including the content of the labels and the standards that a product shall meet in order to bear a particular label. Requires the labels to be consistent with public perceptions of the meaning of descriptions of the extent to which a product is manufactured in the United States.

Requires the Secretary, after receiving an application, to certify a product as meeting a label's standards, notify the manufacturer, conduct monitoring and compliance review to ensure that a product continues to meet such standards, notify a manufacturer of any corrective action needed, and withdraw certification of a product if such action is not taken. Provides for an expedited appeals procedure for actions that adversely affect a person.

Prohibits a person from placing an America Star label on a product, using such label in marketing such product, or in any other way representing that such product meets the standards of such label unless a certification by the Secretary is in effect. Bars the Secretary from certifying the product for a five-year period after determining that a manufacturer has violated the purposes of the Program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
