<bill session="114" type="h" number="4432" updated="2019-02-14T22:58:03Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Commercial UAS Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish an interim rule for the operation of small unmanned aircraft for commercial purposes, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Commercial UAS Modernization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000574"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E98"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Space.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Space and Aeronautics" code="HSSY16" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Aviation" code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1314"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-02T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Commercial UAS Modernization Act

This bill amends the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 to permit an individual to operate a small commercial unmanned aircraft without an airworthiness certificate within the United States until the effective date of a final rule based on the notice of proposed rulemaking "Operation and Certification of Small Unmanned Aircraft Systems" issued on February 23, 2015, subject to the following requirements:

 the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) must receive an attestation that the aircraft owner has liability insurance covering its operation; the owner must register the aircraft; the operator must pass an initial aeronautical knowledge test developed by the FAA and a proficiency test administered by a test site for such aircraft; the aircraft may be operated for commercial purposes only in daylight conditions, under visual line of sight rules, lower than 500 feet above ground level, and only after a preflight inspection; and the aircraft shall yield right of way to all other users of the National Airspace System. Such an aircraft may not be operated: (1) until the operator of a test site certifies that it meets the requirements in the rulemaking notice and can operate within such restrictions; (2) unless the operator has prior authorization from the air traffic control facility having jurisdiction over the Class B, Class C, or Class D airspace or within the lateral boundaries of the surface area of Class E airspace designated for an airport; and (3) by any individual with any physical or mental condition that would interfere with safe operation of the aircraft.

The operator of a such an aircraft involved in an accident causing personal injury or property damage must report it to the FAA within two days.

The FAA shall provide for a micro UAS classification of unmanned aircraft systems, the aircraft component of which may not weigh more than 4.4 pounds, including payload. The operation of such a micro shall be subject to specified restrictions.

The bill directs the FAA to:

 appoint a Deputy Associate Administrator for Unmanned Aircraft who shall create a research and development plan for the safe integration of unmanned aircraft into the National Airspace System; establish a joint aircraft system research and development data collection and analysis program at the William J. Hughes Technical Center; and implement an air traffic management pilot program to research and test a new regulatory structure for operations of such aircraft in airspace below 1,200 feet.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
