<bill session="113" type="h" number="1363" updated="2018-06-05T16:12:54Z">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Exploring for Geothermal Energy on Federal Lands Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Exploring for Geothermal Energy on Federal Lands Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote timely exploration for geothermal resources under existing geothermal leases, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Exploring for Geothermal Energy on Federal Lands Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000573"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000369" joined="2013-07-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-09-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-22">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-690.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-22" calendar="Union" number="521">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 521.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-12-22T13:26:27Z" status="Reported to House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Exploring for Geothermal Energy on Federal Lands Act - (Sec. 2) Exempts geothermal exploration test projects from environmental impact statement requirements under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA) if the project:

 causes less than five acres of soil or vegetation disruption at the location of each well and no more than five additional acres of disruption during access or egress to the test site, is developed no deeper than 2,500 feet and&#160;less than&#160;eight inches in diameter, is developed in a manner that does not require off-road motorized access other than to and from the well site along an identified off-road route, is developed without construction of new roads other than upgrading of existing drainage crossings for safety purposes and with the use of rubber-tired digging or drilling equipment vehicles, is completed in less than 45 days, and requires the restoration of the project site within three years to approximately the condition that existed at the time the project began, unless the site is subsequently used as part of energy development on the lease. Requires a&#160;holder of a geothermal lease on federal land to notify the Department of the Interior within&#160;30 days before the start of drilling under a geothermal exploration test project. Gives Interior 10 days to review a project and notify a leaseholder that the project is exempted from NEPA requirements or that project deficiencies preclude the exemption. Requires Interior to allow a&#160;leaseholder an opportunity to remedy any deficiencies before the date on which the leaseholder intended to start drilling.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 113-690</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
