<bill session="114" type="s" number="684" updated="2018-06-02T06:40:44Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Homeless Veterans Prevention Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the provision of services for homeless veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Homeless Veterans Prevention Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001135"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2015-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2015-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-03">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1105"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6046"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6107"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Homeless Veterans Prevention Act of 2015 

Increases the per diem payment for transitional housing assistance for homeless veterans who are placed in housing that will become permanent upon the termination of such assistance to a maximum of 150% of the per diem rate authorized for veterans receiving domiciliary care in state homes.

Allows services for which a homeless veteran receives a grant under the comprehensive service programs to include furnishing care for a dependent.

Authorizes the the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to enter into partnerships with public or private entities to provide legal services to homeless veterans and veterans at risk of homelessness.

Revises VA authority to provide dental care to veterans receiving certain other assistance through the VA to include those veterans receiving assistance under the United States Housing Act of 1937.

Repeals the September 30, 2013, sunset on the authority of the VA and the Department of Labor to carry out a program of referral and counseling for veterans who are at risk of homelessness and are transitioning from certain institutions, including penal institutions.

 Extends supportive services assistance for very low-income veteran families in permanent housing.

Directs the VA to: (1) assess and measure the capacity of programs for which entities receive grants or per diem payments to assist homeless veterans, and (2) use such information to ensure that such programs effectively serve the needs of such veterans. Requires a VA report on activities under such programs. (Current law requires annual reports.)

Requires a Comptroller General study of VA assistance to homeless veterans.

Repeals the requirement for annual VA reports on assistance to homeless veterans.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
