<bill session="114" type="s" number="3369" updated="2018-06-02T07:48:19Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Empowering Law Enforcement to Keep America Safe Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend section 2709 of title 18, United States Code, to clarify that the Government may obtain a specified set of electronic communication transactional records under that section, and to make permanent the authority for individual terrorists to be treated as agents of foreign powers under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978.</title>
    <title type="display">Empowering Law Enforcement to Keep America Safe Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000303"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2016-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2016-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001141" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2016-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Empowering Law Enforcement to Keep America Safe Act of 2016

This bill amends the federal criminal code to expand the categories of subscriber transactional records that the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) may request from wire or electronic communication service providers about a person or entity for an authorized investigation to protect against international terrorism or clandestine intelligence activities.

Under current law, the FBI may request a person's or an entity's name, address, length of service, and telephone toll billing records. The bill allows the FBI to also request:

 email addresses, telephone numbers, instrument numbers, or other account identifying information; means and sources of payment (including card or bank account information); account numbers, login history, service start dates, or types of services; IP addresses or network addresses; or communication addressing, routing, or transmission information (excluding cell tower information), session times, or durations for an electronic communication. The bill prohibits the FBI from requesting the contents of an electronic communication.

The bill also amends the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 to make permanent the government's authority to track a non-U.S. person who engages in international terrorism or preparatory activities (commonly referred to as a "lone wolf") under the same evidentiary standards that apply to an agent of a foreign power under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978. (Currently, this provision is scheduled to expire on December 15, 2019.)</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
