<bill session="114" type="s" number="3384" updated="2018-06-02T07:48:22Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Middle-Income Housing Tax Credit Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a credit for middle-income housing, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Middle-Income Housing Tax Credit Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2016-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Middle-Income Housing Tax Credit Act of 2016 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a tax credit for the development of housing for middle-income households.

The credit is based on the existing low-income housing tax credit and applies to the development or rehabilitation of residential rental properties if: (1) 60% or more of the residential units in the project are both rent-restricted and occupied by individuals whose income is 100% or less of the area median gross income, and (2) the project is not federally subsidized or financed with a federally funded grant.

The credits are allocated to each state based on population, and state housing agencies then distribute the credits to developers using a competitive process. The credits are paid over a 15-year credit period, and the amounts of the credits are based on a percentage of a project's qualified basis, which is the portion of the project dedicated to affordable middle-income housing.

The credit dollar amount allocated to a project may not exceed the amount that is necessary for the financial feasibility of the project and its viability as a qualified middle-income housing project throughout the credit period.

To qualify for the credit, the developer must make a long-term commitment to middle-income housing, under which the affordability restrictions for a property remain in place for at least an additional 15 years after the close of the credit period.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
