<bill session="114" type="hr" number="34" updated="2018-06-02T01:16:06Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Research Service Electronic Accessibility Resolution of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Access to Congressional Research Service Reports Resolution of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Directing the Clerk of the House of Representatives to provide members of the public with Internet access to certain Congressional Research Service publications, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Congressional Research Service Electronic Accessibility Resolution of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000567"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001286" joined="2015-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000754" joined="2015-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001059" joined="2015-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2015-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2015-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2015-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2015-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000480" joined="2015-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000799" joined="2015-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1381"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional Research Service (CRS)"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-14T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Public Access to Congressional Research Service Reports Resolution of 2015 or the Congressional Research Service Electronic Accessibility Resolution of 2015

Directs the Clerk of the House of Representatives, in consultation with the Director of the Congressional Research Service (CRS), to establish and maintain a centralized, searchable, bulk downloadable, electronic database consisting of: (1) CRS Issue Briefs, Reports, Authorization of Appropriations Products and Appropriations Products, and other materials intended or available for general congressional distribution through the CRS website; and (2) an index of such information.

Exempts: (1) any information determined to be confidential by the CRS Director or the head of the agency that provided it to CRS; and (2) any document produced in response to a confidential research request made by a House Member, officer, employee, or office, provided that the document has not been distributed and is not intended for distribution to anyone other than the individual or office making the request.

Directs the Clerk, in addition to the database, to establish and maintain contemporaneously a website containing a searchable, sortable index of all of the information in the database in both human- and machine-readable formats such as Extensible Markup Language (XML).

Authorizes the Clerk, on the basis of information provided by the Director, to: (1) remove from the database, and from related CRS products, the name and contact information of CRS employees or material that may infringe the copyright of a protected work; and (2) make any changes that the Director determines are necessary to ensure that information in the database is accurate and current.

Requires each official public website of a House Member, House committee, or joint committee of Congress to permit public use to obtain the information contained in such database to the same extent as House users may obtain such information through the CRS website.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
