<bill session="115" type="s" number="2813" updated="2019-04-18T16:43:01Z">
  <state datetime="2018-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Agricultural Adjustment Act to assist small cheese producers.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Local Cheese Promotion and Dairy Support Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Local Cheese Promotion and Dairy Support Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Local Cheese Promotion and Dairy Support Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001169"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2018-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-05-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing and promotion"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Financial literacy"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-05-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Local Cheese Promotion and Dairy Support Act of 2018

This bill amends the Agricultural Adjustment Act to establish a Department of Agriculture (USDA) program to provide competitive grants to small cheese producers and cooperative groups of small cheese producers.

In awarding grants, USDA must define the term "small cheese producer" and give preference to producers that use locally or regionally sourced product to produce cheese.

Grant recipients may use the funds to:

 purchase equipment or renovate and make repairs to production facilities, develop a business plan or perform a feasibility study to grow the business, promote and market cheese, participate in accounting and financial literacy education and training, carry out food safety upgrades and training, and participate in job training. Using no more than 10% of the funds provided for this bill, USDA must establish a cheese production, education, and promotion pilot project at eligible institutions, including:

 land-grant colleges or universities, local offices of the National Institute of Food and Agriculture or other regional USDA offices, groups of regional experts that advise beginning farmers or ranchers, or nonprofit organizations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
