<bill session="115" type="sj" number="55" updated="2019-04-18T16:31:28Z">
  <state datetime="2018-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution to require certifications regarding actions by Saudi Arabia in Yemen, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A joint resolution to require certifications regarding actions by Saudi Arabia in Yemen, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2018-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-03-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="sj" session="115" relation="unknown" number="58"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Saudi Arabia"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Yemen"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-03-08T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This joint resolution requires the Department of State, by 30, 180, and 360 days after this bill's enactment, to submit to Congress certifications of whether the government of Saudi Arabia is undertaking: (1) a good faith effort to conduct diplomatic negotiations to end the civil war in Yemen, and (2) appropriate measures to increase access for all Yemenis to food, fuel, and medicine.

If the State Department is unable to certify that such government is taking such action, no federal funds may be obligated or expended for U.S. air refueling of Saudi-led coalition non-U.S. aircraft conducting missions in Yemen other than missions related to:

 al Qaeda, al Qaeda in the Arabian Peninsula, and the Islamic State in Iraq and Syria; Iranian terrorist activities in Yemen; countering the transport, assembly, or employment of Iranian ballistic missiles or components in Yemen; helping coalition aircraft return safely to base in emergency situations; or force protection of U.S. aircraft or personnel.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
