<bill session="115" type="h" number="4873" updated="2019-04-18T16:19:53Z">
  <state datetime="2018-01-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-01-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-01-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the cancellation of removal and adjustment of status of certain individuals who are long-term United States residents and who entered the United States as children, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DACA Compromise Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DACA Compromise Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">DACA Compromise Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000056"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-01-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Citizenship" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-01-20T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">DACA Compromise Act of 2018

This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to cancel the removal of, and adjust to permanent resident status the status of, an alien: (1) who has been continuously present in the United States since June 15, 2012; (2) who was granted deferred removal as an undocumented alien pursuant to the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals (DACA) program, unless the individual engaged in subsequent conduct that would have rendered the alien ineligible for program renewal; (3) who applies for adjustment not earlier than two years after he or she was granted such deferred removal; (4) who otherwise satisfies the requirements of this bill, and (5) to whom an immigrant visa is available.

The bill reallocates specified family, employment, and diversity visas for such approved individuals.

DHS shall allow eligible individuals, including minors, to apply for relief without requiring: (1) placement in removal proceedings, or (2) immediate immigrant visa availability.

DHS shall provide a reasonable opportunity to apply for relief under this bill to any alien who: (1) requests such an opportunity, or (2) appears prima facie eligible for relief if the alien is in removal proceedings or is the subject of a final removal or voluntary departure order.

An applicant for permanent resident status shall: (1) submit biometric and biographic data, (2) undergo law enforcement and security background checks and a medical examination, and (3) meet applicable selective service registration requirements.

The Department of Justice may not remove certain individuals who: (1) have a pending application and appear prima facie eligible for relief, (2) have an approved application and are awaiting the availability of an immigrant visa, or (3) are ineligible to apply for relief solely due to the date limitation for applying for adjustment under this bill. DHS shall provide provisional protected status to such individuals whose DACA grant has ended.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
