<bill session="114" type="s" number="1765" updated="2018-06-02T06:57:39Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LGBT Elder Americans Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Older Americans Act of 1965 to provide equal treatment of LGBT older individuals, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">LGBT Elder Americans Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001267"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2015-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2015-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3793"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">LGBT Elder Americans Act of 2015

Amends the Older Americans Act of 1965 to include LGBT individuals (lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgendered individuals) within the purview of such Act, particularly their status as LGBT individuals among those with the greatest social need.

Authorizes the Administration of Aging to: (1) designate within it a person with responsibility for addressing issues affecting LGBT older individuals; (2) conduct studies and collect data to determine the services needed by LGBT older individuals; and (3) establish and operate the National Resource Center on Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgendered Aging.

Revises the list of activities of national significance for families and other caregivers, for which the Administration's grants may be used, to specify those provided to individuals with greatest social need which: (1) address physical and mental health, disabilities, and health disparities; (2) provide long-term care, including in-home and community-based care; (3) provide informal care and formal care in a facility setting; (4) provide access to culturally responsive health and human services; and (5) address other gaps in assistance and issues of particular importance to older individuals with the greatest social need.

Requires a State Long-Term Care Ombudsman to collect and analyze discrimination data with respect to LGBT older individuals in the admission to, transfer or discharge from, or lack of adequate care provided in long-term care settings.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
