<bill session="114" type="h" number="643" updated="2018-06-02T02:18:44Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Education Survey Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to enter into a contract with a non-government entity to conduct a survey of individuals who have used or are using their entitlement to educational assistance under the educational assistance programs administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Veterans Education Survey Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001257"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000296" joined="2015-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000368" joined="2015-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2921"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-02T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans Education Survey Act of 2015

Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to enter into a contract with a non-government entity to conduct a survey of a statistically valid sample of individuals who have used or are using their entitlement to veterans educational assistance to pursue a program of education or training.

Requires: (1) the survey to be submitted to the Senate and House Veterans' Affairs Committees not later than one month before the collection of data begins, and (2) the entity to conduct the survey electronically or by other appropriate means and to complete the survey and submit the results to the Secretary not later than 180 days after entering into the contract.

Requires the survey to be designed to collect specified types of information about each individual surveyed, including: (1) demographic information, including the highest level of education completed, military occupational specialties while serving in the Armed Forces, National Guard, or Reserves, and whether the individual has a service-connected disability; (2) the individual's opinion regarding participation in the transition assistance program and the effectiveness of the program; (3) the nature of the individual's experience with the VA's education benefits processing system; and (4) the individual's employment status and whether such status differs from the individual's status prior to enrolling in the program of education or training.

Directs the Secretary to report to the Committees on the results of the survey, including an unedited version of the results submitted, and any recommendations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
