<bill session="114" type="s" number="2143" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:34Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-20">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the authority for the successors and assigns of the Starr-Camargo Bridge Company to maintain and operate a toll bridge across the Rio Grande near Rio Grande City, Texas, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to provide for the authority for the successors and assigns of the Starr-Camargo Bridge Company to maintain and operate a toll bridge across the Rio Grande near Rio Grande City, Texas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7161" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-01-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-02-24">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Inhofe without amendment. With written report No. 114-213.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-02-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="374">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 374.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2016-03-17" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1606" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1606" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-03-18">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-21T14:15:08-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-20">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-05-16T16:40:10-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Royce moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-16T16:40:23-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2397-2399" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-16T16:40:25-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 2143.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote2" datetime="2016-05-16T16:50:47-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2397-2398" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-05-16T16:50:49-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2016-05-18">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2016-05-20" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="114-163" type="public" datetime="2016-05-20">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 114-163.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="3688"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-21T03:59:59Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the Senate reported version is repeated here.)

(Sec. 1) This bill modifies the existing authority for the Starr-Camargo Bridge Company to maintain and operate a toll bridge across the Rio Grande River near Rio Grande City, Texas.

The authority, which currently expires 66 years after completion of the bridge (in 1966), is made permanent and expanded to include the successors or assigns of the company. The bridge must not consist of more than 14 lanes.

The company and its successors and assigns shall have the rights and privileges granted by federal law to the B and P Bridge Company, and may use eminent domain to acquire certain land needed for the bridge, subject to Texas laws and requirements for just compensation and public proceedings.

The company's successors and assigns may fix and charge tolls for transit over the bridge.

Those successors and assigns may also sell, assign, transfer, or mortgage the rights, powers, and privileges conferred on the company by the enacting law, to any public agency, to an international bridge authority or commission, or to a corporation.

Any such corporation may exercise such rights, powers, and privileges (including acquisition by mortgage foreclosure) as if they had been granted by the enacting law directly to the corporation.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-213</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
