<bill session="115" type="h" number="1935" updated="2019-04-18T16:06:29Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to provide for the termination of further retirement coverage for Members of Congress under the Federal Employees' Retirement System, except for the right to continue participating in the Thrift Savings Plan, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Pension Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Pension Reform Act</title>
    <title type="display">Congressional Pension Reform Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000579"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2017-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="4981"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="145"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="322"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Congressional Pension Reform Act 

This bill modifies the Federal Employees Retirement System (FERS) to exclude Members of Congress, except the Vice President, from FERS retirement coverage after the enactment of this bill.

The bill prohibits further government contributions or deductions from a Member's basic pay for deposit in the Treasury to the credit of the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund.

The bill does not affect the rights or benefits of any Member for the period prior to the enactment of this bill, nor does it affect the eligibility of a member to participate in the Thrift Savings Plan.

Members may elect to remain subject to FERS by filing a written election within 90 days after the enactment of this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
