<bill session="114" type="h" number="4464" updated="2019-02-14T22:58:03Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Aviation Research and Development Reauthorization Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that Federal research and development in support of civil aviation remains at the forefront of addressing challenges confronting the Nation's air transportation system, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Federal Aviation Research and Development Reauthorization Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000126"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000290" joined="2016-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000293" joined="2016-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000556" joined="2016-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000563" joined="2016-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Space.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Space and Aeronautics" code="HSSY16" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Noise pollution"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-04T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Aviation R&amp;D Reauthorization Act of 2016

This bill reauthorizes the civil aviation research and development (R&amp;D) program of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) through FY2018.

Department of Transportation (DOT) shall:

 arrange with the National Academies for a comprehensive research survey and strategy over the next decade for FAA civil aviation activities, and develop a Strategic and Integrated Research Plan for an R&amp;D program reflecting survey results. DOT shall also:

 ensure that FAA cybersecurity R&amp;D is constantly updated to reflect the evolving nature of cyber risks and threats, and develop an agencywide threat model. The GAO shall review:

 the effectiveness of the six FAA unmanned aircraft (drone) system test sites and the opportunities for coordinating and integrating the research at them with research by the Center of Excellence on Unmanned Aircraft Systems; and federal government research on aircraft noise levels and its use to inform the DOT noise evaluation processes, adjustments to noise metrics, and development of noise abatement procedures. DOT shall:

 develop an R&amp;D strategy to inform any potential regulatory action regarding the safe integration of evolving drone systems into the National Airspace System, hold at least one workshop to discuss the status of R&amp;D on enhancing general aviation safety, develop a research plan on safety risk assessment methods for development of airport design standards, and develop a plan to implement standards for aircraft cabin air contaminants. The GAO shall review the role of FAA's Research, Engineering, and Development Advisory Committee in advising about:

 the organization, management, and budgetary structure of R&amp;D programs across FAA, and both near-term budget planning and long-term strategic planning for the comprehensive FAA R&amp;D portfolio. DOT shall also arrange for an independent external study to identify the implications that a potential nongovernment U.S. air traffic control system could have on FAA's R&amp;D activities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
