<bill session="115" type="h" number="4914" updated="2019-04-18T16:20:02Z">
  <state datetime="2018-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To better support our early childhood educators and elementary school and secondary school teachers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STRIVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STRIVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting the Teaching profession through Revitalizing Investments in Valuable Educators Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting the Teaching profession through Revitalizing Investments in Valuable Educators Act</title>
    <title type="display">STRIVE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000188"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001037" joined="2018-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000096" joined="2018-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001165" joined="2018-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2018-08-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-02-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Development.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Investment" code="HSED13" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2370"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-02-02T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Supporting the Teaching profession through Revitalizing Investments in Valuable Educators Act or the STRIVE Act

This bill amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide qualifying teachers with a new, incremental&#160;loan-cancellation program. Specifically, with respect to a 12-month period,&#160;the Department of Education (ED) must cancel a specified portion of a borrower's qualifying Federal Direct Loan Program loans if the borrower: (1) has made 12 consecutive on-time monthly payments, (2) is employed in a qualifying teaching position at the time of such cancellation, and (3)&#160;was employed in a qualifying teaching position during the period in which the borrower made the 12 payments.&#160;After&#160;a borrower has received such partial loan&#160;cancellation for&#160;a specified&#160;number of years, ED&#160;must cancel the borrower's eligible loans in full.&#160;&#160;

The bill also:

 increases and extends funding for teacher training; makes changes to the Teacher Education Assistance for College and Higher Education&#160;grant program, including by increasing annual award amounts and&#160;making early childhood teachers eligible for such grants; requires&#160;ED to award grants to states to subsidize teacher certification and licensing fees for low-income individuals who have entered the teaching profession; expands the teacher quality partnership grant program to include early childhood educators; and increases&#160;the tax deduction for school expenses&#160;and extends the deduction&#160;to early childhood educators.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
