<bill session="114" type="h" number="847" updated="2019-04-11T15:42:40Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to invest in innovation for education.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Investing in Innovation for Education Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Investing in Innovation for Education Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000598"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001177" joined="2015-02-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="605"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Investing in Innovation for Education Act of 2015

Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to local educational agencies (LEAs), educational service agencies, and nonprofit organizations that partner with an LEA or consortium of schools to support school innovations.

Requires at least 25% of the grant funds to be awarded for projects in rural areas.

Requires each grant applicant to demonstrate that it has partnered with at least one private entity that will provide matching funds. Allows the Secretary to waive the matching funds requirement upon a showing of exceptional circumstances.

Requires each grant to be used to address at least one of the following areas of school innovation:

 improving the effectiveness and distribution of teachers or principals, strengthening the use of data to improve teaching and learning, providing high-quality instruction that is based on rigorous standards and measuring students' proficiency using high-quality assessments that are aligned to those standards, turning around the lowest-performing schools, supporting the effective use of technology to improve teaching or principals and learning, and any other area of school innovation the Secretary chooses. Directs the Secretary to establish performance measures for tracking each grantee's progress in: (1) improving the academic performance of public elementary and secondary school students, and specified subgroups of those students; and (2) implementing its project in rural schools, as applicable. Requires grantees to use grant funds to develop or expand strategies to improve high-need students' showing on those performance measures.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
