<bill session="115" type="h" number="6653" updated="2019-04-18T16:26:55Z">
  <state datetime="2018-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To encourage the research and use of innovative materials and associated techniques in the construction and preservation of the domestic transportation and water infrastructure system, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IMAGINE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IMAGINE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Innovative Materials for America's Growth and Infrastructure Newly Expanded Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Innovative Materials for America&#8217;s Growth and Infrastructure Newly Expanded Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">IMAGINE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000293"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2018-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2018-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001105" joined="2018-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000560" joined="2018-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001189" joined="2018-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-08-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-08-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Science, Space, and Technology, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-08-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Science, Space, and Technology, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-08-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Science, Space, and Technology, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Highways and Transit" code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3341"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-08-03T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Innovative Materials for America's Growth and Infrastructure Newly Expanded Act of 2018 or the IMAGINE Act

This bill directs the National Institute of Standards and Technology to establish an Interagency Innovative Materials Standards Task Force to coordinate and improve, with respect to infrastructure construction, retrofitting, rehabilitation, and other improvements: (1) federal testing standards, (2) federal design and use guidelines, and (3) other applicable standards.

 The task force shall collaborate with certain nonfederal entities to: (1) identify and carry out appropriate research, testing methods, and processes relating to the development and use of innovative materials; (2) develop new methods and processes relating to the development and use of innovative materials; and (3) contribute to the development of standards and guidelines for the use of innovative materials and approaches in civil infrastructure projects. The term "innovative material," with respect to an infrastructure project, includes high performance asphalt mixtures and concrete formulations, geosynthetic materials, advanced alloys and metals, reinforced polymer composites, including any coating or other corrosion prevention method used in conjunction with those materials, advanced polymers, and any other material or aggregate materials, as determined by the appropriate agency or department head.

The Department of Transportation shall carry out a program to enhance the development of innovative materials in the United States.

The Federal Highway Administration shall establish the Innovative Bridge Program to provide grants for coastal and rural infrastructure bridge projects.

The Environmental Protection Agency shall establish the Water Infrastructure Innovation Program to provide grants for the design and installation of water infrastructure projects.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
