<bill session="115" type="h" number="3027" updated="2019-04-18T16:11:47Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to improve recordkeeping and information sharing with States regarding military training performed by members of the Armed Forces and other skills developed through military service that translate to civilian occupations to expedite the transition of veterans to post-military employment.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing Experienced Returning Veterans Employment Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing Experienced Returning Veterans Employment Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SERVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SERVE Act</title>
    <title type="display">SERVE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000475"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001064" joined="2017-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000188" joined="2017-11-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="4380"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Securing Experienced Returning Veterans Employment Act of 2017 or the SERVE Act

This bill directs that in order to improve the accuracy and completeness of a certification or verification of job skills and experience acquired while on active duty, the Department of Defense (DOD) (and the Department of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy) shall: (1) establish a database to record all training performed by members of the armed forces that may have application to civilian sector employment, (2) make such information that is unclassified available to states and other employers so that they may allow military training to satisfy licensing or certification requirements for civilian professions, and (3) ensure that certifications and verifications of job skills and experience can be confirmed by states and other employers.

A state may use a certification or verification provided to a member of the armed forces and request DOD or the Coast Guard to confirm its accuracy and authenticity. Such information shall be confirmed or denied within five business days.

 A certification or verification provided to a member of the armed forces and accepted by a state to satisfy licensing or certification requirements shall be valid in all states once used in the accepting states.

Pre-separation counseling concerning licensing and certification requirements shall include state-submitted and approved lists of military training and skills that satisfy occupational certifications and licenses.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
