<bill session="114" type="s" number="1336" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:37Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to implement the Convention on the Conservation and Management of the High Seas Fishery Resources in the South Pacific Ocean, as adopted at Auckland on November 14, 2009, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">South Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">South Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act</title>
    <title type="display">South Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2015-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-05-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-04-06">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Thune without amendment. With written report No. 114-235.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-06" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="419">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 419.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4576"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1335"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6452"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-06T12:44:48Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

South Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act

This bill authorizes the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to promulgate regulations to implement U.S. participation in the South Pacific Fisheries Convention. The convention is designed to ensure the long-term conservation and sustainable use of fishery resources and marine ecosystems in the South Pacific Ocean.

(Sec. 3) The United Statesmust be represented by no more than three commissioners on the Commission of the South Pacific Regional Fisheries Management Organisation.

In addition, a permanent advisory committee is established, which shall be comprised of seven members. Advisory committee members shall represent groups concerned with fishery resources covered by the South Pacific Fisheries Convention.

NOAA must develop a memorandum of understanding with the Western Pacific Regional Fishery Management Council describing the role of the council with respect to:

 participation of the United States in consulting with international fishery organizations in the Pacific Ocean, providing recommendations to NOAA and the Department of State regarding domestic and foreign fishing vessels, coordinating with the United States on presentations the council makes to international fishery organizations, and recommending domestic fishing regulations that are consistent with the actions of the international fishery organizations. (Sec. 4)The State Department has the authority to receive and transmit various communications concerning the South Pacific commission, and can approve or disapprove bylaws and rules adopted by the commission.

(Sec. 5) This bill details NOAA's authority in implementing this bill and measures adopted by the commission.

(Sec. 6)NOAA and the U.S. Coast Guard are required to administer and enforce this bill.

(Sec. 7)This bill lists 16 fishing and shipping activities that are prohibited in the South Pacific Ocean.

(Sec. 8)NOAA may cooperate with public and private institutions in the United Statesand abroad to carry out this bill. Federal agencies are authorized to cooperate with NOAA in conducting research and providing facilities and personnel to assist the commission.

(Sec. 9)The State Department must ensure that American Samoa, Guam, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands participate with the commission in the same manner as territories of other nations.

(Sec. 10)Operators of commercial fishing vessels that do not carry vessel monitoring systems capable of communicating with U.S. enforcement authorities must:

 notify the U.S. Coast Guard prior to or within a reasonable time after entering the exclusive economic zone of the convention area; ensure that all fishing gear is stowed below deck and not readily available for fishing; and if requested, proceed to a specified location so that a vessel inspection can be conducted.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-235</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
