<bill session="114" type="s" number="3015" updated="2018-06-02T07:46:04Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">John Thomas Decker Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to direct the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to provide for informational materials to educate and prevent addiction in teenagers and adolescents who are injured playing youth sports and subsequently prescribed an opioid.</title>
    <title type="display">John Thomas Decker Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4969"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5189"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="524"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="School athletics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">John Thomas Decker Act of 2016

This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to report on the availability of information regarding prescription of opioids after youth sports injury, including information on opioid use and misuse, injury treatments that do not involve opioids, and treatment for opioid addiction. (Opioids are drugs with effects similar to opium, such as heroin and certain pain medications.) The report must determine the extent this information is available to teenagers and adolescents who play youth sports, their families, youth sports groups, and health care providers.

Taking into consideration the findings of the report, HHS must develop and disseminate such information.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
