<bill session="114" type="s" number="640" updated="2018-06-02T06:40:29Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ORDEAL Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ozone Regulatory Delay and Extension of Assessment Length Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Clean Air Act to delay the review and revision of the national ambient air quality standards for ozone.</title>
    <title type="display">ORDEAL Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000444"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000542" joined="2015-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2015-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2015-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2015-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2015-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2015-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2015-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2015-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2015-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001141" joined="2015-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2015-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000127" joined="2015-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2015-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-03">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 114-47.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1327"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Ozone Regulatory Delay and Extension of Assessment Length Act of 2015 or the ORDEAL Act of 2015

This bill amends the Clean Air Act to lengthen from 5 years to 10 years the intervals at which the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) is required to review and revise air quality criteria and primary and secondary national ambient air quality standards (NAAQS). This bill eliminates the EPA's authority to review and revise criteria or promulgate new standards for ozone concentrations earlier or more frequently than required. The EPA may not review and revise NAAQS for ozone concentrations before February 1, 2018. The EPA must complete a thorough review of the NAAQS for ozone concentrations and make revisions no later December 31, 2018.

The intervals at which an independent scientific review committee is required to review air quality criteria and NAAQS and recommend any new standards or revisions to existing criteria and standards are lengthened from 5 years to 10 years. The bill delays the review by an independent scientific review committee of NAAQS for ozone concentrations until February 1, 2018.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
