<bill session="114" type="s" number="1078" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:51Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to carry out programs and activities that connect people in the United States, especially children, youth, and families, with the outdoors.</title>
    <title type="display">Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001046"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2014"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2015 

 Authorizes the Department of the Interior to issue an eligible entity a cooperative agreement for each state for the development, implementation, and updating of a five-year Healthy Kids Outdoors State Strategy designed to encourage people in the United States (especially children, youth, and families) to be physically active outdoors.

Requires an entity that receives funding to: (1) update the State Strategy at least once every five years, and (2) provide a 25% match through in-kind contributions or cash.

Requires State Strategies to provide for subgrants to local partners to implement the state strategy through at at least one of specified program activities.

 Directs the President to issue a national strategy for encouraging people to be physically active outdoors.

Directs Interior and the Department of Health and Human Services to carry out a study of national significance on the health impacts of the national strategy and State Strategies.

Requires Interior to provide technical assistance to eligible entities and local partners, and disseminate best practices that emerge from the strategies funded by this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
