<bill session="114" type="s" number="3123" updated="2018-06-02T07:47:00Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United Kingdom Trade Continuity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the continuation with respect to the United Kingdom of existing commercial agreements between the United States and the European Union, to encourage the President to expeditiously negotiate a new comprehensive bilateral trade agreement with the United Kingdom, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">United Kingdom Trade Continuity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000577"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2016-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">United Kingdom Trade Continuity Act

This bill expresses the sense of Congress that the United States supports the decision by the people of the United Kingdom to leave the European Union (EU).

The United States shall continue to comply with the terms of all existing commercial agreements between it and the EU governing commerce between the United States and the United Kingdom, unless specifically provided otherwise.

It is the sense of Congress that the President should initiate negotiations expeditiously with the United Kingdom to reach a final comprehensive bilateral trade agreement.

Trade authorities (fast track) procedures shall apply to a congressional bill implementing such a trade agreement.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
