<bill session="115" type="s" number="3242" updated="2019-04-18T16:44:45Z">
  <state datetime="2018-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an American Savings Account Fund and create a retirement savings plan available to all employees, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Savings Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Savings Act</title>
    <title type="display">American Savings Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001176"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-07-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1083"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Income tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-07-19T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">American Savings Act 

This bill amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) and the Internal Revenue Code to establish a new retirement option for all employees and self-employed individuals to be known as the American Savings Account Fund. This fund operates in a manner similar to the Thrift Savings Fund, which is available to federal employees.

The bill establishes an American Savings Account Board of Directors to establish policies for fund investment and management. The board shall select or establish a list of investment funds and options similar to those in the Thrift Savings Fund, among which participants may choose.

The board shall establish an American Savings Account Fund Advisory Council to advise the board on matters relating to investment policies.

The American Savings Account Fund is tax-exempt and contributions to, or distributions from, it are excludible from gross income.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
