<bill session="114" type="s" number="2330" updated="2018-06-02T07:13:23Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE Check Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strict Alien Firearm Enforcement Check Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to allow the Attorney General additional time to process background checks for alien firearm purchases, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SAFE Check Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-19T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Strict Alien Firearm Enforcement Check Act or the SAFE Check Act

This bill amends the federal criminal code to modify the background check requirements for certain nonimmigrant aliens to purchase firearms in the United States.

Current law permits a licensed gun dealer to transfer a firearm to an unlicensed person, including a nonimmigrant alien lawfully admitted to the United States without a visa, if a submitted background check remains incomplete after three business days.

This bill adds a provision to prohibit a licensed gun dealer from completing a firearm transfer to a nonimmigrant alien lawfully admitted without a visa under the Visa Waiver Program prior to completion of a background check.

Additionally, it requires such background check to review records maintained by the International Criminal Police Organization (i.e., Interpol) and the country that issued the alien's passport.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
