<bill session="115" type="s" number="2323" updated="2019-04-18T16:41:07Z">
  <state datetime="2018-01-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-01-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-01-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill making continuing appropriations for veterans benefits and services in the event of a Government shutdown, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill making continuing appropriations for veterans benefits and services in the event of a Government shutdown, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001041"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-01-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-01-18T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill appropriates for any period during which interim or full-year appropriations for FY2018 are not in effect such sums as are necessary to administer and provide benefits and services to veterans, dependents, and survivors under specified veterans' benefits laws, including those concerning:

 compensation for service-connected disability or death, dependency and indemnity compensation for service-connected deaths, pension for non-service-connected disability or death or for service, benefits for children of certain veterans, specially adapted housing for disabled veterans, burial benefits, certain educational assistance programs, training and rehabilitation for veterans with service-connected disabilities, and automobiles and adaptive equipment for certain disabled veterans and members of the Armed Forces. Such funds shall be available until the earliest of: (1) enactment of an appropriation for any such purpose, (2) enactment of the applicable regular or continuing appropriations resolution or other bill without any appropriation for such purpose, or (3) January 1, 2019.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
