<bill session="114" type="s" number="2017" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:59Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to recognize Alexander Creek, Alaska, as a Native village, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to recognize Alexander Creek, Alaska, as a Native village, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6536" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Small towns"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-09T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill amends the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to recognize Alexander Creek as a Native village. Currently, Alexander Creek is recognized as a Native group. (Under the Act, a Native village is entitled to more land than a Native group.)

Alexander Creek must file any amendments to its corporate charter that are necessary to convert from a Native group to a Native village.

The Department of the Interior must negotiate with Alexander Creek to fairly and equitably settle aboriginal land claims and any other claims against the United States.

Alexander Creek must notify its members that the Cook Inlet regional corporation will make future payments to the village instead of to individual members. The regional corporation is not liable for damages related to cessation of payments to individual members of Alexander Creek.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
