<bill session="114" type="h" number="5383" updated="2018-11-09T00:09:25Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Middle Class College Tuition Tax Credit Expansion Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend and modify the American Opportunity Tax Credit, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Middle Class College Tuition Tax Credit Expansion Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000057"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1260"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="699"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-03T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Middle Class College Tuition Tax Credit Expansion Act of 2016

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to replace the Hope Scholarship and Lifetime Learning tax credits with a new American Opportunity Tax Credit that:

 allows an increased income tax credit for the qualified tuition and related expenses of a student who is carrying at least one half of a normal course load, increases the income threshold for reductions in the credit amount based upon modified adjusted gross income, allows a lifetime dollar limitation on such credit of $25,000 for all taxable years, prohibits taxpayers who have fraudulently or recklessly claimed the credit from receiving the credit during a specified disallowance period, and makes 50% of the credit refundable. The bill also allows an exclusion from gross income of any amount received as a Federal Pell Grant.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
