<bill session="114" type="hr" number="215" updated="2019-04-11T15:41:46Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that any comprehensive plan to reform our national energy policy must promote the sustainable use of renewable and alternative energy sources; increase our domestic refining capacity; promote conservation and increased energy efficiency; expand research and development, including domestic onshore and offshore exploration; and enhance consumer education.</title>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that any comprehensive plan to reform our national energy policy must promote the sustainable use of renewable and alternative energy sources; increase our domestic refining capacity; promote conservation and increased energy efficiency; expand research and development, including domestic onshore and offshore exploration; and enhance consumer education.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000566"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy" code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that, in order to meet our nation's growing long-term energy demands and maintain our economic viability in the world marketplace, any comprehensive and economically viable energy bill must address:

 taking advantage of our abundant domestic coal supply; using recent technological innovations to exploit our vast supply of natural gas; increasing our domestic oil production, infrastructure, and refining capacity; expanding the use of renewable and alternative energy sources; exploring and investing in advanced nuclear reactor technologies; reflecting the discoveries of light sweet crude in the United States and evaluating the capacity and market for extracting and refining it; providing incentives for an increase in conservation and energy efficiency; expanding research and development through new methods such as public-private partnerships; and enhancing consumer awareness and education regarding methods to increase energy efficiency and available alternative fuel sources to reduce America's dependence on Middle Eastern oil and provide energy security.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
