<bill session="114" type="h" number="5669" updated="2019-02-14T22:59:18Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Creating Opportunities for America's Laid-off (COAL) Miners Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide emergency unemployment compensation to coal mining workers who lost their jobs due to Federal environmental regulations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Creating Opportunities for America's Laid-off (COAL) Miners Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000297"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Worker and Family Support" code="HSWM03" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Indiana"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Creating Opportunities for America's Laid-off (COAL) Miners Act of 2016

This bill allows certain states in which the coal mining and related industries have been adversely impacted by regulations promulgated by the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) or the Department of the Interior to enter into and participate in a specified agreement with the Department of Labor.

These states shall include:

 Alabama; Illinois; Indiana; Kentucky; Ohio; Pennsylvania; Tennessee; Virginia; Wyoming; and any other state that has traditionally relied on coal mining for a substantial portion of its economy, and has experienced a significant reduction in coal mining-related activity over five years. The agreement shall require that the state's agency make payments of coal mining emergency unemployment compensation (EUC) to individuals, other than illegal aliens, who:

 have exhausted all rights to regular compensation under the state or federal law for a benefit year (excluding any benefit year that ended before enactment of this bill); have no rights to regular compensation for a week under such law or any other state unemployment compensation law or to compensation under any other federal law; are not receiving compensation for such week under the unemployment compensation law of Canada; and are able to work, available to work, and actively seeking work. A state which enters such an agreement must deliver specified reemployment services and reemployment and eligibility assessment activities to each coal mining EUC recipient while the individual continues to receive such EUC.

The bill requires that, subject to specified conditions, 100% of the coal mining EUC paid to individuals by the state be reimbursed to each such state that enters into the agreement.

Funds in the extended unemployment compensation account of the Unemployment Trust Fund shall be used for making payments to these states.

This bill prescribes penalties for an individual who commits fraud resulting in overpayment of coal mining EUC.

No compensation under this bill shall be payable following 24 months after its enactment.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
