<bill session="114" type="h" number="2387" updated="2019-05-09T23:32:59Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to provide for equitable allotment of land to Alaska Native veterans.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Alaska Native Veterans Land Allotment Equity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alaska Native Veterans Land Allotment Equity Act</title>
    <title type="display">Alaska Native Veterans Land Allotment Equity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22">
      <text>Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-09-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-11-22">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 114-832.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-11-22" calendar="Union" number="653">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 653.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indigenous Peoples of the United States" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="1955"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3004"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3273"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-11-22T12:44:52Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">Alaska Native Veterans Land Allotment Equity Act

 (Sec. 2) This bill amends the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (ANCSA) to declare that any allotment application pending before the Department of the Interior on December 18, 1971, that was closed by Interior pursuant to the civil action Shields v. United States shall be reopened and considered to be approved.

(Sec. 3) The bill revises the eligibility of Alaska Native Vietnam veterans for an allotment. Eligibility for allotments is extended to veterans who served between August 5, 1964, and May 7, 1975.

Eligible persons may file for allotments of up to two parcels of federal land (as under current law) totaling up to 160 acres.

The bill eliminates the limitation of these allotments to lands that were vacant, unappropriated, and unreserved on the date when the person eligible for the allotment first used and occupied them.

Allotments may be selected from vacant federal lands or lands that have been selected by or conveyed to the state of Alaska or a Native corporation, if the state or corporation voluntarily relinquishes or conveys the land to the United States for allotment.

The lands excluded from allotment are revised to: (1) lands in the right-of-way of the TransAlaska Pipeline; (2) the inner or outer corridor of such a right-of-way; or (3) a unit of the National Park System, a National Preserve, or a National Monument.

 The heir of a deceased eligible veteran, regardless of the cause of death, may apply for and receive an allotment.

Persons who made an allotment selection under ANCSA and were not conveyed the allotment before enactment of this bill may reselect land.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-832</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
