<amendment session="114" chamber="h" number="85" updated="2018-06-03T21:09:33Z">
  <amends type="hc" number="27" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2015-03-25T18:17:35-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000591"/>
  <offered datetime="2015-03-25"/>
  <description>Amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in House Report 114-49 and numbered 5 was offered as the Budget Committe mark substitute.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment in the nature of a substitute numbered 5 printed in House Report 114-49 that is identical to the reported resolution.The total level of new budget authority for the Overseas Contingency Operations/Global War on Terrorism function (Function 970) remains at $94 billion in Fiscal Year 2016. The amendment also retains a deficit-neutral reserve fund for Overseas Contingency Operations/Global War on Terrorism in section 513. This section permits the Chair of the Committee on the Budget to adjust the 302(a) allocations to the Committee on Appropriations, and other appropriate levels, for any appropriations measure that provides new budget authority for Overseas Contingency Operations in excess of $73.5 billion up to $94 billion in Fiscal Year 2016.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2015-03-25T18:17:35-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="140">
      <text>On agreeing to the Price, Tom amendment (A005) Failed by recorded vote: 105 - 319 (Roll no. 140).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25T16:54:33-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A005) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mr. Price, Tom.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1983-1998, H2017-2018" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1983-1997" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25"/>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25T18:17:35-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25T18:17:35-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25T18:17:35-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Price, Tom amendment (A005) Failed by recorded vote: 105 - 319 (Roll no. 140).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25T16:54:33-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A005) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mr. Price, Tom.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1983-1998, H2017-2018" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1983-1997" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
