<bill session="115" type="h" number="5463" updated="2019-04-18T16:21:45Z">
  <state datetime="2018-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a credit against income tax for equity investments in research intensive small business concerns, to provide for the proper tax treatment of personal service income earned in pass-thru entities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Creating Tech Startup Jobs Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Creating Tech Startup Jobs Act</title>
    <title type="display">Creating Tech Startup Jobs Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2018-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2018-08-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-04-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2295"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1020"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-04-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Creating Tech Startup Jobs Act 

This bill allows several tax credits for a qualified research intensive small business concern, which is a small business that is not over 10 years old, has fewer than 100 employees, and spends at least 30% of its gross expenditures on research or experimental expenditures.

For a qualified research intensive small business concern, the bill allows

 a research intensive investment credit for taxpayers who acquire an equity investment in the business, a research employment credit for a portion of the first-year research wages that the business pays to full-time research employees, and a research expenditure credit for a portion of the research or experimental expenditures of the business. The bill also (1) sets forth a special rule for the inclusion in gross income of partnership interests transferred in connection with the performance of services, and (2) modifies the tax treatment of partners who provide investment management services to partnerships.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
