<bill session="114" type="h" number="3570" updated="2018-11-09T00:09:06Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STEM Education Opportunity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide incentives for education in the areas of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.</title>
    <title type="display">STEM Education Opportunity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000057" joined="2015-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Behavioral sciences"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Social Sciences and History"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">STEM Education Opportunity Act

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow: (1) individual taxpayers a deduction from gross income for STEM (i.e., science, technology, engineering, and mathematics) higher education expenses; and (2) a business-related tax credit for contributions of STEM&#160;property (e.g., computer equipment&#160;and software, microscopes, and lab equipment), services, and training&#160;made to an elementary or secondary school&#160;to promote education in the biological sciences, mathematics, earth and physical sciences, computer and information science, engineering, geosciences, and social and behavioral sciences. The bill defines "STEM higher education expenses" to include any expenses incurred by an individual attending an institution of higher education who is majoring in science, technology, engineering, or mathematics.

The Government Accountability Office must submit to Congress a report detailing: (1) the efficacy of this Act in increasing higher education enrollment in the fields of mathematics, science, engineering, and technology; and (2) any effect&#160;this Act has had on the price of higher education tuition in such fields.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
