<bill session="113" type="s" number="2930" updated="2016-10-25T16:32:41Z">
  <state datetime="2014-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clay Hunt SAV Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clay Hunt Suicide Prevention for American Veterans Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide for the conduct of an evaluation of mental health care and suicide prevention programs of the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs, to require a pilot program on loan repayment for psychiatrists who agree to serve in the Veterans Health Administration of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Clay Hunt SAV Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000303"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2014-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001265" joined="2014-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2014-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2014-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2014-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2014-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000607" joined="2014-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000444" joined="2014-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2014-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2014-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000291" joined="2014-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2014-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2014-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2014-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2014-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2014-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2014-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2014-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2014-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001141" joined="2014-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="5059"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-11-17T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Clay Hunt Suicide Prevention for American Veterans Act or the Clay Hunt SAV Act - Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) and the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to each arrange for an independent third party evaluation of, respectively, the VA and DOD mental health care and suicide prevention programs.

Directs the VA Secretary to publish an Internet website that serves as a centralized source to provide veterans with regularly updated information regarding all of the VA's mental health care services.

Requires the VA Secretary and the DOD Secretary to enter into certain strategic relationships to facilitate:

 the mental health referrals of members of the reserve components who have a service-connected disability and are being discharged or released from the Armed Forces, timely behavioral health services for such members, communication when such members are at risk for behavioral health reasons, and the transfer of documentation for line-of-duty and fitness-for-duty determinations. Requires the VA Secretary to carry out a three-year pilot program to repay the education loans relating to psychiatric medicine that are incurred by individuals who:

 are eligible to practice psychiatric medicine in the Veterans Health Administration (VHA) or are enrolled in the final year of a residency program leading to a specialty qualification in psychiatric medicine, demonstrate a commitment to a long-term career as a psychiatrist in the VHA, and agree to a period of obligated service with the VHA in the field of psychiatric medicine in exchange for the repayment of such loans. Requires the DOD Secretary to submit to Congress a review of the staffing requirements for individual State National Guard Commands with respect to Directors of Psychological Health.

Authorizes the VA Secretary to collaborate with nonprofit mental health organizations to prevent suicide among veterans. Requires the collaborators to exchange training sessions, best practices, and other resources to enhance their suicide prevention efforts. Directs the Secretary to select a Director of Suicide Prevention Coordination within the VA to undertake any collaboration with nonprofit mental health organizations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
