<bill session="113" type="h" number="2227" updated="2018-06-05T16:25:40Z">
  <state datetime="2013-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the response to and prevention of sexual assaults involving members of the Armed Forces.</title>
    <title type="display">To improve the response to and prevention of sexual assaults involving members of the Armed Forces.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000184"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-06-03T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Directs the Secretary of Defense to: (1) review practices of the military criminal investigative organizations regarding the investigation of alleged sex-related offenses involving members of the Armed Forces (members), and (2) develop a uniform policy regarding the use of case determinations to record the results of such investigations.

Amends the Ike Skelton National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2011 to direct the Secretary to establish minimum standards for: (1) the qualifications necessary for members or civilian employees of the Department of Defense (DOD) to be selected as a sexual assault response and prevention program manager, sexual assault response coordinator, or sexual assault victim advocate; and (2) the training, certification, and status of such members and employees assigned to such positions.

Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 to require the Secretary, by June 30, 2014, to develop a uniform curriculum to provide sexual assault prevention and response training for members and civilian DOD employees. Requires such curriculum to include lesson plans to achieve core competencies and learning objectives.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
