<bill session="114" type="s" number="2542" updated="2018-06-02T07:14:52Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cradle Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for alternative and updated certification requirements for participation under Medicaid State plans under title XIX of the Social Security Act in the case of certain facilities treating infants under one year of age with neonatal abstinence syndrome, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Cradle Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001047"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2016-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="3865"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-11T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Cradle Act

This bill amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to allow for alternative certification requirements for a residential pediatric recovery center to participate in a state Medicaid program. A "residential pediatric recovery center" is a facility that treats infants with neonatal abstinence syndrome (NAS), which is caused by exposure to opioids before birth.

With respect to certifying such facilities, the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid must establish guidelines that: (1)&#160;include requirements specifically applicable to treating infants with NAS, and (2) take into account that certain requirements needed for centers that treat adults may not be necessary for facilities that treat such infants. A residential pediatric recovery center&#160;may satisfy the requirements set forth in these guidelines in lieu of any comparable requirements otherwise applicable for purposes of the center's participation&#160;under a state Medicaid program.

A&#160;facility licensed by a state as a residential pediatric recovery center shall be treated as&#160;having satisfied&#160;certification requirements for participation under&#160;the Medicaid program for that state.&#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
