<bill session="115" type="s" number="2989" updated="2019-04-18T16:43:41Z">
  <state datetime="2018-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Food Security Act of 1985 to encourage soil health, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Conservation for Very Erodible Row Cropland Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Conservation for Very Erodible Row Cropland Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COVER Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COVER Act</title>
    <title type="display">COVER Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001267"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-06-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing and promotion"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-06-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Conservation for Very Erodible Row Cropland Act of 2018 or the COVER Act 

This bill amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to modify Department of Agriculture (USDA) conservation programs to authorize additional assistance for farm practices related to soil health and carbon storage.

The bill modifies the Environmental Quality Incentives Program to require USDA to provide payments under the program for practices that:

 improve soil health, enhance the ability of a farmer to absorb and recover from shocks and stresses to production, increase the storage of carbon on agricultural land, and achieve other conservation outcomes determined by USDA. The bill modifies the Conservation Innovation Grants program to establish a pilot program to provide payments to encourage: (1) the measurement of outcomes relating to the planting of a regionally appropriate cover crop, and (2) opportunities to increase farm income. In carrying out the program, USDA must prioritize certain projects with third-party partners such as academic entities, carbon offset protocol developers, livestock producers, and food manufacturers.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
