<bill session="113" type="h" number="4907" updated="2016-10-25T16:14:18Z">
  <state datetime="2014-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Global Respect Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To impose sanctions with respect to foreign persons responsible for gross violations of internationally recognized human rights against lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender (LGBT) individuals, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Global Respect Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2014-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000179" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000462" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2014-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001185" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001191" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000486" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2014-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001175" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000808" joined="2014-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-06-19T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Global Respect Act - Directs the President to submit to Congress a list of each foreign person that the President determines is responsible, or acted as an agent, for extrajudicial killings, torture, or other gross violations of internationally recognized human rights committed against an individual in a foreign country based on actual or perceived sexual orientation or gender identity.

Makes a listed foreign person ineligible to enter or be admitted to the United States. Requires revocation of any visa issued for such person.

Authorizes the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to waive such prohibition if in U.S. national security interests or if necessary for compliance with the Agreement between the United Nations (U.N.) and the United States regarding the U.N. Headquarters. Requires congressional notification prior to any such waiver.

Directs the Assistant Secretary for Democracy, Human Rights and Labor to designate a senior officer or officers to track violence, criminalization, and restrictions on fundamental freedoms in foreign countries based on actual or perceived sexual orientation or gender identity.

Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to include information on sexual orientation or gender identity violence or restrictions in the annual country reports on human rights practices.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
