<bill session="114" type="s" number="1796" updated="2018-08-16T23:01:10Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">WIC Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wise Investment in our Children Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to increase the age of eligibility for children to receive benefits under the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children and to allow States to certify infants for participation in that program for a period of 2 years, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">WIC Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2015-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2015-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2015-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2015-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2015-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2660"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Wise Investment in our Children Act of 2015 or the WIC Act 

This bill amends the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 and title XIX of the Social Security Act (Medicaid) to permit the age limit for children participating in the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC) to be increased from five to six if a state agency determines it is necessary to accommodate the unique circumstances of an individual child. The bill also permits states to certify infants (under one year of age) participating in the program for a period of up to two years.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
