<bill session="114" type="s" number="3363" updated="2018-06-02T07:48:18Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act for the Defense of Israel, 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill making emergency supplemental appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2016, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act for the Defense of Israel, 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000359"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2016-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2016-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2016-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2016-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2016-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2016-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act for the Defense of Israel, 2016 

This bill provides FY2016 emergency supplemental appropriations to the Department of Defense (DOD) and for the Foreign Military Financing Program to assist Israel in addressing security threats from Iran.

The bill provides funding to DOD for Procurement and Research, Development, Test, and Evaluation to provide to the government of Israel for the procurement of missile defense systems to address security threats from Iran, subject to previously established transfer procedures and in accordance with U.S-Israeli production agreements.

The bill also provides funding to the President for the Foreign Military Financing Program for assistance for Israel to address security threats from Iran.

The funds provided by this bill are designated as an emergency requirement, which exempts the funds from discretionary spending limits and other budget enforcement rules. The funds are only available if the President subsequently designates the amounts as emergency spending and transmits the designations to Congress.

The bill amends the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 to reauthorize sanctions against Iran until December 31, 2031. (Under current law, the sanctions expire on December 31, 2016.)</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
