<bill session="114" type="s" number="2133" updated="2018-06-04T21:15:06Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-30">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fraud Reduction and Data Analytics Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Fraud Reduction and Data Analytics Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Fraud Reduction and Data Analytics Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Fraud Reduction and Data Analytics Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Fraud Reduction and Data Analytics Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve Federal agency financial and administrative controls and procedures to assess and mitigate fraud risks, and to improve Federal agencies' development and use of data analytics for the purpose of identifying, preventing, and responding to fraud, including improper payments.</title>
    <title type="display">Fraud Reduction and Data Analytics Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2015-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2015-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2015-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2015-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2015-10-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-10-07" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-03-15">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson without amendment. With written report No. 114-229.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-03-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="391">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 391.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-04-12">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1981" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2016-04-12" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1981" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-04-13">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-13T12:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-13T14:10:54-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-21T16:24:02-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hurd (TX) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-21T16:24:09-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3999-4000" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3999" label="text as received in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-21T16:24:14-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 2133.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote2" datetime="2016-06-21T16:32:33-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-06-21T16:32:35-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2016-06-23">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2016-06-30" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="114-186" type="public" datetime="2016-06-30">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 114-186.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4180"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3011"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3684"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2016-07-01T03:59:59Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on April 12, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Fraud Reduction and Data Analytics Act of 2015

(Sec. 3) This bill requires the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to establish guidelines for federal agencies to establish financial and administrative controls to identify and assess fraud risks and design and implement control activities in order to prevent, detect, and respond to fraud, including improper payments.

The guidelines shall incorporate the leading practices identified in the report published by the Government Accountability Office on July 28, 2015, entitled "Framework for Managing Fraud Risks in Federal Programs."

The financial and administrative controls shall include:

 conducting an evaluation of fraud risks and using a risk-based approach to design and implement financial and administrative control activities to mitigate identified fraud risks; collecting and analyzing data from reporting mechanisms on detected fraud to monitor fraud trends and using that data and information to continuously improve fraud prevention controls; and using the results of monitoring, evaluation, audits, and investigations to improve fraud prevention, detection, and response. Each agency shall submit as part of its annual financial report a report on its progress in:

 implementing such financial and administrative controls, the fraud risk principle in the Standards for Internal Control in the Federal Government, and OMB Circular A-123 leading practices for managing fraud risk; identifying risks and vulnerabilities to fraud; and establishing steps to curb fraud. (Sec. 4) The OMB must establish a working group to: (1) improve the sharing of financial and administrative controls and other best practices and techniques for detecting, preventing, and responding to fraud, and the sharing and development of data analytics techniques; and (2) submit a plan for a federal interagency library of data analytics and data sets for use by agencies and Offices of Inspectors General to facilitate the detection, prevention, and recovery of fraud.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-229</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
