<bill session="114" type="h" number="5834" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:46Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cell Phone Theft Prevention Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit mobile service providers from providing service on smart phones that have been reported stolen, to require smart phones to be equipped with anti-theft functionality and mobile device identification numbers, and to prohibit the alteration or removal of mobile device identification numbers of smart phones, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Cell Phone Theft Prevention Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000179"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2016-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Cell Phone Theft Prevention Act of 2016 

This bill amends the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit commercial mobile or data service providers from providing service on smart phones that: (1) have been reported to such provider as stolen by an authorized user, or (2) are listed as stolen on the Central Equipment Identity Register (CEIR). When a smart phone is reported stolen to a service provider, the provider must notify the CEIR with information necessary to identify the phone.

Smart phones must be equipped with: (1) preloaded antitheft functionality at no additional cost to purchasers, or be capable of downloading such functionality at no cost; and (2) a mobile device identification number.

A criminal penalty is established for anyone who violates prohibitions against: (1) removing, obliterating, tampering with, or altering a smart phone's mobile device identification number; (2) using, producing, trafficking in, having control or custody of, or possessing hardware or software, knowing it has been configured to engage in such identification number removal or alteration violations; or (3) selling a smart phone for which the identification number is listed as stolen on the CEIR.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
