<bill session="115" type="s" number="3118" updated="2019-04-18T16:44:16Z">
  <state datetime="2018-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to specify and clarify mens rea requirements for certain Federal crimes and to establish the National Criminal Justice Commission.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mens Rea Reform Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mens Rea Reform Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Mens Rea Reform Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2018-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-06-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1607"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1886"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="573"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1902"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-06-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Mens Rea Reform Act of 2018

This bill establishes the National Criminal Justice Commission to conduct a comprehensive review of the criminal justice system; make recommendations for criminal justice reform; and disseminate findings and guidance to the federal government and to state, local, and tribal governments.

Additionally, the bill amends the federal criminal code to establish a default mens rea (i.e., guilty mind) requirement for federal criminal statutory and regulatory offenses that lack a state of mind requirement.

For a new criminal statutory or regulatory offense, the government must prove that a defendant acted willfully with respect to each element of the offense that lacks a specific state of mind requirement.

For an existing criminal statutory or regulatory offense, the bill establishes requirements for the Department of Justice, executive agencies, and the National Criminal Justice Commission with respect to determining the applicable state of mind requirement.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
