<bill session="114" type="h" number="2933" updated="2018-06-02T04:36:10Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">At-Grade Crossing Enhancement Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to establish a local rail facilities and safety program to award grants for freight capacity projects, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">At-Grade Crossing Enhancement Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000560"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000617" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000127" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2015-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2410"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3064"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">At-Grade Crossing Enhancement Act of 2015

This bill directs the Federal Railroad Administration to establish a local rail facilities and safety program to mitigate the impacts of railroad operations in local communities through improvements to highway-rail grade crossings, rail line relocation and improvement projects, and training and technical assistance to local governments. In carrying out the program, the Administration may award grants to eligible entities for freight capacity projects.

The bill defines "eligible entity" to mean one or more states, an Interstate Compact, a local government, a tribal government, or one or more metropolitan planning organizations.

A grant awarded under the program may be used for:

 a capital project to mitigate the impacts of rail infrastructure and operations on a local community; a capital project to improve short-line railroad infrastructure; training and technical assistance to help local governments better understand how to coordinate with railroad carriers on operations and safety issues and on the integration of railroad issues into land use and transportation planning processes; and payment of all or a portion of the subsidy and administrative costs of projects eligible for federal credit assistance under the Railroad Revitalization and Regulatory Reform Act of 1976 for a capital project to improve short-line railroad infrastructure.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
