<bill session="114" type="h" number="4568" updated="2018-08-16T22:57:54Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cooperative Research and Development Fund Authorization Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To make funds available to the Department of Energy National Laboratories for the Federal share of cooperative research and development agreements that support maturing Laboratory technology and transferring it to the private sector, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Cooperative Research and Development Fund Authorization Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000570"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000580" joined="2016-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2016-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy" code="HSSY20" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-12T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Cooperative Research and Development Fund Authorization Act of 2016

 This bill directs the Department of Energy (DOE) to make funds available to DOE national laboratories for the federal cost share of cooperative research and development agreements that support the maturing of laboratory technology and the transferring of it to the private sector. 

 DOE shall: (1) determine the apportionment of such funds to each DOE national laboratory; (2) ensure that special consideration is given to small business firms and consortia involving such firms in the selection of which agreements will receive such funds; and (3) ensure that the performance evaluation metrics of each laboratory's operating contractor provide incentives for, and measure the effectiveness of, such contractor's cooperative research and development agreement program at maturing laboratory technology and transferring it to the private sector.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
