<bill session="115" type="h" number="4266" updated="2019-06-17T18:21:00Z">
  <state datetime="2018-03-13T17:32:08-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-03-13T17:32:08-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-11-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To clarify the boundary of Acadia National Park, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Acadia National Park Boundary Clarification Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Acadia National Park Boundary Clarification Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Acadia National Park Boundary Clarification Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Acadia National Park Boundary Clarification Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Acadia National Park Boundary Clarification Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Acadia National Park Boundary Clarification Act</title>
    <title type="display">Acadia National Park Boundary Clarification Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000611"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2017-11-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-11-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-12">
      <text>Subcommittee on Federal Lands Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-12-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-01-25">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 115-526.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-01-25" calendar="Union" number="391">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 391.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-03-13T17:20:01-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Curtis moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-13T17:20:19-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1518-1520" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-13T17:20:20-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4266.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2018-03-13T17:32:08-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1518" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-03-13T17:32:10-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="2102"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="763"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="257"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Maine"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-11-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Acadia National Park Boundary Clarification Act

This bill confirms that the boundary of Acadia National Park in Maine includes approximately 1,441 acres of land and interests in the Schoodic Peninsula.

The bill ratifies and approves:

 the acquisition by the United States of such land and interests, effective as of September 26, 2013; and any alteration of such land or interests held or claimed by the United State that occurred after such date. The Department of the Interior may make technical boundary and limited boundary revisions, as appropriate, to the permanent boundaries of the park (including any park property located within the peninsula and Isle Au Haut districts) to resolve issues resulting from causes such as survey error or changed road alignments or to take into account acquisitions or losses of land adjacent to or within the park in any case in which the total acreage of the land to be so acquired or lost is less than 10 acres, subject to specified conditions.

Interior shall contribute a specified amount to a regional consortium composed of units of local government on or in the vicinity of Mount Desert Island that was established to improve the management of the disposal and recycling of solid waste.

Interior shall reestablish and appoint members to the Acadia National Park Advisory Commission.

 Certain land in the park that was conveyed by Interior to the town of Tremont, Maine, shall no longer be used exclusively for school purposes, but for public purposes, subject to the conditions that: (1) use of such land shall not degrade or adversely impact the park's resources or values; and (2) such land shall remain in public ownership for recreational, educational, or similar public purposes.

 Interior shall allow for the traditional harvesting of the marine worms, clams, and other shellfish, and other marine species in accordance with the laws of the state of Maine: (1) within the park's boundaries, and (2) on any land outside of the park in which Interior has or obtains a property interest.

Interior shall convey to the town of Bar Harbor a specified parcel of land within the park to be used for a solid waste transfer facility.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-526</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
