<bill session="114" type="h" number="2088" updated="2018-08-16T23:01:09Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-09T15:11:56-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-06-09T15:11:56-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Grain Standards Act Reauthorization Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">United States Grain Standards Act Reauthorization Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">United States Grain Standards Act Reauthorization Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the United States Grain Standards Act to improve inspection services performed at export elevators at export port locations, to reauthorize certain authorities of the Secretary of Agriculture under such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">United States Grain Standards Act Reauthorization Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001087" joined="2015-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000258" joined="2015-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000799" joined="2015-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-04-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-05-29">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Agriculture. H. Rept. 114-133.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-05-29" calendar="Union" number="96">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 96.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-06-09T15:02:37-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Conaway moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-09T15:02:46-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3926-3929" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-09T15:02:48-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2088.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2015-06-09T15:11:56-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3926-3928" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-06-09T15:12:02-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural trade"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Grain"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-09T13:22:55Z" status="Passed House amended">United States Grain Standards Act Reauthorization Act of 2015 

This bill reauthorizes and amends provisions of the United States Grain Standards Act. The Act authorizes the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish official marketing standards for grains, and to provide procedures for grain inspection and weighing. The bill reauthorizes several expiring provisions through FY2020, provides a safeguard mechanism in the event of an interruption of inspection services, revises the process for delegating inspections to state agencies, and revises fees for inspection and weighing services.

(Sec. 2) The bill amends the purposes of the Act to include: promoting the marketing of high quality grain responsive to the purchase specifications of domestic and foreign buyers; and providing an accurate, reliable, consistently available, and cost-effective official grain inspection and weighing system.

The bill revises USDA's discretionary authority to waive weighing and inspection requirements in emergency circumstances to require a waiver in an emergency or major disaster. Transfers of grain into an export elevator by any mode of transportation are not required to be officially weighed.

The bill ends the permanent delegation to state agencies to carry out export inspection and weighing services. USDA must review current delegations, provide public notice and a comment period, establish an application process, and require states to reapply for delegated status after five years.

Official inspection services must be provided in an uninterrupted manner except in the case of a major disaster. In the event of a disruption, the bill sets forth procedures and requirements for resuming official inspection and weighing services.

USDA may waive the geographic boundaries for designated agencies if adjacent agencies have agreed to waive the boundaries.

The bill changes the fee calculation for inspection and weighing services and extends the authority to collect fees through FY2020.

The duration of licenses for inspectors is extended from three to five years, and the qualifications for inspectors are revised.

The bill extends the limitation on total administrative and supervisory costs, the authorization of appropriations, and the authorization of the advisory committee through FY2020.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-133</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
