<bill session="115" type="h" number="4029" updated="2019-07-19T23:27:28Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-10-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Education to make reasonable adjustments to earnings data for graduates of cosmetology gainful employment programs.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accurate Income Measure Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accurate Income Measure Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AIM Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AIM Act</title>
    <title type="display">AIM Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001175"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000188" joined="2017-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000594" joined="2017-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000017" joined="2017-10-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-10-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-10-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Accurate Income Measure Act of 2017 or the AIM Act

This bill requires the Department of Education (ED) to revise gainful employment regulations that require career training programs to meet minimum thresholds with respect to the debt-to-income rates of their graduates. Specifically, the bill requires ED to ensure that those regulations account for estimated underreporting of earned income by graduates of career training programs in cosmetology and related personal grooming arts, holistic health, or massage therapy.

Cosmetology, holistic health, and massage therapy career training programs may appeal a zone or failing debt-to-earning rate by submitting alternative earnings data based on the most current Bureau of Labor Statistics earnings data for the Standard Occupational Classification code.

Until the date on which ED issues adjustments to its gainful employment regulations, the bill: (1) exempts those programs from the regulations, (2) bans ED from publishing final debt-to-earnings rates for those programs, (3) exempts institutions of higher education that provide those programs from a requirement to report the rates on consumer disclosures relating to gainful employment, and (4) prohibits ED from making those programs ineligible for federal financial aid funds due to the application of the regulations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
