<bill session="114" type="h" number="479" updated="2018-11-21T20:30:39Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Jobs Matter Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to require contracting officers to consider information regarding domestic employment before awarding a Federal defense contract, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">American Jobs Matter Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000293"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001286" joined="2015-01-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="26"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-22T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">American Jobs Matter Act of 2015

Requires an executive agency to include the effects on employment within the United States (a jobs impact statement) in the evaluation factors that must be considered in each solicitation for competitive proposals for contracts in excess of $1 million for the procurement of: (1) manufactured goods, (2) goods or services listed in a required report of industrial base capabilities, or (3) any item procured as part of a major defense acquisition program.

Allows an offeror's jobs impact statement to include a guarantee that jobs created or retained in the United States will not be moved outside the United States after award of the contract unless doing so is required to provide the goods or services stipulated in the contract or is in the best interest of the federal government.

Requires each agency to: (1) assess, annually, the accuracy of such a statement submitted by an offeror awarded a contract; and (2) track the number of jobs created or retained during the performance of such contract. Allows the agency, if the number of jobs created or retained falls short of agency estimates, to consider this as a factor that affects a contractor's past performance in the award of future contracts.

Requires: (1) the Secretary of Defense to report annually on the frequency of use within the Department of Defense of jobs impact statements in the evaluation of competitive proposals, and (2) revision of the Department of Defense Supplement to the Federal Acquisition Regulation to implement this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
