<bill session="114" type="h" number="3617" updated="2019-02-06T22:37:43Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IMAGE Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving All Government Efficiency Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve efficiency by consolidating some duplicative and overlapping Government programs.</title>
    <title type="display">IMAGE Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000546"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Improving All Government Efficiency Act of 2015 or the IMAGE Act of 2015 

This bill directs the Office of Management and Budget to coordinate with the heads of relevant federal departments or agencies to: (1) use available administrative authority to eliminate, consolidate, or streamline programs and agencies with duplicative and overlapping missions as identified in specified Government Accountability Office reports released between 2013 and 2015; (2) identify and report to Congress any legislative changes required to further eliminate, consolidate, or streamline duplicative or overlapping missions identified in such reports; (3) estimate the total cost savings from such activities; and (4) rescind from amounts made available to such departments and agencies the total estimated cost savings.

The bill imposes a monetary penalty on any department or agency that does not meet the requirements of this Act before September 30, 2015.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
