<bill session="114" type="h" number="4716" updated="2019-04-11T15:42:42Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to support teacher and school professional training on awareness of student mental health conditions and suicide prevention efforts.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">S.O.S. Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Support Our Students Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="display">S.O.S. Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001281"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational guidance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Support Our Students Act of 2016 or the S.O.S. Act of 2016

This bill amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Department of Education (ED) to award grants to states and, through them, subgrants to local educational agencies (LEAs) to support or develop programs that will train teachers, school personnel, and specialized instructional support personnel regarding mental health conditions in children.

To be&#160;eligible to receive such a&#160;grant or subgrant, a state or LEA must partner with a mental health organization, family advocacy organization, or community nonprofit organization.

Subgrantees shall utilize school counselors, school psychologists, school social workers, or community organizations with experience in mental illness and suicide prevention to develop and conduct the training.

The training program must include an annual in-service training component that enables teachers, school personnel, and specialized instructional support personnel to: (1) better understand mental health conditions and the early warning signs in children and adolescents; (2) effectively communicate their mental health concerns with families and consider family perspectives; (3) identify classroom strategies for working effectively with troubled children; and (4) understand school-specific information, including links to mental health services and supports in the school and community.

ED shall&#160;develop outcome measures for in-depth evaluation of the effectiveness of the training programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
