<bill session="114" type="s" number="454" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:55Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Exascale Computing for Science, Competitiveness, Advanced Manufacturing, Leadership, and the Economy Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ExaSCALE Computing Leadership Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Department of Energy High-End Computing Revitalization Act of 2004 to improve the high-end computing research and development program of the Department of Energy, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">ExaSCALE Computing Leadership Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000360"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2015-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2016-01-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-09">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Biological and life sciences"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Materials"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-11T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Exascale Computing for Science, Competitiveness, Advanced Manufacturing, Leadership, and the Economy Act of 2015 or the ExaSCALE Computing Leadership Act of 2015

 Renames the Department of Energy High-End Computing Revitalization Act of 2004 as the Exascale Computing for Science, Competitiveness, Advanced Manufacturing, Leadership, and the Economy Act of 2015.

Defines "exascale computing" as computing through the use of a computing machine that performs near or above 10 to the 18th power floating point operations per second.

Directs the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to:

 conduct a research program to develop exascale computing machine architectures to promote DOE missions; establish national laboratory partnerships with industry partners and institutions of higher education (IHEs) for the research and development of exascale computing systems across all applicable DOE organizations; provide, on a competitive, merit-reviewed basis, access for researchers in U.S. industries, IHEs, National Laboratories, and other federal agencies to the exascale computing systems developed under this Act; select members for such partnerships through a competitive, peer-review process; and execute the program through an integration of application, computer science, and computer hardware architecture using those partnerships to ensure that exascale computing machine architectures are capable of solving DOE target applications and broader scientific problems.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
