<bill session="114" type="h" number="5209" updated="2018-11-09T00:09:25Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Manufacturing and Worker Protection Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Tariff Act of 1930 to provide for the payment to affected producers and their employees of duties that are collected pursuant to countervailing and antidumping duty orders, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">American Manufacturing and Worker Protection Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001180"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000611" joined="2016-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2016-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000821" joined="2016-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Trade" code="HSWM04" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">American Manufacturing and Worker Protection Act of 2016

 This bill amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to direct the U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) to distribute semiannually all funds (including any interest earned) from duties assessed pursuant to a countervailing duty order or antidumping duty order or finding (antidumping and subsidy protection amount) to affected domestic producers for qualifying expenditures and cash to eligible employees.

The term "affected domestic producer" means a currently operating manufacturer or producer that was a petitioner or interested party in support of a petition for which an antidumping duty order, finding, or countervailing duty order has been entered.

The term "eligible employee" of an affected domestic producer means an individual who: (1) has been totally or partially separated from employment with that producer because of dumping or a subsidy for which an antidumping duty order, finding, or countervailing duty order has been entered; or (2) is an employee of the affected domestic producer at the time a distribution is made.

The term "qualifying expenditures" means certain expenditures incurred by an affected domestic producer after the issuance of an antidumping duty order, finding, or countervailing duty order.

The CBP shall establish in the Treasury a special account for each such order or finding and to deposit in those accounts all funds (including any interest earned) from antidumping or countervailing duties assessed on or after October 1, 2016.

The requirements of this bill shall apply with respect to goods from Canada and Mexico.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
