<bill session="113" type="h" number="5150" updated="2016-10-25T16:15:16Z">
  <state datetime="2014-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">WaterSense Efficiency, Conservation, and Adaptation Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a WaterSense program within the Environmental Protection Agency.</title>
    <title type="display">WaterSense Efficiency, Conservation, and Adaptation Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001166"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-17">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-17">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water, Power and Oceans" code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Environment and the Economy" code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="identical" number="2226"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="5363"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2771"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-07-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">WaterSense Efficiency, Conservation, and Adaptation Act of 2014 - Establishes within the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) a WaterSense program to identify and promote water efficient products, buildings, landscapes, facilities, processes, and services so as to:

 reduce water use; reduce the strain on water, wastewater, and stormwater infrastructure; conserve energy used to pump, heat, transport, and treat water; and preserve water resources through the voluntary labeling of, or other forms of communications about, products, buildings, landscapes, facilities, processes, and services that meet the highest water efficiency and performance criteria. Requires the Administrator of EPA to identify other voluntary approaches to encourage recycling and reuse technologies to improve water efficiency or lower water use and to implement those approaches, if appropriate.

Establishes a State Residential Water Efficiency and Conservation Incentives Program to provide financial incentives for consumers to purchase and install products, buildings, landscapes, facilities, processes, and services labeled under the WaterSense program.

Requires the Administrator to make grants to owners or operators of water systems to address, mitigate, and adapt to address any ongoing or forecasted impact of climate change on the water quality or quantity of a U.S. region.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
