<bill session="114" type="s" number="3190" updated="2018-06-02T07:47:20Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Our Rural Health Workforce Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance the rural health workforce, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Strengthening Our Rural Health Workforce Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000457"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001069" joined="2016-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5188"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Allied health services"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Strengthening Our Rural Health Workforce Act of 2016

This bill amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to reauthorize the National Health Care Workforce Commission.The commission must track information on the career paths of medical school and residency program graduates and make such information publicly available.

The Department of Health and Human Services must revise the definition of medical residency training programs (rural track training programs)in rural areas so that more health care facilities are able to participate.

The Government Accountability Office must: (1) study and report on graduate medical education funding structures and their success in bringing physicians to practice in rural communities, and (2) report on improving data collection on emerging health care professions.

The bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to redistribute unused residency positions to rural hospitals.

The bill amends the Public Health Service Act to (1) reauthorize the Primary Care Residency Expansion Program and Area Health Education Centers, and (2) authorize appropriations through FY2021 for the Quentin N. Burdick Program for Rural Interdisciplinary Training to provide access to health care in rural areas.

The bill incorporates emerging health professionals, such as dental therapists and community paramedics, into existing loan forgiveness programs and other training programs for allied health professionals.

The bill amends the Public Health Service Act to establish mental health and substance use disorder training programs for schools of medicine or nursing, physician assistants, pharmacy, social work, and other allied health professions to ensure that health care providers are able to recognize, diagnose, and treat mental health and substance use disorders.

The bill also funds essential mental and behavioral health education and training grants that are used to recruit and train graduate students in mental and behavioral health fields who practice in rural and other high need areas.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
