<bill session="115" type="s" number="2812" updated="2019-04-18T16:43:01Z">
  <state datetime="2018-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve consumer protections for customers of air ambulance operators, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Air Ambulance Consumer Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Air Ambulance Consumer Protection Act</title>
    <title type="display">Air Ambulance Consumer Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001170"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-05-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-05-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Air Ambulance Consumer Protection Act

This bill requires the Department of Transportation (DOT) to establish an advisory committee to make recommendations for a rulemaking to: (1) require air ambulance operators to clearly disclose charges for air transportation services separately from charges for non-air transportation services within any invoice or bill, and (2) provide other consumer protections for customers of air ambulance operators.

The bill makes provisions relating to air transportation consumer complaints applicable to air ambulance transportation. It also allows an air ambulance customer to file a complaint requiring DOT to investigate whether air carriers or ticket agents have engaged in unfair or deceptive practices or unfair methods of competition.

An air ambulance operator shall include the hotline telephone number established for consumer complaints on any invoice, bill, or other communication provided to a passenger or customer of the operator.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
