<bill session="114" type="h" number="1777" updated="2019-01-09T21:26:08Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-22">PROV_KILL:VETO</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Presidential Allowance Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Presidential Allowance Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Presidential Allowance Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Presidential Allowance Modernization Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Act of August 25, 1958, commonly known as the "Former Presidents Act of 1958", with respect to the monetary allowance payable to a former President, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Presidential Allowance Modernization Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000984" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000576" joined="2015-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-05-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-07-16">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 114-209.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-07-16" calendar="Union" number="157">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 157.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-01-11T16:37:45-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Chaffetz moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-11T16:38:10-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H241-242" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-11T16:38:12-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1777.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2016-01-11T16:48:12-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H241" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-01-11T16:48:15-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-21">
      <text>Senate Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4428" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-21">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2016-06-21" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-06-21">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-08T12:10:26-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Chaffetz asked unanimous consent that the House agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4562-4563" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="without objection" type="pingpong" datetime="2016-07-08T12:11:15-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion that the House agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4562-4563" label="text as House agree to the Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-07-08T12:11:16-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2016-07-12">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <vetoed datetime="2016-07-22" state="PROV_KILL:VETO">
      <text>Vetoed by President.</text>
    </vetoed>
    <action datetime="2016-07-25T12:34:08-04:00">
      <text>The Chair laid before the House the veto message from the President.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5034" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-25T12:34:36-04:00">
      <text>The Chair announced that the objections of the President to H.R. 1777 would be spread at large upon the Journal and the veto message would be printed as a House document (114-155).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22T14:18:53-04:00">
      <text>Notwithstanding the order of the House of July 25, 2016, Mr. Hurd asked unanimous consent that further consideration of the veto message and the bill, H.R. 1777, be postponed until the legislative day of December 9, 2016.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-05">
      <text>Mr. Chaffetz asked unanimous consent, notwithstanding the order of the House of September 22, 2016, that the veto message of the President on the bill, H.R. 1777, together with the accompanying bill, be referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-05T19:10:41-05:00">
      <text>ORDER OF BUSINESS - Mr. Chaffetz asked unanimous consent, notwithstanding the order of the House of September 22, 2016, that the veto message of the President on the bill, H.R. 1777, together with the accompanying bill, be referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-05">
      <text>On motion to refer the bill and the accompanying veto message to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7178" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1411"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3011"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4852"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2016-06-21T14:03:31Z" status="Passed Senate amended">Presidential Allowance Modernization Act of 2016

(Sec. 2) This bill revises provisions relating to presidential pensions to&#160;allow former&#160;Presidents&#160;a lifetime annual annuity&#160;of $200,000&#160;and an additional annual monetary&#160;allowance&#160;of $200,000, each adjusted annually for cost-of-living increases as provided by the Social Security Act. It reduces the annual monetary allowance by the amount that a former President's adjusted gross income in a taxable year exceeds $400,000.&#160;

The bill prohibits the monetary allowance from being less than the amount that the General Services Administration and the U.S. Secret Service determine is needed to pay the increased cost of doing business that is attributable to the security needs of the former President.

The annuity and allowance shall not be payable for any period during which a former President holds an appointive or elective position in or under the federal government that pays more than a nominal rate.

The bill increases from $20,000 to $100,000 the annual annuity of a surviving spouse of a former President.

(Sec. 3) Nothing in this bill shall be construed to affect: (1) a law relating to the security or protection of a former President or a family member of a former President, or (2) funding to carry out such security or protection.

(Sec. 4) The bill applies to an individual who is a former President or the widow of a former President as of the date of enactment.

(Sec. 5) For a former President receiving a monetary allowance before the enactment of this bill, the reduction of the monetary allowance for adjusted gross income required by this bill applies, except to the extent that it would prevent the former President from being able to pay the cost of a lease or other contract that is in effect on the day before enactment of this bill and under which the former President makes payments using the monetary allowance.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-209</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
