<bill session="114" type="s" number="2761" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:37Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to improve the process for establishing and revising flight paths and procedures, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FAA Community Accountability Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="display">FAA Community Accountability Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3965"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Noise pollution"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">FAA Community Accountability Act of 2016

This bill requires the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), in considering flight paths or procedures as part of the implementation of the Next Generation Air Transportation System, to limit negative impacts on the human environment near airports. The FAA may give preference to overlays of existing flight paths or procedures to ensure compatibility with land use.

The FAA shall appoint an FAA Community Ombudsman for each of its regions to:

 act as a liaison with communities regarding problems related to the impact of commercial aviation on the human environment; monitor the impact of System implementation on communities near affected airports; make recommendations to address community concerns and improve the use of community comments in FAA decisionmaking; and report periodically on the impact of commercial aviation on the human environment and on FAA responsiveness to community concerns. The FAA, in implementing the System, may not treat the establishment or revision of a flight path or procedure as covered by a categorical exclusion if an Ombudsman or airport operator submits notification that: (1) extraordinary circumstances exist, or (2) the establishment or revision will have a significant adverse impact on the human environment near such airport. The FAA, before treating such establishment or revision as covered by a categorical exclusion, shall provide notice and an opportunity for comment to persons affected.

The bill requires the FAA to: (1) reconsider a flight path or procedure established or revised after February 14, 2012, as part of the implementation of the System if an Ombudsman or airport operator submits written notification that the establishment or revision is resulting in a significant adverse impact on the human environment near the airport, (2) provide notice of such reconsideration and an opportunity for public comment, (3) assess the impacts on the human environment, and (4) report on comments received, assessment results, and changes to be made.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
