<bill session="114" type="s" number="2163" updated="2018-06-02T07:10:59Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Streamlining and Investing in Broadband Infrastructure Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 23, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Transportation to require that broadband conduits be installed as a part of certain highway construction projects, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Streamlining and Investing in Broadband Infrastructure Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2015-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2015-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2015-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2015-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2015-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7221" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1618"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3805"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates and fees"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Streamlining and Investing in Broadband Infrastructure Act

This bill requires the National Telecommunications and Information Administration to issue best practices relating to broadband infrastructure and installation for state broadband coordination offices, with an emphasis on rural areas.

The Department of Transportation (DOT) must require states to install broadband conduits, which support broadband or wireless facilities for broadband service, in certain highway construction projects. DOT must ensure that: (1) standards are established that apply to all areas, including rural and remote areas with low population density; and (2) any requesting broadband provider has access to such installed conduits on a competitively neutral and nondiscriminatory basis, for a charge not to exceed a cost-based rate.

Federal easement and right-of-way procedures under the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 are revised to allow an executive agency, a state, a person, a firm, or an organization to apply for the grant of a real property interest (including a lease, license, easement, or right-of-way) to, in, over, or on a building or other property owned by the federal government for the right to install, construct, modify, and maintain a communications facility installation. An executive agency that owns the building or other property on behalf of the federal government must grant to the applicant, if technically feasible, a real property interest to perform such installation, construction, modification, and maintenance.

Requirements are set forth concerning the fees and terms of years for the grant of such real property interests. The bill provides for the collection of: (1) a standard fee established by the General Services Administration (GSA), or (2) agency-specific fees established by executive agencies.

The GSA must also consult with designated agencies regarding the master application forms and standard contracts that executive agencies are required to accept for the placement of such facilities. If the GSA determines that master forms or contracts are not adequate for a specific building or property, it must coordinate with the agencies to address the inadequacies and provide an adequate alternative application form or contract to the applicant.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
