<bill session="114" type="s" number="2757" updated="2018-06-02T07:16:24Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Iran Financial System Access Limitation Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit certain transactions with Iran and to impose sanctions with respect to foreign financial institutions that facilitate such transactions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Iran Financial System Access Limitation Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001198"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="International monetary system and foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Iran Financial System Access Limitation Act of 2016

This bill expresses the sense of Congress that Congress must act to preempt any move to grant licenses resulting in Iran's access to the U.S. dollar.

The President may not issue a license to an offshore dollar-clearing entity to conduct a transaction in U.S. dollars with an Iranian financial institution.

A U.S. person may not process (in a U-turn transaction) any transfer of funds to or from Iran, or for the benefit of persons in Iran or the government of Iran, even if the transfer arises from, and is ordinarily incident and necessary to give effect to, an underlying transaction.

The President shall block and prohibit transactions in all property and property interests of any foreign financial institution that serves as an offshore dollar clearing entity to conduct a transaction with an Iranian financial institution in U.S. dollars if such property and property interests are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a U.S. person.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
