<bill session="114" type="h" number="6261" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:53Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ACO Assignment Improvement Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to improve the way beneficiaries are assigned under the Medicare shared savings program by also basing such assignment on primary care services furnished by nurse practitioners, physician assistants, and clinical nurse specialists.</title>
    <title type="display">ACO Assignment Improvement Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000381"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000290" joined="2016-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5667"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1456"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2259"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2261"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">ACO Assignment Improvement Act of 2016

This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to establish additional requirements for assigning Medicare fee-for-service beneficiaries to accountable care organizations (ACOs) under the Medicare shared savings program. (The program enables ACOs to receive payments for savings stemming from care coordination and management.)

Specifically, the bill requires the basis for assignment to reflect beneficiaries' utilization of not only primary care services provided by ACO physicians, but also those provided by other ACO practitioners. Other ACO practitioners include physician assistants, nurse practitioners, clinical nurse specialists, certified registered nurse anesthetists, certified nurse-midwives, clinical social workers, clinical psychologists, and registered dieticians or nutrition professionals.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
