<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <calendarNumbers>
      <item>
        <number>0562</number>
        <calendar>Senate Calendar of Business</calendar>
      </item>
      <item>
        <number />
        <calendar>U00448</calendar>
      </item>
      <item>
        <number />
        <calendar>Senate Calendar of Business</calendar>
      </item>
    </calendarNumbers>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <middleName />
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <district>3</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Chaffetz, Jason [R-UT-3]</fullName>
        <party>R</party>
        <bioguideId>C001076</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <firstName>Jason</firstName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-02-04</sponsorshipDate>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>8191</gpoId>
          <lisID>1956</lisID>
          <bioguideId>C001076</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <state>UT</state>
        <lastName>Chaffetz</lastName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <middleName />
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <district>9</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Shuster, Bill [R-PA-9]</fullName>
        <party>R</party>
        <bioguideId>S001154</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <firstName>Bill</firstName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-02-04</sponsorshipDate>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1681</lisID>
          <gpoId>8127</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>S001154</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <state>PA</state>
        <lastName>Shuster</lastName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <middleName>E.</middleName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <district>7</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Cummings, Elijah E. [D-MD-7]</fullName>
        <party>D</party>
        <bioguideId>C000984</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <firstName>ELIJAH</firstName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-02-04</sponsorshipDate>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>256</lisID>
          <gpoId>7982</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>C000984</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <state>MD</state>
        <lastName>CUMMINGS</lastName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <middleName>A.</middleName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <district>4</district>
        <fullName>Rep. DeFazio, Peter A. [D-OR-4]</fullName>
        <party>D</party>
        <bioguideId>D000191</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <firstName>PETER</firstName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-02-04</sponsorshipDate>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>D000191</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8117</gpoId>
          <lisID>279</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <state>OR</state>
        <lastName>DEFAZIO</lastName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <middleName />
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <district>11</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Barletta, Lou [R-PA-11]</fullName>
        <party>R</party>
        <bioguideId>B001269</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <firstName>Lou</firstName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-02-04</sponsorshipDate>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2054</lisID>
          <bioguideId>B001269</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8129</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <state>PA</state>
        <lastName>Barletta</lastName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <middleName />
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <district>7</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Carson, Andre [D-IN-7]</fullName>
        <party>D</party>
        <bioguideId>C001072</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <firstName>Andre</firstName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-02-04</sponsorshipDate>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>7946</gpoId>
          <lisID>1889</lisID>
          <bioguideId>C001072</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <state>IN</state>
        <lastName>Carson</lastName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <middleName />
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <district>1</district>
        <fullName>Rep. LaMalfa, Doug [R-CA-1]</fullName>
        <party>R</party>
        <bioguideId>L000578</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <firstName>Doug</firstName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-02-23</sponsorshipDate>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2100</lisID>
          <gpoId />
          <bioguideId>L000578</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <state>CA</state>
        <lastName>LaMalfa</lastName>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>[Congressional Record Volume 162, Number 21 (Thursday, February 4, 2016)]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. DENHAM:H.R. 4465.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8 of the United States Constitution,specifically Clause 1 (relating to providing for the generalwelfare of the United States) and Clause 18 (relating to thepower to make all laws necessary and proper for carrying outthe powers vested in Congress) and clause 17 (relating toauthority over district as the seat of government), andArticle IV, Section 3, Clause 2 (relating to the power ofCongress to dispose of and make all needful rules andregulations respecting the territory or other propertybelonging to the United States).[Page H591]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-12-16</actionDate>
      <text>Became Public Law No: 114-287.</text>
      <links>
        <link>
          <name>Public Law No: 114-287</name>
          <url>https://www.congress.gov/bill/114th-congress/house-bill/4465/text/pl</url>
        </link>
      </links>
    </latestAction>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>House</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <latestTitle>Federal Asset Sale and Transfer Act of 2015</latestTitle>
        <number>2375</number>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2016-07-06</actionDate>
          <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 544.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <type>S</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <latestTitle>Bolster Accountability to Drive Government Efficiency and Reform Washington Act of 2016</latestTitle>
        <number>3011</number>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2016-06-06</actionDate>
          <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 505.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <type>S</type>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2016-05-19T21:53:31Z</pubDate>
        <title>H.R. 4465, Federal Assets Sale and Transfer Act of 2016</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/51604</url>
      </item>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2016-05-19T21:54:34Z</pubDate>
        <title>H.R. 4465, Federal Assets Sale and Transfer Act of 2016</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/51602</url>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-05-09T18:58:02Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <actionDate>2016-02-04</actionDate>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <updateDate>2016-02-04T05:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Federal Assets Sale and Transfer Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill establishes the Public Buildings Reform Board to identify opportunities for the federal government to reduce significantly its inventory of civilian real property and reduce its costs. The Board shall terminate six years after enactment of this Act.</p> <p>Each federal agency shall submit to the General Services Administration (GSA) and the Office of Management and Budget (OMB): (1) current data on all federal civilian real properties owned, leased, or controlled by each agency; (2) recommendations on such properties that can be disposed of or outleased or that otherwise no longer meet agency needs or that can be transferred, exchanged, consolidated, co-located, reconfigured, or redeveloped; and (3) recommendations on operational efficiencies that the government can realize in its operation and maintenance of such properties. The OMB shall review agency recommendations, develop standards for reviewing such recommendations, and submit such standards and its recommendations to the Board.</p> <p>The Board shall: (1) identify at least five federal civilian properties not on the list of surplus or excess properties that have a total fair market value of not less than $500 million and not more than $750 million, (2) transmit a list of such properties to the OMB and Congress as Board recommendations, (3) analyze the inventory of federal civilian real property and the associated agency recommendations, (4) implement an accounting system to evaluate the cost of and returns on recommendations, and (5) report its conclusions and recommendations to the OMB. The Board's first report shall include transactions valued, in total, at not more than $2.5 billion and its second report shall include transactions valued, in total, at not more than $4.75 billion.</p> <p>The OMB shall: (1) review Board recommendations and transmit to the Board and Congress a report on its approval or disapproval of such recommendations, and (2) report information about the properties involved to the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD). </p> <p>Each agency shall: (1) submit a report of excess to the GSA regarding the federal civilian properties for which recommendations have been approved (which properties shall be sold by the GSA for fair market value), (2) immediately begin preparation to carry out the Board's recommendations after the OMB transmits such recommendations to Congress, (3) initiate all activities necessary for implementation of such recommendations not later than two years after such transmittal, and (4) complete implementation within six years after transmittal unless extenuating circumstances prevent timely completion. </p> <p>HUD shall identify any suitable properties for use as a property benefitting the mission of assistance to the homeless for the purposes of further screening pursuant to the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act. The OMB may exclude from the Board's recommendations properties that are not suitable to benefit the homeless but that the OMB determines are suitable for use as a state or local public park or recreation area.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office shall annually review and report to Congress on agency implementation activities under this Act.</p> <p>The net proceeds from the transfer of excess real property to another federal agency or from the sale, lease, or other disposition of surplus real property shall be deposited into the real property account of the agency that had custody of the real property at the time it was determined to be excess. Such proceeds may be expended only as authorized in annual appropriations Acts. Any net proceeds that are not expended shall be used for deficit reduction. The net proceeds of the disposition, lease, or transfer of excess personal property shall be deposited in the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts. </p> <p>GSA shall publish a database of all federal real property under the custody and control of all executive agencies, other than federal real property excluded for reasons of national security. </p> <p>The bill amends the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act to allow the use of surplus property to provide permanent housing with or without supportive services to assist the homeless.</p>]]></text>
        </item>
        <item>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-06-13T13:49:42Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDesc>Passed House amended</actionDesc>
          <actionDate>2016-05-23</actionDate>
          <name>Passed House amended</name>
          <versionCode>36</versionCode>
          <updateDate>2016-05-23T13:34:05Z</updateDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Federal Assets Sale and Transfer Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 4) This bill establishes the Public Buildings Reform Board to identify opportunities for the federal government to reduce significantly its inventory of civilian real property and reduce its costs. </p> <p>(Sec. 10) The Board shall terminate six years after enactment of this Act.</p> <p>(Sec. 11) Each federal agency shall submit to the General Services Administration (GSA) and the Office of Management and Budget (OMB): (1) current data on all federal civilian real properties owned, leased, or controlled by each agency; (2) recommendations on such properties that can be disposed of or outleased or that otherwise no longer meet agency needs or that can be transferred, exchanged, consolidated, co-located, reconfigured, or redeveloped; and (3) recommendations on operational efficiencies that the government can realize in its operation and maintenance of such properties. The OMB shall review agency recommendations, develop standards for reviewing such recommendations, and submit such standards and its recommendations to the Board.</p> <p>The OMB shall incorporate specified factors in developing such standards, including the extent and timing of potential costs and savings beginning with the date of completion of the proposed recommendation, the economic impact on existing communities in the vicinity of the civilian real property, and the extent to which:</p> <ul> <li>the civilian real property could be used to produce the highest and best value and return for the taxpayer; </li> <li>the operating and maintenance costs are reduced through consolidating, co-locating, and reconfiguring space and through realizing other operational efficiencies; </li> <li>the utilization rate is being maximized and is consistent with nongovernmental industry standards; </li> <li>reliance on leasing for long-term space needs is reduced; </li> <li>a civilian real property aligns with the current mission of the agency; </li> <li>there are opportunities to consolidate similar operations across or within agencies; </li> <li>energy consumption is reduced; and </li> <li>public access to agency services is maintained or enhanced. </li></ul> <p>Standards developed by OMB shall incorporate and apply clear standard utilization rates to the extent that such rates increase efficiency and provide performance data. The utilization rates shall be consistent throughout each applicable category of space and with nongovernment space utilization rates. To the extent the space utilization rate of a given agency exceeds the utilization rates to be applied under this bill, the OMB may recommend realignment, co-location, consolidation, or other action to improve space utilization.</p> <p>(Sec. 12) The Board shall: (1) identify at least five federal civilian properties not on the list of surplus or excess properties that have a total fair market value of not less than $500 million and not more than $750 million, (2) transmit a list of such properties to the OMB and Congress as Board recommendations, (3) analyze the inventory of federal civilian real property and the associated agency recommendations, (4) implement an accounting system to evaluate the cost of and returns on recommendations (under which the Board shall set a standard performance period of not less than 15 years), and (5) report its conclusions and recommendations to the OMB. The Board's first report shall include transactions valued, in total, at not more than $2.5 billion and its second report shall include transactions valued, in total, at not more than $4.75 billion.</p> <p>(Sec. 13) The OMB shall: (1) review Board recommendations and transmit to the Board and Congress a report on its approval or disapproval of such recommendations, and (2) report information about the properties involved to the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD). </p> <p>(Sec. 14) Each agency shall: (1) submit a report of excess to the GSA regarding the federal civilian properties for which recommendations have been approved (which properties shall be sold by the GSA within one year for fair market value at highest and best use), (2) immediately begin preparation to carry out the Board's recommendations after the OMB transmits such recommendations to Congress, (3) initiate all activities necessary for implementation of such recommendations not later than two years after such transmittal, and (4) complete implementation within six years after transmittal unless extenuating circumstances prevent timely completion. </p> <p>HUD shall identify any suitable properties for use as a property benefitting the mission of assistance to the homeless for the purposes of further screening pursuant to the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act. The OMB may exclude from the Board's recommendations properties that are not suitable to benefit the homeless but that the OMB determines are suitable for use as a state or local public park or recreation area.</p> <p>The bill permits the transfer of federal civilian property only if: (1) the disposing agency certifies that the costs of all environmental restoration, waste management, and environmental compliance activities otherwise to be paid by the agency with respect to the property equal or exceed the fair market value of the property; or (2) such costs are lower than the fair market value of the property and the recipient agrees to pay the difference. The agency may pay a recipient the amount by which such environmental costs exceed the property's fair market value.</p> <p>(Sec. 15) The bill authorizes specified sums to be appropriated for salaries and expenses of the Board and sums to be deposited into the Asset Proceeds and Space Management Fund for activities related to the implementation of the Board's recommendations. </p> <p>(Sec. 16) There is established in the Treasury the Public Buildings Reform Board Salaries and Expenses Account and the Public Buildings Reform Board--Asset Proceeds and Space Management Fund.</p> <p>(Sec. 17) The GSA shall include, among other requirements for transmission to Congress of a prospectus of a proposed facility, a statement of how the proposed project is consistent with the standards and criteria developed under this bill.</p> <p>(Sec. 18) Actions taken pursuant to provisions of this bill regarding Board duties and OMB review, and actions of the Board, are not subject to judicial review.</p> <p>(Sec. 19) The Government Accountability Office shall annually review and report to Congress on agency implementation activities under this bill.</p> <p>(Sec. 20) After termination of the Board, the net proceeds from the transfer of excess real property to another federal agency or from the sale, lease, or other disposition of surplus real property shall be deposited into the real property account of the agency that had custody of the real property at the time it was determined to be excess. Such proceeds may be expended only as authorized in annual appropriations Acts. Any net proceeds that are not expended shall be used for deficit reduction. Any net proceeds not obligated within three years after the date of deposit and not expended within five years after such date shall be deposited in the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts. </p> <p>(Sec. 21) The GSA shall: (1) publish a database of all federal real property under the custody and control of all executive agencies, other than federal real property excluded for reasons of national security, and (2) make such database available to other federal agencies and accessible by the public at no cost through GSA's website. </p> <p>(Sec. 22) The bill amends the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act to allow the use of surplus property to provide permanent housing with or without supportive services to assist the homeless.</p> <p>(Sec. 23) The GSA, in determining whether a museum is attended by the public and therefore eligible, as a nonprofit, tax-exempt educational or public health institution or organization, to receive donated federal surplus property, shall consider the museum to be public if it, at a minimum, accedes to any request submitted for access during business hours.</p> <p>(Sec. 24) The bill directs the GSA, by December 31, 2018, to sell, at fair market value at highest and best use: (1) a specified property bounded by 12th Street, Independence Avenue, C Street, and the James Forrestal Building in Southwest Washington, D.C.; and (2) the building known as the Cotton Annex in Southwest Washington, D.C. Any net proceeds received shall be paid into the Federal Buildings Fund and may be expended only subject to a specific future appropriation.</p>]]></text>
        </item>
        <item>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-12-16T19:51:26Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDesc>Passed Senate without amendment</actionDesc>
          <actionDate>2016-12-10</actionDate>
          <name>Passed Senate without amendment</name>
          <versionCode>82</versionCode>
          <updateDate>2016-12-10T22:01:59Z</updateDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the House on May 23, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><strong>Federal Assets Sale and Transfer Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 4) This bill establishes the Public Buildings Reform Board to identify opportunities for the federal government to reduce significantly its inventory of civilian real property and reduce its costs. </p> <p>(Sec. 10) The Board shall terminate six years after enactment of this Act.</p> <p>(Sec. 11) Each federal agency shall submit to the General Services Administration (GSA) and the Office of Management and Budget (OMB): (1) current data on all federal civilian real properties owned, leased, or controlled by each agency; (2) recommendations on such properties that can be disposed of or outleased or that otherwise no longer meet agency needs or that can be transferred, exchanged, consolidated, co-located, reconfigured, or redeveloped; and (3) recommendations on operational efficiencies that the government can realize in its operation and maintenance of such properties. The OMB shall review agency recommendations, develop standards for reviewing such recommendations, and submit such standards and its recommendations to the Board.</p> <p>The OMB shall incorporate specified factors in developing such standards, including the extent and timing of potential costs and savings beginning with the date of completion of the proposed recommendation, the economic impact on existing communities in the vicinity of the civilian real property, and the extent to which:</p> <ul> <li>the civilian real property could be used to produce the highest and best value and return for the taxpayer; </li> <li>the operating and maintenance costs are reduced through consolidating, co-locating, and reconfiguring space and through realizing other operational efficiencies; </li> <li>the utilization rate is being maximized and is consistent with nongovernmental industry standards; </li> <li>reliance on leasing for long-term space needs is reduced; </li> <li>a civilian real property aligns with the current mission of the agency; </li> <li>there are opportunities to consolidate similar operations across or within agencies; </li> <li>energy consumption is reduced; and </li> <li>public access to agency services is maintained or enhanced. </li></ul> <p>Standards developed by OMB shall incorporate and apply clear standard utilization rates to the extent that such rates increase efficiency and provide performance data. The utilization rates shall be consistent throughout each applicable category of space and with nongovernment space utilization rates. To the extent the space utilization rate of a given agency exceeds the utilization rates to be applied under this bill, the OMB may recommend realignment, co-location, consolidation, or other action to improve space utilization.</p> <p>(Sec. 12) The Board shall: (1) identify at least five federal civilian properties not on the list of surplus or excess properties that have a total fair market value of not less than $500 million and not more than $750 million, (2) transmit a list of such properties to the OMB and Congress as Board recommendations, (3) analyze the inventory of federal civilian real property and the associated agency recommendations, (4) implement an accounting system to evaluate the cost of and returns on recommendations (under which the Board shall set a standard performance period of not less than 15 years), and (5) report its conclusions and recommendations to the OMB. The Board's first report shall include transactions valued, in total, at not more than $2.5 billion and its second report shall include transactions valued, in total, at not more than $4.75 billion.</p> <p>(Sec. 13) The OMB shall: (1) review Board recommendations and transmit to the Board and Congress a report on its approval or disapproval of such recommendations, and (2) report information about the properties involved to the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD). </p> <p>(Sec. 14) Each agency shall: (1) submit a report of excess to the GSA regarding the federal civilian properties for which recommendations have been approved (which properties shall be sold by the GSA within one year for fair market value at highest and best use), (2) immediately begin preparation to carry out the Board's recommendations after the OMB transmits such recommendations to Congress, (3) initiate all activities necessary for implementation of such recommendations not later than two years after such transmittal, and (4) complete implementation within six years after transmittal unless extenuating circumstances prevent timely completion. </p> <p>HUD shall identify any suitable properties for use as a property benefitting the mission of assistance to the homeless for the purposes of further screening pursuant to the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act. The OMB may exclude from the Board's recommendations properties that are not suitable to benefit the homeless but that the OMB determines are suitable for use as a state or local public park or recreation area.</p> <p>The bill permits the transfer of federal civilian property only if: (1) the disposing agency certifies that the costs of all environmental restoration, waste management, and environmental compliance activities otherwise to be paid by the agency with respect to the property equal or exceed the fair market value of the property; or (2) such costs are lower than the fair market value of the property and the recipient agrees to pay the difference. The agency may pay a recipient the amount by which such environmental costs exceed the property's fair market value.</p> <p>(Sec. 15) The bill authorizes specified sums to be appropriated for salaries and expenses of the Board and sums to be deposited into the Asset Proceeds and Space Management Fund for activities related to the implementation of the Board's recommendations. </p> <p>(Sec. 16) There is established in the Treasury the Public Buildings Reform Board Salaries and Expenses Account and the Public Buildings Reform Board--Asset Proceeds and Space Management Fund.</p> <p>(Sec. 17) The GSA shall include, among other requirements for transmission to Congress of a prospectus of a proposed facility, a statement of how the proposed project is consistent with the standards and criteria developed under this bill.</p> <p>(Sec. 18) Actions taken pursuant to provisions of this bill regarding Board duties and OMB review, and actions of the Board, are not subject to judicial review.</p> <p>(Sec. 19) The Government Accountability Office shall annually review and report to Congress on agency implementation activities under this bill.</p> <p>(Sec. 20) After termination of the Board, the net proceeds from the transfer of excess real property to another federal agency or from the sale, lease, or other disposition of surplus real property shall be deposited into the real property account of the agency that had custody of the real property at the time it was determined to be excess. Such proceeds may be expended only as authorized in annual appropriations Acts. Any net proceeds that are not expended shall be used for deficit reduction. Any net proceeds not obligated within three years after the date of deposit and not expended within five years after such date shall be deposited in the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts. </p> <p>(Sec. 21) The GSA shall: (1) publish a database of all federal real property under the custody and control of all executive agencies, other than federal real property excluded for reasons of national security, and (2) make such database available to other federal agencies and accessible by the public at no cost through GSA's website. </p> <p>(Sec. 22) The bill amends the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act to allow the use of surplus property to provide permanent housing with or without supportive services to assist the homeless.</p> <p>(Sec. 23) The GSA, in determining whether a museum is attended by the public and therefore eligible, as a nonprofit, tax-exempt educational or public health institution or organization, to receive donated federal surplus property, shall consider the museum to be public if it, at a minimum, accedes to any request submitted for access during business hours.</p> <p>(Sec. 24) The bill directs the GSA, by December 31, 2018, to sell, at fair market value at highest and best use: (1) a specified property bounded by 12th Street, Independence Avenue, C Street, and the James Forrestal Building in Southwest Washington, D.C.; and (2) the building known as the Cotton Annex in Southwest Washington, D.C. Any net proceeds received shall be paid into the Federal Buildings Fund and may be expended only subject to a specific future appropriation.</p>]]></text>
        </item>
        <item>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-12-22T20:28:15Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDesc>Public Law</actionDesc>
          <actionDate>2016-12-16</actionDate>
          <name>Public Law</name>
          <versionCode>49</versionCode>
          <updateDate>2016-12-17T04:59:58Z</updateDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the House on May 23, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><strong>Federal Assets Sale and Transfer Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 4) This bill establishes the Public Buildings Reform Board to identify opportunities for the federal government to reduce significantly its inventory of civilian real property and reduce its costs. </p> <p>(Sec. 10) The Board shall terminate six years after enactment of this Act.</p> <p>(Sec. 11) Each federal agency shall submit to the General Services Administration (GSA) and the Office of Management and Budget (OMB): (1) current data on all federal civilian real properties owned, leased, or controlled by each agency; (2) recommendations on such properties that can be disposed of or outleased or that otherwise no longer meet agency needs or that can be transferred, exchanged, consolidated, co-located, reconfigured, or redeveloped; and (3) recommendations on operational efficiencies that the government can realize in its operation and maintenance of such properties. The OMB shall review agency recommendations, develop standards for reviewing such recommendations, and submit such standards and its recommendations to the Board.</p> <p>The OMB shall incorporate specified factors in developing such standards, including the extent and timing of potential costs and savings beginning with the date of completion of the proposed recommendation, the economic impact on existing communities in the vicinity of the civilian real property, and the extent to which:</p> <ul> <li>the civilian real property could be used to produce the highest and best value and return for the taxpayer; </li> <li>the operating and maintenance costs are reduced through consolidating, co-locating, and reconfiguring space and through realizing other operational efficiencies; </li> <li>the utilization rate is being maximized and is consistent with nongovernmental industry standards; </li> <li>reliance on leasing for long-term space needs is reduced; </li> <li>a civilian real property aligns with the current mission of the agency; </li> <li>there are opportunities to consolidate similar operations across or within agencies; </li> <li>energy consumption is reduced; and </li> <li>public access to agency services is maintained or enhanced. </li></ul> <p>Standards developed by OMB shall incorporate and apply clear standard utilization rates to the extent that such rates increase efficiency and provide performance data. The utilization rates shall be consistent throughout each applicable category of space and with nongovernment space utilization rates. To the extent the space utilization rate of a given agency exceeds the utilization rates to be applied under this bill, the OMB may recommend realignment, co-location, consolidation, or other action to improve space utilization.</p> <p>(Sec. 12) The Board shall: (1) identify at least five federal civilian properties not on the list of surplus or excess properties that have a total fair market value of not less than $500 million and not more than $750 million, (2) transmit a list of such properties to the OMB and Congress as Board recommendations, (3) analyze the inventory of federal civilian real property and the associated agency recommendations, (4) implement an accounting system to evaluate the cost of and returns on recommendations (under which the Board shall set a standard performance period of not less than 15 years), and (5) report its conclusions and recommendations to the OMB. The Board's first report shall include transactions valued, in total, at not more than $2.5 billion and its second report shall include transactions valued, in total, at not more than $4.75 billion.</p> <p>(Sec. 13) The OMB shall: (1) review Board recommendations and transmit to the Board and Congress a report on its approval or disapproval of such recommendations, and (2) report information about the properties involved to the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD). </p> <p>(Sec. 14) Each agency shall: (1) submit a report of excess to the GSA regarding the federal civilian properties for which recommendations have been approved (which properties shall be sold by the GSA within one year for fair market value at highest and best use), (2) immediately begin preparation to carry out the Board's recommendations after the OMB transmits such recommendations to Congress, (3) initiate all activities necessary for implementation of such recommendations not later than two years after such transmittal, and (4) complete implementation within six years after transmittal unless extenuating circumstances prevent timely completion. </p> <p>HUD shall identify any suitable properties for use as a property benefitting the mission of assistance to the homeless for the purposes of further screening pursuant to the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act. The OMB may exclude from the Board's recommendations properties that are not suitable to benefit the homeless but that the OMB determines are suitable for use as a state or local public park or recreation area.</p> <p>The bill permits the transfer of federal civilian property only if: (1) the disposing agency certifies that the costs of all environmental restoration, waste management, and environmental compliance activities otherwise to be paid by the agency with respect to the property equal or exceed the fair market value of the property; or (2) such costs are lower than the fair market value of the property and the recipient agrees to pay the difference. The agency may pay a recipient the amount by which such environmental costs exceed the property's fair market value.</p> <p>(Sec. 15) The bill authorizes specified sums to be appropriated for salaries and expenses of the Board and sums to be deposited into the Asset Proceeds and Space Management Fund for activities related to the implementation of the Board's recommendations. </p> <p>(Sec. 16) There is established in the Treasury the Public Buildings Reform Board Salaries and Expenses Account and the Public Buildings Reform Board--Asset Proceeds and Space Management Fund.</p> <p>(Sec. 17) The GSA shall include, among other requirements for transmission to Congress of a prospectus of a proposed facility, a statement of how the proposed project is consistent with the standards and criteria developed under this bill.</p> <p>(Sec. 18) Actions taken pursuant to provisions of this bill regarding Board duties and OMB review, and actions of the Board, are not subject to judicial review.</p> <p>(Sec. 19) The Government Accountability Office shall annually review and report to Congress on agency implementation activities under this bill.</p> <p>(Sec. 20) After termination of the Board, the net proceeds from the transfer of excess real property to another federal agency or from the sale, lease, or other disposition of surplus real property shall be deposited into the real property account of the agency that had custody of the real property at the time it was determined to be excess. Such proceeds may be expended only as authorized in annual appropriations Acts. Any net proceeds that are not expended shall be used for deficit reduction. Any net proceeds not obligated within three years after the date of deposit and not expended within five years after such date shall be deposited in the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts. </p> <p>(Sec. 21) The GSA shall: (1) publish a database of all federal real property under the custody and control of all executive agencies, other than federal real property excluded for reasons of national security, and (2) make such database available to other federal agencies and accessible by the public at no cost through GSA's website. </p> <p>(Sec. 22) The bill amends the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act to allow the use of surplus property to provide permanent housing with or without supportive services to assist the homeless.</p> <p>(Sec. 23) The GSA, in determining whether a museum is attended by the public and therefore eligible, as a nonprofit, tax-exempt educational or public health institution or organization, to receive donated federal surplus property, shall consider the museum to be public if it, at a minimum, accedes to any request submitted for access during business hours.</p> <p>(Sec. 24) The bill directs the GSA, by December 31, 2018, to sell, at fair market value at highest and best use: (1) a specified property bounded by 12th Street, Independence Avenue, C Street, and the James Forrestal Building in Southwest Washington, D.C.; and (2) the building known as the Cotton Annex in Southwest Washington, D.C. Any net proceeds received shall be paid into the Federal Buildings Fund and may be expended only subject to a specific future appropriation.</p>]]></text>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <type>President</type>
        <actionCode>E40000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>Public Law No: 114-287</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/bill/114th-congress/house-bill/4465/text/pl</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <actionDate>2016-12-16</actionDate>
        <text>Became Public Law No: 114-287.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>BecameLaw</type>
        <actionCode>36000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>Public Law No: 114-287</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/bill/114th-congress/house-bill/4465/text/pl</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <actionDate>2016-12-16</actionDate>
        <text>Became Public Law No: 114-287.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>President</type>
        <actionCode>E30000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <actionDate>2016-12-16</actionDate>
        <text>Signed by President.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>BecameLaw</type>
        <actionCode>36000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <actionDate>2016-12-16</actionDate>
        <text>Signed by President.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>E20000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <actionDate>2016-12-14</actionDate>
        <text>Presented to President.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>President</type>
        <actionCode>28000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <actionDate>2016-12-14</actionDate>
        <text>Presented to President.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-12-12</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-12-10</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>S7135</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-162/senate-section/page/S7135</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent. (consideration: CR S7135)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>17000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>S7135</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-162/senate-section/page/S7135</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <actionDate>2016-12-10</actionDate>
        <text>Passed/agreed to in Senate: Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.(consideration: CR S7135)</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-07-14</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 562.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-07-13</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-05-24</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H38310</actionCode>
        <actionTime>19:53:15</actionTime>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <actionDate>2016-05-23</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H37300</actionCode>
        <actionTime>19:53:08</actionTime>
        <committee />
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H2933-2938</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-162/house-section/page/H2933-2938</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <actionDate>2016-05-23</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote. (text: CR H2933-2938)</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>8000</actionCode>
        <actionTime>19:53:08</actionTime>
        <committee />
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H2933-2938</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-162/house-section/page/H2933-2938</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <actionDate>2016-05-23</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Passed/agreed to in House: On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.(text: CR H2933-2938)</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <actionTime>19:31:13</actionTime>
        <committee />
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H.R. 4465</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/bill/114th-congress/house-bill/4465</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <actionDate>2016-05-23</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4465.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H30000</actionCode>
        <actionTime>19:31:09</actionTime>
        <committee />
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H2933-2940</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-162/house-section/page/H2933-2940</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <actionDate>2016-05-23</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Considered under suspension of the rules. (consideration: CR H2933-2940)</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H30300</actionCode>
        <actionTime>19:31:02</actionTime>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <actionDate>2016-05-23</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Mr. Barletta moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Calendars</type>
        <actionCode>H12410</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <actionDate>2016-05-23</actionDate>
        <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 448.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>H12200</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee>
          <name>Oversight and Reform Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H. Rept. 114-578</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-report/114th-congress/house-report/578</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <actionDate>2016-05-23</actionDate>
        <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 114-578, Part II.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>5000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee>
          <name>Oversight and Reform Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H. Rept. 114-578</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-report/114th-congress/house-report/578</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <actionDate>2016-05-23</actionDate>
        <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 114-578, Part II.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>H12200</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee>
          <name>Transportation and Infrastructure Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hspw00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H. Rept. 114-578</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-report/114th-congress/house-report/578</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <actionDate>2016-05-23</actionDate>
        <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 114-578, Part I.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>5000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee>
          <name>Transportation and Infrastructure Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hspw00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H. Rept. 114-578</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-report/114th-congress/house-report/578</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <actionDate>2016-05-23</actionDate>
        <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 114-578, Part I.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-04-14</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Oversight and Reform Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-04-14</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Oversight and Reform Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-03-02</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Transportation and Infrastructure Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hspw00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-03-02</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Transportation and Infrastructure Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hspw00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-03-02</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Transportation and Infrastructure Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hspw00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management Discharged.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-02-05</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management Subcommittee</name>
          <systemCode>hspw13</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee>
          <name>Oversight and Reform Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <actionDate>2016-02-04</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100-A</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <actionDate>2016-02-04</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee>
          <name>Transportation and Infrastructure Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hspw00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <actionDate>2016-02-04</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <actionDate>2016-02-04</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <actionDate>2016-02-04</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <placeholderTextForH>4</placeholderTextForH>
        <finalPassageUnderSuspensionOfTheRulesResults>1</finalPassageUnderSuspensionOfTheRulesResults>
        <reportedToHouse>2</reportedToHouse>
        <placedOnCalendarSection>2</placedOnCalendarSection>
        <committeeReportOfABill>2</committeeReportOfABill>
        <sentToHouse>1</sentToHouse>
        <passedSenate>1</passedSenate>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
        <becamePublicLaw>2</becamePublicLaw>
        <considerationByHouse>1</considerationByHouse>
        <motionMadeToSuspendTheRules>1</motionMadeToSuspendTheRules>
        <actionStageOverride>2</actionStageOverride>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <passedAgreedToInHouse>1</passedAgreedToInHouse>
        <motionToReconsiderResults>1</motionToReconsiderResults>
        <passedAgreedToInSenate>1</passedAgreedToInSenate>
        <billReferralsAggregate>1</billReferralsAggregate>
        <billReferrals>2</billReferrals>
        <unionCalendarAssignment>1</unionCalendarAssignment>
        <presentedToPresident>1</presentedToPresident>
        <generalDebate>1</generalDebate>
        <placeholderTextForE>3</placeholderTextForE>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>6</senate>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>22</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <introducedDate>2016-02-04</introducedDate>
    <billNumber>4465</billNumber>
    <updateDate>2019-02-12T19:45:39Z</updateDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2016-05-23T16:21:47Z</date>
              <name>Reported by</name>
            </item>
            <item>
              <date>2016-04-14T16:01:42Z</date>
              <name>Markup by</name>
            </item>
            <item>
              <date>2016-02-04T15:01:30Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <name>Oversight and Reform Committee</name>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
          <subcommittees />
        </item>
        <item>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2016-05-23T16:21:00Z</date>
              <name>Reported by</name>
            </item>
            <item>
              <date>2016-03-02T16:54:40Z</date>
              <name>Markup by</name>
            </item>
            <item>
              <date>2016-02-04T15:01:25Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <name>Transportation and Infrastructure Committee</name>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <systemCode>hspw00</systemCode>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <systemCode>hspw13</systemCode>
              <name>Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management Subcommittee</name>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <date>2016-03-02T16:54:27Z</date>
                  <name>Discharged from</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                  <date>2016-02-05T21:31:28Z</date>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                </item>
              </activities>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <firstName>Jeff</firstName>
        <middleName />
        <district>10</district>
        <state>CA</state>
        <fullName>Rep. Denham, Jeff [R-CA-10]</fullName>
        <bioguideId>D000612</bioguideId>
        <party>R</party>
        <lastName>Denham</lastName>
        <byRequestType />
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1995</lisID>
          <bioguideId>D000612</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>7824</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <version>1.0.0</version>
    <recordedVotes />
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Accounting and auditing</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Budget deficits and national debt</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government buildings, facilities, and property</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government information and archives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government trust funds</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Homelessness and emergency shelter</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Land transfers</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Parks, recreation areas, trails</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Enacted</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType>Short Title</parentTitleType>
        <title>Federal Assets Sale and Transfer Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Passed House</titleType>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles House of Representatives</parentTitleType>
        <title>Federal Assets Sale and Transfer Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Federal Assets Sale and Transfer Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>To decrease the deficit by consolidating and selling Federal buildings and other civilian real property, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Federal Assets Sale and Transfer Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114hr4465enr/xml/BILLS-114hr4465enr.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
        <type>Enrolled Bill</type>
        <date>2016-12-14T05:00:00Z</date>
      </item>
      <item>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114hr4465pcs/xml/BILLS-114hr4465pcs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
        <type>Placed on Calendar Senate</type>
        <date>2016-07-14T04:00:00Z</date>
      </item>
      <item>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114hr4465rds/xml/BILLS-114hr4465rds.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
        <type>Received in Senate</type>
        <date>2016-05-24T04:00:00Z</date>
      </item>
      <item>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114hr4465eh/xml/BILLS-114hr4465eh.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
        <type>Engrossed in House</type>
        <date>2016-05-23T04:00:00Z</date>
      </item>
      <item>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114hr4465rh/xml/BILLS-114hr4465rh.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
        <type>Reported in House</type>
        <date>2016-05-23T04:00:00Z</date>
      </item>
      <item>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114hr4465ih/xml/BILLS-114hr4465ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2016-02-04T05:00:00Z</date>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <title>Federal Assets Sale and Transfer Act of 2016</title>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>H. Rept. 114-578</citation>
      </committeeReport>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>H. Rept. 114-578</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <createDate>2016-02-05T05:14:18Z</createDate>
    <notes />
    <amendments />
    <laws>
      <item>
        <number>114-287</number>
        <type>Public Law</type>
      </item>
    </laws>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

