<bill session="114" type="h" number="4178" updated="2018-11-09T00:09:08Z">
  <state datetime="2015-12-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-12-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Unemployed Worker Investment Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend the work opportunity tax credit and to allow small employers a credit against income tax for hiring individuals receiving unemployment compensation.</title>
    <title type="display">American Unemployed Worker Investment Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000579"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001097" joined="2015-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2015-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000382" joined="2015-12-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-12-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">American Unemployed Worker Investment Act of 2015

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) extend the work opportunity tax credit through 2017; (2) allow a small business employer (i.e., an employer who employs more than 10 but fewer than 25 full-time employees throughout the taxable year) an increased work opportunity tax credit for hiring a qualified unemployment compensation recipient; and (3) allow tax-exempt organizations a work opportunity tax credit for hiring qualified unemployment compensation recipients.

The bill defines "qualified unemployment compensation recipient" as any individual who is certified as: (1) not being a student for at least six months during the one-year period ending on the hiring date, (2) being in receipt of unemployment compensation on the hiring date, and (3) having a hiring date during the two-year period which begins on the enactment of this Act.

The bill denies such credit unless: (1) the&#160;qualified unemployment compensation recipient is employed for not&#160;less than 35 hours per week for not&#160;less than 1 year, and (2) the number of full-time employees of the employer receiving such credit is increased by 1 for at least 1 year.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
