<bill session="114" type="s" number="1551" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:37Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for certain requirements relating to the Internet Assigned Numbers Authority stewardship transition.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Domain Openness Through Continued Oversight Matters Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">DOTCOM Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Domain Openness Through Continued Oversight Matters Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DOTCOM Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">DOTCOM Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2015-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2015-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2015-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2015-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2015-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-06-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-10-27">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Thune under authority of the order of the Senate of 09/29/2016 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-10-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="657">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 657.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="805"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-10-27T14:37:29Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Domain Openness Through Continued Oversight Matters Act of 2015 or the DOTCOM Act of 2015

(Sec. 2) This bill prohibits the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information from permitting the National Telecommunications and Information Administration's (NTIA's) role in the performance of the Internet Assigned Numbers Authority (IANA) functions to cease until 30 legislative days after the Assistant Secretary&#160;submits to Congress a report that contains: (1) the proposal relating to the transition of the NTIA's stewardship of the IANA functions that was developed in a process convened by the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers (ICANN) at the request of the NTIA, and (2) the following required certifications by the Assistant Secretary.

The bill requires the Assistant Secretary to certify that: (1) such proposal supports and enhances the multistakeholder model of Internet governance, maintains the security, stability, and resiliency of the Internet domain name system, meets the needs of global customers and partners of the IANA services, maintains the openness of the Internet, and does not replace the role of the NTIA with a government-led or intergovernmental organization solution; and (2) the required changes to ICANN's bylaws contained in the final report of ICANN's Cross Community Working Group on Enhancing ICANN Accountability and the changes to ICANN's bylaws required by ICANN's IANA Stewardship Transition Coordination Group have been adopted.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
