<bill session="114" type="h" number="5315" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:36Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clarifying Legality and Enforcement Action Reasoning Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CLEAR Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Trade Commission Act to require annual reports to Congress regarding the status of investigations of unfair or deceptive acts or practices, and of unfair methods of competition, in or affecting commerce.</title>
    <title type="display">CLEAR Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000558"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001248" joined="2016-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000820" joined="2016-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5109"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5510"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-24T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Clarifying Legality and Enforcement Action Reasoning Act of 2016 or the CLEAR Act of 2016

This bill amends the Federal Trade Commission Act to require the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to submit an annual report to Congress about its investigations concerning unfair or deceptive acts or practices, or unfair methods of competition, in or affecting commerce. The reports must detail:

 the number of such investigations the FTC has commenced and the disposition of investigations that concluded with official agency action; and the number of investigations the FTC has closed with no official agency action, along with a description that indicates the legal analysis supporting the FTC's decision not to continue such investigations, and the industry sectors of the entities subject to each such investigation. The bill prohibits the FTC from identifying a person who is the subject of an investigation in its description of an investigation that closed with no official agency action.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
