<bill session="114" type="s" number="2517" updated="2018-06-02T07:14:45Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-10">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Combat Terrorist Use of Social Media Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Combat Terrorist Use of Social Media Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require a report on United States strategy to combat terrorist use of social media, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Combat Terrorist Use of Social Media Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000293"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2016-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2016-02-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-02-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-07-11">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson with amendments. With written report No. 114-295.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="551">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 551.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3654"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-11T14:20:09Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Combat Terrorist Use of Social Media Act of 2016

(Sec. 3) This bill requires the President to transmit to Congress a report, an evaluation, and a strategy on U.S. efforts to combat terrorists' and terrorist organizations' use of social media.

The report, to be submitted within 90 days after enactment of this bill, must include:

 an evaluation of the role social media plays in the radicalization of individuals to facilitate or commit international or domestic terrorism; an analysis of how terrorists and terrorist organizations are using social media; the federal government's efforts to monitor, review, disrupt, and counter the use of social media by terrorists and terrorist organizations; an assessment of the value to law enforcement and the intelligence community of reviewing terrorists' social media posts; an overview of local, state, and federal training available to combat terrorists' use of social media, the required qualifications of trainers, the intended participants of each program, and recommendations for improving or expanding existing training participation and incorporating training on civil rights and liberties; an assessment of the value to the federal government of collaborating with civil society to counter terrorist propaganda and radicalization; and an assessment of any impact the efforts of the federal government to combat terrorists' and terrorist organizations' use of social media may have upon the civil rights and liberties of U.S. persons who are not engaged in terrorist activities. The evaluation, to be submitted within 180 days after enactment of this bill, must:

 recommend improvements to the federal government's efforts to monitor, review, disrupt, and counter the use of social media by terrorists and terrorist organizations; analyze how the federal government is using social media to counter terrorist propaganda and radicalization, and how such tactics fit within the broader efforts of the federal government to combat domestic terrorism and international terrorism; and assess again any impact the efforts of the federal government to combat terrorists' and terrorist organizations' use of social media may have upon the civil rights and liberties of U.S. persons who are not engaged in terrorist activities. (Sec. 4) The President, within 180 days after enactment of this bill, must also transmit to Congress a comprehensive strategy to counter terrorists' and terrorist organizations' use of social media, as committed to in the President's 2011 Strategic Implementation Plan for Empowering Local Partners to Prevent Violent Extremism in the United States.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-295</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
