<bill session="114" type="h" number="933" updated="2019-04-11T15:42:40Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Head Start Act to ensure that all children in Head Start and Early Head Start programs are vaccinated, and allow exemptions only for children with underlying medical conditions, for whom vaccines are therefore medically contraindicated.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Head Start on Vaccinations Act</title>
    <title type="display">Head Start on Vaccinations Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000197" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000216" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001163" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001175" joined="2015-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="486"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-12T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Head Start on Vaccinations Act

Amends the Head Start Act to prohibit the enrollment of a child in a Head Start or Early Head Start program unless the child's parent or guardian: (1) provides the program with information establishing that the child is vaccinated in accordance with the pediatric vaccine list; or (2) submits a signed agreement to provide such information and consents to the provision, by a program employee or other health care provider, of any vaccines on the pediatric vaccine list that the child has not yet received. Requires that information to be provided on an annual basis in order for a child to maintain enrollment in such program.

Requires any child who is not in compliance with such requirements to be removed from such program, but provides for the exemption of children for whom the administration of such vaccines is medically contraindicated.

Authorizes the director of a Head Start or Early Head Start agency to use program funds to: (1) administer the required vaccines to children, at the request of the parent or guardian; or (2) assist the parent or guardian in gaining access to the required vaccines.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
