<bill session="114" type="h" number="1955" updated="2018-06-02T03:22:13Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Great Lakes Nutrient Removal Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to provide assistance for nutrient removal technologies to States in the Great Lakes System.</title>
    <title type="display">Great Lakes Nutrient Removal Assistance Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000455" joined="2015-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2015-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000263" joined="2015-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2015-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2015-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000480" joined="2015-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Great Lakes Nutrient Removal Assistance Act 

This bill amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to require the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish a program to provide grants to states in the Great Lakes System (i.e., Illinois, Indiana, Michigan, Minnesota, New York, Ohio, Pennsylvania, and Wisconsin) and municipalities in those states to install nutrient removal technologies at a municipal wastewater treatment facility that has a permitted design capacity to treat an annual average of at least 500,000 gallons of wastewater per day.

The EPA must give priority to facilities at which nutrient removal technology installations would: (1) produce the greatest nutrient load reductions at points of discharge, (2) result in the greatest environmental benefits to the Great Lakes System, and (3) help meet the objectives related to nutrients outlined in Annex 4 of the 2012 Great Lakes Water Quality Agreement.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
