<bill session="114" type="h" number="5243" updated="2019-02-06T22:37:44Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-18T21:13:46-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-05-18T21:13:46-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Zika Response Appropriations Act, 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Zika Response Appropriations Act, 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2016, to strengthen public health activities in response to the Zika virus, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Zika Response Appropriations Act, 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000395"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000059" joined="2016-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2016-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001045" joined="2016-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001048" joined="2016-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000600" joined="2016-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000377" joined="2016-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000583" joined="2016-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001192" joined="2016-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000809" joined="2016-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000066" joined="2016-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-17T23:53:01-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 736 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4974 and H.R. 5243.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-18T15:06:38-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 736 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-18T19:27:35-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 736.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2787-2804" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-18T19:27:40-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4974 and H.R. 5243.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-18T19:28:21-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 5243.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-18T20:36:33-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2800" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-18T20:37:02-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Castor (FL) moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2800-2803" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2800-2802" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-18T20:37:42-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Castor (FL) motion to recommit with instructions, pending a reservation of a point of order. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to strike all after the enacting clause and insert a new text to the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-18T20:42:34-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Rogers (KY) raised a point of order against the motion to recommit with instructions. Mr. Rogers (KY) stated that the provisions of the motion sought to change existing law and constituted legislation in an appropriations bill. Sustained by the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-18T20:42:34-04:00">
      <text>Point of order sustained against the motion to recommit with instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-18T20:45:36-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Castor (FL) appealed the ruling of the chair. The question was then put on sustaining the ruling of the chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-18T20:45:45-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Rogers (KY) moved to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the chair</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-18T21:06:17-04:00">
      <text>On motion to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the chair Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 240 - 183 (Roll no. 206).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="207" datetime="2016-05-18T21:13:46-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 241 - 184 (Roll no. 207).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2787-2788" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-05-18T21:13:48-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2577"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="114" relation="procedurally-related" number="736"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-18T16:41:32Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Highlights:

This bill provides FY2016 supplemental appropriations to the Departments of Health and Human Services (HHS) and State to respond to the Zika virus. The bill also rescinds unobligated balances of prior appropriations.

The bill permits the funds to be used for the duration of FY2016, designates specified funds as emergency requirements, and sets forth congressional reporting and notification requirements.

Full Summary: 

Zika Response Appropriations Act, 2016 

TITLE I--DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES

Provides appropriations to HHS for:

 the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to prevent, prepare for, and respond to the Zika virus, domestically and internationally; the National Institutes of Health for the preclinical and clinical development of vaccines for the Zika virus; and the Public Health and Social Services Emergency Fund within the Office of the Secretary to develop necessary countermeasures and vaccines to respond to the Zika virus, domestically and internationally. (Sec. 101) Requires HHS to notify Congress at least 15 days in advance of obligating the funds provided by this title. Permits a waiver for a substantial risk to human health or welfare.

(Sec. 102) Requires HHS to report monthly to Congress on the proposed uses of funds provided by this title.

(Sec. 103) Provides funding to the HHS Office of Inspector General and the Government Accountability Office (GAO) for the oversight of activities funded by this title.

TITLE II--DEPARTMENT OF STATE

Provides appropriations to the State Department for the Administration of Foreign Affairs, the United States Agency for International Development (USAID), and Bilateral Economic Assistance, including funds for:

 Diplomatic and Consular Programs for medical evacuations and other response efforts related to the Zika virus and directly associated health conditions; USAID response efforts related to the Zika virus and directly associated health conditions; and Global Health Programs for mosquito control (vector control) efforts to prevent, prepare for, and respond to the Zika virus internationally. (Sec. 201) Permits specified funds provided by this bill for Diplomatic and Consular Programs to be: (1) used for medical evacuation costs of any U.S. department or agency under Chief of Mission authority, and (2) transferred and merged with funds available for Emergencies in the Diplomatic and Consular Service.

(Sec. 202) Requires the State Department or the USAID to notify Congress at least 15 days in advance of obligating the funds provided by this title. Permits a waiver for a substantial risk to human health or welfare.

(Sec. 203) Requires the State Department, in consultation with the USAID, to report monthly to Congress on the proposed uses of funds provided by this title.

(Sec. 204) Provides funding to the USAID Office of Inspector General and the GAO for the oversight of activities funded by this title.

TITLE III--GENERAL PROVISIONS--THIS ACT

(Sec. 301) Rescinds specified unobligated balances of funds that were previously provided to HHS and the State Department for the Ebola outbreak and to HHS for the Nonrecurring Expenses Fund.

(Sec. 302) Specifies that, unless otherwise indicated in this bill, the funds provided by this bill are subject to the requirements contained in the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
