<bill session="113" type="s" number="1564" updated="2016-10-25T16:27:06Z">
  <state datetime="2013-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Those Who Protected Us Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill making continuing appropriations for veterans benefits and services in the event of a Government shutdown.</title>
    <title type="display">Protecting Those Who Protected Us Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001265" joined="2013-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2013-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2013-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2013-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2013-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2013-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2013-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-09-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting Those Who Protected Us Act of 2013 - Appropriates for FY2014, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for any period during which interim or full-year appropriations for FY2014 are not in effect, such sums as are necessary to administer and provide benefits and services to veterans, dependents, and survivors under specified veterans' benefits laws, including those concerning:

 compensation for service-connected disability or death, dependency and indemnity compensation for service-connected deaths, pension for non-service-connected disability or death or for service, benefits for children of certain veterans, specially adapted housing for disabled veterans, burial benefits, certain educational assistance programs, training and rehabilitation for veterans with service-connected disabilities, and automobiles and adaptive equipment for certain disabled veterans and members of the Armed Forces. Makes appropriations and funds made available and authority granted pursuant to this Act available until whichever of the following first occurs: (1) enactment of an appropriation (including a continuing appropriation) for any purpose for which amounts are made available by this Act, (2) enactment of the applicable regular or continuing appropriations resolution or other Act without any appropriation for such purpose, or (3) January 1, 2015.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
