<amendment session="114" chamber="s" number="750" updated="2018-06-04T02:15:42Z">
  <amends type="sc" number="11" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2015-03-27">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000577"/>
  <offered datetime="2015-03-25"/>
  <description>To modify the spending-neutral reserve fund reauthorizing funding for payments to counties and other units of local government to include the option of payment at levels roughly equivalent to property tax revenues lost due to the presence of Federal land.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2015-03-27" how="roll" result="pass" roll="126">
      <text>Amendment SA 750 as modified agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 56 - 43. Record Vote Number: 126.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Amendment SA 750 proposed by Senator Enzi for Senator Lee. (consideration: CR S1979-1980, S1995; text: CR S1979; text as modified: CR S1995) To modify the spending-neutral reserve fund reauthorizing funding for payments to counties and other units of local government to include the option of payment at levels roughly equivalent to property tax revenues lost due to the presence of Federal land.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25"/>
    <action datetime="2015-03-27">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 750 as modified agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 56 - 43. Record Vote Number: 126.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-27">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 750 as modified agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 56 - 43. Record Vote Number: 126.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 750 proposed by Senator Enzi for Senator Lee.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1979-1980, S1995" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1979" label="text"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1995" label="text as modified"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
