<bill session="114" type="h" number="5774" updated="2019-04-11T15:40:30Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Act to allow small business concerns, homeowners, or nonprofit entities to use certain Superstorm Sandy grant funds or other disaster assistance received to repay certain disaster assistance provided by the Small Business Administration.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Equity for Disaster Victims Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="display">Equity for Disaster Victims Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000522"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000081" joined="2016-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Equity for Disaster Victims Act of 2016

This bill amends the Small Business Act to allow a small business concern, homeowner, or nonprofit entity that received a Small Business Administration (SBA) disaster loan for repairing, rehabilitating, or replacing real property damaged or destroyed by or because of Superstorm Sandy or that received such an SBA loan to refinance a mortgage or other lien against a home or business concern totally destroyed or substantially damaged by or because of the storm to receive Superstorm Sandy CDBG-DR grant funds only if they will be used to repay:

 the principal and any interest accrued on the loan for such repair, rehabilitation, or replacement; or the loan received to refinance the mortgage or other lien. The bill allows these recipients of additional SBA disaster assistance resulting from a declared major disaster to use CDBG-DR grant funds only if they are used for such repayments.

The term Superstorm Sandy CDBG-DR grant funds means mandatory amounts made available by the Department of Housing and Urban Development only for impacted and distressed areas resulting from a declared major disaster due to Superstorm Sandy for activities authorized under the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974.

A small business concern, homeowner, or nonprofit entity who receives assistance pursuant to any other law to repair, rehabilitate, or replace real property damaged or destroyed by or as a result of a declared major disaster on or after enactment of this bill may use such assistance to repay the principal and any interest accrued on a loan or the amount of other assistance received under it.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
