<amendment session="114" chamber="h" number="772" updated="2018-11-09T00:02:54Z">
  <amends type="h" number="22" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2015-11-04T13:57:50-05:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000598"/>
  <offered datetime="2015-11-03"/>
  <description>Amendment exempts projects to reconstruct any road, highway, railway, bridge, or transit facility that is damaged by an emergency declared by the Governor of the State and concurred in by the Secretary of Homeland Security from any environmental reviews, approvals, licensing, and permit restrictions if reconstruction takes place in the same location and using the same design, capacity, and dimensions as before the emergency.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment printed in Part B of House Report 114-325 to exempt projects to reconstruct any road, highway, railway, bridge, or transit facility that is damaged by an emergency declared by the Governor of the State and concurred in by the Secretary of Homeland Security from any environmental reviews, approvals, licensing, and permit restrictions if reconstruction takes place in the same location and using the same design, capacity, and dimensions as before the emergency.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2015-11-04T13:57:50-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Rothfus amendment (A039) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7650" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-11-03T19:50:53-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A039) offered by Mr. Rothfus to the Rules amendment (A001).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7616-7617" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7616" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-03"/>
    <action datetime="2015-11-04T13:57:50-05:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-03T19:50:53-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A039) offered by Mr. Rothfus to the Rules amendment (A001).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7616-7617" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7616" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-04T13:57:50-05:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Rothfus amendment (A039) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7650" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-03">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
