<bill session="115" type="h" number="4650" updated="2019-04-18T16:19:01Z">
  <state datetime="2017-12-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to develop and make available guidance relating to domestic preparedness for and collective response to terrorism regarding active shooter and mass casualty incident response assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PROTECT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PROTECT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Rational Options Toward the Elimination of Catastrophic Terrorism Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Rational Options Toward the Elimination of Catastrophic Terrorism Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">PROTECT Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000371"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000059" joined="2018-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2017-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2017-12-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-12-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-12-14T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Providing Rational Options Toward the Elimination of Catastrophic Terrorism Act of 2017 or the PROTECT Act

This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct: (1) the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to develop and provide guidance on terrorism preparedness and response to assist in the development of plans for addressing active shooter and mass casualty incidents, including in facilities identified by DHS as vulnerable targets; and (2) the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to consider the threat from active shooters in allocating grant funds under the Urban Area Security Initiative and the State Homeland Security Grant Program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
