<bill session="114" type="h" number="691" updated="2018-11-21T21:22:55Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Telehealth Modernization Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote the provision of telehealth by establishing a Federal standard for telehealth, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Telehealth Modernization Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001163"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000454" joined="2015-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000292" joined="2015-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Telehealth Modernization Act of 2015

Calls for states to authorize health care professionals to deliver health care to individuals through telehealth and consider adopting conditions under which a health care professional delivering care through telehealth should:

 have access to the individual's medical history and should review it with the individual as if delivering the health care in person; attempt to identify any conditions underlying the symptoms reported by the individual before providing any diagnosis or treatment and, if recommending a treatment, should review with the individual the contraindications; have a conversation with the individual adequate to establish any diagnosis rendered; document any evaluation and treatment delivered to the individual to generate a medical record of the encounter; provide to the individual information regarding the professional's health care education, certification, and credentials; offer no assurance to the individual that any item or service will be issued or provided in exchange for the payment of the consultation fee or solely in response to the individual completing a form or questionnaire; and only issue a prescription if it is issued by a health care professional who has obtained a medical history and conducted an evaluation of the individual adequate to establish a diagnosis, not for certain controlled substances, and filled by a licensed dispensing entity.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
