<bill session="113" type="h" number="4400" updated="2016-10-25T16:12:14Z">
  <state datetime="2014-04-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Data Accountability and Trust Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect consumers by requiring reasonable security policies and procedures to protect data containing personal information, and to provide for nationwide notice in the event of a security breach.</title>
    <title type="display">Data Accountability and Trust Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000515"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000213" joined="2014-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2014-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000563" joined="2014-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001166" joined="2014-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2014-04-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1193"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1976"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2025"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-04-04T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Data Accountability and Trust Act - Requires the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to promulgate regulations requiring each person engaged in interstate commerce that owns or possesses data containing personal information to establish specified security policies and procedures to treat and protect such information.

Requires the regulations to include methods for disposing of both electronic and nonelectronic data.

Requires information brokers to submit their security policies to the FTC in conjunction with a notification of a security breach notification or on FTC request. Authorizes the FTC to conduct information security practices audits of brokers who have had a security breach or require such brokers to conduct independent audits.

Requires information brokers to: (1) establish procedures to verify the accuracy of information that identifies individuals, (2) provide to individuals whose personal information it maintains a means to review it, (3) place a conspicuous notice on the Internet instructing individuals how to request access to such information, and (4) correct inaccurate information.

Directs the FTC to require information brokers to establish measures which facilitate the auditing or retracing of access to, or transmissions of, any data containing personal information.

Makes it unlawful for information brokers to obtain or disclose personal information by false pretenses (pretexting).

Requires such person to notify the FTC and affected individuals of information security breaches. Sets forth requirements concerning such notification, including method of notification requirements and timeliness requirements. Allows an exemption from notification requirements if such person determines that there is no reasonable risk of identity theft, fraud, or other unlawful conduct.

Preempts state information security laws.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
