<bill session="114" type="h" number="5316" updated="2019-02-13T17:31:25Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Healthy Soils and Rangelands Solutions Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a carbon sequestration pilot program under which the Secretary of the Interior may make grants for projects to evaluate methods to increase the amount of carbon captured on qualified public lands in order to achieve a wide range of benefits, including reductions in greenhouse gases, increased water retention and water quality in watersheds, nutrient cycling, reduced erosion, and forage quality.</title>
    <title type="display">Healthy Soils and Rangelands Solutions Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001068"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-24T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Healthy Soils and Rangelands Solutions Act

This bill directs the Department of the Interior, through the Bureau of Land Management, to establish a Carbon Sequestration Pilot Program to make grants to owners or operators of qualified public lands, universities, nongovernmental organizations, or Indian tribes for projects for sequestering carbon through:

 grazing practices, restoring degraded qualified public lands, application of compost on qualified public lands, or using biochar (carbonized biomass) as an amendment on qualified public lands. Interior shall establish a science advisory board to furnish analysis and recommendations regarding:

 the selection of such eligible entities and activities to receive grants based on the best available science, and appropriate monitoring requirements to quantify project performance and communicate results. Interior shall make grants, through a challenge competition, to eligible entities for projects to carry out innovative approaches to eligible activities.

Interior:

 may furnish technical assistance for eligible activities, and shall expand outreach and education respecting carbon sequestration and best practices related to those activities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
