<bill session="114" type="s" number="3079" updated="2018-08-16T22:54:10Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fairness, Accountability, and Certainty for Taxpayers in Coal Leasing Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the management of the Federal coal leasing program.</title>
    <title type="display">Fairness, Accountability, and Certainty for Taxpayers in Coal Leasing Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fairness, Accountability, and Certainty for Taxpayers in Coal Leasing Act

This bill establishes a deadline for the Department of the Interior to complete a comprehensive review of the federal coal leasing program.The review, in the form of a Programmatic Environmental Impact Statement, is designed to ensure that the federal coal program is properly structured to provide a fair return to taxpayers and toreflect its impacts on the environment, while continuing to helpmeet energy needs.

In addition, Interior shall reestablish the Royalty Policy Committee to ensure consultation among state, tribal, environmental, energy, and federal stakeholders.The committee must provide advice to Interior on the management of federal and Indian mineral leases and shall be composed of federal and non-federal members.

The bill also requires Interior to authorize earlier emergency coal leasing than is currently authorized under federal regulations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
