<bill session="115" type="s" number="1914" updated="2019-04-18T16:39:28Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-10-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act in order to strengthen rules in case of competition for diabetic testing strips, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Access to Diabetes Supplies Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Access to Diabetes Supplies Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Protecting Access to Diabetes Supplies Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000805"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2017-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2017-12-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-10-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1892"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3271"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-10-04T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting Access to Diabetes Supplies Act of 2017

This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to modify provisions relating to Medicare's competitive acquisition&#160;program&#160;(through which rates are set through a competitive bidding program rather than by an established fee schedule) with respect to diabetic testing strips. Specifically, the bill requires the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS)&#160;to:

 use specified data to determine whether a bid satisfies certain requirements related to volume of coverage with respect to such products, reject a bid if the bidder does not demonstrate its ability to furnish such products in a manner consistent with its bid, and establish a process to monitor the extent to which an entity continues to cover the product types included in its bid. The CMS may terminate a contract if it determines that an entity, for reasons other than product discontinuation, market-wide shortage,&#160;or introduction of a newer model,&#160;fails to maintain ready access to such products included its bid.

In addition, the bill specifies that an entity furnishing such products to beneficiaries under the program: (1)&#160;must furnish to each beneficiary a brand of strips that is compatible with the beneficiary's home blood glucose monitor, (2) may not attempt to influence or incentivize a beneficiary&#160;to switch the brand of either type of product, and (3) must contact and receive a request from a beneficiary no more than 14 days prior to dispensing a refill to the beneficiary.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
