<bill session="114" type="sr" number="442" updated="2018-06-02T06:20:09Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-12">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution condemning the terrorist attacks in Brussels and honoring the memory of the United States citizens murdered in those attacks, and offering thoughts and prayers for all the victims, condolences to their families, resolve to support the Belgian people, and the pledge to defend democracy and stand in solidarity with the country of Belgium and all our allies in the face of continuing terrorist attacks on freedom and liberty.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution condemning the terrorist attacks in Brussels and honoring the memory of the United States citizens murdered in those attacks, and offering thoughts and prayers for all the victims, condolences to their families, resolve to support the Belgian people, and the pledge to defend democracy and stand in solidarity with the country of Belgium and all our allies in the face of continuing terrorist attacks on freedom and liberty.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2016-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2016-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2016-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2495-2496" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-04-28">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Corker without amendment and with a preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="452">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 452.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2016-05-12" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2794" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Belgium"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-12T17:44:49Z" status="Passed Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Condemns the terrorist attacks on March 22, 2016, in Brussels, Belgium.

 Honors the memories of Justin and Stephanie Shults, Alexander and Sascha Pinczowski, and Gail Martinez, who were murdered by the Islamic State in these attacks.

 Expresses deepest sympathies for the victims and their families.

 Renews the solidarity of the government and people of the United States with the people and the leadership of Belgium, as well as with those throughout the world who work to eliminate terrorism.

 Pledges U.S. support to Belgium, Europe, and all U.S. allies in the effort to defeat the Islamic State and associated groups.

 Reaffirms the Senate's commitment to the transatlantic relationship and the shared values of freedom, democracy, and human rights.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
