<bill session="115" type="s" number="853" updated="2019-04-18T16:34:54Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to identify and combat corruption in countries, to establish a tiered system of countries with respect to levels of corruption by their governments and their efforts to combat such corruption, and to assess United States assistance to designated countries in order to advance anti-corruption efforts in those countries and better serve United States taxpayers.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Combating Global Corruption Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Combating Global Corruption Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Combating Global Corruption Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2017-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2017-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2017-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2017-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2017-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2017-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2017-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2017-04-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Combating Global Corruption Act of 2017

This bill directs the the Department of State to annually publish on a publicly accessible website a three-tiered ranking based upon the extent of compliance by a foreign country's government with the minimum anti-corruption standards prescribed in this bill.

The bill states that a government is complying with such standards if it:

 has enacted and judicially enforces laws, and has established structures and practices, that prohibit corruption; prescribes punishment for grand corruption that is commensurate with the punishment for serious crimes; prescribes punishment for petty corruption that provides a sufficient deterrent and reflects the nature of the offense; and is making sustained anti-corruption efforts. The State Department shall, prior to the obligation of any foreign assistance (except humanitarian, disaster, and anti-corruption assistance) to a tier 3 country:

 conduct a corruption risk assessment and create a corruption mitigation strategy for all foreign assistance programs to that country, require the inclusion of anti-corruption clauses for all foreign assistance contracts and grants, require the inclusion of clawback clauses for all foreign assistance contracts and grants to recover U.S. taxpayer funds that have been misappropriated through corruption, require disclosure of the beneficial ownership of all entities receiving foreign assistance funding, and establish a mechanism for investigating allegations of misappropriated foreign assistance funds or equipment. The State Department and the U.S. Agency for International Development shall: (1) consolidate existing reports with anti-corruption components into one online, public platform; and (2) incorporate anti-corruption components into existing Foreign Service and Civil Service training courses.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
