<bill session="113" type="h" number="2261" updated="2016-10-25T16:04:20Z">
  <state datetime="2013-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Mitigation Fisheries Coordination Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure the continuation of successful fisheries mitigation programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">National Mitigation Fisheries Coordination Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001093" joined="2014-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2014-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000567" joined="2013-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000582" joined="2013-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000796" joined="2013-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000413" joined="2013-11-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water, Power and Oceans" code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" code="HSII22" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" code="HSPW07" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="West Virginia"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-06-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">National Mitigation Fisheries Coordination Act - Directs the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (USFWS) to impose a charge for conducting mitigation fishery activities in connection with federal water resources development projects carried out by water development agencies (Army Corps of Engineers, the Bureau of Reclamation, or the Tennessee Valley Authority [TVA]). Requires such agencies to pay the charge in accordance with a fishery mitigation plan developed and approved by the USFWS Director and the agency head.

Defines "mitigation fishery activities" as rearing and stocking of native and nonnative fish to replace or maintain fishery resources or harvest levels lost as a result of such a project, including project planning, population assessment and evaluation, genetic monitoring, broodstock development, and fish health sampling.

Requires USFWS's charges to be reasonably related to expenditures necessary to: (1) operate, maintain, and rehabilitate certain USFWS-owned and -operated mitigation fishery facilities, hatcheries, and health centers; and (2) conduct mitigation fishery activities, including expenditures for personnel, transportation, utilities, contractual services, fish feed, supplies, equipment, routine maintenance, deferred maintenance, fish eggs, technical support, fish health, management and administration, planning, outreach and education, and hatchery product evaluations.

Sets forth a listing of applicable mitigation fishery facilities in Arkansas, Georgia, Kentucky, Missouri, Montana, North Dakota, Pennsylvania, South Dakota, Tennessee, Utah, West Virginia, Wisconsin, and Wyoming.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
