<bill session="114" type="h" number="2841" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:14Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Access for Safe and Timely Generics Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FAST Generics Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to ensure that eligible product developers have competitive access to approved drugs and licensed biological products, so as to enable eligible product developers to develop and test new products, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">FAST Generics Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001187"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2015-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000197" joined="2015-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000449" joined="2015-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2015-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001180" joined="2015-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000586" joined="2015-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2015-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000462" joined="2015-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2015-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Fair Access for Safe and Timely Generics Act of 2015 or the FAST Generics Act of 2015

This bill amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to prohibit the license holder of a Food and Drug Administration (FDA)-approved drug or biological product from restricting availability of the medication for testing by a product developer seeking to develop a drug, generic drug, or biosimilar, including restricting availability with a risk evaluation and mitigation strategy (REMS).

Upon request, the license holder of a medication that is not subject to a REMS must provide a product developer with the medication for testing.

For a medication subject to a REMS, a product developer must have FDA authorization to obtain the medication before the license holder must provide it. The FDA may authorize a product developer to conduct testing and clinical trials with the medication.

A wholesaler or specialty distributor who receives a request from a product developer for a medication for testing may not disclose to the license holder the identity of the product developer. The FDA may prohibit or limit transfer of a medication to a product developer if the transfer poses an imminent hazard to public health.

License holders are not liable for claims arising from a product developer testing the medication.

The FDA may waive the requirement that a drug use a single, shared system of elements to assure safe use with a comparable approved drug if the product developer is unable to finalize terms for a shared system with the license holder of the approved drug.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
