<amendment session="113" chamber="h" number="1116" updated="2016-10-25T12:45:55Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4984" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2014-07-24T13:07:46-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000363"/>
  <offered datetime="2014-07-24"/>
  <description>Amendment clarifies the information provided to first-time borrowers; clarifies that borrowers must accept their loans annually after the completion of the other counseling requirements; requires that the Secretary of Education, acting through the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences, must conduct a longitudinal study of the impact and effectiveness of the student loan counseling required under this act; and makes other technical corrections.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment No. 1 printed in part B of House Report 113-546 to clarify the information provided to first-time borrowers; clarify that borrowers must accept their loans annually after the completion of the other counseling requirements; require that the Secretary of Education, acting through the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences, must conduct a longitudinal study of the impact and effectiveness of the student loan counseling required under this act; and other minor technical edits.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2014-07-24T13:07:46-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Kline amendment (A001) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24T13:03:26-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Kline.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6763" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6763" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24"/>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24T13:03:26-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Kline.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6763" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6763" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24T13:07:46-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24T13:07:46-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Kline amendment (A001) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
