<bill session="113" type="hr" number="34" updated="2016-10-25T15:54:21Z">
  <state datetime="2013-01-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Calling on the United States and Russia to continue cooperation in securing safe and loving homes for unparented children.</title>
    <title type="display">Calling on the United States and Russia to continue cooperation in securing safe and loving homes for unparented children.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000522"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000451" joined="2013-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000804" joined="2014-01-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Europe, Eurasia, and Emerging Threats.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Europe, Eurasia, and Emerging Threats" code="HSFA14" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-01-15T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Appeals to the Russian government to allow the adoptions initiated before January 1, 2013, to proceed to conclusion, and invites Russia to continue participation in the bilateral adoption agreement that went into force November 1, 2012.

Expresses deep sadness over the deaths in the United States of 19 adopted Russian children and over the other cases of abuse.

 Celebrates the tens of thousands of U.S. families who have opened their homes and hearts to Russian children.

Affirms the extensive work of the Russian Foreign Ministry and the Department of State to create safeguards against future abuse through such bilateral adoption agreement.

Urges federal, state, and local governments and adoptive families to accommodate official inquiries into the well-being of adopted Russian children and to comply with all adoption requirements delineated by the bilateral agreement.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
