<bill session="113" type="h" number="253" updated="2016-10-25T15:57:41Z">
  <state datetime="2013-06-17T19:04:23-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-06-17T19:04:23-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Y Mountain Access Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Y Mountain Access Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Y Mountain Access Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the conveyance of a small parcel of National Forest System land in the Uinta-Wasatch-Cache National Forest in Utah to Brigham Young University, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To provide for the conveyance of approximately 80 acres of National Forest System land in the Uinta-Wasatch-Cache National Forest in Utah to Brigham Young University, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Y Mountain Access Enhancement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001076"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-24">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-04-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-98.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-06-06" calendar="Union" number="68">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 68.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-06-17T17:17:26-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bishop (UT) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-17T17:17:38-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3661-3663" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-17T17:17:40-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 253.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-17T17:24:16-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-17T18:58:12-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3667-3668" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="246" datetime="2013-06-17T19:04:23-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 397 - 1 (Roll no. 246).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3661-3662" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-06-17T19:04:24-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-17T19:04:28-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-18">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="identical" number="28"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-06-17T13:06:22Z" status="Passed House amended">Y Mountain Access Enhancement Act - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA), upon request by Brigham Young University, to convey an approximately 80-acre parcel of National Forest System land in the Uinta-Wasatch-Cache National Forest in Utah.

Requires the University to pay to the Secretary an amount equal to the fair market value of such land. Requires such consideration to be deposited in the general Treasury fund to reduce the federal deficit.

Directs the University, after the conveyance, to represent that it will: (1) continue allowing the same reasonable public access to the trailhead, and the part of the Y Mountain Trail already owned by the University, as has been historically allowed; and (2) allow such access to the part of the Trail and the "Y" symbol located on the conveyed land.

Requires the exact acreage and legal description of the conveyed land to be determined by a survey that is satisfactory to the Secretary.

Requires Brigham Young University to pay the costs of the survey and appraisal and any administrative analyses required by law.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 113-98</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
