<bill session="114" type="h" number="5731" updated="2018-11-09T00:09:34Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAVE UP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Secure, Accessible, Valuable, Efficient Universal Pension Accounts Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish SAVE UP Accounts, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SAVE UP Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001038"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business expenses"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Secure, Accessible, Valuable, Efficient Universal Pension Accounts Act or the SAVE UP Act 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish the SAVE UP Account program to provide tax-exempt retirement accounts to employees who are not otherwise eligible for certain retirement plans.

The bill establishes: (1) a board of trustees to create and manage the accounts, (2) a board of governors to establish policies for the investment and management of fund assets, and (3) a trust fund and accounts in the Treasury for the program.

An employer must establish an account contribution program if: (1) the employer's aggregate number of employee hours of service during the preceding year was at least 1,600; (2) the employer does not offer a retirement plan to all employees. Government entities and churches are exempt from this requirement.

Under the contribution program, employers must: (1) contribute at least 50 cents per hour worked by the employee; and (2) make automatic contributions on behalf of employees who do not opt-out, beginning with 3% of wages and eventually increasing to 5%.

The bill sets forth requirements for: (1) determining an employee's share of positive net investment returns, and (2) paying benefits from the accounts in the form of an annuity

The bill allows a tax credit for certain small employers who elect to set up contribution programs for their employees.

If an employer fails to maintain a required contribution program, the bill disallows the deduction for compensation for services performed by employees of the employer.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
