<bill session="113" type="h" number="4709" updated="2016-10-25T16:13:29Z">
  <state datetime="2014-07-29T14:57:19-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-07-29T14:57:19-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Patient Access and Effective Drug Enforcement Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Ensuring Patient Access and Effective Drug Enforcement Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve enforcement efforts related to prescription drug diversion and abuse, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Ensuring Patient Access and Effective Drug Enforcement Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001179"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000369" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2014-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2014-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001093" joined="2014-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2014-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000567" joined="2014-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001065" joined="2014-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000292" joined="2014-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000566" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000244" joined="2014-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000583" joined="2014-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2014-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 113-605, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T14:37:25-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Pitts moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T14:37:40-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7004-7007" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T14:37:42-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4709.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2014-07-29T14:57:19-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7004-7005" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T14:57:21-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="4069"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2862"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-07-29T13:17:27Z" status="Passed House amended">Ensuring Patient Access and Effective Drug Enforcement Act of 2014 - Amends the Controlled Substances Act to define: (1) "factors as may be relevant to and consistent with the public health and safety," for purposes of the Attorney General's determination of whether registering an applicant to manufacture or distribute a controlled substance in schedule I or II is in the public interest, as factors that are relevant to and consistent with the findings of such Act; and (2) "imminent danger to the public health or safety," for purposes of the suspension of such a registration, to mean that in the absence of an immediate suspension order, controlled substances will continue to be intentionally diverted outside of legitimate distribution channels or distributed or dispensed outside the usual course of professional practices or in a manner that poses a present or foreseeable risk of serious adverse health consequences or death.

Requires an order to show cause as to why such a registration should not be denied, revoked, or suspended to: (1) contain a statement of the basis for the denial, revocation, or suspension, including specific citations to any laws or regulations alleged to be violated; (2) direct the applicant or registrant to appear before the Attorney General at a specific place and time within 30 days after receipt of the order; and (3) notify the applicant or registrant of the opportunity to submit a corrective action plan on or before such appearance. Requires the Attorney General, upon review of any such plan, to determine whether denial, revocation, or suspension proceedings should be discontinued or deferred for purposes of modifications to such plan. Makes such requirements inapplicable to the issuance of an immediate suspension order.

Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs (FDA) and the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to submit a report identifying: (1) obstacles to legitimate patient access to controlled substances; (2) issues with diversion of controlled substances; and (3) how collaboration between federal, state, local, and tribal law enforcement agencies and the pharmaceutical industry can benefit patients and prevent diversion and abuse of controlled substances.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 113-605</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
