<bill session="114" type="h" number="2176" updated="2019-05-09T23:32:57Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To extend Federal recognition to the Duwamish Tribe, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Duwamish Tribal Recognition Act</title>
    <title type="display">Duwamish Tribal Recognition Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000404"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E636-637"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indigenous Peoples of the United States" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Duwamish Tribal Recognition Act

 Extends federal recognition to the Duwamish Tribe.

Makes the Tribe and its members eligible for all services and benefits provided by the federal government to federally recognized tribes without regard to the existence of a reservation for the Tribe or the location of the residence of any member on or near any Indian reservation. Defines the Tribe's service area for purposes of the delivery of federal services.

Requires the Tribe to submit to the Department of the Interior a membership roll of all individuals enrolled in the Tribe.

Requires the Tribe to conduct an election by secret ballot to adopt a constitution and bylaws for the Tribe. Requires the Tribe to elect a governing body in accordance with the procedures set forth in its constitution and bylaws.

Requires Interior to take Tribe service area or aboriginal lands into trust for the benefit of the Tribe if the Tribe transfers all interest in and to the land to Interior within ten years. Requires Interior and the Department of Agriculture to identify those lands which shall be considered the aboriginal homelands of the Tribe.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
