<bill session="114" type="h" number="5595" updated="2018-06-02T05:25:33Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reservoir Operations Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, to revise the water manuals of certain flood control projects, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Reservoir Operations Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2016-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2016-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2016-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001166" joined="2016-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2016-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2016-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001175" joined="2016-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2016-07-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hydrology and hydrography"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Reservoir Operations Improvement Act

This bill directs the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers to submit a report with respect to each drought state (a state for which the governor has declared a drought or that contains at least one county for which the Department of Agriculture has designated a drought disaster) during water year 2015 or 2016 that includes:

 a list of flood control projects in such state; the year during which the original water manual (water operations manuals, flood control rule curves, and water control manuals) for each project was approved; the years during which any revisions to a project's water manual occurred or are requested to occur; a list of projects for which operational deviations for drought contingency, and changes to storage allocations, have been requested and the status of such requests; and a description of the means by which water conservation and water quality improvements were addressed in any response to such requests. The Corps of Engineers shall: (1) identify each project included in the report that includes a reservoir and for which a non-federal interest has submitted a written request to revise the project's water manual; (2) revise the water manuals of not more than 15 of such projects; and (3) in collaboration with the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, create a forecast-informed reservoir operations plan for each selected project. The water manual revision shall incorporate such plan, new watershed data, and the effects of any structural improvement completed after the date of the most recent prior revision of the water manual.

 A revision of a water manual may not reduce the water supply for any authorized purpose, other than flood control, of a flood control project.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
