<bill session="114" type="h" number="492" updated="2018-11-21T21:22:57Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ultrasound Informed Consent Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that women seeking an abortion receive an ultrasound and the opportunity to review the ultrasound before giving informed consent to receive an abortion.</title>
    <title type="display">Ultrasound Informed Consent Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000615"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000448" joined="2015-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000563" joined="2015-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001058" joined="2015-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2015-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000566" joined="2015-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001189" joined="2015-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001144" joined="2015-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000186" joined="2015-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000588" joined="2015-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000582" joined="2015-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000604" joined="2015-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-22T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Ultrasound Informed Consent Act

Amends the Public Health Service Act to require abortion providers, before a woman gives informed consent to any part of an abortion, to perform an obstetric ultrasound on the pregnant woman, provide a simultaneous explanation of what the ultrasound is depicting, display the ultrasound images so the woman may view them, and provide a complete medical description of the images, including the dimensions of the embryo or fetus, cardiac activity if present and visible, and the presence of external members and internal organs if present and viewable.

Prohibits construing this Act to require a woman to view the images or penalizing the provider or the woman if she declines to look at the images.

Exempts an abortion provider if the abortion is necessary to save the life of a woman whose life is endangered by a physical condition. Requires the provider to include in the woman's medical file a certification of the specific medical circumstances that support this determination.

Authorizes the Attorney General to commence a civil action in federal court against any abortion provider who knowingly violates this Act. Prescribes penalties. Directs the Attorney General to notify the appropriate state medical licensing authority of penalties assessed. Authorizes a woman upon whom an abortion has been performed in violation of this Act to commence a civil action against the provider for actual and punitive damages.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
