<bill session="113" type="h" number="5018" updated="2016-10-25T16:14:47Z">
  <state datetime="2014-07-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Reserve Accountability and Transparency Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Reserve Act to establish requirements for policy rules and blackout periods of the Federal Open Market Committee, to establish requirements for certain activities of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Federal Reserve Accountability and Transparency Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001058"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001256" joined="2014-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001282" joined="2014-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001250" joined="2014-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001262" joined="2014-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000266" joined="2014-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000614" joined="2014-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000458" joined="2014-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000456" joined="2014-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000448" joined="2014-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000548" joined="2014-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000552" joined="2014-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000567" joined="2014-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001057" joined="2014-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001059" joined="2014-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000296" joined="2014-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000362" joined="2014-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000573" joined="2014-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2014-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001189" joined="2014-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001182" joined="2014-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000588" joined="2014-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2014-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000582" joined="2014-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001186" joined="2014-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001188" joined="2014-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000816" joined="2014-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-07">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-10">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 32 - 26.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1062"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="3928"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="International monetary system and foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Monetary policy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-07-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Reserve Accountability and Transparency Act of 2014 - Amends the Federal Reserve Act (FRA) to direct the Chairman of the Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) to submit to the Comptroller General (GAO) and to certain congressional committees a Directive Policy Rule (DPR), including an identification of FOMC members who voted in its favor.

Defines DPR as a policy rule developed by the FOMC that meets specified requirements and provides the basis for the Open Market Operations Directive.

Directs GAO to study whether the DPR has materially changed, audit any materially changed DPR, and report to certain congressional committees on whether the ensuing DPR and the FOMC are in compliance with this Act.

Requires the Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (Federal Reserve Board) to testify before certain congressional committees as to why non-compliance with this Act, if any, exists.

Establishes a one-week blackout period during which permissible public communications by FOMC members and staff are restricted with respect to: (1) macroeconomic or financial developments; or (2) current, or prospective monetary policy issues.

Amends the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (Dodd-Frank) to direct the Federal Reserve Board to issue regulations, after public notice and comment, that provide for the at least three different sets of conditions (baseline, adverse, and severely adverse) and related methodologies required under current law for the evaluation of nonbank financial companies and certain bank holding companies with over $50 billion in assets.

Directs the Federal Reserve Board to disclose publicly the aggregate number of supervisory letters sent to such bank holding companies, including the aggregate number of such letters designated as either "Matters Requiring Attention" or "Matters Requiring Immediate Attention."

Increases from semi-annual to quarterly the number of times the Chairman of the Federal Reserve Board is required to give testimony to Congress.

Amends the FRA to require the Vice Chairman for Supervision to give written testimony on the status of all pending and anticipated rulemakings made by the Board.

Requires the Federal Reserve Board, before issuing any regulation, to assess the costs and benefits of available regulatory alternatives and choose the approach that maximizes net benefits and is tailored to impose the least impact on the availability of credit, economic growth, and the least burden on society.

Prescribes the contents of a post-adoption impact assessment plan the Board must develop whenever it adopts or amends a major rule.

Amends the FRA to prescribe ethics standards governing Federal Reserve Board members and employees, including requirements for disclosure of staff salaries and financial information.

Prescribes requirements for Federal Reserve Board negotiations with any foreign or multinational entity.

Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to prescribe requirements for negotiations by the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) with any foreign or multinational entity.

Directs the Secretary of the Treasury, as a prerequisite to entering into negotiations with any foreign or multinational entity, to notify and consult with certain congressional committees regarding the nature of the agreement and its anticipated effects upon the economy.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
