<bill session="114" type="s" number="826" updated="2018-06-02T06:44:09Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Regulatory Examination Vital for Improving and Evaluating Working Solutions Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REVIEWS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 5, United States Code, to sunset rules after 10 years unless agencies undergo notice and comment rulemaking, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">REVIEWS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000618"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1668" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1668-1669" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Federal appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-19T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Regulatory Examination Vital for Improving and Evaluating Working Solutions Act of 2015 or the REVIEWS Act

This bill makes existing rules of a federal agency (i.e. each authority of the federal government, except the Congress, U.S. courts, the governments of U.S. territories or possessions, and the government of the District of Columbia) inoperative 10 years after promulgation, but allows extensions for additional periods of not more than 10 years if the agency promulgates the expiring rule in compliance with the notice and comment requirements of the Administrative Procedure Act.

The bill expands the definition of "final agency action" for purposes of judicial review to include interpretative rules, general statements of policy, and rules of agency organization, procedure or practice issued by an agency.

The bill grants exclusive jurisdiction to the federal courts of appeal (except for the Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit) to review all rules of an agency that cease to be effective under this Act and that the agency continues to enforce.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
