<bill session="114" type="s" number="3377" updated="2018-06-02T07:48:20Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancing Military and Police Operations through Women's Engagement and Recruitment Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase the participation of women in foreign security forces, specifically the military and police, with United States foreign assistance.</title>
    <title type="display">Enhancing Military and Police Operations through Women's Engagement and Recruitment Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000711"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2016-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Enhancing Military and Police Operations through Women's Engagement and Recruitment Act of 2016

This bill requires the Department of State, in coordination with the Department of Defense (DOD), to seek to increase the participation of women receiving training under the International Military Education and Training program at U.S. military schools and training institutions, with the goal of doubling female participation globally by September 30, 2019.

The State Department shall seek to increase the participation of women receiving training under its Anti-Terrorism Assistance (ATA) programs, with the goal of doubling the total women receiving such training by September 30, 2019, and make explicit in its mandate for ATA programs its priority to increase women's participation.

State shall work with partner countries receiving peacekeeping training assistance to: (1) prioritize the integration, training, and deployment of qualified female peacekeepers in peace operations; (2) prioritize the employment, development, and integration of female peacekeeping trainers; and (3) double the number of qualified women deployed to peace operations within five years.

State also shall:

 promote an increase in the recruitment, retention, and leadership roles of female personnel assigned to United Nations peacekeeping missions; establish female participation requirements for its police training programs and work with partner countries to ensure that women account for at least 10% of nominees for U.S.-funded police training programs; make explicit its priority to increase women's participation in the design and implementation of all police training programs; develop a plan for the monitoring and independent evaluation of programs, projects, and activities carried out under this bill; and designate officials to brief Congress regarding actions taken under this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
