<bill session="115" type="h" number="5078" updated="2019-04-18T16:20:33Z">
  <state datetime="2018-02-27T15:50:43-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-02-27T15:50:43-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-02-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act of 1974 to modify requirements related to mortgage disclosures, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">TRID Improvement Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">TRID Improvement Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TRID Improvement Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TRID Improvement Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">TRID Improvement Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001072"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-02-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-27T15:35:55-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Hill moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-27T15:36:02-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1306-1308" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-27T15:36:03-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5078.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2018-02-27T15:50:43-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1306" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-02-27T15:50:45-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="6147"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3040"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="435"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3978"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2490"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="488"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-02-27T14:16:14Z" status="Passed House amended">TRID Improvement Act of 2018

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Real Estate Settlement Procedures of 1974 to modify disclosure requirements&#160;applicable to mortgage loan transactions. Specifically, the disclosed charges for any title insurance premium shall be equal to the amount charged for each individual title insurance policy, subject to any discounts as required by either state regulation or the title company rate filings.

(Sec. 3) The bill amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to allow the reporting of certain positive consumer-credit information to consumer reporting agencies. Specifically, a person or the Department of Housing and Urban Development may report information related to a consumer's performance in making payments either under a lease agreement for a dwelling or pursuant to a contract for a utility or telecommunications service. However, information about a consumer's usage of any utility or telecommunications service may be reported only to the extent that the information relates to payment by the consumer for such service or other terms of the provision of that service. Furthermore, an energy-utility firm may not report a consumer's outstanding balance as late if the firm and the consumer have entered into a payment plan and the consumer is meeting the obligations of that plan.

Specified provisions of the Consumer Credit Protection Act that establish civil liability with respect to furnishers of information to consumer reporting agencies shall not apply to any violation of the bill.

The Government Accountability Office must report on the consumer impact of such reporting.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
