<bill session="114" type="h" number="5318" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:36Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SHIELD Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Solidifying Habitual and Institutional Explanations of Liability and Defenses Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Trade Commission Act to specify certain effects of guidelines, general statements of policy, and similar guidance issued by the Federal Trade Commission.</title>
    <title type="display">SHIELD Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000602"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001293" joined="2016-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2016-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001248" joined="2016-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001045" joined="2016-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000567" joined="2016-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001190" joined="2016-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5118"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5510"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-24T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Solidifying Habitual and Institutional Explanations of Liability and Defenses Act of 2016 or the SHIELD Act of 2016

This bill amends the Federal Trade Commission Act to prohibit the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) guidelines or general statements of policy related either to unfair methods of competition, or to unfair or deceptive acts or practices, in or affecting commerce from: (1) conferring rights upon any person, state, or locality; or (2) binding the FTC or any person, state, or locality to a recommended approach.

In enforcement actions, the FTC must prove a violation of a law enforced by the FTC. The FTC's enforcement actions or consent orders may not be based solely on allegations that acts or practices are inconsistent with guidelines or general policy statements unless the acts or practices violate FTC-enforced law.

Compliance with guidelines or general statements of policy may be used as evidence of compliance with a law under which the guidelines or statements were issued.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
