<bill session="114" type="h" number="2153" updated="2019-04-11T15:42:41Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reclassify certain low-level felonies as misdemeanors, to eliminate the increased penalties for cocaine offenses where the cocaine involved is cocaine base, to reinvest in our communities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reclassification to Ensure Smarter and Equal Treatment Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RESET Act</title>
    <title type="display">RESET Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2015-11-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="1138"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1255"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1610"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Reclassification to Ensure Smarter and Equal Treatment Act of 2015 or the RESET Act

 Amends the Controlled Substances Act (CSA) to reduce penalties (to not greater than a one-year term of imprisonment and/or a $1,000 fine) for simple possession of a controlled substance by a person who has one or more prior convictions for a controlled substance offense.

Repeals a provision providing for up to three years' imprisonment for the possession of flunitrazepam. Revises penalties for possession of drugs classified as date rape drugs after a prior drug-related conviction.

Reduces the maximum term of imprisonment (to one year) for the sale, use of the mails to transport, or importation or exportation of drug paraphernalia.

Eliminates provisions of the CSA and the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act that apply the same penalties applicable to offenses involving a specified amount of a substance containing cocaine to offenses involving a lesser amount of a substance containing cocaine base.

Amends the CSA to provide that in determining the weight of a controlled substance or mixture of controlled substances that is in a compound with a food product for purposes of provisions concerning controlled substance offenses, the weight of the food product shall not be included.

Makes this Act applicable to any offense committed before its enactment, if a sentence for the offense has not been imposed as of such enactment date. Provides for the reduction of the term of imprisonment of a defendant who was convicted and sentenced before such date for an offense for which the penalty is amended by this Act.

Directs the Sentencing Commission to review and, if appropriate, amend the federal sentencing guidelines and policy statements applicable to any person convicted of an offense affected by this Act.

Establishes within the Department of Justice the Safe Neighborhoods and Schools Fund, which (subject to specified limitations) shall be disbursed as follows by August 15 of each fiscal year beginning in 2016:

 15% to the Department of Education to administer a grant program to public agencies aimed at improving outcomes for public school pupils in kindergarten and grades 1 to 12 by reducing truancy and supporting students who are at risk of dropping out or are victims of crime; 10% to the Federal Crime Victim Assistance Fund to make grants to trauma recovery centers to provide services to victims of crime; 25% to Federal Reentry/Drug Court programs to administer a grant program to public agencies aimed at supporting mental health treatment, substance abuse treatment, and diversion programs for people in the criminal justice system; and 50% to the General Treasury in order to pay down the national debt.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
