<bill session="113" type="h" number="1657" updated="2018-06-05T16:15:43Z">
  <state datetime="2013-04-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to improve the supplemental nutrition assistance program.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to improve the supplemental nutrition assistance program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001188"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001271" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001280" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001052" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001053" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000220" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000186" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000606" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000796" joined="2013-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, and Nutrition.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Commodity Exchanges, Energy, and Credit" code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="identical" number="762"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor and aged"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-04-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to make eligible for the supplemental nutrition assistance program (SNAP, formerly the food stamp program) households in which each member receives cash assistance under the temporary assistance to needy families program (TANF), cash assistance under the supplemental security income program (SSI), or aid to the aged, blind, or disabled program (AABD). (Current law bases categorical SNAP eligibility upon state benefits received rather than such assistance.)

Requires an eligible household that previously received SNAP benefits and applies for program reenrollment to complete a new application and verify that household income and assets are in program compliance.

Limits the employment requirement waiver to areas with an unemployment rate over 10%.

Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to develop a centralized database to facilitate USDA-state agency cooperation in order to ensure that individuals do not enroll for benefits in more than one state.

Requires states that are sanctioned for three consecutive years of improper payments to pay the entire liability amount, with no alternative payment option available.

Eliminates: (1) the exclusion of low-income home energy assistance from SNAP household income determinations, (2) funding of employment and training programs, and (3) bonuses for states with low SNAP allocation error rates.

Provides funding for state nutrition and obesity prevention grant programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
