<bill session="114" type="s" number="2544" updated="2018-06-02T07:14:53Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Illegal Trafficking in Firearms Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase public safety by punishing and deterring firearms trafficking.</title>
    <title type="display">Stop Illegal Trafficking in Firearms Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2016-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2016-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2016-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2016-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S877-879" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-11T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stop Illegal Trafficking in Firearms Act of 2016

This bill amends the federal criminal code to prohibit and punish the straw purchasing of firearms. A straw purchase occurs when: (1) a person buys a firearm from an unlicensed seller on behalf of a person prohibited by law from possessing one, or (2) a person buys a firearm from a licensed dealer on behalf of another person.

Any person that commits, attempts, or conspires to commit a straw purchasing offense is subject to a fine and/or prison term of up to 15 years (25 years if the firearm is used to commit a crime of violence).

The bill expands the penalty for committing a firearms trafficking offense. Individuals who commit such an offense are subject to a fine and/or prison term of up to 15 years. Under current law, the penalty is a fine and/or prison term of up to 10 years.

The U.S. Sentencing Commission shall amend the sentencing guidelines and policy statements to reflect increased penalties for persons convicted of straw purchasing firearms or firearms trafficking offenses.

Under current law, it is unlawful to import firearms into the United States with the intent to engage in illegal activity. This bill extends the prohibition to the exportation of firearms.

The bill makes it unlawful for any person to sell or otherwise dispose of any firearm or ammunition to any person knowing or having reasonable cause to believe that such person intends to transfer the firearm or ammunition in furtherance of a federal crime of terrorism, a crime of violence, or a drug trafficking offense.

Neither the Department of Justice (DOJ) nor its law enforcement coordinate agencies shall facilitate the transfer of an operable firearm to an individual if any DOJ law enforcement officer involved knows or has reasonable cause to believe that the recipient is an agent of a drug cartel, unless U.S. law enforcement personnel continuously monitor or control the firearm at all times.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
