<bill session="114" type="hr" number="636" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:28Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding Burma's 2015 elections.</title>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding Burma's 2015 elections.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000266" joined="2016-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Asia and the Pacific.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Asia and the Pacific" code="HSFA05" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Burma"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Recognizes the Burmese peoples' profound desire for change as reflected in the vote on November 8, 2015.

Acknowledges the important roles played by the international community, Election Day workers, party observers, and domestic election observers in preventing fraud.

Acknowledges that while Burma has taken steps toward democratic rule, constitutional, legal, economic, and security issues remain unresolved.

Expresses concern about ongoing attacks in the Kachin and Shan states and the plight of the Rohingya people.

Urges the government and all other stakeholders to support constitutional reform.

Calls on the President and the Department of State to focus on:

 securing solutions to human rights and humanitarian problems, including fulfillment of the 11 human rights and security commitments made by the current President of Burma to President Obama; supporting changes to structural and systemic impediments to the realization of full democratic and civilian government; bringing about the release of all political prisoners, including those awaiting trial or sentencing; and supporting an end to offensives against ethnic nationalities and the creation of a peaceful federal union acceptable to the people of Burma. Urges the incumbent government to support a timely and peaceful transfer of power to the new government.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
