<bill session="113" type="h" number="5093" updated="2016-10-25T16:15:05Z">
  <state datetime="2014-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Children's Firearm Marketing Safety Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Federal Trade Commission to prescribe rules prohibiting the marketing of firearms to children, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Children's Firearm Marketing Safety Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000385"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Children's Firearm Marketing Safety Act - Directs the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to promulgate rules to prohibit the marketing of firearms to children, including prohibitions against:

 the use of cartoon characters to promote firearms and firearm products, firearm brand name merchandise marketed for children, the use of firearm marketing campaigns with the specific intent to appeal to children, the manufacturing of a gun with colors or designs that are specifically designed to appeal to children, and the manufacturing of a gun intended for use by children that does not clearly and conspicuously note, by specified warnings on the firearm, the risk posed by the firearm by labeling somewhere visible on the firearm. Treats violations of such rules as violations of Federal Trade Commission Act regulations regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices. Provides for enforcement of this Act by the FTC and through civil actions by state attorneys general.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
