<bill session="115" type="h" number="7148" updated="2019-04-18T16:28:25Z">
  <state datetime="2018-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for USA Retirement Funds, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">USA Retirement Funds Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">USA Retirement Funds Act</title>
    <title type="display">USA Retirement Funds Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001090"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-11-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-11-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-11-16T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">USA Retirement Funds Act 

This bill amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to require employers who do not already offer specified retirement plans to provide tax-exempt retirement funds (USA Retirement Fund arrangements) to their employees. The bill includes exemptions for certain small or new employers, governments, and churches.

Employees may elect to contribute to the funds using payroll deductions (or other periodic direct deposits) or to receive payments directly in cash. Unless employees opt out of a fund or elect a different contribution amount, they are automatically enrolled to make contributions that begin with 3% of annual compensation in 2019 and eventually increase to 6% after 2021.

The Department of Labor must review and select retirement plans that qualify for the funds. The bill establishes a board of trustees to administer the funds and a commission to advise Labor regarding the funds.

An employee may not contribute more than $15,000 per year to a fund. Employers may contribute up to $5,000 per year on behalf of an employee. The limits must be adjusted annually for inflation.

The funds must pay benefits to employees in the form of an annuity, in accordance with specified requirements.

The bill establishes limits on withdrawals and transfers from the funds. It also establishes civil and criminal penalties to enforce the requirements for the funds and prevent fraud.

The funds are tax-exempt, and the bill specifies requirements for the tax treatment of contributions, rollover contributions, and distributions. The bill also specifies reporting and disclosure requirements for the funds.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
