<bill session="114" type="s" number="1225" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:56Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Land Asset Inventory Reform Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve Federal land management, resource conservation, environmental protection, and use of Federal real property, by requiring the Secretary of the Interior to develop a multipurpose cadastre of Federal real property and identifying inaccurate, duplicate, and out-of-date Federal land inventories, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Federal Land Asset Inventory Reform Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3121"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Federal Land Asset Inventory Reform Act of 2015 

 Directs the Department of the Interior to develop and maintain a current, accurate multipurpose cadastre of federal real property (an inventory of real property of the federal government) to assist with federal land management activities, including resource development and conservation, agricultural use, active forest management, environmental protection, and use of real property. Authorizes Interior to enter into cost-sharing agreements with states to include any nonfederal land in a state in such cadastre. Limits the federal share of any such agreement to 50% of the total cost to a state for the development of the cadastre of the nonfederal land in the state.

Requires Interior to submit a report, covering all cadastres and inventories authorized, operated, or maintained by all executive agencies, on: (1) existing real property inventories or any components of any cadastre, (2) consolidation of inventories and components, (3) the use of existing inventories and components of any cadastre, (4) cost savings that will be achieved, and (5) recommendations for legislation.

 Requires Interior to: (1) make the cadastre required under this Act available on the Internet in a graphically geoenabled and searchable format; (2) ensure that the inventory required under this Act includes the identification of all lands and parcels suitable for disposal by resource management plans conducted under the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976; and (3) prevent the disclosure of the identity of any one or more parcels of land, buildings or facilities on the parcels or information related to those parcels, if this would impair or jeopardize national security or homeland defense.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
