<bill session="115" type="h" number="6427" updated="2019-04-18T16:26:14Z">
  <state datetime="2018-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve oversight by the Federal Communications Commission of the wireless and broadcast emergency alert systems.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">READI Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">READI Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reliable Emergency Alert Distribution Improvement Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reliable Emergency Alert Distribution Improvement Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">READI Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001050" joined="2018-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2018-10-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-07-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="3238"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-07-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Reliable Emergency Alert Distribution Improvement Act of 2018 or the READI Act

This bill amends the Warning, Alert, and Response Network Act to include emergency alerts from the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) as a type of alert that subscribers of commercial mobile service licensees may not block from their devices (currently, alerts from the President may not be blocked).

The Federal Communications Commission (FCC) must adopt regulations that encourage states to establish a State Emergency Communications Commission (SECC) and provide that each SECC meet at least annually to review and update its Emergency Alert System Plan (State EAS Plan). The FCC must approve or disapprove the updated plan.

FEMA shall develop and issue guidance for state, tribal, and local governments relating to emergency alerts.

 The FCC shall complete: (1) a rulemaking proceeding to establish a system to receive from FEMA or state, tribal, or local governments reports of false alerts under the emergency alert system (EAS) or the Wireless EAS to record such false alerts and examine their causes; (2) a rulemaking proceeding to modify the EAS to provide for repeating messages while an alert remains pending; and (3) an inquiry to examine the feasibility of establishing systems and signaling to offer EAS alerts to audio and video streaming services delivered over the Internet.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
