<bill session="115" type="s" number="972" updated="2019-04-18T16:35:28Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote democracy and the rule of law on Nicaragua, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nicaraguan Investment Conditionality Act (NICA) of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nicaraguan Investment Conditionality Act (NICA) of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Nicaraguan Investment Conditionality Act (NICA) of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2017-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2017-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1918"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2265"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Nicaragua"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Nicaraguan Investment Conditionality Act (NICA) of 2017

This bill directs the President to instruct the U.S. Executive Director at each international financial institution to use U.S. influence to oppose any loan for the government of Nicaragua's benefit, other than for basic human needs or to promote democracy, unless the Department of State certifies that Nicaragua is taking effective steps to:

 hold free elections overseen by credible domestic and international electoral observers; promote democracy and an independent judicial system and electoral council; strengthen the rule of law; respect the right to freedom of association and expression; combat corruption, including investigating and prosecuting government officials credibly alleged to be corrupt; and protect the right of political opposition parties, journalists, trade unionists, human rights defenders, and other civil society activists to operate without interference. The Department of the Treasury shall submit to Congress a report assessing: (1) the effectiveness of the international financial institutions in enforcing applicable program safeguards in Nicaragua, and (2) the effects of specified constitutional and election concerns in Nicaragua on long-term prospects for positive development outcomes there.

The President may waive such requirements in the U.S. national interest.

The bill requires: (1) the President to direct the U.S. Permanent Representative to the Organization of American States to use U.S. influence to advocate for an Electoral Observation Mission to be sent to Nicaragua in 2017, and (2) the State Department to report on the involvement of senior Nicaraguan government officials in acts of public corruption or human rights violations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
