<bill session="114" type="h" number="6316" updated="2018-11-21T20:31:17Z">
  <state datetime="2016-11-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VET Bonus Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Earned Their Bonus Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To stop the Secretary of the Army from recouping a bonus or similar benefit provided to members of the California Army National Guard between January 1, 2004, and December 31, 2010, unless the Secretary can prove that the member knowingly secured the bonus or similar benefit through fraud or misrepresentation or knowingly failed to perform the service requirement upon which the bonus or similar benefit was conditioned, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">VET Bonus Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000612"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000059" joined="2016-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001094" joined="2016-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001048" joined="2016-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000056" joined="2016-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000387" joined="2016-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2016-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001177" joined="2016-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000181" joined="2016-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000409" joined="2016-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000603" joined="2016-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000487" joined="2016-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001175" joined="2016-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000129" joined="2016-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000820" joined="2016-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-11-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-11-15T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans Earned Their Bonus Act or the VET Bonus Act

This bill prohibits the Department of the Army from recouping a bonus or similar benefit that was provided to a member of the California Army National Guard between January 1, 2004, and December 31, 2010, unless the Army proves, after a hearing opportunity, that the member knowingly: (1) participated in fraud or misrepresentation to receive the bonus or benefit, or (2) failed to satisfy the service requirement upon which the bonus or benefit was conditioned.

A member shall be presumed to have acted in good faith in procuring the bonus or benefit and to have satisfied the service requirement.

The Army shall: (1) reimburse a member for any amount previously recouped, plus interest; (2) notify each consumer reporting agency that any debt and recoupment measures linked to the bonus or benefit were not valid; and (3) provide financial assistance to a member who is facing financial hardship because of the recoupment measures.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
