<bill session="114" type="h" number="3854" updated="2018-06-02T04:47:23Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Real Time Transparency Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to require all political committees to notify the Federal Election Commission within 48 hours of receiving cumulative contributions of $1,000 or more from any contributor during a calendar year, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Real Time Transparency Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000170"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="2212"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Real Time Transparency Act of 2015

 This bill amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to revise the requirement of a 48-hour notification of a campaign contribution of $1,000 or more to the Federal Election Commission (FEC) and certain other officials by the principal campaign committee of a candidate for federal office.

(Currently, a candidate's principal campaign committee is required to give a written 48-hour notification to the Secretary of the Senate or the FEC, and the Secretary of State, as appropriate, after the receipt of any contribution of $1,000 or more by any authorized committee of such candidate after the 20th day, but more than 48 hours before, any election.)

This requirement, with certain additions, shall now apply to any political committee, not just a candidate's principal campaign committee, regarding cumulative contributions (instead of single contributions) of $1,000 or more from any contributor during a calendar year. A report shall now be made only to the FEC.

Any amount transferred by a joint fundraising committee established by a candidate's authorized committee to any other authorized committee of that candidate shall be treated as a contribution by the joint fundraising committee to such authorized committee (and thus subject to the 48-hour notification requirement).

Senate candidates must file designations, statements, and reports directly with the FEC (instead of via the Secretary of the Senate, as currently required).</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
