<amendment session="113" chamber="h" number="832" updated="2016-10-25T16:42:56Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4745" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2014-06-10T18:50:48-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001150"/>
  <offered datetime="2014-06-10"/>
  <description>Amendment sought to prohibit the use of funds to enforce section 47524 of title 49, United States Code, or part 161 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, with regard to noise or access restrictions or to enforce section 47107 of title 49, United States Code, with regard to access restriction on the operation of aircraft by the operator of Bob Hope Airport in Burbank, California.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment to prohibit the use of funds to enforce section 47524 of title 49, United States Code, or part 161 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, with regard to noise or access restrictions or to enforce section 47107 of title 49, United States Code, with regard to access restriction on the operation of aircraft by the operator of Bob Hope Airport in Burbank, California.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2014-06-10T18:50:48-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="293">
      <text>On agreeing to the Schiff amendment (A055) Failed by recorded vote: 208 - 212 (Roll no. 293).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-06-10T16:28:51-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A055) offered by Mr. Schiff.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5221-5222, H5235-5236" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5221-5222" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-10"/>
    <action datetime="2014-06-10T18:50:48-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-10T18:50:48-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-10T18:50:48-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Schiff amendment (A055) Failed by recorded vote: 208 - 212 (Roll no. 293).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-10T16:28:51-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A055) offered by Mr. Schiff.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5221-5222, H5235-5236" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5221-5222" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-10">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
