<bill session="114" type="s" number="1271" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:54Z">
  <state datetime="2015-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FLARE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fuel Loss Abatement and Royalty Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Interior to issue regulations to prevent or minimize the venting and flaring of gas in oil and gas production operations in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">FLARE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-19">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2089"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-05-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fuel Loss Abatement and Royalty Enhancement Act or the FLARE Act

This bill requires the Department of the Interior to issue regulations to: (1) prevent or minimize the venting and flaring of gas in oil and gas production operations on federal land onshore and offshore in the United States, and (2) promote the capture and beneficial use or reinjection of gas in such operations.

Such regulations shall also treat gas that is flared or vented in operations under a lease as production for which a royalty is required to be paid to the United States.

The Government Accountability Office shall assess such venting and flaring and estimate the volume of gas vented or flared in such operations each year.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
