<bill session="114" type="h" number="3803" updated="2018-06-02T04:46:44Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Legally Binding Budget Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to establish joint resolutions on the budget, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Legally Binding Budget Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001273"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000533" joined="2015-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001036" joined="2015-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000290" joined="2015-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001182" joined="2015-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000587" joined="2015-10-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Legally Binding Budget Act of 2015 

This bill amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to replace the concurrent resolution on the budget required under current law with a legally binding joint resolution on the budget.

(Concurrent resolutions, which are currently used for congressional budget resolutions, address internal congressional matters, are not presented to the President for approval, and are not legally binding. A joint resolution is presented to the President after passing both chambers of Congress and has the force of law.)

At any time after the annual budget resolution has been enacted and before the end of the fiscal year, Congress and the President may enact a new budget resolution revising or reaffirming the most recently enacted budget resolution.

The contents of a budget resolution are limited to material that is permitted by the Congressional Budget Act of 1974. For purposes of congressional budget enforcement and the rules of the House and the Senate, the budget resolution is enforceable upon the earlier of enactment or 15 days following presentment to the President.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
