<bill session="114" type="sr" number="237" updated="2018-06-02T06:17:49Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution condemning Joseph Kony and the Lord's Resistance Army for continuing to perpetrate crimes against humanity, war crimes, and mass atrocities, and supporting ongoing efforts by the United States Government, the African Union, and governments and regional organizations in central Africa to remove Joseph Kony and Lord's Resistance Army commanders from the battlefield and promote protection and recovery of affected communities.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution condemning Joseph Kony and the Lord's Resistance Army for continuing to perpetrate crimes against humanity, war crimes, and mass atrocities, and supporting ongoing efforts by the United States Government, the African Union, and governments and regional organizations in central Africa to remove Joseph Kony and Lord's Resistance Army commanders from the battlefield and promote protection and recovery of affected communities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001236"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2015-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2015-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2015-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2015-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2015-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2015-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2015-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2015-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2015-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2015-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2015-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2015-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2015-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2015-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2015-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2015-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6192-6193" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="114" relation="identical" number="394"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Central African Republic"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Democratic Republic of the Congo"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="South Sudan"/>
    <term name="Sudan"/>
    <term name="Uganda"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Condemns Joseph Kony and the Lord's Resistance Army (LRA) for perpetrating crimes against humanity and mass atrocities, and supports efforts by the United States, the African Union (AU), the international community, and governments in central Africa to remove Joseph Kony and LRA commanders from the battlefield and promote protection and recovery for affected communities.

Supports efforts to provide the Regional Task Force with the logistics support and authorizations needed to access areas of suspected LRA activity in the Central African Republic and the Democratic Republic of the Congo.

Urges the President to reauthorize the deployment of U.S. Armed Forces personnel in support of Operation Observant Compass.

Urges the AU and the Regional Task Force, with the support of the European Union (EU), as well as the governments of Uganda, South Sudan, the Central African Republic, and the Democratic Republic of the Congo, to implement the United Nations (U.N.) Regional Strategy.

Welcomes the continued LRA defections, and calls on governments in the region and the international community to support such demobilization.

Calls on the Department of State, the Department of Defense, the U.S. Agency for International Development, and the heads of relevant U.S. agencies to utilize funds to: (1) enhance intelligence support to the Regional Task Force; (2) work with the U.N., the AU, and regional government partners to help non-indicted LRA members, abductees, and noncombatants defect; (3) expand efforts to prevent the LRA from funding its operations through the theft and trade of illicit ivory, gold, and diamonds; and (4) support rehabilitation and reintegration programs for abducted children, youth, and adults.

Commends those members of the U.S. Armed Forces previously or currently deployed in support of Operation Observant Compass for their critical contributions to efforts to remove Joseph Kony and LRA commanders and protect civilians.

Urges the President to develop a strategy aimed at supporting sustainable recovery and security within areas affected by the LRA in partnership with other donors and multilateral bodies, including the World Bank, the EU, and others.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
