<bill session="115" type="h" number="4021" updated="2019-04-18T16:16:23Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-10-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to provide funding for public transportation services offered by high-performing public and private systems, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Leveraging Performance-Based Transportation Services Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Leveraging Performance-Based Transportation Services Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Leveraging Performance-Based Transportation Services Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000605"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-10-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Highways and Transit" code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-10-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Leveraging Performance-Based Transportation Services Act of 2017

This bill authorizes an owner or operator of a leveraged system to submit directly to the National Transit Database data regarding the public transportation service provided by the system.

"Leveraged system" means a provider of public transportation services, whether public or private, including commuter bus services and services provided by a private provider of public transportation by vanpool that the Department of Transportation determines: (1) is able to recover, through fare revenue or payments made directly by the provider, all operating costs associated with the services; (2) meets Federal Transit Administration requirements with respect to the provision of services; and (3) does not negatively impact other publicly subsidized or privately provided public transportation services.

The data submitted by the owner or operator of a leveraged system to the National Transit Database shall be used by DOT in calculating apportionments for capital payments.

 A public transportation service meets the requirements of this bill unless the service: (1) overlaps or directly competes with a service provided by the designated recipient concerned and has a direct effect on such service, including a projected ridership reduction of more than 3% along a corridor served by the designated recipient; or (2) is provided by a service provider that has fewer than 10 vehicles serving the recipient's designated area.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
