<bill session="113" type="h" number="2534" updated="2016-10-25T16:05:13Z">
  <state datetime="2013-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transportation and Regional Infrastructure Project Bonds Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TRIP Bonds Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide $50,000,000,000 in new transportation infrastructure funding through bonding to empower States and local governments to complete significant infrastructure projects across all modes of transportation, including roads, bridges, rail and transit systems, ports, and inland waterways, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">TRIP Bonds Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000413"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001162" joined="2013-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="identical" number="1250"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-06-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Transportation and Regional Infrastructure Project Bonds Act of 2013 or TRIP Bonds Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an income tax credit for any TRIP bond issued by or for the benefit of a state infrastructure bank as part of an issue, if 100% of the available project proceeds from such issue are to be used for expenditures incurred for one or more qualified projects. Requires proceeds from the sale of bonds issued under this Act to be held in a TRIP Bonds Trust Account (including one or more subaccounts).

Defines "qualified project" as a capital transportation infrastructure project (including roads, bridges, rail and transit systems, ports, and inland waterways) proposed and approved by a state infrastructure bank, as well as any flood damage risk reduction project with a completed Report of the Chief of Engineers of the Army Corps of Engineers.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
