<bill session="114" type="h" number="4648" updated="2018-06-02T04:55:42Z">
  <state datetime="2016-02-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-02-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Green Stormwater Infrastructure Investment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide incentives for investment in green stormwater infrastructure, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Green Stormwater Infrastructure Investment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000381"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001064" joined="2016-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000510" joined="2016-04-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Hydrology and hydrography"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-29T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Green Stormwater Infrastructure Investment Act

This bill amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to assist state, tribal, and local governments toinvest in green stormwater infrastructure.Green stormwater infrastructure is a stormwater management technique that uses natural or engineered systems designed to promote the uptake and filtration of stormwater at its source to protect habitats and reduce flood risks.

The bill establishes a 20% reserve within each state's Water Pollution Control Revolving Fund for installation, operation, and maintenance of green stormwater infrastructure.

The Department of Transportation must prioritize projects that include green stormwater infrastructure for competitive federal transportation infrastructure grants.

The bill also authorizes the Environmental Protection Agency to extend National Pollutant Discharge Elimination System permits for green stormwater infrastructure systems for up to 10 years.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
