<bill session="114" type="s" number="2026" updated="2018-06-02T07:09:23Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Nuclear Waste by Our Lakes Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to foster bilateral engagement and scientific analysis of storing nuclear waste in permanent repositories in the Great Lakes Basin.</title>
    <title type="display">Stop Nuclear Waste by Our Lakes Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000770"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2015-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2015-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2015-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2015-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="3483"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stop Nuclear Waste by Our Lakes Act of 2015

This bill directs the Department of State to request that the International Joint Commission:

 review the long-term impacts of the location of the Deep Geological Repository (proposed by the Ontario Power Generation for disposal of 7 million cubic feet of low- and intermediate-level nuclear waste at the Bruce Nuclear Power Plant in Kincardine, Ontario), including an examination of the conclusions reached in the Environmental Assessment Report of the Joint Review Panel, and whether those conclusions would adequately protect Lake Huron and the other Great Lakes from the risks posed by the operation of the Deep Geological Repository for low and intermediate-level nuclear waste; and issue a report on the Commission's findings to the governments of the United States and Canada. If Canada decides to dispose permanently of high-level nuclear waste at a site in close proximity to the Deep Geological Repository or another site in the Great Lakes Basin the Department shall:

 request the Commission to study the risks to the Great Lakes Basin of storing high-level nuclear waste in close proximity to the Deep Geological Repository or another site in the Great Lakes Basin, and bring the matter before the Commission. The Department shall undertake negotiations with Canada to:

 delay the final decision on the Deep Geologic Repository until after the Commission delivers the report required by this Act, delay any final decision to store high-level nuclear waste in close proximity to the Deep Geological Repository or another site in the Great Lakes Basin until after the Commission conducts the study required by this Act, and consent to bringing the matter of such disposal of high-level nuclear waste before the Commission.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
