<bill session="115" type="s" number="2073" updated="2019-04-18T16:40:05Z">
  <state datetime="2017-11-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-11-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-11-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a vegetation management pilot program on National Forest System land to better protect utility infrastructure from passing wildfire, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Forest System Vegetation Management Pilot Program Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Forest System Vegetation Management Pilot Program Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">National Forest System Vegetation Management Pilot Program Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001267"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2017-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001069" joined="2018-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2017-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2017-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2017-11-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-11-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2921"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-11-02T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Forest System Vegetation Management Pilot Program Act of 2017

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish a limited, voluntary pilot program under which owners and operators of rights-of-way on National Forest System (NFS) land may conduct vegetation management projects on NFS land adjacent to or near those rights-of-way to better protect utility infrastructure from potential passing wildfires.

 USDA shall give priority to an owner or operator of a right-of-way that has worked with Forest Service fire scientists and used technologies to improve utility infrastructure protection prescriptions.

Vegetation management projects shall involve only limited and selective vegetation management activities that:

 create the least amount of disturbance necessary to protect utility infrastructure from passing wildfires; may include thinning, fuel reduction, creation, and treatment of shaded fuel breaks; are conducted only on NFS land adjacent to the participant's right-of-way or within 75 feet of it; and are not conducted on a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System, a designated wilderness area, or an inventoried roadless area. Each vegetation management project, including each of those activities selected, shall be subject to approval by the Forest Service.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
