<bill session="114" type="s" number="989" updated="2018-06-02T06:45:22Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Residue Entries and Streamlining Trade Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to exempt from duty residue of bulk cargo contained in instruments of international traffic previously exported from the United States.</title>
    <title type="display">Residue Entries and Streamlining Trade Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000542"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001069" joined="2015-04-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1907"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="1773"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1916"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Residue Entries and Streamlining Trade Act

This bill amends the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to exempt from duty treatment the residue of bulk cargo contained in instruments of international traffic previously exported from the United States.

The following terms are defined:

 "residue" means material of bulk cargo, of no or de minimis value, that remains in an instrument of international traffic after a certain amount of the bulk cargo is removed; "bulk cargo" means cargo that is unpackaged and is in either solid, liquid, or gaseous form; and "instruments of international traffic" means certain reusable containers or holders (i.e. lift vans, cargo vans, shipping tanks, skids, pallets, caul boards, and cores for textile fabrics) arriving (whether loaded or empty) for use in the shipment of merchandise in international traffic, as well as any additional articles that the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection designates as instruments of international traffic.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
