<bill session="114" type="s" number="2410" updated="2018-06-02T07:13:56Z">
  <state datetime="2015-12-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cybersecurity Disclosure Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote transparency in the oversight of cybersecurity risks at publicly traded companies.</title>
    <title type="display">Cybersecurity Disclosure Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2015-12-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8795" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-12-17T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Cybersecurity Disclosure Act of 2015

This bill directs the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to issue final rules requiring each reporting company to:

 disclose in its mandatory annual report or annual proxy statement whether any member of its governing body has expertise or experience in cybersecurity, including details necessary to describe fully the nature of that expertise or experience; and if no member has such expertise or experience, describe what other company cybersecurity steps were taken into account by any persons, such as a nominating committee, responsible for identifying and evaluating nominees for the governing body. The SEC shall also, in coordination with the National Institute of Standards and Technology, define what constitutes expertise or experience in cybersecurity, such as professional qualifications to administer information security program functions or experience detecting, preventing, mitigating, or addressing cybersecurity threats.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
