<bill session="114" type="h" number="4579" updated="2019-02-13T17:31:25Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Utah Test and Training Range Encroachment Prevention and Temporary Closure Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Utah Test and Training Range Encroachment Prevention and Temporary Closure Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To withdraw certain Bureau of Land Management land in the State of Utah from all forms of public appropriation, to provide for the shared management of the withdrawn land by the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of the Air Force to facilitate enhanced weapons testing and pilot training, enhance public safety, and provide for continued public access to the withdrawn land, to provide for the exchange of certain Federal land and State land, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Utah Test and Training Range Encroachment Prevention and Temporary Closure Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001192"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001250" joined="2016-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001076" joined="2016-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000584" joined="2016-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-15">
      <text>Subcommittee on Federal Lands Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-03-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 19 - 14.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 114-857, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08">
      <text>Committee on Armed Services discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-12-08" calendar="Union" number="670">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 670.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Readiness" code="HSAS03" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2383"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4909"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-08T17:17:46Z" status="Reported to House amended, Part I">Utah Test and Training Range Encroachment Prevention and Temporary Closure Act

This bill directs the Departments of the Interior and the Air Force to enter into a memorandum of agreement for the continued management by Interior of approximately 625,643 acres of Bureau of Land Management (BLM) land in Utah in a manner that provides for its limited use by the Air Force.

Under such Agreement the BLM shall continue to manage the BLM land, subject to use by the Air Force for:

 the preservation of the Utah Test and Training Range against encroachments incompatible with test and training requirements; the testing of advanced weapons systems, including hypersonic weapons, and the standoff distance for weapons; increased public safety for civilians accessing the BLM land; and other purposes related to meeting national security needs. If military operations, public safety, or national security require the temporary closure of the use of roads, trails, or other portions of the BLM land to the public, the Air Force may take necessary action to carry out such closure.

The bill establishes the Utah Test and Training Range Community Resource Group to give input to Interior and the Air Force on matters involving public access to, use of, and management of the BLM land.

Interior shall convey to the state of Utah, through the School and Institutional Trust Lands Administration in Utah, BLM land in Box Elder, Millard, Juab, Tooele, and Beaver Counties, Utah, in exchange for non-federal land owned by Utah in Box Elder, Juab, and Tooele Counties. Upon conveyance, the non-federal land located: (1) within the Utah Test and Training Range shall be managed according to the memorandum of agreement, and (2) within the Cedar Mountains Wilderness shall be added to and administered as part of such Wilderness.

Interior, respecting BLM land, and the Department of Agriculture, respecting Forest Service land, shall convey to Utah and to Box Elder, Juab, and Tooele Counties separate easements for motorized travel rights of way across the federal land for all Class B and Class D R.S. 2477 roads.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-857</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
