<bill session="115" type="h" number="1567" updated="2019-04-18T16:04:38Z">
  <state datetime="2018-11-27T17:10:03-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-11-27T17:10:03-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote economic partnership and cooperation between the United States and Mexico.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">United States-Mexico Economic Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States-Mexico Economic Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States-Mexico Economic Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="display">United States-Mexico Economic Partnership Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2018-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000179" joined="2017-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000581" joined="2018-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2018-11-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2018-10-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Western Hemisphere.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-09-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <calendar datetime="2018-09-27">
      <text>Committee Agreed to Seek Consideration Under Suspension of the Rules, by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-11-27T16:55:46-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Royce (CA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-11-27T16:56:12-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9591-9593" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-11-27T16:56:16-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1567.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2018-11-27T17:10:03-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9591" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-11-27T17:10:11-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-11-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Western Hemisphere, Civilian Security and Trade" code="HSFA07" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">United States-Mexico Economic Partnership Act

This bill declares that it shall be U.S. policy to increase U.S.-Mexico academic exchanges at the secondary, post-secondary, and post-graduate levels. The United States and Mexico should seek to contribute to doubling the number of students studying in each other's country within five years.

Priority should be given to strengthening ties between communities and academic institutions in those portions of the United States and Mexico that are within 100 kilometers of the international boundary between those countries.

The President shall develop a plan to implement policies and programs that support cooperation, training, and mentoring of entrepreneurs. Such policies and programs should seek to provide not less than 100 grants of not more than $25,000 each for program participants to better leverage participation by the private sector.

The President shall develop a plan to implement policies and programs that promote U.S.-Mexico energy infrastructure coordination and cooperation through support of vocational-level education, internships, and exchanges between the two countries. Such policies and programs should seek to provide education, internships, and exchanges for at least 1,000 program participants.

The President shall develop a plan to implement a pilot program to develop a pipeline between undergraduate colleges and universities in the United States and medical school programs in Mexico. Such program should be utilized to prepare medical students to become doctors who can pass U.S. medical licensing board exams. The pilot program should seek to increase the number of bilingual medical professionals in a cost-effective manner who can practice in U.S. underserved communities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
