<bill session="114" type="h" number="2144" updated="2019-01-09T21:26:09Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Program Management Improvement and Accountability Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 31, United States Code, to establish entities tasked with improving program and project management in Federal agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Program Management Improvement and Accountability Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001293" joined="2016-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001284" joined="2015-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2016-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000266" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001105" joined="2015-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2015-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000616" joined="2016-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2016-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000546" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001051" joined="2016-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000378" joined="2016-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000601" joined="2016-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000588" joined="2016-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000395" joined="2016-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2016-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000813" joined="2015-12-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1550"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Program Management Improvement and Accountability Act of 2015

Establishes as additional functions of the Deputy Director for Management of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) requirements to:

 adopt and oversee government-wide standards, policies, and guidelines for program and project management for executive agencies; chair the Program Management Policy Council (established by this Act); issue regulations and establish standards and policies for executive agencies in accordance with nationally accredited standards for program and project management planning and delivery issues; engage with the private sector; conduct portfolio reviews to address programs identified as high risk by the Government Accountability Office; conduct portfolio reviews of agency programs at least annually; and establish a five-year strategic plan for program and project management. Requires the head of each federal agency that is required to have a Chief Financial Officer to designate a Program Management Improvement Officer to implement agency program management policies and develop a written strategy for enhancing the role of program managers within the agency.

Establishes the Program Management Policy Council within OMB to act as the principal interagency forum for improving agency practices related to program and project management.

Requires the Office of Personnel Management to issue regulations that: (1) identify key skills and competencies needed for an agency program and project manager, (2) establish a new job series for program and project management within an agency, and (3) establish a new career path for program and project managers.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
