<bill session="114" type="s" number="1631" updated="2018-06-02T06:56:24Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keep Our Pension Promises Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify certain provisions relating to multiemployer pensions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Keep Our Pension Promises Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2015-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2016-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2015-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2015-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2016-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2016-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2015-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2015-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2015-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="identical" number="2844"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Transfer and inheritance taxes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Keep Our Pension Promises Act 

This bill repeals the elimination of the pension anti-cutback provisions under the Multiemployer Pension Reform Act of 2014. The anti-cutback provisions prohibit reductions in pension benefits to participants in multiemployer pension plans.

The bill amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to allow a plan sponsor of an eligible multiemployer plan to petition the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation for a partition of a financially-troubled pension plan. PBGC is required to establish a legacy fund to cover the administrative and benefit costs resulting from a partition..

The bill amends the federal bankruptcy code to assign first claim priority to pension obligations under ERISA.

The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) impose a limit of $1 million on the exemption of the gain from the exchange of real property in a like kind exchange, (2) prohibit the use of like kind exchanges for collectibles, (3) establish estate valuation rules for certain transfers of nonbusiness assets, and (4) limit estate tax discounts for certain individuals with minority interests in a business acquired from a decedent.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
