<bill session="114" type="s" number="2930" updated="2018-06-02T07:18:45Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Limiting Contributions to the United Nations and Affiliated Organizations that Accord the Palestine Liberation Organization the Same Standing as Member States Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that Federal funding for the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change complies with applicable statutory limitations.</title>
    <title type="display">Limiting Contributions to the United Nations and Affiliated Organizations that Accord the Palestine Liberation Organization the Same Standing as Member States Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2016-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2016-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2016-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Limiting Contributions to the United Nations and Affiliated Organizations that Accord the Palestine Liberation Organization the Same Standing as Member States Act

This bill directs the Department of State to ensure that the use of federal funding supporting the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change, including the Green Climate Fund, complies with applicable federal law, including:

 provisions of the United Nations Participation Act of 1945 authorizing appropriations for the U.S. annual payment to the U.N. and for necessary salaries and expenses of U.S. representatives to the U.N., provisions of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1990 and 1991 prohibiting making funds authorized under such Act available to the U.N. or any specialized agency that accords the Palestine Liberation Organization the same standing as member states, and provisions of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1994 and 1995 prohibiting contributions to the U.N. or to any affiliated U.N. organization that grants full state membership to a group that does not have internationally recognized attributes of statehood.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
