<bill session="115" type="h" number="3747" updated="2019-04-19T13:48:53Z">
  <state datetime="2017-09-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-09-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-09-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require financial institutions to freeze the assets of individuals arrested under suspicion of participating in domestic terrorism or providing material support to terrorists, to establish a national clearinghouse for information on incidents of homegrown "lone wolf" terrorism, domestic terrorism, and persons providing material support to terrorists, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FASTER Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FASTER Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Freezing Assets of Suspected Terrorists and Enemy Recruits Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Freezing Assets of Suspected Terrorists and Enemy Recruits Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">FASTER Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000583"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2017-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000585" joined="2017-09-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-09-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Freezing Assets of Suspected Terrorists and Enemy Recruits Act of 2017 or the FASTER Act of 2017

This bill directs a federal law enforcement agency to notify the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network (FinCEN)&#160;in the Department of the Treasury of an arrest of an individual under suspicion of participating in domestic terrorism or providing material support&#160;for terrorism. FinCEN must then order any appropriate financial institution to freeze that individual's assets.

The bill also sets forth provisions for contesting&#160;a freeze, unfreezing assets, and disposing&#160;of assets in the event of a conviction.

The Federal Bureau of Investigation must establish a national clearinghouse of incidents of homegrown "lone wolf" terrorism, domestic terrorism, and&#160;the provision of&#160;material support to terrorists. The clearinghouse must maintain information for purposes of cross-referencing and assisting investigations of law enforcement agencies.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
