<bill session="114" type="h" number="860" updated="2019-02-01T21:05:37Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FAFSA Fairness Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to amend the process by which students with certain special circumstances apply for Federal financial aid.</title>
    <title type="display">FAFSA Fairness Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000984"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001097" joined="2015-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2015-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2015-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001137" joined="2015-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2015-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2015-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000130" joined="2015-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000808" joined="2015-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Investment" code="HSED13" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-11T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">FAFSA Fairness Act of 2015

Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require the Secretary of Education to disclose, on the form notifying students of their expected family contribution, the special circumstances under which students may qualify as independent for purposes of the determination regarding their need and eligibility for title IV assistance.

Allows students who may qualify as independent on the basis of those special circumstances to complete the Free Application for Federal Student Aid as independent students for purposes of the initial determination of their title IV assistance by a financial aid administrator at an institution of higher education to which they are applying.

Requires the financial aid administrators to: (1) provide those students with an initial determination regarding their title IV assistance in the same manner as, and by no later than the date that, they provide other independent students with that determination; and (2) use, in making a final determination regarding that assistance, the discretion provided to them under title IV to verify whether such students meet the special circumstances to qualify as independent students.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
