<bill session="114" type="h" number="3824" updated="2019-02-13T17:31:24Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Forest Service and Department of the Interior Law Enforcement Improvement Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reform oversight of law enforcement activities of the Forest Service and the Department of the Interior and to improve coordination and cooperation with local law enforcement agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Forest Service and Department of the Interior Law Enforcement Improvement Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001070"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Conservation and Forestry" code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Forest Service and Department of the Interior Law Enforcement Improvement Act of 2015

This bill makes a Regional Forester for a Forest Service region responsible for all Forest Service law enforcement personnel assigned to that Region. The Chief of the Forest Service, however, acting through the Director of Law Enforcement, shall remain responsible for the Investigations Division.

The Department of Agriculture (USDA), with respect to the Forest Service, and the Department of the Interior, with respect to its land management agencies, shall establish a Federal Lands Law Enforcement Review Board to review and make recommendations regarding:

 law enforcement incidents of concern involving agency law enforcement personnel, proposed changes to agency law enforcement policy, the cooperative law enforcement program, and training of agency law enforcement personnel. If a political subdivision of a state contains 25,000 acres or more of federal land, all or a majority of which is either National Forest System land or land under Interior jurisdiction, USDA or Interior, as appropriate, shall try to develop a memorandum of understanding with that political subdivision to address the specific roles and coordination between Forest Service or Interior law enforcement personnel and local law enforcement.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
