<bill session="114" type="s" number="2708" updated="2018-06-02T07:16:01Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Religious Persecution Relief Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the admission to the United States of up to 10,000 Syrian religious minorities as refugees of special humanitarian concern in each of the fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</title>
    <title type="display">Religious Persecution Relief Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001095"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001197" joined="2016-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2016-04-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1594-1596" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Religious Persecution Relief Act

This bill declares that Syrian nationals who are religious minorities in their country of origin:

 shall be classified as refugees of special humanitarian concern, shall be eligible for priority two processing under the refugee resettlement priority system, and may apply directly to the U.S. refugee admissions program for admission to the United States. The Immigration and Nationality Act is amended to authorize, in addition to the current worldwide refugee resettlement quota, the refugee admission of up to 10,000 religious-minority Syrian nationals for each of FY2016-FY2020.

The Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 1990 is amended to establish as a protected refugee category persons who:

 are or were nationals and residents of the Syrian Arab Republic; as members of a religious minority in Syria, share common characteristics that identify them as targets of persecution in that state on account of religion, creed, or ethnicity; and have been underrepresented in the U.S. refugee resettlement program during the five-year period ending on September 30, 2015, when compared to their representation in the Syrian population as a whole.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
