<bill session="114" type="h" number="6155" updated="2019-02-13T17:31:26Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Safety of Federal Wilderness Areas Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Wilderness Act to ensure access to wilderness areas by Federal, State, and local emergency response personnel during an emergency, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Ensuring Safety of Federal Wilderness Areas Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001187"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-10-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Conservation and Forestry" code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Ensuring Safety of Federal Wilderness Areas Act of 2016

This bill amends the Wilderness Act to prohibit the Department of Agriculture (for wilderness areas under the jurisdiction of the Forest Service) and the Department of the Interior (for wilderness areas under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management) from adopting, amending, or enforcing, any regulations, policies, or guidance that would delay federal, state, or local emergency response personnel from entering into a wilderness area or wilderness study area to respond to an emergency.

Any entrance by federal, state, or local emergency response personnel into a wilderness area or wilderness study area in response to an emergency shall be reported to the appropriate Department within 24 hours of the time at which such personnel first entered such area.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
