<bill session="114" type="h" number="1484" updated="2019-02-13T17:31:09Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Honor the Nevada Enabling Act of 1864 Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain Federal lands to the State of Nevada in fulfillment of the Nevada Statehood Enabling Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Honor the Nevada Enabling Act of 1864 Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000369"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001070" joined="2015-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001055" joined="2016-01-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-19T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Honor the Nevada Enabling Act of 1864 Act

Directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) and the Department of the Interior to convey, in phases and without consideration, to the state of Nevada all interest of the United States in federal lands owned, managed, or controlled by the federal government through the USDA or Interior for the purpose of permitting the state to use them to support select beneficiaries. Specifies exceptions, including components of the National Wilderness Preservation System, National Park System, and National Wildlife System, and federally recognized Indian reservations and lands.

Defines "select beneficiaries" as

 public elementary and secondary education; public higher education; public specialized education; public mental and medical health services; social, senior, and veterans services; public programs for recovery plan development and implementation for candidate and threatened or endangered species; and political subdivisions of the state, but only with respect to payment for services and infrastructure on conveyed identified federal lands that would otherwise be financed through property taxes or other revenues available to a political subdivision of the state.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
