<bill session="114" type="h" number="5862" updated="2019-04-11T15:42:42Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a grant program to assist local educational agencies in improving student retention and engagement and providing resources and support to families of at-risk children, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keep Students in School Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="display">Keep Students in School Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001166"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2016-09-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational guidance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Keep Students in School Act of 2016

This bill establishes a grant program through which the Department of Education (ED) shall assist local educational agencies in carrying out one or more of the following activities:

 establishing an attendance program; funding after-school programs and recreational activities; establishing a teacher training and development program that focuses on issues relating to racial inequality and poverty; if applicable, making a zero tolerance policy more compatible with the goals of student retention and engagement; establishing a student absence policy with respect to at-risk children; collaborating with local agencies and social workers to address issues facing at-risk children; providing parents of at-risk children with resources and support; establishing or expanding a mentoring program; or providing schools with licensed social workers. ED shall provide technical assistance to grantees upon request.

In addition, ED shall establish a task force to develop a comprehensive work plan to address the hardships that disadvantaged youth may face in attending school and attaining academic success. The task force shall: (1) coordinate interagency efforts to address such hardships, (2) assess the effectiveness of federal programs aimed at addressing&#160;those hardships, and&#160;(3) develop a plan that implements improvements to such federal programs and incorporates positive youth development practices.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
