<bill session="114" type="s" number="3234" updated="2019-06-21T11:07:13Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Native American Business Development, Trade Promotion, and Tourism Act of 2000, the Buy Indian Act, the Indian Trader Act, and the Native American Programs Act of 1974 to provide industry and economic development opportunities to Indian communities.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Indian Community Economic Enhancement Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="display">Indian Community Economic Enhancement Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2016-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5167" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-07">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 114-538.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-09-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Indian Community Economic Enhancement Act of 2016

This bill amends the Native American Business Development, Trade Promotion, and Tourism Act of 2000 to establish duties for the Office of Native American Business Development (ONABD), including: (1) advising the Department of Commerce regarding the relationship between the United States and Indian tribes; and (2) serving as the point of contact for tribes, tribal organizations, and members of tribes regarding economic development.

The ONABD, the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Indian Affairs, and the Community Development Financial Institutions (CDFI) Fund must coordinate to support economic development in Native American communities.

CDFI Fund assistance for Native American communities provided through certain entities does not require matching funds.

For purposes of financing and economic or community development, the essential governmental functions of a tribe are the same as those of a state or local government with general taxing authority.

The bill establishes the Indian Economic Development Fund to provide credit subsidies for the Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA) loan guarantee program and for certain community development financial institutions.

This bill amends the Buy Indian Act, including to require the Department of Health and Human Services to use Native American labor and purchase Native American products.

This bill amends the Indian Trader Act to permit the BIA, under specified conditions, to waive the requirement for persons to be licensed to engage in trade with a tribe.

This bill amends the Native American Programs Act of 1974 to permit the BIA to provide financial assistance to certain community development financial institutions for Native American projects.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
