<bill session="115" type="h" number="4577" updated="2019-04-18T16:18:47Z">
  <state datetime="2018-01-09T12:38:59-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-01-09T12:38:59-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-12-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Domestic Explosives Detection Canine Capacity Building Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Domestic Explosives Detection Canine Capacity Building Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Domestic Explosives Detection Canine Capacity Building Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Domestic Explosives Detection Canine Capacity Building Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Domestic Explosives Detection Canine Capacity Building Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Domestic Explosives Detection Canine Capacity Building Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a working group to determine ways to develop a domestic canine breeding network to produce high quality explosives detection canines, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000575"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2017-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001269" joined="2017-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000625" joined="2017-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001077" joined="2017-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2017-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000386" joined="2017-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2017-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2017-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2017-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-12-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-12-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-01-09">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 115-488.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-01-09" calendar="Union" number="362">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 362.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-01-09T12:29:24-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Rogers (AL) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-09T12:29:36-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H32-34" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-09T12:29:37-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4577.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2018-01-09T12:38:59-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H32-33" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-01-09T12:39:01-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Service animals"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-01-09T16:53:14Z" status="Passed House amended">Domestic Explosives Detection Canine Capacity Building Act of 2017

(Sec. 3) This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to establish a working group to determine ways to develop a decentralized domestic canine breeding network to produce high quality explosives detection canines and modernize canine training standards.

The working group shall be comprised of representatives from the TSA, the Science and Technology Directorate of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), national domestic canine associations with expertise in breeding and pedigree, universities with expertise related to explosives detection canines and canine breeding, and domestic canine breeders and vendors.

The working group shall submit to the TSA preliminary behavioral standards, medical standards, and technical standards for the domestic canine breeding network and canine training, including recommendations on how the TSA can engage stakeholders to further the development of such network and training. The TSA shall submit a strategy for expanding the network based on such recommendations.

The TSA, in developing the strategy, must consult with other DHS officials to incorporate mission needs across DHS for an expanded domestic explosives detection canine breeding network that can be leveraged to help meet DHS's operational needs. The working group shall terminate two years after submitting the strategy.

(Sec. 4) The TSA shall issue baseline behavioral standards, medical standards, and technical standards for explosives detection canines. Such standards shall be incorporated into all statements of work for the TSA explosives detection canine contracts and reflect the detection capabilities required to effectively mitigate terrorist threats.

(Sec. 5) The requirements of the Federal Advisory Committee Act shall not apply to the working group.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-488</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
