<bill session="114" type="s" number="130" updated="2018-06-02T06:29:32Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IDEA Full Funding Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend part B of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act to provide full Federal funding of such part.</title>
    <title type="display">IDEA Full Funding Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000127"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="551"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-08T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">IDEA Full Funding Act

Amends the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA) to reauthorize and make appropriations for the grant program to assist states and outlying areas to provide special education and related services to children with disabilities.

Sets the amount authorized each fiscal year at a percentage of the maximum amount of the grants all states may receive for special education. Increases that percentage each fiscal year from FY2016-FY2025, until it reaches 100% in FY2025 and each succeeding fiscal year.

Sets the appropriation for each fiscal year as an amount equal to the difference between the amount of such percentage that is applicable that fiscal year and a specified amount.

Makes funds appropriated for a fiscal year available for obligation on July 1 of such fiscal year through September 30 of the succeeding year.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
