<bill session="114" type="h" number="6266" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:41Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to clarify the definition of a deposit broker, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to clarify the definition of a deposit broker, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001156"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000454" joined="2016-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to exclude from the definition of "deposit broker" an affiliate of an insured depository institution, with respect to funds of an individual retirement account, pension, retirement, profit-sharing, bonus, thrift savings, incentive, or other similar benefit plan for which the depository institution acts as custodian or directed trustee, to the extent the affiliate provides brokerage, advisory, or agency services to participants or beneficiaries of the benefit plan and the services result in the investment of its assets as deposits of the depository institution.

(Generally, an insured depository institution that is not well capitalized may not accept funds obtained by or through any deposit broker for deposit into one or more deposit accounts.)

Consumer credit Information regarding deposit accounts shared by an insured depository institution with its affiliates that is a communication among persons related by common ownership or affiliated by corporate control shall not be a factor in determining whether: (1) an affiliate is considered a deposit broker, or (2) deposits resulting from referrals of customers to an affiliate are subject to the brokered deposit restrictions.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
