<bill session="113" type="h" number="1220" updated="2016-10-25T16:01:05Z">
  <state datetime="2013-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Asthma Inhalers Relief Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to allow for the distribution, sale, and consumption in the United States of remaining inventories of over-the-counter CFC epinephrine inhalers.</title>
    <title type="display">Asthma Inhalers Relief Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001248"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001051" joined="2013-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000355" joined="2013-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001142" joined="2013-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Power" code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-03-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Asthma Inhalers Relief Act of 2013 - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to: (1) permit the distribution, sale, and consumption in the United States of remaining inventories of CFC epinephrine inhalers manufactured pursuant to the exception for medical devices under the Clean Air Act; (2) not take any enforcement action or otherwise seek to restrict the distribution, sale, or consumption of such inhalers on the basis of any federal law implementing the Montreal Protocol on Substances that Deplete the Ozone Layer; and (3) issue, in response to a request of any distributor or seller of such inhalers, a No Action Assurance Letter stating that the EPA will not initiate an enforcement action relating to the distribution or sale of any such inhaler occurring prior to August 1, 2013.

Defines "CFC epinephrine inhaler" to mean any epinephrine inhaler containing chlorofluorocarbons that was manufactured and classified as over-the-counter before January 1, 2012.

Terminates this Act on August 1, 2013.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
