<amendment session="113" chamber="h" number="613" updated="2016-10-25T12:38:43Z">
  <amends type="hc" number="96" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2014-04-09T17:32:57-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001160"/>
  <offered datetime="2014-04-09"/>
  <description>Amendment in the nature of a substitute comprises the budget proposal of the Congressional Black Caucus and appears on page H3104 of the Congressional Record of April 9, 2014.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment in the nature of a substitute numbered 2 printed in House Report 113-405 to make significant investments in education, job training, transportation and infrastructure, and advanced research and development programs that will accelerate our economic recovery. Includes funding for a comprehensive jobs bill and targeted investments to reduce and eradicate poverty in America. Protects the social safety net without cutting Social Security, Medicare, Medicaid, or SNAP and makes tough but responsible decisions to raise new revenue by making our tax system fairer, saving more than $1.7 trillion on the deficit over the next decade. Puts our nation on a sustainable fiscal path by reducing our annual budget deficit to 2.5% of GDP by FY 2024.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2014-04-09T17:32:57-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="172">
      <text>On agreeing to the Moore amendment (A002) Failed by recorded vote: 116 - 300 (Roll no. 172).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09T15:44:28-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A002) in the nature of a substitute offered by Ms. Moore.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3104-3113, H3122-3123" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3104-3107" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09"/>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09T17:32:57-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09T17:32:57-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09T17:32:57-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Moore amendment (A002) Failed by recorded vote: 116 - 300 (Roll no. 172).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09T15:44:28-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A002) in the nature of a substitute offered by Ms. Moore.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3104-3113, H3122-3123" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3104-3107" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
