<bill session="114" type="s" number="2950" updated="2018-06-02T07:45:24Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gold King Accountability and Compensation for Taxpayers</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gold King ACT</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to receive, process, and pay certain claims relating to the Gold King Mine spill.</title>
    <title type="display">Gold King ACT</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000562"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2016-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3602"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4483"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2063"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Gold King Accountability and Compensation for Taxpayers or the Gold King ACT

This bill allows a person to bring a compensation claim for allowable damages (i.e., property, business, or financial losses) under the Federal Tort Claims Act if the claim is related to an injury resulting from the spill in Cement Creek from the Gold King Mine near Silverton, Colorado. The spill occurred on August 5, 2015. The bill prohibits certain exemptions and limitations on tort claims against the United States under the Act from applying to claims for injuries resulting from the spill.

The EPA must receive, process, and pay under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 claims related to the Gold King Mine spill, including claims that otherwise would be ineligible under that Act or the national oil and hazardous substances pollution contingency plan if the response action carried out by the claimant is not inconsistent with the plan. The EPA must pay claims from unobligated balances in its accounts.

The EPA must develop and implement a program for long-term water quality monitoring of the Animas River.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
