<amendment session="114" chamber="h" number="826" updated="2018-11-09T00:02:54Z">
  <amends type="h" number="22" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2015-11-05T00:48:06-05:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000289"/>
  <offered datetime="2015-11-05"/>
  <description>Amendment assigns to the Executive Director of the Federal Permitting Improvement Steering Council, power to authorize extensions of permitting timetables, up to a total of fifty percent of the time specified in an original timetable, and to the Director of OMB, the power to authorize any additional extensions, subject to requirements to consult with the permit applicant and report to Congress, and makes further improvements to further streamline administrative procedures for permit review.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment No. 20 printed in Part B of House Report 114-326 to the Senate amendment to the text to assign to the Executive Director of the Federal Permitting Improvement Steering Council power to authorize extensions of permitting timetables, up to a total of fifty percent of the time specified in an original timetable, and to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget the power to authorize any additional extensions, subject to requirements to consult with the permit applicant and report to Congress, and makes further improvements to further streamline administrative procedures for permit review.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2015-11-05T00:48:06-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Goodlatte amendment (A093) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05T00:37:25-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A093) offered by Mr. Goodlatte.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 11/4/2015 H7730-7732" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref=" CR 11/4/2015  H7730-7731" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05"/>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05T00:48:06-05:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05T00:48:06-05:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Goodlatte amendment (A093) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05T00:37:25-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A093) offered by Mr. Goodlatte.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 11/4/2015 H7730-7732" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref=" CR 11/4/2015  H7730-7731" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
