<bill session="114" type="s" number="3525" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:38Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance the security operations of the Transportation Security Administration and the stability of the transportation security workforce by applying a unified personnel system under title 5, United States Code, to employees of the Transportation Security Administration who are responsible for screening passengers and property, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening American Transportation Security Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="display">Strengthening American Transportation Security Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2016-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6924-6925" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6925-6926" label="text of measure as introduced in Senate"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4488"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-08T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Strengthening American Transportation Security Act of 2016

This bill expresses the sense of Congress that the personnel system used by the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) provides insufficient workplace protections for its workforce and such personnel should be entitled to protections under the civil service system applicable to all federal employees.

The bill repeals personnel authorities of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) and the Department of Transportation governing the conditions of employment for TSA employees, thus making TSA employees subject to the personnel management system applicable to all other federal employees.

Within 60 days after the enactment of this bill or an earlier date set by DHS: (1) all TSA personnel management policies, directives, letters, and guidelines and any DHS human resources management system shall cease to be effective with respect to TSA employees; and (2) TSA employees shall become subject to labor provisions applicable to other federal transportation employees.

The bill sets forth transition rules that protect the pay rates and other rights of TSA employees. DHS shall consult with the labor organization certified by the Federal Labor Relations Authority to carry out the conversion of TSA employees and positions to the civil service system.

The provisions of this bill do not affect the prohibitions against disloyalty and asserting the right to strike against the federal government.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
