<bill session="113" type="h" number="4348" updated="2016-10-25T16:12:04Z">
  <state datetime="2014-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transferring Credits for College Completion Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To increase transparency and reduce students' burdens related to transferring credits between institutions of higher education.</title>
    <title type="display">Transferring Credits for College Completion Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000725"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001242" joined="2014-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001069" joined="2014-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000455" joined="2014-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2014-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000636" joined="2014-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2014-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000486" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000030" joined="2014-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001193" joined="2014-04-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" code="HSED13" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-04-01T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Transferring Credits for College Completion Act of 2014 - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA) to require the Secretary of Education to include on the College Navigator website the percentage of undergraduates at an institution of higher education (IHE) who have transferred from another IHE and earned their degree or certificate in their program of study within: (1) the normal time for its completion, (2) 150% of the normal time for its completion, and (3) 200% of the normal time for its completion.

Requires private IHEs participating the programs under title IV (Student Assistance) of the HEA to publicly disclose, in a readable and comprehensible manner, their transfer of credit policies, including a list of IHEs with which they have established an articulation agreement.

Requires each public IHE participating in a title IV program to publicly disclose, by July 1, 2017, on a central location of its website and in a readable and comprehensible manner:

 a list of the public IHEs with which it has an articulation agreement, a list of the courses in the common general education core curriculum of such public IHEs, and a description of each associate degree program at a public IHE in the state that is acceptable in transfer and that will provide credit toward the first two years of a related baccalaureate program at a public IHE in such state. Requires each public IHE, to the extent practicable, to include in its course schedule publication information on whether each listed course or program of study is part of its common general education core curriculum and is transferable for credit toward the completion of a degree at any public IHE with which it has an articulation agreement.

Requires each public IHE, by July 1, 2017, to enter into an articulation agreement with the other public IHEs located in its state.

Requires those agreements to include:

 a common general education core curriculum consisting of at least 30 credit hours or equivalent coursework that are fully transferable toward meeting specific degree or certificate requirements at other public IHEs in the state, common course numbering for substantially similar courses in that curriculum, and a guarantee that an associate degree in an academic major in the arts and sciences at a public IHE in the state will be credited as the first two years of a related baccalaureate program at other public IHEs in the state. Excepts Tribal Colleges or Universities from those articulation agreement requirements.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
