<bill session="114" type="h" number="1782" updated="2019-02-20T18:37:51Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cuba Human Rights Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote human rights in Cuba, urge the Cuban Government to meet certain human rights milestones, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Cuba Human Rights Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000522"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001107" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000600" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000372" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000377" joined="2015-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2015-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000567" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000554" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001193" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001187" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000409" joined="2015-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000435" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001165" joined="2015-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Africa, Global Health, Global Human Rights and International Organizations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Western Hemisphere.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Western Hemisphere, Civilian Security and Trade" code="HSFA07" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Africa, Global Health, Global Human Rights and International Organizations" code="HSFA16" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Cuba Human Rights Act of 2015

This bill expresses the sense of Congress that:

 the United States-Cuba relationship should not be changed, nor should any federal law or regulation be amended, until the government of Cuba ceases violating the human rights of the people of Cuba; the United States should overcome the jamming of radio and television signals of the Radio y Television Marti by the government of Cuba, and that the Broadcasting Board of Governors should not cut staffing, funding, or broadcast hours for Radio y Television Marti; if certain human rights conditions are not met the U.S. Permanent Representative to the United Nations (U.N.) should oppose and encourage other U.N. members to oppose Cuba's continued membership on the United Nations Human Rights Council; and the annual trafficking victims report to Congress should include an in-depth analysis of the facilitation of or involvement in severe forms of human trafficking by any official of the government of Cuba or of companies wholly or partially owned by the government of Cuba. Nothing in this Act may be construed as:

 prohibiting the donation of food to nongovernmental organizations or individuals in Cuba; restricting the export of medicine or medical supplies to Cuba, or abrogating any requirement that such exports be verified in conformity with the Cuban Democracy Act of 1992 or any other applicable federal law; or prohibiting or restricting any other form of assistance specified in the Cuban Democracy Act of 1992, including telecommunications, mail, and support for democracy.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
