<bill session="114" type="h" number="1981" updated="2019-01-09T21:09:51Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Employee Bonus Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to provide that an employee's `regular rate' for purposes of calculating overtime compensation will not be affected by certain additional payments.</title>
    <title type="display">Employee Bonus Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000059"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001094" joined="2015-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000377" joined="2015-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001048" joined="2015-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000387" joined="2015-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001144" joined="2015-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000181" joined="2015-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000018" joined="2015-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000238" joined="2016-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000031" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000129" joined="2015-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Workforce Protections" code="HSED10" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Employee Bonus Protection Act

This bill amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to exclude from the regular rate at which an employee is employed (and at which overtime compensation is calculated) any sums paid in recognition of services performed during a given period if the payments are made to reward an employee or group of employees for meeting or exceeding the productivity, quality, efficiency, or sales goals specified in writing in a gainsharing plan, incentive bonus plan, commission plan, or performance contingent bonus plan and made available to the employees.

The amount of the payments made under the plan (and excluded from calculation of overtime compensation) must be:

 based upon a formula stated in the plan, and established and maintained in good faith for the purpose of distributing to employees additional remuneration over and above the wages and salaries that are not dependent upon the existence of the plan or payments made pursuant to it.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
