<bill session="114" type="s" number="3274" updated="2018-06-02T07:47:45Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Countering Foreign Propaganda and Disinformation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to counter foreign disinformation and propaganda, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Countering Foreign Propaganda and Disinformation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000449"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2016-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5181"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2692"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Countering Foreign Propaganda and Disinformation Act

This bill directs the Department of State to establish a Center for Information Analysis and Response to:

 coordinate the sharing among government agencies of information on foreign government information warfare efforts, establish a process for integrating information on foreign propaganda and disinformation efforts into national strategy, and develop and synchronize interagency activities to expose and counter foreign information operations directed against U.S. national security interests and advance narratives that support U.S. allies and interests. The President is authorized to designate a U.S. government official to lead an interagency team and to manage the center.

 The center may provide grants to or contract with specified entities to:

 support local independent media to refute foreign disinformation and manipulation in their communities, collect and store examples of disinformation and propaganda directed at the United States and its allies, analyze foreign government information warfare tactics and techniques, and support center efforts to counter foreign disinformation and propaganda efforts to influence the policies and social and political stability of the United States and its allies. The President shall ensure that the State Department, when selecting participants for U.S. educational and cultural exchange programs, gives special consideration to students and community leaders from populations and countries deemed vulnerable to foreign propaganda and disinformation campaigns.

The center shall terminate 15 years after enactment of this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
