<bill session="115" type="s" number="1775" updated="2019-04-18T16:38:52Z">
  <state datetime="2017-09-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-09-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to make permanent the authority of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to transport individuals to and from facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs in connection with rehabilitation, counseling, examination, treatment, and care, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Veterans Travel Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Veterans Travel Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Rural Veterans Travel Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2017-09-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-09-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="3720"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-09-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Rural Veterans Travel Enhancement Act of 2017

This bill requires Vet Centers (centers for readjustment counseling and related mental health services for veterans) to be treated as Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) facilities for purposes of payment of medical-related expenses or allowances for travel to or from a VA facility.

 The bill makes permanent VA authority to transport individuals to and from VA facilities in connection with vocational rehabilitation or counseling or for examination, treatment, or care.

The Caregivers and Veterans Omnibus Health Services Act of 2010 is amended to reauthorize through FY2020 grants to state veterans service organizations to assist veterans in highly rural areas to travel to VA medical centers.

The VA shall: (1) establish a national protocol to administer medical examinations for volunteer drivers to participate in the veterans transportation program, and (2) implement the protocol by first conducting a one-year pilot program. The Government Accountability Office shall report to Congress on such program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
