<bill session="114" type="h" number="3085" updated="2018-08-28T23:10:22Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lead Exposure Accountability During Sales Avoids Lead Endangerment Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LEAD SALE Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 1018 of the Residential Lead-Based Paint Hazard Reduction Act of 1992 to make violators of such section liable to residents and invitees of target housing for such violations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">LEAD SALE Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2015-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000984" joined="2015-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2015-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2016-09-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Lead Exposure Accountability During Sales Avoids Lead Endangerment Act of 2015 or the LEAD SALE Act of 2015

This bill amends the Residential Lead-Based Paint Hazard Reduction Act of 1992 with respect to federal regulations governing the disclosure of lead-based paint hazards in target housing that is offered for sale or lease.

A civil liability shall be imposed upon any violators of these regulations who fail to disclose lead-based paint hazards to residents or invitees of the target housing suffering damages from them.

Authority is granted to:

 the Department of Housing and Urban Development to investigate, administer oaths, and subpoena the production of documents, and the attendance and testimony of witnesses, in order to implement lead disclosure requirements; and any U.S. district court within the jurisdiction of a noncompliance inquiry to enforce such requirements.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
