<amendment session="115" chamber="h" number="527" updated="2019-06-13T18:49:58Z">
  <amends type="h" number="1865" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2018-02-27T15:33:12-05:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <offered datetime="2018-02-27"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 3 printed in House Report 115-583 to request a GAO study of: (1) civil damages claimed and awarded in civil actions where the claimant alleges the defendant promoted or facilitated the prostitution of five or more people, or acted in reckless disregard of the fact that their conduct contributed to sex trafficking, filed pursuant to 18 USC 2421A(c); and (2) mandatory restitution requested and orders imposed by courts where a defendant is convicted of using or operating a facility or means of interstate or foreign commerce with intent to promote or facilitate the prostitution of another, promoted or facilitated the prostitution of five or more people, or acted in reckless disregard of the fact that their conduct contributed to sex trafficking, pursuant to 18 USC 2421A(d).</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2018-02-27T15:33:12-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Jackson Lee amendment (A003) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-02-27T15:23:27-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A003) offered by Ms. Jackson Lee.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1304-1305" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1304" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-27"/>
    <action datetime="2018-02-27T15:23:27-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A003) offered by Ms. Jackson Lee.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1304-1305" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1304" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-27T15:33:12-05:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Jackson Lee amendment (A003) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-27T15:33:12-05:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-27">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
