<bill session="114" type="h" number="5494" updated="2019-01-09T21:26:33Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">We the People Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Democracy Is Strengthened by Casting Light On Spending in Elections Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">DISCLOSE Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Federal Election Administration Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Financial Services Conflict of Interest Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Real Time Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Stop Super PAC-Candidate Coordination Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reform our government, reduce the grip of special interests, and return our democracy to the American people through increased transparency and oversight of our elections and government.</title>
    <title type="display">We the People Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000523"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000557" joined="2016-07-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, Oversight and Government Reform, Financial Services, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, Oversight and Government Reform, Financial Services, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, Oversight and Government Reform, Financial Services, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, Oversight and Government Reform, Financial Services, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, Oversight and Government Reform, Financial Services, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="430"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3065"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5439"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="229"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1779"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1838"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="425"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2212"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2611"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Election Commission (FEC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Housing Finance Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="National Credit Union Administration"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">We the People Act of 2016

Democracy Is Supported by Casting Light On Spending in Elections Act of 2016 or the DISCLOSE Act of 2016

This bill amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) to:

 redefine "independent expenditure" to expand the meaning of express advocacy for the election or defeat of a candidate; expand the period for treating communications as electioneering communications; repeal the prohibition against contributions by minors; prescribe disclosure requirements for campaign-related disbursements by corporations, labor organizations, and certain other entities, including super political action committees (PACs); prescribe requirements for (Stand by Your Ad) disclosure of top funders of radio, television, and telephone advocacy communications; and prescribe requirements for disclosures by covered organizations to shareholders, members, and donors of information on campaign-related disbursements. The Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 is amended to require the disclosure of any independent expenditure and electioneering communication equal to or greater than $1,000.

Stop Super PAC-Candidate Coordination Act

The bill amends FECA to treat payments for coordinated expenditures as contributions to candidates under certain conditions, and set forth rules for coordinated expenditures.

The bill also prohibits candidates, individual federal officeholders, agents of a candidate or an individual federal officeholder, or certain related entities from soliciting, receiving, directing, or transferring funds to or on behalf of any political committee which accepts donations or contributions that do not comply with FECA limitations, prohibitions, and reporting requirements, or to or on behalf of any political organization which accepts such donations or contributions.

Real Time Transparency Act

The bill amends FECA to require 48-hour notification to the Federal Election Commission (FEC) by all political committees receiving cumulative contributions (instead of single contributions) of $1,000 or more during a year from any contributor.

Federal Election Administration Act of 2016

FECA is also amended to replace the FEC with the Federal Election Administration (FEA).

The Government Accountability Office shall: (1) examine the enforcement of the criminal provisions of FECA and prohibitions regarding the Presidential Election Campaign Fund and the Presidential Primary Matching Payment Account, and (2) study the adequate level of resources for the FEA to execute competently the responsibilities imposed by this bill.

 The Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 is amended to revise the definition of lobbyist to mean any individual who is employed or retained by a client for financial or other compensation for services that include more than one lobbying contact over a two-year (currently three-month) period.

Financial Services Conflict of Interest Act

The federal criminal code is amended regarding application of certain conflict-of-interest restrictions to a private sector employer that makes payment of compensation contingent on accepting a position in the federal government.

The Ethics in Government Act of 1978 is amended to prohibit a covered financial services regulator from making, participating in making, or in any way attempting to use his or her official position to influence a particular matter that provides a direct and substantial pecuniary benefit for a former employer or former client.

The Office of Government Ethics must discharge certain record keeping duties to implement this bill.

Violators of this bill shall be subject to specified criminal and civil penalties.

The bill revises and extends certain restrictions on subsequent employment on current and former procurement officers.

The federal criminal code is also amended to place specified time restrictions on subsequent employment for financial service regulators.

The Federal Deposit Insurance Act is amended to revise restrictions on federal examiners and supervisors of financial institutions.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
