<bill session="114" type="s" number="460" updated="2018-06-02T06:33:22Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Drinking Water Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to provide for the assessment and management of the risk of algal toxins in drinking water, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Drinking Water Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000449"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2015-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="212"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1709"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-11T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Drinking Water Protection Act 

This bill amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to direct the Environmental Protection Agency to develop and submit to Congress a strategic plan for assessing and managing risks associated with algal toxins in drinking water provided by public water systems. Cyanobacteria, also known as blue-green algae, have the ability to produce cyanotoxins, or algal toxins. When certain conditions are favorable, algae can rapidly multiply causing blooms, or dense surface scums, that may be toxic.

The plan must include steps and time lines to:

 evaluate the risk to human health from drinking water contaminated with algal toxins; establish, publish, and update a comprehensive list of algal toxins that may have an adverse effect on human health; summarize the known adverse human health effects of algal toxins and the factors that cause toxin-producing cyanobacteria and algae to grow rapidly and make toxins; determine whether to publish health advisories for algal toxins and establish relevant guidance; recommend feasible treatment options; and enter into cooperative agreements with, and provide technical assistance to, affected states and public water systems to manage risks associated with algal toxins.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
