<bill session="114" type="s" number="1039" updated="2018-08-16T22:53:53Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require certain agencies to conduct assessments of data centers and develop data center consolidation and optimization plans to achieve energy cost savings.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to require certain agencies to conduct assessments of data centers and develop data center consolidation and optimization plans to achieve energy cost savings.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000584"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1008"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Requires the Department of Energy (DOE), assisted by its chief information officer, to submit each year, beginning in FY2015 through FY2019, to the Office of E-Government and Information Technology of the Office of Management and Budget: (1) a comprehensive asset inventory of the data centers owned, operated, or maintained by or on behalf of DOE; and (2) an updated consolidation plan for such data centers. Requires the DOE Inspector General to issue a public report evaluating the completeness of the DOE asset inventory.

Requires the Office of E-Government and Information Technology to: (1) establish the deadline, on an annual basis, for agencies to submit information required by this Act; (2) develop and publish a goal for the total amount of planned cost savings through the Federal Data Center Consolidation Initiative during a five-year period and report on the actual savings achieved through the Initiative; and (3) report to Congress on DOE data center cost savings. Directs the Government Accountability Office to publish an annual report on DOE asset inventory and consolidation plans and DOE's implementation of such plans.

Requires DOE to migrate to cloud computing in a manner consistent with federal guidelines on cloud computing security, including applicable provisions in the Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program of the General Services Administration and guidance published by the National Institute of Standards and Technology.

Authorizes the Director of National Intelligence to waive requirements of this Act for any element of the intelligence community.

Repeals this Act effective on October 1, 2019.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
