<bill session="114" type="s" number="1767" updated="2018-06-02T06:57:40Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Combination Product Regulatory Fairness Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Combination Product Regulatory Fairness Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to combination products, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Combination Product Regulatory Fairness Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2015-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2015-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000607" joined="2015-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2015-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2015-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000461" joined="2015-08-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-03-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-04-05">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Alexander with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-04-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="414">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 414.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="34"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-04-05T11:08:31Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Combination Product Regulatory Fairness Act of 2016

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to revise provisions regarding products that are a combination of a drug, medical device, or biological product.

The primary mode of action of a combination product must be the mode of action that makes the greatest contribution to the product's therapeutic effect. (Combination products are regulated based on their primary mode of action.) The FDA is prohibited from determining that a combination product is a drug or biological product solely because the product has a chemical action. If the sponsor of a combination product disagrees with the FDA's determination of the primary mode of action of the product, the FDA must provide the rationale for its determination and the sponsor and the FDA may agree to studies to inform a reevaluation of the product.

After the primary mode of action of a product is determined, the sponsor and the FDA may agree to a combination product review plan that may address the standards and requirements applicable to the product's review, postmarket modification, or manufacturing. The plan must remain in effect unless the sponsor and the FDA agree otherwise or an issue essential to determining the safety or effectiveness of the product is identified.

The FDA may require the sponsor of a combination product that contains an approved constituent part to submit to the FDA only information that is necessary to assess the safety and effectiveness of the combination product, taking into account prior findings regarding the approved constituent part. If the approved constituent part is a drug, the application for the combination product must comply with specified requirements for drug applications.

The FDA Office of Combination Products must coordinate reviews of combination products and oversee feedback regarding such reviews. The office must review FDA agreements, guidance, and practices regarding combination products.

The FDA must: (1) issue guidance that describes the process and best practices for review of combination products, and (2) propose that certain types of combination products may adopt good manufacturing practices that vary from requirements in regulations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
