<bill session="113" type="s" number="1784" updated="2016-10-25T16:27:54Z">
  <state datetime="2014-11-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-11-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Oregon and California Land Grant Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Oregon and California Land Grant Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve timber management on Oregon and California Railroad and Coos Bay Wagon Road grant land, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Oregon and California Land Grant Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8572"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-06">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 113-349.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-11-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Landrieu with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 113-307.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="646">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 646.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2488"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="352"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1414"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1415"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1215"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1230"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2491"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="5511"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="5512"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-12-11T18:35:36Z" status="Reported to Senate amended">Oregon and California Land Grant Act of 2014 - Amends the O&amp;C Lands Act of 1937 to establish uses and management requirements for the Oregon and California Railroad and Coos Bay Wagon Road grant land and other Oregon land administered by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), the Forest Service, and the Army Corps of Engineers. Designates separate portions of the land for conservation and timber harvesting.

Specifies requirements for managing the land, including: prohibiting the harvesting of trees of a specified age in certain areas, stating that Oregon retains jurisdiction over fish and wildlife, restricting the use of pesticides, and authorizing treatment of hazardous fuels on adjacent private lands.

Directs the Department of the Interior to identify projects proposed under this Act, assess implementation, and complete other specified reports and analyses.

Establishes requirements for timber harvests on designated lands, including calculating projected harvests, restricting roads, harvesting timber to reduce the likelihood of wildfires, and prioritizing treatments near communities.

Designates lands for conservation purposes and establishes requirements for management, including restricting timber harvesting, motorized vehicles, and roads.

Sets forth procedures for administrative and judicial review of projects under this Act. Specifies a formula for sharing receipts generated on land between the U.S. Treasury, the BLM, and counties.

Transfers specified BLM-administered lands to be held in trust as reservations for the Confederated Tribes of Coos, Lower Umpqua, and Siuslaw Indians; and the Cow Creek Band of Umpqua Tribe of Indians.

Establishes and modifies specified wilderness areas and designations under the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 113-307</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
