<bill session="114" type="h" number="804" updated="2018-11-21T21:22:59Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expanding the Availability of Medicare Data Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to increase access to Medicare data.</title>
    <title type="display">Expanding the Availability of Medicare Data Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000570"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000614" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000576" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000188" joined="2015-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2015-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000587" joined="2015-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000244" joined="2015-02-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1470"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="810"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Expanding the Availability of Medicare Data Act 

Expands the kinds of uses of Medicare data available to qualified entities for quality and patient care improvement activities.

(A "qualified entity" is a public or private entity that: [1] is qualified to use claims data to evaluate the performance of service providers and suppliers on measures of quality, efficiency, effectiveness, and resource use; and [2] agrees to meet specified requirements, such as ensuring data security.) Authorizes a qualified entity to use claims data combined with non-claims data the entity has received, as well as information derived from evaluation of service provider and supplier performance, to conduct additional non-public analyses and provide or sell them to authorized users for non-public use (including to assist service providers and suppliers to develop and participate in quality and patient care improvement activities, including new models of care).

Defines "authorized users" as service providers, suppliers, employers, health insurance issuers, medical societies or hospital associations, or any other entities approved by the Secretary of Health and Human Services.

Prohibits a qualified entity from charging a fee to provide Medicare claims data.

Requires a qualified entity and an authorized user to enter into a data use agreement, and prohibits the use of data or analyses for marketing purposes or, except in certain circumstances, its redisclosure.

Directs the Secretary to provide Medicare data to qualified clinical data registries for purposes of linking it with clinical outcomes data and performing risk-adjusted, scientifically valid analyses and research to support quality improvement or patient safety. Requires charging a fee to a registry for such data.

Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSAct) to include among standardized extracts of Medicare claims data that may be made available to qualified entities, if the Secretary determines appropriate, also claims data under SSAct titles XIX (Medicaid) and XXI (State Children's Health Insurance) (CHIP).

Requires any fees charged for making standardized extracts available to qualified entities to be deposited into the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services Program Management Account (currently, into the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund).</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
