<bill session="115" type="h" number="3389" updated="2019-04-18T16:13:35Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To give priority in allocation of rental assistance vouchers under the Veterans Affairs Supported Housing program of the Department of Housing and Urban Development to areas having the largest populations of homeless veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Housing Homeless Veterans Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Housing Homeless Veterans Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Housing Homeless Veterans Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001300"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Housing Homeless Veterans Act of 2017

This bill amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to require the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), in making Veterans Affairs-Supported Housing (VASH) program funds available among public-housing agencies (PHAs) for rental voucher assistance for homeless veterans who have chronic mental illnesses or chronic substance-use disorders, to&#160;give priority to PHAs that: (1) serve areas having the highest numbers of homeless veterans, and (2) have fully utilized their available HUD-VASH funds for the preceding fiscal year and have demonstrated need for such incremental assistance.

HUD shall: (1) recapture from a PHA certain unused HUD-VASH assistance, and (2)&#160;reallocate recaptured amounts to PHAs that have used their entire allocations of HUD-VASH assistance.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
