<bill session="113" type="sr" number="4" updated="2016-10-25T16:18:06Z">
  <state datetime="2013-01-03">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution to limit certain uses of the filibuster in the Senate to improve the legislative process.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution to limit certain uses of the filibuster in the Senate to improve the legislative process.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000039"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001265" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2013-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2013-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000206" joined="2013-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2013-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2013-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2013-01-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-03">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Over, Under the Rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="sr" session="113" relation="unknown" number="6"/>
    <bill type="sr" session="113" relation="unknown" number="600"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amends Rule XXII (Precedence of Motions) of the Standing Rules of the Senate to limit, with exceptions, consideration of a motion to proceed to the consideration of any debatable matter to not more than two hours, equally divided between, and controlled by, the Majority Leader and the Minority Leader or their designees.

Considers cloture of debate to have been invoked upon affirmative vote on the question of closing debate by three-fifths of Senators (two-thirds of those present and voting on a measure or motion to amend the Senate rules).

Makes it in order for the Majority Leader (or his or her designee), if the question on closing debate is decided in the affirmative by a majority of Senators voting but less than three-fifths of the Senators duly chosen and sworn (or less than two-thirds of the Senators voting, a quorum being present, in the case of a measure or motion to amend the Senate rules), to initiate a period of extended debate, to begin one hour later, upon the measure, motion, or other matter pending before the Senate, or the unfinished business, in relation to which the motion to close debate was offered.

Provides procedures applicable during such extended debate concerning: (1) the consideration of the measure, motion, or other pending matter, or the unfinished business, as the unfinished business to the exclusion of all other business; (2) the raising of a question about the presence of a quorum; (3) motions to adjourn or recess during such debate; (4) the number of times a Senator may speak; (5) postponement of a vote by the Majority Leader; and (6) the effects upon cloture if at any time no Senator seeks recognition.

Limits to two hours post-cloture debate on the question of advice and consent to a nomination other than one to a position as Justice of the Supreme Court.

Amends Rule XXVIII (Conference Committees; Reports; Open Meetings) to make in order and limit to two hours consideration of a nondivisible motion to: (1) disagree to a House amendment or insist upon a Senate amendment, (2) request a committee of conference with the House or to agree to a House request for a committee of conference, and (3) authorize the Presiding Officer to appoint conferees (or to appoint conferees).</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
