<bill session="113" type="h" number="4107" updated="2016-10-25T16:11:07Z">
  <state datetime="2014-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reduce Expenditures in Nuclear Infrastructure Now Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REIN-IN Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reduce the number of nuclear-armed submarines operated by the Navy, to prohibit the development of a new long-range penetrating bomber aircraft, to prohibit the procurement of new intercontinental ballistic missiles, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">REIN-IN Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000574"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2014-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000399" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000290" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2014-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2014-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2014-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2014-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2014-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2014-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2014-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001175" joined="2014-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E271-272"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="505"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="1506"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="2070"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Chemistry"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-02-27T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Reduce Expenditures in Nuclear Infrastructure Now Act or the REIN-IN Act - Prohibits the obligation or expenditure of funds authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Defense (DOD) for FY2014-FY2023: (1) for the research, development, test, and evaluation (RDT&amp;E) or procurement of a long-range penetrating bomber aircraft; (2) to procure an SSBN-X submarine (and prohibits the use of such funds for FY2024 and thereafter to procure more than eight such submarines); or (3) for the RDT&amp;E or procurement of a new intercontinental ballistic missile (ICBM).

Prohibits the obligation or expenditure of funds authorized to be appropriated for FY2014 or thereafter for DOD or the Department of Energy (DOE): (1) to make the F-35 Joint Strike Fighter aircraft capable of carrying nuclear weapons; (2) until the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Energy jointly certify that the total cost of the B61 life extension program has been reduced to not more than $5 billion; (3) for the W78 life extension program; (4) for the mixed oxide fuel fabrication facility project; (5) to replace the chemistry and metallurgy research building at Los Alamos National Laboratory, Los Alamos, New Mexico; or (6) for the uranium processing facility at the Y-12 National Security Complex, Oak Ridge, Tennessee.

Prohibits Navy forces, beginning in FY2020, from including more than eight operational ballistic-missile submarines available for deployment.

Prohibits the use of DOD funds for FY2014 or thereafter: (1) to maintain more than 250 submarine-launched ballistic missiles; (2) to maintain more than 150 intercontiental ballistic missiles (ICBMs) on a 24-hour, high alert status; or (3) for the medium extended air defense system.

Requires initial and annual reports from the Secretaries of Defense and Energy outlining their respective plans to carry out the requirements of this Act.

Directs the President to submit to Congress an annual report containing a comprehensive accounting by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) of the amounts obligated or expended by the federal government for each nuclear weapon and related nuclear program during the fiscal year covered by the report for the life cycle of such weapon or program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
