<bill session="115" type="h" number="4142" updated="2019-04-18T16:16:56Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-10-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect individuals by strengthening the Nation's mental health infrastructure, improving the understanding of violence, strengthening firearm prohibitions and protections for at-risk individuals, and improving and expanding the reporting of mental health records to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safer Communities Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safer Communities Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Safer Communities Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000460"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2018-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2017-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2018-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2018-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000375" joined="2018-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000593" joined="2017-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001165" joined="2018-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-10-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2913"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1370"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-10-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Safer Communities Act of 2017

This bill provides grants to expand mental health crisis assistance programs, support comprehensive school mental health programs, and enhance mental health and substance abuse needs of prisoners.

The Department of Health and Human Services must expand research on violence associated with mental illness and substance abuse disorders.

The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention must expand the National Violent Death Reporting System to all 50 states and research the causes, mechanisms, prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of injuries from gun violence.

The bill states that no provision of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act prohibits physicians from asking patients about guns in their homes, speaking to a patient about gun safety, or reporting a patient's threat of violence.

It amends the federal criminal code to specify that the term "committed to a mental institution" applies to involuntary inpatient or outpatient treatment.

 It amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to authorize state grants to remove firearms from individuals who pose a threat to themselves or others.

The Department of Justice must promptly notify law enforcement agencies when a prohibited person attempts to purchase a firearm.

The bill replaces statutory references to persons "adjudicated as a mental defective" with persons "adjudicated as ineligible due to disqualifying mental status."

It amends the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007 to:

 establish procedures to restore firearm ownership rights after a mental health adjudication or commitment, require an annual report on record submissions due to domestic violence misdemeanor convictions, authorize state grants to improve the automation and transmittal of mental health and criminal history records, and require quarterly updates to federal agency record submissions. The bill reauthorizes the National Criminal History Records Improvement Program through FY2023.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
