<bill session="114" type="s" number="2922" updated="2018-06-02T07:18:43Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhanced Veteran Healthcare Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for partnerships and contracts between the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and eligible academic affiliates for the mutually beneficial coordination, use, or exchange of health-care resources, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Enhanced Veteran Healthcare Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000802"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3879"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Enhanced Veteran Healthcare Act of 2016

 This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to seek to enter into covered partnerships and contracts for the mutually beneficial coordination, use, or exchange of covered VA health-care resources with eligible academic affiliates in order to improve access to, and quality of, VA hospital care and medical services.

 The VA shall use non-competitive procedures in the case of a partnership or contract for:

 coordination, use, or exchange of a clinical service; use of medical equipment or space; research; construction or lease of clinical space; use of any full-time equivalent VA employee or contractor; or use of any full-time equivalent employee jointly hired by the VA and an eligible academic affiliate.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
