<bill session="114" type="s" number="1851" updated="2018-06-02T06:58:13Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Human Rights for Girls Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to require States to eliminate the use of restraints on pregnant juveniles in State correction facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Human Rights for Girls Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000148"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2015-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5963"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="6459"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Human Rights for Girls Act 

This bill amends the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to require a state that receives a formula grant under the juvenile justice and delinquency prevention program to limit the use of restraints with respect to pregnant juvenile offenders.

Specifically, the legislation requires a state's juvenile justice plan to: (1) contain a plan to limit restraints during pregnancy and eliminate restraints during labor, delivery, and post-partum recovery, unless a pregnant juvenile offender poses a serious threat of harm or credible risk of escape; and (2) describe the policies, procedures, and training for state correctional facility staff to eliminate dangerous practices related to pregnant juveniles, including unreasonable restraints. &#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
