<bill session="114" type="s" number="1776" updated="2019-06-21T11:07:12Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-10">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-12-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">TIRES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Tribal Infrastructure and Roads Enhancement and Safety Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TIRES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tribal Infrastructure and Roads Enhancement and Safety Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">TIRES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Tribal Infrastructure and Roads Enhancement and Safety Act</title>
    <title type="display">TIRES Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance tribal road safety, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2015-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2016-04-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5131" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-07-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-02-29">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Barrasso with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 114-217.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-02-29" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="378">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 378.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-12-10">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7147-7149" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7147-7148" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-10">
      <text>The committee substitute withdrawn by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7148" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2016-12-10" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-12-12">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-12T15:05:19-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-12T16:50:10-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s5184"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2016-12-10T22:23:58Z" status="Passed Senate amended">Tribal Infrastructure and Roads Enhancement and Safety Act or the TIRES Act

(Sec. 3) This bill modifies the approval process used for certain transportation projects on Indian reservations by allowing&#160;categorical exclusions from National Environmental Policy Act (NEPA) requirements.

A "categorical exclusion" is a category of actions which do not individually or cumulatively have a significant effect on the human environment and which have been found to have no such effect in procedures adopted by a federal agency in implementing environmental regulations and for which, therefore, neither an environmental assessment nor an environmental impact statement is required.

A "tribal transportation safety project" is one that is eligible for assistance under the tribal transportation program and that:

 corrects or improves a hazardous road location or feature, or addresses a highway safety problem. The Department of the Interior shall review existing categorical exclusions for tribal transportation program projects and identify tribal transportation safety projects that meet categorical exclusion requirements.

The bill prescribes requirements for the expedited review and approval of tribal transportation safety projects under NEPA or other federal laws.

(Sec. 4) Interior shall enter into five-year programmatic agreements with Indian tribes that establish efficient administrative procedures for carrying out environmental reviews for tribal transportation projects, including whether any project is categorically excluded from the preparation of an environmental assessment or impact statement under NEPA.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-217</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
