<bill session="114" type="h" number="1079" updated="2019-04-11T15:42:41Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to provide grants to States to establish a comprehensive school counseling program.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Counseling for Career Choice Act</title>
    <title type="display">Counseling for Career Choice Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000559"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000911" joined="2015-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001286" joined="2015-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2015-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2015-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000375" joined="2015-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000379" joined="2015-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000560" joined="2015-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000604" joined="2015-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2015-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2015-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000467" joined="2015-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational guidance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-25T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Counseling for Career Choice Act

Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to award competitive establishment grants to states to develop and implement comprehensive school career counseling programs that provide students with effective postsecondary education planning and career guidance services.

Requires each program to be aligned with a statewide counseling framework that: (1) encompasses grades 6 through 12 and postsecondary education; and (2) is developed in consultation with, or exists with the support of, at least five stakeholders that include at least one business or industry and at least one local educational agency (LEA) or secondary school.

Requires establishment grant funds to be used to:

 train and hire school counselors; identify regional workforce trends and postsecondary options available in the state; establish, improve, or coordinate postsecondary opportunities; recommend curricular improvements to better align curricula with workforce trends and available postsecondary opportunities; establish partnerships with American Job Centers; and leverage the resources and emerging technologies being developed by stakeholders to support the counseling framework. Allows states to carry out program activities directly or through competitive subgrants to LEAs, or consortia consisting of an LEA, and one or more LEAs, educational service agencies, tribal organizations, postsecondary institutions, or nonprofit organizations with expertise in counseling or career and technical education.

Directs the Secretary to reserve at least 10%, but no more than 20%, of the amount appropriated for this Act's counseling program to award competitive capacity-building grants to states that do not receive an establishment grant.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
