<bill session="115" type="s" number="1707" updated="2019-04-18T16:38:34Z">
  <state datetime="2017-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to provide for a standard medical expense deduction under the supplemental nutrition assistance program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SNAP Standard Medical Expense Deduction Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SNAP Standard Medical Expense Deduction Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">SNAP Standard Medical Expense Deduction Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000555"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2017-11-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-08-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="3749"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-08-02T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">SNAP Standard Medical Expense Deduction Act of 2017 

This bill amends the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to allow households containing an elderly or disabled member to use a standard medical expense deduction for calculating income to apply for Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP, formerly known as the food stamp program) benefits.

If the amount of actual costs of allowable medical expenses incurred by the elderly or disabled member for a month, exclusive of special diets, is equal to or greater than $35, the standard medical deduction for each month is: (1) $140 for FY2018, and (2) the preceding year's amount with a specified adjustment for inflation for FY2019 and each subsequent year. If the monthly costs are greater than the sum of the standard medical deduction and $35, the household may deduct the actual costs.

The Department of Agriculture (USDA) may approve a standard medical deduction that is higher than the amount required by this bill.

USDA must submit specified studies and reports to Congress regarding: (1) state performance in enrolling disabled and elderly individuals in SNAP and specified Medicare programs, (2) disability and food insecurity, and (3) the effectiveness of the standard medical deduction.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
