<bill session="114" type="s" number="832" updated="2018-06-02T06:44:11Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Care and Readiness Enhancement for Reservists Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CARE for Reservists Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to authorize the provision of behavioral health readiness services to certain members of the Selected Reserve of the Armed Forces based on need, to expand eligibility to such members for readjustment counseling from the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">CARE for Reservists Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Care and Readiness Enhancement for Reservists Act of 2015 or the CARE for Reservists Act of 2015

Authorizes the Secretary of the military department concerned to provide care for behavioral health conditions to any member of the Selected Reserve for whom such Secretary determines, based on the member's most recent medical exam or mental health assessment, that the receipt of such care will ensure that the member meets applicable standards of medical readiness.

Provides funding for such care through the Defense Health Program.

 Authorizes the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to furnish counseling, which may include a comprehensive individual assessment, to any member of the Selected Reserve who has a behavioral health condition or psychological trauma. States that such counseling or assessment shall not require a prior referral.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
