<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <latestTitle>America COMPETES Reauthorization Act of 2015</latestTitle>
        <type>HR</type>
        <number>1806</number>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-05-21</actionDate>
          <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        </latestAction>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114hr5639rfs/xml/BILLS-114hr5639rfs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
        <date>2016-07-12T04:00:00Z</date>
        <type>Referred in Senate</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114hr5639eh/xml/BILLS-114hr5639eh.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
        <date>2016-07-11T04:00:00Z</date>
        <type>Engrossed in House</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114hr5639ih/xml/BILLS-114hr5639ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
        <date>2016-07-06T04:00:00Z</date>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <billNumber>5639</billNumber>
    <committeeReports />
    <amendments />
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <byRequestType />
        <district>4</district>
        <middleName>R.</middleName>
        <fullName>Rep. Moolenaar, John R. [R-MI-4]</fullName>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId />
          <bioguideId>M001194</bioguideId>
          <lisID>2248</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <lastName>Moolenaar</lastName>
        <firstName>John</firstName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>MI</state>
        <bioguideId>M001194</bioguideId>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <notes />
    <introducedDate>2016-07-06</introducedDate>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Advanced technology and technological innovations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Advisory bodies</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of Commerce</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Freedom of information</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government information and archives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government lending and loan guarantees</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Higher education</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Industrial facilities</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>International organizations and cooperation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Israel</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Manufacturing</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Middle East</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Public contracts and procurement</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Public-private cooperation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Research administration and funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Research and development</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Science and engineering education</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Scientific communication</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Small business</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Student aid and college costs</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Teaching, teachers, curricula</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Trade secrets and economic espionage</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <updateDate>2019-04-11T15:46:39Z</updateDate>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          <subcommittees />
          <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2016-07-12T19:43:19Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
        </item>
        <item>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <name>Science, Space, and Technology Committee</name>
          <subcommittees />
          <systemCode>hssy00</systemCode>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2016-07-06T14:02:50Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <title>To update the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <title>National Institute of Standards and Technology Improvement Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <title>National Institute of Standards and Technology Improvement Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <version>1.0.0</version>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>[Congressional Record Volume 162, Number 108 (Wednesday, July 6, 2016)]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. MOOLENAAR:H.R. 5639.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8, Clause 18:The Congress shall have power to make all laws which shallbe necessary and proper for carrying into Execution theforegoing Powers, and all other Powers vested by thisConstitution in the Government of the United States, or inany Department of Officer thereof.[Page H4467]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <createDate>2016-07-07T05:54:28Z</createDate>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <updateDate>2016-07-06T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <actionDate>2016-07-06</actionDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>National Institute of Standards and Technology Improvement Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill amends the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act regarding the functions of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) of the Department of Commerce, the membership of the Visiting Committee on Advanced Technology, police protection of NIST buildings and plant facilities, and research fellowships (including the Post-Doctoral Fellowship Program). </p> <p>The NIST shall contract with:</p> <ul> <li>the National Academy of Sciences to review NIST laboratory programs; and</li> <li>the National Research Council to assess the technical quality and impact of the work conducted at NIST laboratories, and conduct additional assessments of NIST programs and projects that involve collaboration across NIST laboratories and centers and assessments of selected scientific and technical topics. </li> </ul> <p>The bill revises requirements for the Hollings Manufacturing Extension Partnership and Hollings Manufacturing Extension Centers to eliminate from Center activities the making of selective, short-term loans of advanced manufacturing equipment to small manufacturing firms with less than 100 employees.</p> <p>Center activities shall instead include facilitation of collaborations and partnerships between small and medium-sized manufacturing companies and community colleges and area career and technical education schools to help achieve mutual understanding. </p> <p>The bill repeals the six-year limitation on financial support Commerce may give to any Center created under the Partnership. </p> <p>A Center must: (1) undergo an independent review in its eighth year of operation, and (2) be placed on probation for one year if the evaluation is not positive.</p> <p>The bill requires each Center's advisory boards to institute a conflict of interest policy that ensures representation of local small and medium-sized manufacturers in the Center's region.</p> <p>The bill changes the membership on the Manufacturing Extension Partnership Advisory Board. </p> <p>Under the competitive grant program, the NIST shall select proposals that will promote the transfer and commercialization of research and technology from institutions of higher education, national laboratories, and nonprofit research institutes.</p> <p>The Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 is amended to repeal the limitation to 75% of the total program cost on the total amount of any grant or cooperative agreement to assist technology innovation activities under the Act. </p> <p>The bill expresses the sense of Congress concerning U.S.-Israeli cooperation with regard to basic scientific research. </p>]]></text>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-07-13T19:19:57Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        </item>
        <item>
          <updateDate>2016-07-11T14:33:53Z</updateDate>
          <actionDate>2016-07-11</actionDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>National Institute of Standards and Technology Improvement Act of 2016</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (NISTA) to authorize the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) of the Department of Commerce to serve as the President's principal advisor on standards policy pertaining to technological competitiveness and innovation ability.</p> <p>The NIST shall:</p> <ul> <li>facilitate standards-related information sharing and cooperation between federal agencies,</li> <li>participate in and support scientific and technical conferences, and</li> <li>perform pre-competitive measurement science and technology research with institutions of higher education and industry. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 3) The bill revises the membership of the Visiting Committee on Advanced Technology from a maximum of 15 to a minimum of 11, requiring that at least two-thirds of them (currently 10) be from U.S. industry. The Committee may consult with the National Research Council (NRC) in making recommendations regarding general policy for NIST.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) Commerce may undertake activities to give police protection to NIST buildings and other plant facilities, equipment, and property and persons located in them or associated with them. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) The bill revises requirements for research fellowships.</p> <p>The NIST may support, promote, and coordinate activities and efforts to enhance awareness and understanding of measurement sciences, standards, and technology.</p> <p>The Post-Doctoral Fellowship Program shall include no fewer than 20 fellows per fiscal year (currently, no fewer than 20 nor more than 120 new fellows per fiscal year). The bill eliminates the separate manufacturing fellowship and teacher science and technology enhancement programs. </p> <p>(Sec. 6) The three-year programmatic planning document for NIST shall describe how the NIST Director is addressing recommendations from the Visiting Committee on Advanced Technology. </p> <p>(Sec. 7) The NIST shall contract with the National Academy of Sciences to review NIST laboratory programs. </p> <p>The NIST shall contract with the NRC to assess the technical quality and impact of the work conducted at NIST laboratories. (Currently, NIST may contract with the NRC for advice and studies to serve industry and science.) </p> <p>The NIST may contract with the NRC also to conduct additional assessments of NIST programs and projects that involve collaboration across NIST laboratories and centers and assessments of selected scientific and technical topics. </p> <p>(Sec. 8) The bill revises requirements for the Hollings Manufacturing Extension Partnership and Hollings Manufacturing Extension Centers. </p> <p>One objective of the Centers shall be the promotion and expansion of certification systems offered through industry, associations, and local colleges. </p> <p>The bill eliminates from Center activities the making of selective, short-term loans of advanced manufacturing equipment to small manufacturing firms with less than 100 employees.</p> <p>Those activities shall instead include facilitation of collaborations and partnerships between small and medium-sized manufacturing companies and community colleges and area career and technical education schools to help: (1) the colleges and schools better understand the specific needs of manufacturers, and (2) manufacturers better understand the skill sets that students learn in the programs offered by those institutions. </p> <p>The bill repeals the six-year limitation on financial support Commerce may give to any Center created under the Partnership. </p> <p>Commerce shall implement, review, and update regulations related to the Partnership at least once every three years. </p> <p>The bill revises cost-sharing requirements for the receipt by an applicant of financial assistance under the Partnership. </p> <p>A Center must: (1) undergo an independent review in its eighth year of operation, and (2) be placed on probation for one year if the evaluation is not positive. If a Center, upon reevaluation, has not shown a significant improvement in its performance, the NIST shall conduct a new competition to select an operator for the Center; or, as an alternative, the Center may be closed.</p> <p>The NIST shall: (1) transmit to Congress a plan for how it will conduct reviews, assessments, and reapplication competitions; and (2) contract with an independent organization to assess the implementation of the reapplication competition process required for any Center after 10 consecutive years of financial assistance. </p> <p>The Freedom of Information Act shall apply to:</p> <ul> <li>confidential information obtained by the government on the business operation of any participant in a Partnership program or of a client of a Center, and </li> <li>trade secrets possessed by any client of a Center. </li> </ul> <p>Each Center's advisory boards shall institute a conflict of interest policy that ensures representation of local small and medium-sized manufacturers in the Center's region. No board members shall serve or deliver services to the Center or serve on more than one Center's oversight board simultaneously. </p> <p>The bill changes the membership of the Manufacturing Extension Partnership Advisory Board from a maximum to a minimum of 10, at least one of whom represents a community college. </p> <p>Under the competitive grant program, the NIST shall select proposals that will promote the transfer and commercialization of research and technology from institutions of higher education, national laboratories, and nonprofit research institutes.</p> <p>The bill eliminates the separate innovative services initiative to assist small- and medium-sized manufacturers.</p> <p>(Sec. 9) The bill also eliminates the requirement for NIST, through the Technology Innovation Program (TIP), to continue providing support originally awarded under the Advanced Technology Program. </p> <p>(Sec. 10) The Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 is amended to repeal the limitation to 75% of the total program cost on the total amount of any grant or cooperative agreement to assist technology innovation activities under the Act.</p> <p>(Sec. 11) In developing standards and guidelines for information systems, the NIST shall not consult with the Department of Defense and the National Security Agency in contravention of the NISTA requirement that it do so. </p> <p>(Sec. 12) The bill expresses the sense of Congress concerning U.S.-Israeli cooperation with regard to basic scientific research. </p> <p>The NIST should continue to facilitate scientific collaborations between Israel and the U.S. technical agencies working in measurement science and standardization.</p>]]></text>
          <actionDesc>Passed House amended</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-07-13T19:19:08Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <name>Passed House amended</name>
          <versionCode>36</versionCode>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
    </policyArea>
    <recordedVotes />
    <laws />
    <latestAction>
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <actionDate>2016-07-12</actionDate>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <generalDebate>1</generalDebate>
        <passedAgreedToInHouse>1</passedAgreedToInHouse>
        <finalPassageUnderSuspensionOfTheRulesResults>1</finalPassageUnderSuspensionOfTheRulesResults>
        <considerationByHouse>1</considerationByHouse>
        <motionMadeToSuspendTheRules>1</motionMadeToSuspendTheRules>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
        <motionToReconsiderResults>1</motionToReconsiderResults>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-07-12</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
          <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>H38310</actionCode>
        <links />
        <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionTime>19:46:11</actionTime>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-07-11</actionDate>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>H37300</actionCode>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H4641-4644</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-162/house-section/page/H4641-4644</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote. (text: CR H4641-4644)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionTime>19:46:09</actionTime>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-07-11</actionDate>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>8000</actionCode>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H4641-4644</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-162/house-section/page/H4641-4644</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>Passed/agreed to in House: On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.(text: CR H4641-4644)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionTime>19:46:09</actionTime>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-07-11</actionDate>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H.R. 5639</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/bill/114th-congress/house-bill/5639</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5639.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionTime>19:35:38</actionTime>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-07-11</actionDate>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>H30000</actionCode>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H4641-4645</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-162/house-section/page/H4641-4645</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>Considered under suspension of the rules. (consideration: CR H4641-4645)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionTime>19:35:34</actionTime>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-07-11</actionDate>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>H30300</actionCode>
        <links />
        <text>Mr. Moolenaar moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionTime>19:35:21</actionTime>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-07-11</actionDate>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <links />
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-07-06</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hssy00</systemCode>
          <name>Science, Space, and Technology Committee</name>
        </committee>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-07-06</actionDate>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2016-07-06</actionDate>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>1</senate>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>9</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <title>National Institute of Standards and Technology Improvement Act of 2016</title>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <district>30</district>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>J000126</bioguideId>
          <lisID>599</lisID>
          <gpoId>8186</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <state>TX</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-07-06</sponsorshipDate>
        <bioguideId>J000126</bioguideId>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <middleName>BERNICE</middleName>
        <lastName>JOHNSON</lastName>
        <firstName>EDDIE</firstName>
        <party>D</party>
        <fullName>Rep. Johnson, Eddie Bernice [D-TX-30]</fullName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>21</district>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>S000583</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1075</lisID>
          <gpoId>8177</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <state>TX</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-07-06</sponsorshipDate>
        <bioguideId>S000583</bioguideId>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <middleName />
        <lastName>SMITH</lastName>
        <firstName>LAMAR</firstName>
        <party>R</party>
        <fullName>Rep. Smith, Lamar [R-TX-21]</fullName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>3</district>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1781</lisID>
          <gpoId>7923</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>L000563</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <state>IL</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-07-06</sponsorshipDate>
        <bioguideId>L000563</bioguideId>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <middleName>William</middleName>
        <lastName>Lipinski</lastName>
        <firstName>Daniel</firstName>
        <party>D</party>
        <fullName>Rep. Lipinski, Daniel [D-IL-3]</fullName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>8</district>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>P000599</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1915</lisID>
          <gpoId>7887</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <state>FL</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-07-06</sponsorshipDate>
        <bioguideId>P000599</bioguideId>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <middleName />
        <lastName>Posey</lastName>
        <firstName>Bill</firstName>
        <party>R</party>
        <fullName>Rep. Posey, Bill [R-FL-8]</fullName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>5</district>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId />
          <bioguideId>C001101</bioguideId>
          <lisID>2196</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <state>MA</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-07-06</sponsorshipDate>
        <bioguideId>C001101</bioguideId>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <middleName>M.</middleName>
        <lastName>Clark</lastName>
        <firstName>Katherine</firstName>
        <party>D</party>
        <fullName>Rep. Clark, Katherine M. [D-MA-5]</fullName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>20</district>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1942</lisID>
          <gpoId>8082</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>T000469</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <state>NY</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-07-06</sponsorshipDate>
        <bioguideId>T000469</bioguideId>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <middleName />
        <lastName>Tonko</lastName>
        <firstName>Paul</firstName>
        <party>D</party>
        <fullName>Rep. Tonko, Paul [D-NY-20]</fullName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>9</district>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>7302</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>G000556</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1914</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <state>FL</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-07-06</sponsorshipDate>
        <bioguideId>G000556</bioguideId>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <middleName />
        <lastName>Grayson</lastName>
        <firstName>Alan</firstName>
        <party>D</party>
        <fullName>Rep. Grayson, Alan [D-FL-9]</fullName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>10</district>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2273</lisID>
          <gpoId />
          <bioguideId>C001105</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <state>VA</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-07-07</sponsorshipDate>
        <bioguideId>C001105</bioguideId>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <middleName />
        <lastName>Comstock</lastName>
        <firstName>Barbara</firstName>
        <party>R</party>
        <fullName>Rep. Comstock, Barbara [R-VA-10]</fullName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>5</district>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId />
          <lisID>2114</lisID>
          <bioguideId>E000293</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <state>CT</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-07-07</sponsorshipDate>
        <bioguideId>E000293</bioguideId>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <middleName>H.</middleName>
        <lastName>Esty</lastName>
        <firstName>Elizabeth</firstName>
        <party>D</party>
        <fullName>Rep. Esty, Elizabeth H. [D-CT-5]</fullName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>1</district>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>B001278</bioguideId>
          <lisID>2092</lisID>
          <gpoId>8367</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <state>OR</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-07-07</sponsorshipDate>
        <bioguideId>B001278</bioguideId>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <middleName />
        <lastName>Bonamici</lastName>
        <firstName>Suzanne</firstName>
        <party>D</party>
        <fullName>Rep. Bonamici, Suzanne [D-OR-1]</fullName>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

