<bill session="114" type="s" number="2625" updated="2018-06-02T07:15:29Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Our Servicemembers' Children from Sexual and Violent Predators Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect our servicemembers' children from convicted pedophiles and other felons infiltrating the classroom.</title>
    <title type="display">Protecting Our Servicemembers' Children from Sexual and Violent Predators Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000461"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4666"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="474"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2943"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting Our Servicemembers' Children from Sexual and Violent Predators Act

This bill requires each Department of Defense domestic dependent elementary and secondary school and each&#160;local educational agency (LEA) that receives, under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965,&#160;specified funds for children with a parent on active duty in the uniformed services to:

 require, for each employee of the LEA or school, a criminal background check that includes a search of specified registries and repositories; prohibit the employment of an individual who refuses to consent to, or who makes a false statement in connection with, a background check or who has been convicted of&#160;one of&#160;specified crimes; require background checks to be periodically repeated or updated in accordance with established policies; provide an employee&#160;with a timely process to appeal the results of a background check; and allow the LEA or school to share the results of a school employee's&#160;recent background check with another LEA that is considering that individual for employment.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
