<bill session="113" type="hr" number="545" updated="2016-10-25T15:55:35Z">
  <state datetime="2014-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the Federal Government should adopt and use accrual basis generally accepted accounting principles for Government budgeting, financial reporting, and performance evaluation purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the Federal Government should adopt and use accrual basis generally accepted accounting principles for Government budgeting, financial reporting, and performance evaluation purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000586"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001062" joined="2014-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000564" joined="2014-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001191" joined="2014-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000258" joined="2014-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2014-04-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-04-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Declares that the House of Representatives: (1) agrees to consider legislation to implement accrual basis generally accepted accounting principles for U.S. government budgeting, financial reporting, and performance measures; and (2) acknowledges that the use of accrual basis accounting would provide a more accurate measure of the federal government's finances and their impact on the nation's economy.

Requests the Comptroller General to prescribe the manner in which such principles can be applied to the U.S. government in the fiscal year following the passage of legislation to implement them.

Recognizes that the use of accrual accounting standards in the federal government can assist in management improvement for federal agencies with regard to publicizing true costs, minimizing government waste, and controlling inefficient spending, especially on long-term government contracts.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
