<bill session="115" type="h" number="6416" updated="2019-04-18T16:26:12Z">
  <state datetime="2018-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to direct the Federal Communications Commission, upon the request of a very high frequency commercial television broadcast station that has relocated to an underserved State, to provide that the virtual major channel number of such station shall be considered to be the same as the radio frequency channel number of such station.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Local Television Service and Emergency Preparedness Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Local Television Service and Emergency Preparedness Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="display">Local Television Service and Emergency Preparedness Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000522"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2018-08-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000567" joined="2018-08-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000554" joined="2018-08-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001193" joined="2018-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000188" joined="2018-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000604" joined="2018-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001165" joined="2018-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2018-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-07-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-07-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Local Television Service and Emergency Preparedness Act of 2018

This bill amends the Communications Act of 1934 to direct the Federal Communications Commission, upon the request of a very high frequency commercial television broadcast station that has relocated to an underserved state, to issue an order providing that the virtual major channel number of such station shall be considered to be the same as the radio frequency channel number of that station.

The order shall apply to a station only if the licensee includes in the request a certification that such station will provide at least one hour daily of news, information, or public affairs programming focused on, or of general interest to, local audiences in the state to which the channel of such station has been reallocated. The order shall cease to apply if the licensee fails to initiate the programming within a 90-day period or fails to make the programming available to other television broadcast stations or through Internet streaming.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
