<bill session="115" type="h" number="4442" updated="2019-04-18T16:18:19Z">
  <state datetime="2017-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to authorize the Secretary of Energy to enter into contracts for the storage of certain high-level radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel, take title to certain high-level radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel, and make certain expenditures from the Nuclear Waste Fund.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Removing Nuclear Waste from our Communities Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Removing Nuclear Waste from our Communities Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Removing Nuclear Waste from our Communities Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000480"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-11-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy" code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="474"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-11-16T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Removing Nuclear Waste from our Communities Act of 2017

This bill amends the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to authorize the Department of Energy (DOE) to enter into new contracts (or modify existing contracts) with the licensee of an interim consolidated storage facility in order to take title to and store in it either high-level radioactive waste or spent nuclear fuel of domestic origin.

The bill defines:

 "interim consolidated storage facility" as a facility licensed by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission for the storage of high-level radioactive waste or spent nuclear fuel received from DOE or from two or more persons that generate or hold title to such fuel generated at a civilian nuclear power reactor, and "high-level radioactive waste" as including Greater than Class C waste. The bill assigns priority to storage of such waste and spent fuel located on sites without an operating nuclear reactor and with over 15 million residents within a 50-mile radius.

The bill makes appropriations targeted for the Nuclear Waste Fund available to pay for costs in connection with storage in an interim consolidated storage facility.

Beginning in FY2020 DOE shall not expend, on fees for dry modes of storage of high-level radioactive waste or spent nuclear fuel, any amounts exceeding the cumulative amount of interest generated by the fund each fiscal year.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
