<bill session="114" type="h" number="5643" updated="2019-02-14T23:14:56Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Active Shooter Preparedness Enhancement Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to provide for active shooter and mass casualty incident response assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Active Shooter Preparedness Enhancement Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000622"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Preparedness, Response and Communications.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Emergency Preparedness, Response, and Communications" code="HSHM12" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2377"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3186"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Active Shooter Preparedness Enhancement Act of 2016

This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to develop and make available to state, local, tribal, territorial, and nongovernmental partners guidance to assist in the development of emergency action and response plans for active shooter and mass casualty incidents.

Such guidance may relate to the development of:

 a strategy for properly responding to such incidents, a plan for establishing a unified command, a schedule for regular testing of equipment used to receive communications during such incidents, a practiced method and plan to communicate with occupants of locations of such incidents and with the surrounding community, a plan for coordinating with volunteer organizations to expedite assistance for victims, a schedule for joint exercises and training, and a plan for outreach to facilities that have been identified by DHS as potentially vulnerable targets. The bill permits funds under homeland security grants to states and high-risk urban areas to be used for training exercises to enhance preparedness for and response to mass casualty and active shooter incidents and security events at private locations (current law permits such funds to be used for such exercises at public locations). In allocating grant funds among states and high-risk urban areas, the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) shall consider the threat from active shooters to critical infrastructure and U.S. populations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
