<bill session="113" type="h" number="5333" updated="2016-10-25T16:15:57Z">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expanding Access for Veterans' Service Animals Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to ensure that a service animal of a patient receiving inpatient medical care at a medical facility of the Department of Veterans Affairs is able to access the room of the patient.</title>
    <title type="display">Expanding Access for Veterans' Service Animals Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000618"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Service animals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-07-31T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Expanding Access for Veterans' Service Animals Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) certified therapeutic animals should be provided the same access to facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) as service animals, and (2) the Secretary of Veterans Affairs should implement a certification process for therapeutic animals that mitigate the effects of a medically diagnosed mental health condition.

Bars the Secretary from prohibiting any service animal that is allowed to access VA medical facilities from accessing the room of a patient who is receiving inpatient care at such a facility, including with respect to staying overnight. Authorizes the Secretary to prescribe regulations to ensure the safety and health of VA employees, patients, and the public, including by requiring that a patient maintain responsibility for such animal.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
