<bill session="115" type="s" number="1722" updated="2019-04-18T16:38:38Z">
  <state datetime="2017-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States to consider the reciprocity of foreign investment, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">True Reciprocity Investment Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">True Reciprocity Investment Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">True Reciprocity Investment Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001198"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-08-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-08-02T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">True Reciprocity Investment Act of 2017

This bill amends the Defense Production Act of 1950 to direct the Office of the United States Trade Representative to submit an annual report assessing the extent to which foreign governments allow investments by U.S. persons (i.e., U.S. citizens, permanent residents, or U.S. entities) in their countries that are similar to investments in the United States made by entities organized in such foreign countries.

 The report shall include, with respect to each major trading partner of the United States: (1) a description of the laws, policies, and practices of the country with respect to foreign investment; and (2) an assessment of the transparency of the process for making such laws, policies, and practices.

The report shall also include the determination of the office whether each major trading partner: (1) has high barriers to investment by U.S. persons; (2) has recently taken measures that constitute barriers to investment by U.S. persons or has indicated an intention to take such measures; or (3) has investment laws, policies, and practices that should be monitored.

If the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States recommends that the President not suspend or prohibit a transaction made by a party that is subject to the jurisdiction of a high barrier country, it shall provide an explanation of the reasons for its recommendation.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
