<bill session="114" type="h" number="2171" updated="2019-02-13T17:31:10Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Owyhee Wilderness Areas Boundary Modifications Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To modify the boundaries of the Pole Creek Wilderness, the Owyhee River Wilderness, and the North Fork Owyhee Wilderness and to authorize the continued use of motorized vehicles for livestock monitoring, herding, and grazing in certain wilderness areas in the State of Idaho.</title>
    <title type="display">Owyhee Wilderness Areas Boundary Modifications Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000573"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="1167"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Owyhee Wilderness Areas Boundary Modifications Act 

Adjusts the boundaries of the North Fork Owyhee Wilderness, the Owyhee River Wilderness, and the Pole Creek Wilderness in Idaho to exclude certain land.

Amends the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 to allow motor vehicles to continue to be used for livestock monitoring, herding, and gathering in the Big Jacks Creek Wilderness, Bruneau-Jarbidge Rivers Wilderness, Little Jacks Creek Wilderness, North Fork Owyhee Wilderness, Owyhee River Wilderness, and Pole Creek Wilderness.

Requires the Department of the Interior to: (1) report to Congress on all livestock grazing management activities that were authorized in such wilderness areas on the day before they were designated as wilderness, and (2) use the report to assist in the management of livestock grazing in those areas.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
