<bill session="113" type="h" number="5789" updated="2016-10-25T16:17:35Z">
  <state datetime="2014-12-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-12-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rapid DNA Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a system for integration of Rapid DNA instruments for use by law enforcement to reduce violent crime and reduce the current DNA analysis backlog.</title>
    <title type="display">Rapid DNA Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001193" joined="2014-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-12-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Rapid DNA Act of 2014 - Amends the DNA Identification Act of 1994 to require:

 the advisory board on DNA quality assurance methods appointed by the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to include members from federal, state, and local law enforcement agencies; such board to develop, and the Director to issue, standards for testing the proficiency of qualified agencies (i.e., booking stations, jails, prisons, detention centers, other law enforcement organizations and facilities outside of forensic laboratories) and operators in conducting analyses of DNA samples using sample-to-answer DNA analysis systems (i.e., fully automated systems that prepare and analyze DNA samples with no operator intervention); the National Institute of Justice to certify that the blind external proficiency testing program for DNA analyses has been established and made available to such qualified agencies or is not feasible; and the Index to facilitate law enforcement exchange of DNA identification information to include information on DNA identification records and DNA analyses prepared by such qualified agencies that are engaged in the intake, processing, booking, detention, or incarceration of individuals charged or convicted of qualifying offenses and that conduct the analysis of DNA samples on a sample-to-answer DNA analysis system.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
