<amendment session="114" chamber="s" number="4039" updated="2019-02-17T14:41:30Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2577" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2016-05-18">offered</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000303"/>
  <offered datetime="2016-05-18"/>
  <description>To extend and expand eligibility for the Veterans Choice Program of the Department of Veterans Affairs and to establish consistent criteria and standards relating to the use of amounts under the Medical Community Care account of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</description>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-19">
      <text>Amendment SA 4039 ruled non-germane by the chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-19">
      <text>Point of order raised in Senate with respect to amendment SA 4039.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-19">
      <text>Amendment SA 4039 ruled in order by the chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-19">
      <text>Motion to waive all applicable budgetary discipline with respect to amendment SA 4039 (the section within the amendment regarding an emergency designation) agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 84 - 14. Record Vote Number: 79.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3009" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-19">
      <text>Point of order that the emergency designation within the amendment violates the CBA raised in Senate with respect to amendment SA 4039.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-19">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3004, S3007, S3008-3009" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-18">
      <text>Amendment SA 4039 proposed by Senator McCain to Amendment SA 3896. (consideration: CR S2956-2958; text: CR S2957) To extend and expand eligibility for the Veterans Choice Program of the Department of Veterans Affairs and to establish consistent criteria and standards relating to the use of amounts under the Medical Community Care account of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-18"/>
    <action datetime="2016-05-19">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Motion to waive all applicable budgetary discipline with respect to amendment SA 4039 (the section within the amendment regarding an emergency designation) agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 84 - 14. Record Vote Number: 79.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3009" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-18">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 4039 proposed by Senator McCain to Amendment SA 3896.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2956-2958" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2957" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-18">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
