<bill session="114" type="sr" number="238" updated="2018-06-02T06:17:49Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the determination of the Senate that the 60-calendar day period for congressional review of the nuclear agreement with Iran did not begin with the transmittal of the agreement on July 19, 2015, because that transmittal did not include all materials required to be transmitted pursuant to the Iran Nuclear Agreement Review Act of 2015.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution expressing the determination of the Senate that the 60-calendar day period for congressional review of the nuclear agreement with Iran did not begin with the transmittal of the agreement on July 19, 2015, because that transmittal did not include all materials required to be transmitted pursuant to the Iran Nuclear Agreement Review Act of 2015.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001098"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6193" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">It is the determination of the Senate that:

 for purposes of section 135(b)(2) of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, as added by section 2 of the Iran Nuclear Agreement Review Act of 2015, the 60-calendar day period for congressional review of the nuclear program agreement with Iran did not begin with the transmittal of the agreement on July 19, 2015, because that transmittal did not include all materials required to be transmitted under the definition of agreement, including specifically side agreements with Iran and U.S. government-issued guidance materials in relation to Iran; and the 60-calendar day period for the Senate's review of such agreement cannot be considered to have begun until the Majority Leader certifies that all of the materials required to be transmitted have been transmitted to the Majority Leader.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
