<bill session="115" type="hr" number="467" updated="2019-04-18T15:54:15Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the United Nations Security Council should immediately impose an arms embargo against the Government of South Sudan and all other parties to hostilities in South Sudan.</title>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the United Nations Security Council should immediately impose an arms embargo against the Government of South Sudan and all other parties to hostilities in South Sudan.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000583"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001037" joined="2017-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000179" joined="2017-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2017-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="South Sudan"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that:

 the United Nations (U.N.) Security Council should impose an arms embargo against the government of South Sudan and hold such government accountable for obstructing or constraining the operations of the U.N. Mission in the Republic of South Sudan, committing other repeated violations of the status of forces agreement with the U.N. signed on August 8, 2011, inhibiting the free movement of members of the Ceasefire and Transitional Security Arrangements Monitoring Mechanism, and obstructing humanitarian access to civilian populations; the lifting of such embargo should be contingent upon such government implementing a permanent ceasefire, complying with its obligations under such status of forces agreement, bearing the primary responsibility as a sovereign state to protect its citizens from gross human rights abuses and forced displacement perpetrated by warring parties, cooperating with and supporting the work of the Joint Monitoring and Evaluation Commission, establishing the Commission for Truth, Reconciliation, and Healing, the Hybrid Court for South Sudan, and the Compensation and Reparation Authority, and permitting consistent, unimpeded humanitarian access to vulnerable civilian populations; and the international community should continue to support civilians who have been adversely affected by the civil war in South Sudan and should promote peace and reconciliation dialogues within local civil society.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
