<bill session="115" type="h" number="6740" updated="2019-04-18T16:27:11Z">
  <state datetime="2018-09-25T14:32:49-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-09-25T14:32:49-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Border Tunnel Task Force Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Border Tunnel Task Force Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Border Tunnel Task Force Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Border Tunnel Task Force Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Border Tunnel Task Force Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Border Tunnel Task Force Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish Border Tunnel Task Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2018-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2018-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-09-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-09-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-09-25">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 115-962.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-09-25" calendar="Union" number="750">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 750.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-09-25T14:17:34-04:00">
      <text>Mr. McCaul moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-25T14:18:03-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8748-8750" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-25T14:18:08-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6740.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2018-09-25T14:32:49-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8748" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-09-25T14:32:51-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-09-25T16:10:46Z" status="Passed House amended">Border Tunnel Task Force Act

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish border tunnel task forces in jurisdictions in which such task forces can contribute to border security missions after evaluating: (1) whether the areas in which they would be established are significantly impacted by cross-border threats; and (2) the availability of federal, state, local, and tribal law enforcement resources to participate in such task forces.

The purpose of the task forces is to enhance and integrate border security efforts by addressing and reducing cross-border tunnel related threats and violence by facilitating collaboration among law enforcement agencies and enhancing information sharing among such agencies.

DHS shall:

 ensure that the task forces do not unnecessarily duplicate the efforts of other existing interagency task forces or centers within such jurisdiction, establish targets and performance measures for the task forces that include consideration of whether border barriers impact cross-border tunnel threats, direct leadership of each task force to monitor progress on such targets and performance measures for each such task force, and periodically report to the congressional homeland security committees regarding progress on such targets and performance measures.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-962</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
