<bill session="114" type="h" number="3057" updated="2018-11-21T21:23:09Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">EAT for Health Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Education and Training for Health Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to issue to Federal agencies guidelines for developing procedures and requirements relating to certain primary care Federal health professionals completing continuing medical education on nutrition and to require Federal agencies to submit annual reports relating to such guidelines, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">EAT for Health Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000551"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000467" joined="2015-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Education and Training for Health Act of 2015 or the EAT for Health Act of 2015

 Directs the Department of Health and Human Services to issue guidelines to federal agencies for developing procedures and requirements to ensure that every primary care health professional employed full-time for such agencies have continuing education courses relating to nutrition. Requires each agency to report to Congress annually on the extent to which it has adopted and encouraged such guidelines for such primary care professionals it employed during any portion of the previous year.

Requires such courses to: (1) include content on the role of nutrition in the prevention, management, and reversal of obesity, cardiovascular disease, diabetes, or cancer; and (2) meet requirements for Continuing Medical Education or Continuing Education by medical or nurse practitioner professional organizations or certified accrediting bodies.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
