<bill session="114" type="h" number="1447" updated="2019-04-11T15:42:41Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 to improve the Act.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Perkins Modernization Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Perkins Modernization Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000379"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2015-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000619" joined="2015-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000378" joined="2015-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2015-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Perkins Modernization Act of 2015

This bill amends the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 to revise its purposes, which are to develop more fully the academic and career and technical skills of secondary education students and postsecondary students who elect to enroll in career and technical education programs (as under current law), by:

 preparing those students for employment in current or emerging in-demand industry sectors or occupations; aligning the skills, certifications, and credentials of the students with those needed by employers in the labor markets served by educational institutions; and ensuring that the selection of skills, certifications, and credentials acquired by such students is guided by timely labor market information. An "in-demand industry sector or occupation" is:

 an industry sector that has a substantial current or potential impact on the state, regional, or local economy, and that contributes to the growth or stability of other supporting businesses, or the growth of other industry sectors; or an occupation that currently has or is projected to have a number of positions in an industry sector so as to have a significant impact on the state, regional, or local economy.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
