<bill session="115" type="h" number="5362" updated="2019-04-18T16:21:27Z">
  <state datetime="2018-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modernize and improve the management of Internal Revenue Service information technology.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IRS Information Technology Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IRS Information Technology Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="display">IRS Information Technology Accountability Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000813"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-03-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3427"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="5445"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="5444"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="88"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="7227"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-03-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">IRS Information Technology Accountability Act 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish the position of Internal Revenue Service (IRS) Chief Information Officer (CIO) to be responsible for the development, implementation, and maintenance of information technology for the IRS.

The duties and responsibilities of the CIO include:

 ensuring that the information technology is secure and integrated, maintaining operational control of the information technology, being the principal advocate for the information technology needs of the IRS, developing and implementing a multiyear strategic plan for IRS information technology needs, and consulting with the IRS Chief Procurement Officer to ensure that requirements of this bill and the strategic plan are met. The IRS must enter into a contract with an independent reviewer to verify and validate the implementation plans developed for the Customer Account Data Engine 2 and the Enterprise Case Management System.

The IRS Chief Procurement Officer must identify all significant IRS information technology acquisitions and notify the CIO before the acquisitions. The officer must also regularly consult with the CIO regarding acquisitions of IRS information technology.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
