<bill session="115" type="h" number="1700" updated="2019-04-18T16:05:24Z">
  <state datetime="2018-07-10T19:24:18-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-07-10T19:24:18-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Act to reauthorize the SCORE program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">SCORE for Small Business Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SCORE for Small Business Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SCORE for Small Business Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">SCORE for Small Business Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000370"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2017-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-10T19:14:16-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Chabot moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-10T19:14:23-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6028-6030" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-10T19:14:24-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1700.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2018-07-10T19:24:18-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6028-6029" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-07-10T19:24:19-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-11">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2810"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2034"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1774"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">SCORE for Small Business Act of 2017

 This bill amends the Small Business Act to reauthorize the SCORE program (Service Corps of Retired Executives) for FY2018-FY2019. The program is renamed as simply the SCORE program.

The Small Business Administration (SBA) shall award a grant to the SCORE Association (or any successor group) to manage the program.

Based on business experience and knowledge, a volunteer participating in the program shall:

 provide at no cost to individuals who own, or aspire to own, small business concerns personal counseling, mentoring, and coaching relating to the process of starting, expanding, managing, buying, and selling a business; and facilitate low-cost education workshops for individuals who own, or aspire to own, small business concerns. The SBA shall ensure that the program and each of its chapters develop and implement plans and goals to provide services more effectively and efficiently to individuals in rural areas, economically disadvantaged communities, and other traditionally underserved communities, including plans for electronic initiatives, web-based initiatives, chapter expansion, partnerships, and the development of new skills by participating volunteers.

The bill prescribes general privacy requirements for the disclosure of information of businesses assisted under such program.

The association shall:

 make use of online counseling, including by webinars and an electronic mentoring platform; study the future role of the program; and develop a strategic plan for how the program will evolve to meet the needs of small business concerns over the next five years.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
