<bill session="113" type="s" number="217" updated="2016-10-25T16:20:30Z">
  <state datetime="2013-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">High School Data Transparency Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require the Secretary of Education to collect information from coeducational elementary schools and secondary schools on such schools' athletic programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">High School Data Transparency Act of 2013</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001111"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001265" joined="2013-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2013-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2013-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2013-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2013-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2013-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2013-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2013-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2013-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2014-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2013-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="School athletics"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-02-04T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">High School Data Transparency Act of 2013 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require the Secretary of Education to collect the following information annually from each coeducational elementary and secondary school that receives federal financial assistance and has an interscholastic athletic program: (1) the number, gender, and race or ethnicity of students that attended the school; and (2) for each team that competed in athletic competition, the number, gender, and race or ethnicity of participants, the total expenditures, the number, gender, and employment status of trainers, medical personnel, and coaches, the number of competitions, and postseason record.

Requires such schools to: (1) make such information available to students, potential students, and their parents, upon request, and to the public by October 15 of each school year; (2) ensure that all students and parents at the school are informed of their right to request such information; and (3) annually provide such information to the Secretary.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) ensure that such information is posted on the Department of Education's website, (2) notify all elementary and secondary schools regarding the availability of the information, and (3) issue guidance to the schools on how to collect and report the information required under this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
