<bill session="114" type="h" number="2634" updated="2019-04-11T15:42:41Z">
  <state datetime="2015-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for temporary emergency impact aid for local educational agencies.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public School Emergency Relief Act</title>
    <title type="display">Public School Emergency Relief Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000057"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2015-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000602" joined="2015-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health and welfare"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-03T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Public School Emergency Relief Act

This bill authorizes a program of emergency impact aid payments to states and, through them, to local educational agencies and Indian schools for each quarter of the 2015-2016 school year to respond to any increase in the enrollment of immigrant children from the corresponding quarter of the 2013-2014 school year.

Payments shall be used to provide services and assistance to schools that enroll immigrant students.

Funds may be used for:

 compensating school personnel, identifying and acquiring curricular material and mobile educational units and leasing sites or spaces, basic instructional services for immigrant students, reasonable transportation costs, health and counseling services, education and support services, and other uses allowed under title III (Language Instruction for Limited English Proficient and Immigrant Students) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965. Any payment made on behalf of a disabled immigrant student is to be used for special education and related services.

Emergency impact aid funds that are not obligated during the 2015-2016 school year must be returned to the Department of Education.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
