<bill session="113" type="h" number="4410" updated="2016-10-25T16:12:16Z">
  <state datetime="2014-04-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DoD Laboratory Authorities for Breakthrough Scientific Research Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DoD LABS Research Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the national defense laboratories by increasing retention and hiring flexibility to enable the laboratories to perform breakthrough scientific research and effectively fulfill the needs of members of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">DoD LABS Research Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000465"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001101" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000292" joined="2014-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000379" joined="2014-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000559" joined="2014-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2014-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000576" joined="2014-04-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Intelligence, Emerging Threats &amp; Capabilities.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Emerging Threats and Capabilities" code="HSAS26" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-04-04T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">DoD Laboratory Authorities for Breakthrough Scientific Research Act or the DoD LABS Research Act - Prohibits the Secretary of Defense (DOD) from disallowing an employee of a defense laboratory from traveling to a technical symposium or conference if the head of such laboratory determines that there is a sufficient amount available to the laboratory for such travel and approves such travel using standard travel approval procedures.

Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014 to allow the director of any DOD science and technology laboratory to appoint as an employee, through 2019, any student enrolled in a program of undergraduate or graduate instruction leading to a bachelor's or master's degree in a scientific, technical, engineering, mathematical, or medical course of study. (Under current law, such a director may only appoint through such period a candidate already possessing a bachelor's degree or a qualified veteran.)

Directs the Secretary to report to the congressional defense committees on the implementation and use by DOD of specified hiring authorities provided under federal law, prior defense authorization Acts, and the Intergovernmental Personnel Act.

Amends the Strom Thurmond National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1999 to reinstate and make permanent a DOD personnel program for the hiring of scientific and technical personnel.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
