<bill session="113" type="h" number="4338" updated="2016-10-25T16:12:02Z">
  <state datetime="2014-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pipeline Modernization and Consumer Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to require gas pipeline facilities to accelerate the repair, rehabilitation, and replacement of high-risk pipelines used in commerce, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Pipeline Modernization and Consumer Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000053"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2014-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-27">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Power" code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="identical" number="1767"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-03-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Pipeline Modernization and Consumer Protection Act - Requires each operator of a gas pipeline facility, in accordance with an integrity management program, if applicable, to accelerate the repair, rehabilitation, and replacement of gas piping or equipment that is leaking or may pose high risk of leaking.

Requires each state regulatory authority and each nonregulated gas utility, in complying with such requirements, to: (1) develop prioritized timelines to repair or replace all leaking or high-risk piping or equipment, and (2) require use of best available technology to detect gas leaks.

Directs the Administrator of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration to issue non-binding best practices guidelines for identifying and classifying high-risk pipeline infrastructure and leaks for repair or replacement.

Directs the Administrator and the heads of other applicable federal agencies to work jointly to establish and publish forms that adopt a standard definition and methodology for calculating and reporting information on the causes of unaccounted-for gas.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
