<bill session="115" type="h" number="3291" updated="2019-04-18T16:12:56Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to provide for a State option to provide for maternal, infant, and early childhood home visiting programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alleviating Adverse Childhood Experiences Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alleviating Adverse Childhood Experiences Act</title>
    <title type="display">Alleviating Adverse Childhood Experiences Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000577"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2017-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Alleviating Adverse Childhood Experiences Act

This bill amends XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to allow a state Medicaid program to cover, as medical assistance, services furnished under an early-childhood home-visitation program that:&#160;

 conforms to a clear, consistent, research-based home-visitation model; is&#160;designed to result in&#160;improvements for participating families in areas related to maternal and newborn health, child health and development, school readiness and academic achievement, crime and domestic violence, economic self-sufficiency, parenting skills, and resource coordination; gives priority to serving certain high-risk populations; and meets other specified requirements. A state Medicaid program that opts to cover such services must establish procedures to ensure that the participation of each eligible family is voluntary.

In addition, the bill requires each state to conduct a statewide needs-assessment to identify:

 at-risk communities in the state, according to specified indicators; the capacity of existing home-visitation programs&#160;and initiatives in the state; and the state's capacity for providing substance-abuse treatment and counseling services to individuals and families in need. The Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services must carry out specified research and evaluation activities related to the implementation and effectiveness of home-visitation programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
