<bill session="114" type="s" number="702" updated="2019-02-24T14:44:13Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Illegal Insider Trading Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to strengthen the prohibitions on insider trading, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Stop Illegal Insider Trading Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2015-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1440-1441" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stop Illegal Insider Trading Act 

This bill amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 governing manipulative and deceptive devices to make it unlawful for any person to: (1) purchase, sell, or cause the purchase or sale of any security on the basis of material information that the person knows or has reason to know is not publicly available; or (2) knowingly or recklessly communicate material information that the person knows or has reason to know is not publicly available to any other person under circumstances in which it is reasonably foreseeable that the communication is likely to result in a violation of this prohibition.

Excludes from the definition of "not publicly available" any information a person has developed independently from publicly available sources.

 The Securities and Exchange Commission is permitted to exempt, by rule, any person, transaction, communication, or any class of persons, transactions, or communications from the prohibitions of this Act, if it determines that the exemption is necessary or appropriate in the public interest and consistent with the protection of investors.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
