<bill session="114" type="h" number="1020" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:36Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-07">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To define STEM education to include computer science, and to support existing STEM education programs at the National Science Foundation.</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">STEM Education Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">STEM Education Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">STEM Education Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">STEM Education Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STEM Education Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">STEM Education Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000583"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001275" joined="2015-02-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001092" joined="2015-02-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001105" joined="2015-02-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000293" joined="2015-02-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001056" joined="2015-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001059" joined="2015-02-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000563" joined="2015-02-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001180" joined="2015-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001194" joined="2015-02-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-24T16:27:43-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (TX) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-24T16:27:55-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1098-1100" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-24T16:27:57-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1020.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-24T16:47:30-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-25T14:22:04-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1135" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="88" datetime="2015-02-25T14:31:06-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed/agreed to in House: On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 412 - 8 (Roll no. 88).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 2/24/2015 H1098-1100" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-02-25T14:31:06-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="88" datetime="2015-02-25T14:31:06-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 412 - 8 (Roll no. 88).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 2/24/2015 H1098-1100" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-02-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-05-20">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-08-04">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Thune without amendment. With written report No. 114-115.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-08-04" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="195">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 195.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-09-24">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6948-6949" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="2015-09-24" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-09-25">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-01T13:47:22-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (TX) asked unanimous consent that the House agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6780" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="without objection" type="pingpong" datetime="2015-10-01T13:47:58-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion that the House agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6780" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-10-01T13:47:59-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2015-10-01">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2015-10-07" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="114-59" type="public" datetime="2015-10-07">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 114-59.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1898"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1806"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2694"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2015-10-08T03:59:58Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on September 24, 2015. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

STEM Education Act of 2015

 (Sec. 3) Requires the Director of the National Science Foundation (NSF) to continue to award competitive, merit-reviewed grants to support: (1) research and development of innovative out-of-school STEM (science, technology, engineering, and mathematics) learning and emerging STEM learning environments; and (2) research that advances the field of informal STEM education.

Requires supported activities to include research and development that improves understanding of learning and engagement in informal environments and design and testing of innovative STEM resources for such environments to improve STEM learning outcomes and increase engagement for elementary and secondary school students and teachers and the public.

(Sec. 4) Amends the National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 2002 to allow award of NSF Master Teaching Fellowships to mathematics and science teachers who possess a bachelor's degree in their field (currently limited to those with a master's degree).

Requires fellowship grants to be used, in the case of Master Teaching Fellowships for teachers with bachelor's degrees in their field who are working toward a master's degree, to: (1) offer academic courses leading to a master's degree and leadership training to prepare individuals to become master teachers, and (2) offer programs both during and after matriculation to enable fellows to become highly effective mathematics and science teachers and to exchange ideas with others in their fields. Limits fellowship support during such a master's degree program to one year, with a prorated amount in the case of enrollment in a part-time program.

Includes elementary or secondary school computer science teachers as mathematics and science teachers for purposes of the program of teacher recruiting and training grants known as the Robert Noyce Teacher Scholarship Program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
