<bill session="113" type="s" number="1744" updated="2016-10-25T16:27:45Z">
  <state datetime="2014-12-15">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Security Clearance Accountability, Reform, and Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Security Clearance Accountability, Reform, and Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Security Clearance Accountability, Reform, and Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to strengthen the accountability of individuals involved in misconduct affecting the integrity of background investigations, to update guidelines for security clearances, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by senate">A bill to strengthen the accountability of individuals involved in misconduct affecting the integrity of background investigations, to update guidelines for position designation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Security Clearance Accountability, Reform, and Enhancement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000243" joined="2013-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001265" joined="2013-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2013-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2013-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2013-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2013-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-05-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Carper with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-11-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="606">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 606.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-01">
      <text>By Senator Carper from Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs filed written report. Report No. 113-276.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="2014-12-15" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6866-6867" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6866" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-12-16">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-16T12:11:06-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-16T13:24:13-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-12-15T12:06:19Z" status="Passed Senate amended">Security Clearance Accountability, Reform, and Enhancement Act - (Sec. 3) Deems a federal agency employee to be unfit for federal employment if the agency determines that such employee has engaged in misconduct affecting the integrity of a background investigation, including falsification of any information relating to such an investigation (covered misconduct). Prohibits an individual who has engaged in covered misconduct from being appointed to or continuing to occupy a position that requires the performance of background investigations.

Extends such sanctions to employees performing background investigations under a contract between an agency and a prime contractor and subcontractors (covered contract). Requires a covered contract to include provisions requiring mandatory disclosure of covered misconduct within 24 hours after the contractor discovers such misconduct and referral to the agency for investigation.

Requires the President to report to specified congressional committees on: (1) the number of individuals determined to be unfit for federal employment due to covered misconduct or ineligible to perform work under a covered contract; and (2) the details of such misconduct.

(Sec. 4) Requires the President to: (1) review and update guidance to assist agencies in determining position sensitivity designation and the appropriate background investigation to initiate for each position designation; (2) review, not less frequently than every five years, and revise the position designation of positions within federal agencies; and (3) report on any issues identified and the number of position designations revised as a result of the review.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 113-276</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
