<bill session="115" type="s" number="902" updated="2019-06-17T18:45:37Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to provide for certain acquisition authorities for the Under Secretary of Management of the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DHS Acquisition Authorities Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DHS Acquisition Authorities Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">DHS Acquisition Authorities Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2017-04-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Legislative Interest"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1252"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2825"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">DHS Acquisition Authorities Act of 2017

This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to designate the&#160;Department of Homeland Security's (DHS's) Under Secretary for Management as&#160;DHS's&#160;Chief Acquisition Officer. Such officer's duties shall include: (1) establishing acquisition policies that implement an approach that takes into account risks of failure to achieve cost, schedule, or performance parameters for all DHS components; and (2) ensuring that each major acquisition program has a DHS-approved acquisition program baseline. The bill specifies criteria governing the Under Secretary's delegation of acquisition decision authority to the relevant Component Acquisition Executive for such programs.

The bill sets forth the responsibilities of DHS's Under Secretary for Science and Technology with respect to operational testing and evaluation of such programs.

The bill includes among the responsibilities of DHS's: (1) Office of Program Analysis and Evaluation, ensuring that acquisition program costs are in accordance with budget estimates and are affordable, or can be adequately funded, over their life cycle; and (2) Chief Information Officer, ensuring that information technology acquisitions comply with DHS's information technology management processes, technical requirements, and the Homeland Security Enterprise Architecture, providing recommendations to an acquisition review board within DHS regarding information technology programs, and developing information technology acquisition strategic guidance.

The bill establishes within the Management Directorate of DHS a Program Accountability and Risk Management Office to: (1) provide consistent accountability, standardization, and transparency of major acquisition programs; and (2) serve as the central oversight function for all DHS acquisition programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
