<bill session="114" type="s" number="2685" updated="2018-06-02T07:15:52Z">
  <state datetime="2016-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mental Health on Campus Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to improve mental and behavioral health services on campuses of institutions of higher education.</title>
    <title type="display">Mental Health on Campus Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2016-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2016-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1506-1508" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4374"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="2680"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Mental Health on Campus Improvement Act

This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA) to award grants to institutions of higher education to provide and improve mental and behavioral health services, conduct research regarding improving the mental health of students, and expand outreach and training at institutions of higher education.

SAMHSA must give special consideration to programs that: (1) demonstrate the greatest need, (2) propose effective approaches for initiating or expanding campus services, (3) target underserved and at-risk populations, (4) coordinate with a community mental health center or other community mental health resources, (5) identify how the institution of higher education will address psychiatric emergencies, (6) propose innovative practices to improve care or prevention programs, and (7) demonstrate the greatest potential for replication and dissemination.

SAMHSA must convene an interagency, public-private sector working group to plan, establish, and begin coordinating and evaluating a targeted public education campaign that is designed to focus on mental and behavioral health at institutions of higher education.

The Department of Health and Human Services must establish the College Campus Task Force to discuss mental and behavioral health concerns at institutions of higher education.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
