<bill session="114" type="s" number="2119" updated="2018-06-02T07:10:29Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Iran Policy Oversight Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for greater congressional oversight of Iran's nuclear program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Iran Policy Oversight Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2016-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2015-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2015-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2015-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2015-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000607" joined="2015-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2016-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2015-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2015-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2015-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2015-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2015-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2015-10-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="4333"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli relations"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Egypt"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Gulf States"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Jordan"/>
    <term name="Lebanon"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Yemen"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-01T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Iran Policy Oversight Act of 2015

This bill directs the Department of State, the Department of Defense, the Department of the Treasury, and the Director of National Intelligence to submit to Congress every two years a joint 10-year strategy to counter Iranian activities in the Middle East, North Africa, and beyond.

The President is authorized to:

 take appropriate measures to enhance Israel's qualitative military edge, deter Iranian conventional and nuclear threats, and counter non-peaceful Iranian nuclear activities; provide any additional foreign military financing to Israel in FY2018-FY2028 to address Iranian threats; and accelerate co-development and support Israeli development of missile defense systems, and to engage in discussions to bolster Israel's conventional deterrent and deepen intelligence cooperation. The President shall provide assistance to ensure Israel's qualitative military edge and deter Iranian conventional and nuclear threats.

It is the sense of Congress that Treasury's Office of Foreign Assets Control should be fully funded to ensure strict enforcement of sanctions against Iranian actors in the areas of ballistic or cruise missile proliferation, terrorism, and human rights abuses, and to ensure effective re-imposition of sanctions in the event of Iran's violation or breach of the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPOA).

 U.S. property sanctions shall be continued against Iranian persons/entities engaged in the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction, including missile proliferation, terrorism, or human rights abuses, until the President makes public a notification that justifies lifting sanctions.

The President shall report to Congress every 180 days regarding specified uses of funds by Iran received as part of sanctions relief under the JCPOA.

If the President determines that Iran has directed or conducted an act of terrorism against the United States or that Iran has substantially increased its operational or financial support for a terrorist organization that threatens U.S. interests or allies, there shall be an expedited procedure for congressional approval of new sanctions against Iran.

The Atomic Energy Act of 1954 is amended to require the President to report to Congress every 180 days regarding Iranian research and development and breakout times.

The President shall designate within the State Department a special coordinator for implementation of and compliance with the JCPOA regarding the Iran's nuclear program.

It is the sense of Congress that:

 Iran should continue to be prohibited from undertaking any activity related to ballistic or cruise missiles capable of delivering nuclear weapons; and the International Atomic Energy Agency must have sufficient funding, manpower, and authority to undertake its verification responsibilities related to the JCPOA or any other related agreement.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
