<bill session="114" type="h" number="4164" updated="2019-01-09T21:26:16Z">
  <state datetime="2015-12-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-12-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Regulatory Agency Demilitarization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit certain Federal agencies from using or purchasing certain firearms, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Regulatory Agency Demilitarization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001192"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000369" joined="2015-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001076" joined="2016-07-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2015-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2015-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000450" joined="2015-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000546" joined="2015-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000566" joined="2016-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001177" joined="2016-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2016-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000587" joined="2015-12-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-12-02T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Regulatory Agency Demilitarization Act

 This bill prohibits a federal agency from purchasing or using a firearm. The bill excludes the Departments of Defense, Justice, and Homeland Security, the military departments, the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, the U.S. Capitol Police, the Bureau of Diplomatic Security, and the Central Intelligence Agency.

The Government Accountability Office shall submit to Congress, within 18 months after this Act's enactment, a report that includes:

 information regarding each federal agency that has specialized units that receive special tactical or military-style training or use hard-plated body armor, shields, or helmets and that respond to high-risk situations that fall outside the capabilities of regular law enforcement officers; a description of each such unit; a description of the training and weapons of each such unit; the criteria for activating each such unit and how often each such unit was activated for each of the previous ten years; the annual cost of equipping and operating each such unit; and any other information that is relevant to understanding the usefulness and justification for the units. The bill amends the Inspector General Act of 1978 to repeal provisions authorizing law enforcement powers for an Inspector General, any Assistant Inspector General for Investigations under an Inspector General, and any special agent supervised by such an Assistant Inspector General.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
