<bill session="115" type="s" number="2883" updated="2019-07-16T21:20:11Z">
  <state datetime="2018-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Defense to submit a plan to improve research and development on therapies for traumatic brain injury and post-traumatic stress disorder, to document information on blast exposures in service records of military personnel, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Blast Exposure and Brain Injury Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Blast Exposure and Brain Injury Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="display">Blast Exposure and Brain Injury Prevention Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2018-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-05-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Blast Exposure and Brain Injury Prevention Act 

 This bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to submit to Congress a report setting forth: (1) a plan for the Defense Health Agency to accelerate cooperative research and development on therapies for traumatic brain injury and post-traumatic stress disorder; and (2) recommendations for legislative or administrative actions to carry out the plan.

The bill requires military departments to include in the military service records of members of the Armed Forces documentation of information on any blasts to which such members were exposed during service in the Armed Forces (whether in combat or training).

DOD shall: (1) review the firing limits for heavy weapons during training exercises, and (2) establish a research and development program to improve the efficacy of personal protective equipment to reduce blast pressure or protect against brain injury from exposure to blast pressure waves.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
