<bill session="114" type="s" number="2160" updated="2018-06-02T07:10:57Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Enlistment Opportunity Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, relating to enlistment and consequences of certain service in the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Military Enlistment Opportunity Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000360"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2015-10-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="3698"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Military Enlistment Opportunity Act of 2015

Amends citizenship and residency qualifications for enlistment in the U.S. Armed Forces to permit enlistment of additional persons who: (1) have resided continuously in a lawful status in the United States for at least two years, or (2) possess an employment authorization document issued by U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services under requirements of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) policy entitled Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals.

 Requires authorized enlistees who are not citizens or other nationals of the United States or lawfully admitted for permanent residence to be adjusted to the status of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence under an exception to specified provisions of Immigration and Nationality Act. (Such enlistees need not establish that they entered the United States prior to January 1, 1972, or comply with other specified requirements.)

Directs DHS to rescind such adjusted status if the person is separated from the armed forces under other than honorable conditions before the person served for a period or periods aggregating five years.

Deems any person who has received an award from the U.S. Armed Forces for engagement in active combat or active participation in combat to have satisfied specified naturalization requirements.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
