<bill session="114" type="h" number="1128" updated="2018-06-02T02:25:13Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Veterans Affairs Cyber Security Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to make certain improvements in the information security of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Department of Veterans Affairs Cyber Security Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000368"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2015-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000382" joined="2015-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" code="HSVR08" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-26T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Department of Veterans Affairs Cyber Security Protection Act 

 Directs the Assistant Secretary of Veterans Affairs for Information and Technology to submit to the congressional veterans committees (under current law only to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs) quarterly reports on Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) compliance with federally-required information security improvements.

Directs the Assistant Secretary to submit to such committees: (1) quarterly, a plan of action to address critical known VA information security vulnerabilities; and (2) annually, a plan for identifying and replacing VA operating systems that are out-of-date or unsupported.

 Directs the Assistant Secretary to ensure that any software or Internet applications used on VA operating systems are secure from vulnerabilities that could affect the confidentiality of sensitive personal information on veterans.

Directs the Secretary to:

 report quarterly to such committees on any incidents of failure to comply with established information security policies, any actions taken in response to such incidents, and certain related information; submit a strategic plan to such committees for improving VA information security and to update such plan at least every two years; and report to such committees within five years on information security protection and accountability of the VA for information security breeches and incidents. Requires VA contractors with access to sensitive personal information to provide protective measures to safeguard from possible information security threats any information provided by the VA that will be resident on, or transiting through, information systems controlled by that contractor.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
