<bill session="114" type="h" number="3941" updated="2019-04-11T15:41:47Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-11-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-11-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for emergency preparedness for energy supply disruptions.</title>
    <title type="display">To provide for emergency preparedness for energy supply disruptions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000567"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy" code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="8"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="22"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-11-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">The Department of Energy (DOE) shall adopt procedures to:

 improve communication and coordination between DOE's energy response team, federal partners, and industry; leverage the Energy Information Administration's subject matter expertise within DOE's energy response team to improve supply chain situation assessments; establish company liaisons and direct communication with DOE's energy response team to improve situation assessments; streamline and enhance processes for obtaining temporary regulatory relief to speed up emergency response and recovery; facilitate and increase engagement among states, the oil and natural gas industry, and DOE in developing state and local energy assurance plans; establish routine education and training programs for key government emergency response positions with DOE and states; and involve states and the oil and natural gas industry in comprehensive drill and exercise programs. These activities shall include collaborative efforts with state and local government officials and the private sector.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
