<bill session="115" type="s" number="3704" updated="2019-04-18T16:46:39Z">
  <state datetime="2018-12-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-12-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the San Gabriel National Recreation Area as a unit of the National Park System in the State of California, to modify the boundaries of the San Gabriel Mountains National Monument in the State of California to include additional National Forest System land, to designate certain Federal land in the State of California as wilderness areas and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System, to designate portions of the San Gabriel River and Little Rock Creek in that State as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">San Gabriel Mountains Foothills and Rivers Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">San Gabriel Mountains Foothills and Rivers Protection Act</title>
    <title type="display">San Gabriel Mountains Foothills and Rivers Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001075"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-12-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2323"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-12-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">San Gabriel Mountains Foothills and Rivers Protection Act

This bill establishes the San Gabriel National Recreation Area in California, establishes the San Gabriel National Recreation Area Public Advisory Council and the San Gabriel National Recreation Area Partnership, modifies the boundaries of the San Gabriel Mountains National Monument in California, designates specified National Forest System lands in Angeles National Forest in California as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System, and designates specified river segments in California as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
