<bill session="114" type="h" number="6301" updated="2018-11-21T20:31:14Z">
  <state datetime="2016-11-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-11-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-11-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Honor Our National Guard Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for certain requirements and limitations relating to the recoupment of bonuses and similar payments made to members of the uniformed services, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Honor Our National Guard Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001285"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-11-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-11-14T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Honor Our National Guard Act

This bill prohibits the department concerned (the Department of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Homeland Security, Commerce, or Health and Human Services) from requiring the repayment by a member of the uniformed services of any bonus or similar payment under provisions regarding special pay and repayment of an unearned portion of a bonus, incentive pay, or a similar benefit unless the Department, in the case of such a required repayment for failure to perform the required service:

 obtains a signed statement from a commanding officer of at least at the grade of O-6 in the member's chain of command, provides notice to the member of the intent to require repayment, and provides specified notice for the member to respond and provide evidence that the member fulfilled the required service. In the case of such a required repayment by reason that the contract providing for the payment of the bonus is found invalid, the department shall:

 appoint an investigating officer; confirm that such officer determines that the member committed fraud or did not complete the service requirement; and obtain the written concurrence of a general or flag officer in the member's chain of command. The department shall repay, and pay interest on, any amount a member repaid the Department of Defense for a bonus or similar payment the contract for which was found to be invalid.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
