<bill session="114" type="h" number="3242" updated="2018-11-21T21:40:13Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Child Nicotine Poisoning Prevention Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Child Nicotine Poisoning Prevention Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require special packaging for liquid nicotine containers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Child Nicotine Poisoning Prevention Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001284"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000293" joined="2015-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-09-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-01-11">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 114-394.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-01-11" calendar="Union" number="297">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 297.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="142"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-01-11T14:13:34Z" status="Reported to House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Child Nicotine Poisoning Prevention Act of 2015

(Sec. 2) This bill requires any nicotine provided in a liquid nicotine container sold, offered for sale, manufactured for sale, distributed in commerce, or imported into the United States to be packaged in accordance with the Consumer Product Safety Commission's (CPSC's) standards and testing procedures for special packaging that is difficult for children under five years of age to open or to obtain harmful contents from. The requirement must be treated as a standard for the special packaging of a household substance under the Poison Prevention Packaging Act of 1970.

"Liquid nicotine container" is defined to: (1) include a package from which nicotine in a solution or other form is accessible through normal and foreseeable use by a consumer and that is used to hold soluble nicotine in any concentration; and (2) exclude a sealed, pre-filled, and disposable container of nicotine in a solution or other form in which such container is inserted directly into an electronic cigarette, electronic nicotine delivery system, or other similar product, if the nicotine in the container is inaccessible through customary or reasonably foreseeable handling or use, including reasonably foreseeable ingestion or other contact by children.

The bill applies to any form of chemical nicotine, including any salt or complex, regardless of whether the chemical is naturally or synthetically derived.

The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must consult with the CPSC if HHS maintains, enforces, imposes, or continues in effect any packaging requirement for liquid nicotine containers, including a child-resistant packaging requirement.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-394</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
