<bill session="115" type="h" number="2757" updated="2019-04-18T16:09:56Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a National Center for Violence Prevention, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Health Violence Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Health Violence Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="display">Public Health Violence Prevention Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Q000023"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2018-06-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Public Health Violence Prevention Act

This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to establish the National Center for Violence Prevention in the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to take over the duties and authorities relating to violence prevention&#160;from the National Center for Injury Prevention and Control. The National Center for Violence Prevention, to address violence and prevention as health issues, must establish:&#160;(1) the Public Health Violence Prevention Program to award competitive grants&#160;to public health departments, schools of public health, criminal justice agencies, and public school districts, with preference given to projects serving areas with the highest rates of violence or the highest increases in violence; and (2) the Private Health Care Sector Violence Prevention Program to award competitive grants to health care providers, community-based organizations, and academic medical centers.

The bill establishes the National Health Violence Prevention Program with the following offices and programs:

 the Office of Applied Violence Prevention Research, the National Advisory Board on Violence Prevention, the Violence Prevention Training Program, the Office of Data Collection and Evaluation, and&#160; the Office of Violence Prevention Education and Outreach. The Department of Health and Human Services must rename the Office of Noncommunicable Diseases, Injury, and Environmental Health as the Office of Noncommunicable Diseases, Violence, Injury, and Environmental Health.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
