<bill session="114" type="s" number="927" updated="2018-06-02T06:44:58Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CLEAR Plus Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide regulatory relief for certain financial institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">CLEAR Plus Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000934"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2015-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2016-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2015-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2015-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-23">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 114-366.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1523"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1816"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">CLEAR Plus Act of 2015

This bill amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to: (1) subject a savings and loan holding company to registration requirements for securities whose issuer has total assets exceeding $10 million and a class of non-exempt equity security held of record by 2,000 or more persons; and (2) apply the automatic termination of registration, and suspension of the duty to file supplementary and periodic information, to a savings and loan holding company whose securities are found to be held by less than 1,200 persons.

The Federal Deposit Insurance Act is amended to require the federal banking agencies to issue regulations allowing for a reduced reporting requirement for certain depository institutions when making the first and third report of condition for a year. These reporting requirements apply to any insured depository institution that:

 as of the most recent examination has a CAMELS composite rating of 1 or 2 under the Uniform Financial Institutions Rating System (or an equivalent rating under a comparable rating system) for capital adequacy, assets, management capability, earnings, liquidity or asset liability management, and sensitivity to market risk; and satisfies other appropriate criteria as such agencies determine.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
