<bill session="115" type="h" number="2924" updated="2019-04-18T16:11:23Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Security Act of 1947 to establish the National Russian Threat Response Center within the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the National Security Act of 1947 to establish the National Russian Threat Response Center within the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000379"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2017-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001101" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000610" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000375" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000562" joined="2017-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2017-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000015" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000187" joined="2017-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), and in addition to the Committee on Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), and in addition to the Committee on Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="6437"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Director of National Intelligence"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill amends the National Security Act of 1947 to establish within the Office of the Director of National Intelligence (DNI) a National Russian Threat Response Center.

The primary missions of the center shall be:

 to serve as the primary U.S. government organization for analyzing and integrating all intelligence pertaining to threats posed by the Russian Federation to the national security, political sovereignty, and economic activity of the United States and its allies; to synchronize the efforts of the intelligence community regarding countering efforts by Russia to undermine such security, sovereignty, and activity; in coordination with the relevant elements of the Department of State, the Department of Defense, the intelligence community, and other U.S. agencies, to develop policy recommendations for the President to detect, deter, and respond to such threats and to monitor and assess Russian efforts to carry out such threats; in coordination with the Global Engagement Center, to examine Russian efforts to use propaganda and information operations relating to such threats; and to identify and close gaps across federal agencies with respect to expertise, readiness, and planning to address such threats. The Director of the center shall be appointed by the DNI with the concurrence of the State Department. The Director shall: (1) ensure that the relevant federal agencies participate in the center's mission, and (2) have primary responsibility for establishing requirements for collecting intelligence regarding threats posed by Russia.

A Board of the center is established to conduct oversight.

The Director may convene biannual conferences to coordinate international efforts against such threats.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
