<amendment session="114" chamber="h" number="1337" updated="2019-02-17T14:41:31Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5538" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2016-07-13T18:15:51-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001191"/>
  <offered datetime="2016-07-13"/>
  <description>At the end of the bill (before the short title), insert the following:    SEC.__. None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to carry out seismic airgun testing or seismic airgun surveys in the Eastern Gulf of Mexico Outer Continental Shelf Planning Area, the Straits of Florida Outer Continental Shelf Planning Area, or the South Atlantic Outer Continental Shelf Planning Area located within the exclusive economic zone (as defined in section 107 of title 46, United States Code) bordering the State of Florida.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment No. 72 printed in House Report 114-683 to prohibit use of funds to carry out seismic airgun testing or seismic airgun surveys in the OCS Planning Areas located within the EEZ bordering the State of Florida.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2016-07-13T18:15:51-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="451">
      <text>On agreeing to the Murphy (FL) amendment (A058) Failed by recorded vote: 197 - 231 (Roll no. 451).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13T01:36:54-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A058) offered by Mr. Murphy (FL).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4808-4809" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4808" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13"/>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13T18:15:51-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13T18:15:51-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13T18:15:51-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Murphy (FL) amendment (A058) Failed by recorded vote: 197 - 231 (Roll no. 451).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13T01:36:54-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A058) offered by Mr. Murphy (FL).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4808-4809" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4808" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-13">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
