<bill session="114" type="hr" number="955" updated="2019-02-06T19:37:29Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the progress of peace and justice, accountability, and reconciliation in Sri Lanka after 26 years of a debilitating armed conflict, and support for inclusive development and a strong and enduring relationship between the United States and Sri Lanka.</title>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the progress of peace and justice, accountability, and reconciliation in Sri Lanka after 26 years of a debilitating armed conflict, and support for inclusive development and a strong and enduring relationship between the United States and Sri Lanka.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000616" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000034" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000523" joined="2016-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000580" joined="2016-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-08T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Commends: (1) the people of Sri Lanka for their commitment to democracy, and (2) President Sirisena and Prime Minister Wickremesinghe for their commitment to peace and reconciliation for all Sri Lankans.

 Calls on the government of Sri Lanka to fulfill the commitments it has made to all communities, ethnicities, and religions and its commitments under United Nations Human Rights Council Resolution A/HRC/30/L.29.

Expresses support for:

 Sri Lanka's continuing efforts to rid the country of land mines; the normalization of the military presence of Sri Lanka; the Sri Lankan government's efforts to provide a peace dividend to the people of Sri Lanka, including by advancing accountability, reconciliation, devolution of power, broad-based economic development, and further integrating the Sri Lankan economy into the global trading system; and U.S. assistance in the development of Sri Lanka.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
