<bill session="114" type="s" number="303" updated="2018-06-02T06:32:29Z">
  <state datetime="2015-01-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Employee Tax Accountability Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 5, United States Code, to provide that individuals having seriously delinquent tax debts shall be ineligible for Federal employment.</title>
    <title type="display">Federal Employee Tax Accountability Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000307"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2015-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2015-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000127" joined="2015-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S619-620" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1206"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1563"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-01-29T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Federal Employee Tax Accountability Act of 2015

Makes any&#160;individual who has a seriously delinquent tax debt ineligible to receive a bonus from a federal agency (i.e., an executive agency, the U.S. Postal Service, the Postal Regulatory Commission, or an employing agency in the legislative branch). Defines "seriously delinquent tax debt" as an outstanding tax debt for which a notice of lien has been filed in public records. Exempts a tax debt: (1) that is being paid in a timely manner under an approved installment payment agreement or an offer-in-compromise, (2) for which a collection due process hearing has been requested or pending, (3) for which a levy has been issued or agreed to by an applicant for employment, or (4) that is determined to be an economic hardship to the taxpayer.

Requires each agency to review public records to determine if a notice of tax lien has been filed against an agency employee or applicant for employment.&#160;Prohibits an agency head or agency employee from using or disclosing tax delinquency information other than for the administration of this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
