<bill session="113" type="s" number="2608" updated="2016-10-25T16:31:29Z">
  <state datetime="2014-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improved National Monument Designation Process Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for congressional approval of national monuments and restrictions on the use of national monuments, to establish requirements for the declaration of marine national monuments, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Improved National Monument Designation Process Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2014-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000127" joined="2014-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="4988"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-07-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Improved National Monument Designation Process Act - Amends the Antiquities Act of 1906 to bar the President from declaring any area of the exclusive economic zone to be a national monument unless:

 the declaration is specifically authorized by an Act of Congress; the President has submitted a proposal to make such declaration to the governor of each state, and of each territory, any part of which is located within 100 nautical miles of the proposed national monument; each governor submits to the President a notice that the legislature of that state or territory has approved the proposal; and the declaration is substantially the same as the proposal. Prohibits the Department of the Interior or the Department of Commerce, with respect to any area of the exclusive economic zone that is designated as a national monument, from implementing any restrictions on the public use of such a national monument until the expiration of a review period providing for public input and congressional approval.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
