<bill session="115" type="s" number="1383" updated="2019-04-18T16:37:14Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify safe harbor requirements applicable to automatic contribution arrangements, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Retirement Security Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Retirement Security Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Retirement Security Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2017-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3651-3652" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="854"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3902"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2526"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Retirement Security Act of 2017 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to modify various requirements for employer-provided retirement plans.

The bill modifies the qualification requirements for certain multiple employer plans with pooled providers. The bill applies to defined contribution plans that: (1) are sponsored by employers all of which have both a common interest other than having adopted the plan and control of the plan, or (2) have a pooled plan provider. Such a plan that meets specified requirements may not be disqualified or otherwise lose its tax-favored status because a participating employer fails to take actions required with respect to the plan.

The bill also: (1) permits pooled employer plans that meet certain requirements to be treated under ERISA as a single employee pension benefit plan or single pension plan that is a multiple employer plan, and (2) modifies reporting requirements for pooled employer and multiple employer plans.

With respect to 401(k) retirement plans, the bill: (1) modifies requirements related to default rates for elective deferrals under automatic enrollment plans, the election of safe harbor 401(k) status, and nondiscrimination rules; (2) allows a business-related safe harbor adoption tax credit for small employers, and (3) requires the Department of the Treasury to simplify regulations regarding the timing of participant notices.

The bill also: (1) increases the limit on the amount of the credit for small employer pension plan startup costs, (2) allows a business-related tax credit for small employers who include and maintain an automatic contribution arrangement in an employer-sponsored retirement plan, and (3) requires Treasury to modify tax forms to permit individuals to claim the saver's credit on Form 1040EZ.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
