<bill session="114" type="s" number="864" updated="2018-06-02T06:44:38Z">
  <state datetime="2015-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Nursing Shortage Reform and Patient Advocacy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish direct care registered nurse-to-patient staffing ratio requirements in hospitals, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">National Nursing Shortage Reform and Patient Advocacy Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000711"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2015-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2015-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2015-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2015-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1602"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-03-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Nursing Shortage Reform and Patient Advocacy Act

Amends the Public Health Service Act to require hospitals to implement and submit to the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) a staffing plan that complies with specified minimum nurse-to-patient ratios by unit. Requires HHS to develop a transparent method for establishing nurse staffing requirements above minimum ratios.

Directs HHS to adjust Medicare payments to hospitals to cover additional costs incurred in providing services to Medicare beneficiaries that are attributable to compliance with such ratios.

Gives nurses the right to act as the patient's advocate by initiating action to improve health care and by giving the patient an opportunity to make informed health care decisions. Allows a nurse to object to, or refuse to participate in, any assignment if it would violate minimum ratios or if the nurse is not prepared by education or experience to fulfill the assignment without compromising the safety of a patient or jeopardizing the nurse's license. Prohibits a hospital from: (1) taking specified actions against a nurse based on the nurse's refusal to accept an assignment for such a reason; or (2) discriminating against any individual for good faith complaints relating to the care, services, or conditions of the hospital or of any related facilities.

Adds stipends to the nurse workforce loan repayment and scholarship program. Expands the nurse retention grant program to authorize programs to implement nurse preceptorship and mentorship projects.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
