<bill session="114" type="sr" number="71" updated="2018-06-02T06:15:47Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-05">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution designating the week of February 8 through February 14, 2015, as "Internet Governance Awareness Week".</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution designating the week of February 8 through February 14, 2015, as "Internet Governance Awareness Week".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2015-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2015-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2015-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2015-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2015-02-05" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S842" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S841" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-02-05T13:40:15Z" status="Passed Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

(Sec. 1) Designates the week of February 8-February 14, 2015, as Internet Governance Awareness Week to:

 increase public awareness of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration's announcement on March 14, 2014, regarding its intent to transition stewardship of the Internet Assigned Numbers Authority to the global multistakeholder community, and call the attention of the participants at the next global meeting of the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers (ICANN) to the importance of designing accountability and governance reforms to prepare ICANN for executing the responsibilities that it may receive under such a transition. Calls attention to reforms that would:

 insist that the domain name system continues to function as part of a secure, stable, resilient, single, decentralized, open, and interoperable Internet; separate policymaking, implementation, and dispute resolution functions; limit and maintain ICANN's authority to coordinate Internet unique identifiers; protect ICANN from undue influence or capture by governments, multilateral or intergovernmental organizations, or commercial or noncommercial stakeholders; maintain ICANN's commitment for final action regarding key policy decisions to demonstrate broad support by ICANN stakeholders; expand transparency measures to ensure community access to ICANN documents and records; and be incorporated into ICANN's articles of incorporation and by-laws, subject to independent adjudication or arbitration. (Sec. 2) Prohibits this resolution from being construed as congressional approval of any ICANN transition proposal.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
