<bill session="114" type="s" number="2987" updated="2019-04-11T15:46:39Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Transportation Security Administration to establish pilot programs to develop and test airport security systems, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe, Convenient, Reliable, Efficient, Effective, Next-Generation, Functional, and Secure TSA Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SCREEN FAST Act</title>
    <title type="display">SCREEN FAST Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000562"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Safe, Convenient, Reliable, Efficient, Effective, Next-Generation, Functional, and Secure TSA Act of 2016 or the SCREEN FAST Act

This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) of the Department of Homeland Security to establish a pilot program at three category X airports to reconfigure and install security systems that increase efficiency and reduce vulnerabilities in airport terminals, particularly those that have large open areas where screening occurs.

The TSA shall also establish a pilot program at those airports to develop and test prototypes of screening security systems and security checkpoint configurations to expedite the movement of passengers by deploying an array of technologies including passive and active systems, new types of security baggage and passenger screening systems, and new systems to address passenger and baggage anomalies.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
