<bill session="113" type="h" number="5865" updated="2016-10-25T16:17:50Z">
  <state datetime="2014-12-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CAM Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Camera Authorization and Maintenance Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a grant program providing for the acquisition, operation, and maintenance of body-worn cameras for law enforcement officers.</title>
    <title type="display">CAM Act of 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001061"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-12-11T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Camera Authorization and Maintenance Act of 2014 or the CAM Act of 2014 - Prohibits a state or local government that does not require its law enforcement officers to use body-worn cameras from receiving any grant from the Attorney General in the following fiscal year, subject to a financial hardship waiver.

Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to authorize the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance to make grants to states, local governments, and Indian tribes for the acquisition, operation, and maintenance of body-worn cameras for law enforcement officers. Sets forth requirements for the wearing and use of such body cameras and for recordings made. Requires funds to be awarded to each qualifying local government with fewer than 100,000 residents, with any remaining funds awarded to other qualifying applicants on a pro rata basis.

Establishes in the Department of Justice (DOJ) a task force to:

 provide recommendations on community policing; develop proper body-worn camera training protocol; study the impact that citizen review boards could have on investigating cases of alleged police misconduct; and conduct a survey, one year after implementation of the body camera requirement policy, to determine best practices and policy effectiveness. Directs the Comptroller General to submit a report on the Department of Defense Excess Personal Property Program that includes information on which jurisdictions equipment is sent to, the value of equipment sent to each jurisdiction, the level of training provided, and how the equipment is used.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
