<bill session="114" type="h" number="6144" updated="2018-11-09T00:09:37Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accurate Accounting Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to include the outlays and revenue totals relating to social security benefits in a concurrent resolution on the budget, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Accurate Accounting Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000560"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Social Security" code="HSWM01" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="identical" number="2513"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Accurate Accounting Act of 2016 

This bill amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 and the Budget Enforcement Act of 1990 to permit Social Security spending and revenues to be counted in the totals included in the congressional budget resolution and the President's budget.

The bill amends the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010 (PAYGO) to prohibit increases in Social Security revenues or decreases in Social Security spending from being counted as savings for the purpose of PAYGO rules that restrict legislation that increases the deficit.

(Under current law, the Social Security trust funds are off-budget and all budgetary effects are excluded from the budget totals and PAYGO calculations.)

The President must submit a budget for each department and agency that includes:

 a description of each activity for which funds were appropriated for the current year or requested for the budget year, the legal basis for each activity, three alternative funding levels and the priorities that could be accomplished with each, and measures of cost efficiency and effectiveness for each activity. The Office of Management and Budget must publish guidelines to require: (1) the baseline budget of each department or agency to be assumed to be zero, and (2) each proposed expenditure to be justified as if it were new.

The Government Accountability Office must revise a study of mandatory spending required under current law at least every five years.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
