<bill session="115" type="s" number="2061" updated="2019-04-18T16:40:02Z">
  <state datetime="2017-11-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-11-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-11-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to further deployment of Next Generation 9-1-1 services to enhance and upgrade the Nation's 9-1-1 systems, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Next Generation 9-1-1 Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Next Generation 9&#8211;1&#8211;1 Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="display">Next Generation 9-1-1 Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2018-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2017-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2018-04-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-11-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="4672"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-11-02T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Next Generation 9-1-1 Act of 2017

This bill amends the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act to require that the 911 Implementation Coordination Office (Office) assist and encourage federal, state, regional, and local entities to implement Next Generation 911 services. The bill eliminates the October 1, 2022, sunset date for the Office.

The Advisory Board for Next Generation 911 Interoperability is established within the&#160;Office to recommend updates to the definition of Next Generation 911 services.

The bill adds requirements for entities seeking federal grants to implement Next Generation 911 services and requires that the Department of&#160;Commerce and the National&#160;Highway Traffic Safety Administration issue&#160;new regulations accordingly. The bill authorizes additional appropriations for these grants through FY2022.

The Office&#160;shall provide support to entities in addressing cybersecurity issues related to Next Generation 911 services.&#160;The National Institute of Standards and Technology must identify cybersecurity vulnerabilities unique to implementing Next Generation 911 services, recommend best practices and assistance that the federal government can&#160;provide,&#160;and report its recommendations for protecting such services.

The Federal Communications Commission (FCC) must report about the adoption and adherence by: (1) telecommunications carriers to the FCC's network reliability best practices, and (2)&#160;public safety answering points to the public safety answering point&#160;best practices for cybersecurity as recommended by the Task Force on Optimal Public Safety Answering Point Architecture.&#160;(A public safety answering point is a facility designated to receive emergency calls and route the calls&#160;to emergency service personnel.)

The Government Accountability Office must report about the resiliency, reliability, and survivability of public safety answering points during natural disasters and other catastrophes.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
