<bill session="114" type="h" number="1195" updated="2018-09-07T15:04:15Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-22T14:33:34-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-04-22T14:33:34-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection Advisory Boards Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection Advisory Boards Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection Advisory Boards Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 to establish advisory boards, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection Advisory Boards Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000606"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001282" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000451" joined="2015-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001064" joined="2015-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001058" joined="2015-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000296" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2015-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2015-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000569" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001156" joined="2015-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001187" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001189" joined="2015-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000182" joined="2015-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000588" joined="2015-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000603" joined="2015-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2015-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2015-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001187" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000470" joined="2015-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000812" joined="2015-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-03-26" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 53 - 5.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-04-06">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 114-55.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-04-06" calendar="Union" number="36">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 36.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21T16:37:26-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 200.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2335-2343" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21T16:37:46-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 200 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21T16:37:47-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable John J. Duncan, Jr. to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21T16:38:19-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1195.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21T17:36:22-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Chair announced that pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 200, the amendment printed in part C of House Report 114-74 is adopted.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21T17:37:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 200, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kuster (NH) part D amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21T17:40:54-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Kuster (NH) part D No. 1 amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Maxine Waters demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21T17:41:50-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 200, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kuster (NH) part D amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21T17:46:38-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Neugebauer moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21T17:46:42-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-21T17:46:59-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1195 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22T13:58:09-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2378-2381" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22T13:58:26-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22T13:58:32-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of the Kuster (NH) amendment No. 1 printed in part D of House Report 114-74.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22T14:06:23-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1195.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22T14:07:18-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2379" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22T14:07:27-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2341-2342" label="text of measure as amended in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22T14:08:26-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Kuster moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Financial Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2379-2380" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2379" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22T14:08:55-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kuster motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to add at the end of the bill a section on prohibition against participation by persons employed by companies engaged in predatory practices related to servicemembers pending reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the reservation was removed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22T14:17:22-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2380" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22T14:25:55-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 184 - 234 (Roll no. 166).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="167" datetime="2015-04-22T14:33:34-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 235 - 183 (Roll no. 167).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22T14:33:35-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-23">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="114" relation="unknown" number="200"/>
    <bill type="s" session="114" relation="unknown" number="1963"/>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="5983"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h91"/>
    <amendment number="h90"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2015-04-22T13:33:35Z" status="Passed House amended">Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection Advisory Boards Act

 (Sec. 2) Amends the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 to direct the Director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) to establish a Small Business Advisory Board to: (1) advise and consult with the CFPB in the exercise of its functions under the federal consumer financial laws regarding eligible financial products or services, and (2) provide information on evolving small business practices.

Requires Board members to be representatives of small business concerns that:

 provide financial products or services for use by consumers primarily for personal, family, or household purposes, are service providers to covered persons; and use consumer financial products or services in financing the business activities of such small businesses. Requires the Director, in making such Board appointments, to include members representing minority-, women-, and veteran-owned small business concerns and their interests, without regard to party affiliation.

Requires the Director to establish a Credit Union Advisory Council and a Community Bank Advisory Council to advise and consult with the CFPB on consumer financial products or services that impact credit unions and community banks, respectively.

 Directs the Director, in making appointments to the Councils, to include members representing credit unions and community banks predominantly serving traditionally underserved communities and populations and their interests, without regard to party affiliation.

(Sec. 3) Prohibits the Director from requesting funds: (1) during FY 2020 in an amount that would exceed $655 million, and (2) during FY 2025 in an amount that would exceed $720 million.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-55</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
