<bill session="114" type="s" number="1149" updated="2018-06-02T06:46:29Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to require reporting of certain data by providers and suppliers of air ambulance services for purposes of reforming reimbursements for such services under the Medicare program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to require reporting of certain data by providers and suppliers of air ambulance services for purposes of reforming reimbursements for such services under the Medicare program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2015-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2016-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2015-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2015-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2015-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2015-04-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="114" relation="unknown" number="822"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-04-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services, with respect to air ambulance services furnished during 2017 or any subsequent year, to reduce the mandatory percentage increase (inflation adjustment) for payments under the fee schedule by 2.0% for any supplier or provider that fails to submit to the Secretary specified data.

The Secretary is required to select at least two quality measures with respect to which such providers and suppliers may voluntarily submit such data.

The Government Accountability Office is required to report to Congress on all such data, together with a recommendation on the adequate amount of Medicare reimbursement to providers and suppliers that would reflect their operational costs and preserve access to critical air medical services.

The Secretary is required, in the case of air ambulance services furnished during calendar 2017 through 2021 to make a percentage increase in the base rate of the fee schedule: (1) by 20% during 2017, and (2) by 5% during 2018-2020.

The Secretary must also, for 2017 through 2020, adjust such percentages, by either increasing or reducing them (but in no case below zero) to ensure that the increased expenditures under this Act are equal to the reduced expenditures.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
